<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP19769664B1" file="EP19769664NWB1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3811187" kind="B1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSK..HRIS..MTNORS..SM..................</B001EP><B003EP>*</B003EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  2100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3811187</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT SPECIFICATION</B121></B120><B130>B1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>19769664.4</B210><B220><date>20190830</date></B220><B240><B241><date>20200724</date></B241></B240><B250>en</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20210428</date><bnum>202117</bnum></B430><B450><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B450><B452EP><date>20210331</date></B452EP></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>G06F   3/01        20060101AFI20210305BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>G06F   3/017       20130101 FI20200421BHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>EINGABEVERFAHREN FÜR MOBILE VORRICHTUNGEN</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>INPUT METHODS FOR MOBILE DEVICES</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>PROCÉDÉS D'ENTRÉE POUR DISPOSITIFS MOBILES</B542></B540><B560><B561><text>US-A1- 2017 243 389</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2018 164 893</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2019 138 109</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2019 162 010</text></B561></B560></B500><B600><B620EP><parent><cdoc><dnum><anum>21191070.8</anum></dnum><date>20210812</date></cdoc></parent></B620EP></B600><B700><B720><B721><snm>STERN, Devon, James, O'Reilley</snm><adr><str>1600 Amphitheatre Parkway</str><city>Mountain View
California 94043</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>GIUSTI, Leonardo</snm><adr><str>1600 Amphitheatre Parkway</str><city>Mountain View
California 94043</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>SACHIDANANDAM, Vignesh</snm><adr><str>1600 Amphitheatre Parkway</str><city>MountainView
California 94043</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B730><B731><snm>Google LLC</snm><iid>101696670</iid><irf>GGL1786EP</irf><adr><str>1600 Amphitheatre Parkway</str><city>Mountain View, CA 94043</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B731></B730><B740><B741><snm>Maikowski &amp; Ninnemann 
Patentanwälte Partnerschaft mbB</snm><iid>101537572</iid><adr><str>Postfach 15 09 20</str><city>10671 Berlin</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840><B860><B861><dnum><anum>US2019049204</anum></dnum><date>20190830</date></B861><B862>en</B862></B860><B870><B871><dnum><pnum>WO2021040745</pnum></dnum><date>20210304</date><bnum>202109</bnum></B871></B870></B800></SDOBI>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<heading id="h0001"><b>BACKGROUND</b></heading>
<p id="p0001" num="0001">Electronic devices such as smartphones, wearable computers, and tablets, are powerful tools that are regularly relied upon for both business and personal use. The processing power of these devices is augmented by machine learning that helps the devices anticipate their users' preferences. For all this computing power and artificial intelligence, however, these devices are still reactive communicators. That is, however "smart" a smartphone is, and however much the user talks to it like it is a person, the electronic device is still dependent on being activated before it can provide feedback. To activate the mobile device, the user typically has to first pick up the device to make it aware of the user's intention to use the electronic device. Only after this physical interaction can the device make applications and functionality available for the user. Consequently, many electronic devices provide poor user experiences prior to explicit interaction by the user. <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US2019138109A1"><text>US 2019/138109 A1</text></patcit> discloses gesture detection and interaction techniques. Object detection used to support the gestures may be accomplished in a variety of ways, such as by using radio waves as part of a radar technique. In a first example, the techniques are implemented such that one hand of a user sets a context for a gesture that is defined by another hand of the user. In another example, a gesture recognition mode is utilized. In yet another example, detection of distance is used such that the same motions may be used to differentiate between operations performed. In a further example, split gestures are supported In another instance, entry into a gesture recognition mode may be implemented through touch and then recognized through three-dimensional orientation and motion of that hand or another. In yet another example, a computing device, using the radar technique, detects that a finger of a user's hand has approached within a predefined threshold distance. In response, the computing device establishes a starting point for user interaction with a user interface displayed by the computing device and outputs an visual indication as feedback. Subsequent movement of the finger of the user's hand causes corresponding movement of the visual indication, such that the user may readily determine where in the user interface the interaction is to occur.</p>
<p id="p0002" num="0002"><patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="US2018164893A1"><text>US 2018/164893 A1</text></patcit> discloses a method for assisting a user during interaction with a user interface, comprising detecting a crossing motion of an input means of the user in relation to a border of a detection region for detecting gestures freely executed in the area, and in<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> response thereto, displaying this crossing motion by means of a light strip in an edge region of a display device of the user interface.</p>
<p id="p0003" num="0003"><patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="US2017243389A1"><text>US 2017/243389 A1</text></patcit> discloses a device and a method for signaling a successful gesture input by means of a user. A user gesture is sensed and classified by a processing device. In response to the classified gesture, an animation may be generated that visually emphasizes a position that can change linearly at least in certain parts, along an edge of a screen assigned to the gesture input. If an application-related function cannot be executed in response to the recognised gesture, a different color scheme is used for the animation. In this way, the user obtains feedback as to whether the performed gesture has been recognized successfully and as to whether it has caused the launch of a function.</p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004"><patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="US2019162010A1"><text>US 2019/162010 A1</text></patcit> discloses a radar detection system for activation of a powered closure member (e.g., liftgate) of a vehicle. The radar detection system includes a visible indicator located on the vehicle to inform a user of the appropriate location to make an activation gesture which initiates opening of the closure member. The indicator is formed by a backlit picture of the closure member, wherein the backlight is only switched on when the radar detection system is activated.</p>
<heading id="h0002"><b>SUMMARY</b></heading>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">This document describes techniques and systems that enable input methods for mobile devices. The proposed solution is specified by a first independent claim referring to a method implemented in an electronic device (claim 1) and a second independent claim referring to an electronic device (claim 11). The techniques and systems use a radar field to enable an electronic device to accurately determine the presence or absence of a user near the electronic device. Further, the electronic device determines whether an application that can receive input through radar-based touch-independent gestures (radar gestures) is operating on the electronic device. Using these techniques, the electronic device presents a feedback indicator when the user's hand is within a gesture zone around the electronic device. The feedback indicator lets the user know, when radar-gesture input is generally available for interacting with the electronic device, that the user's hand is close enough to the electronic device to make specific radar gestures. This allows the device to provide the user with feedback, which can educate the user about what the electronic device is capable of and allow the user to take advantage of the additional functionality and features provided by the availability of the radar gesture.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">This summary is provided to introduce simplified concepts concerning the input methods for mobile devices, which is further described below in the Detailed Description and Drawings. This summary is not intended to identify essential features of the claimed subject matter, nor is it intended for use in determining the scope of the claimed subject matter.</p>
<heading id="h0003"><b>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</b></heading>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">The details of one or more aspects of input methods for mobile devices are described in this document with reference to the following drawings. The same numbers are used throughout the drawings to reference like features and components:
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li><figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates an example environment in which techniques enabling the input methods for mobile devices can be implemented.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates an example implementation of an electronic device, including a radar system, that can implement the input methods for mobile devices.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates an example implementation of the radar system of <figref idref="f0001">FIGS. 1</figref> and <figref idref="f0002">2</figref>.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0004">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates example arrangements of receiving antenna elements for the radar system of <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref>.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0005">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates additional details of an example implementation of the radar system of <figref idref="f0001">FIGS. 1</figref> and <figref idref="f0002">2</figref>.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0006">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates an example scheme that can be implemented by the radar system of <figref idref="f0001">FIGS. 1</figref> and <figref idref="f0002">2</figref>.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0007">FIG. 7</figref> depicts an example method that enables the input methods for mobile devices.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></li>
<li><figref idref="f0008 f0009 f0010 f0011 f0012">FIGS. 8-12</figref> illustrate visual elements, including the feedback indicator, which can be presented on the display of the electronic device of <figref idref="f0001">FIGS. 1</figref> and <figref idref="f0002">2</figref> when a radar-gesture application is running on the electronic device.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0013 f0014 f0015">FIGS. 13-15</figref> illustrate the electronic device of <figref idref="f0001">FIGS. 1</figref> and <figref idref="f0002">2</figref> operating in multiple modes with examples of the visual elements that can be presented on the display in the different modes.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0016">FIG. 16</figref> illustrates an example computing system that can be implemented as any type of client, server, and/or electronic device as described with reference to <figref idref="f0001 f0002 f0003 f0004 f0005 f0006 f0007 f0008 f0009 f0010 f0011 f0012 f0013 f0014 f0015">FIGS. 1-15</figref> to implement, or in which techniques may be implemented that enable, the input methods for mobile devices.</li>
</ul></p>
<heading id="h0004"><b>DETAILED DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
<heading id="h0005"><b>Overview</b></heading>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">This document describes techniques and systems that enable input methods for mobile devices. The described techniques employ a radar system that determines the user's presence (or absence) and location relative to the electronic device. The techniques also determine when the device is running an application that can receive input through radar-based touch-independent gestures. When the device is running one of these applications and a user is present, the techniques provide a feedback indicator, giving the user feedback that radar gestures can be received and are effective to control an application operating on the electronic device.</p>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">In this description, the terms "radar-based touch-independent gesture," "3D gesture," or "radar gesture" refer to the nature of a gesture in space, away from the electronic device (<i>e.g.,</i> the gesture does not require the user to touch the device, though the gesture does not preclude touch). The radar gesture itself may often only have an active informational component that lies in two dimensions, such as a radar gesture consisting of an upper-left-to-lower-right swipe in a plane, but because the radar gesture also has a<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> distance from the electronic device (a "third" dimension), the radar gestures discussed herein can be generally be considered three-dimensional.</p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">Using these techniques, the electronic device can provide feedback and a notification to make the user aware of the available radar-gesture input mode and, in some cases, provide feedback regarding the use and results of the radar gestures. A determination of the user's absence, presence, and location can also be used to provide a more-responsive and more-efficient authentication process. For example, the techniques enable the device to anticipate when the user is ready to be authenticated and to more-accurately determine when to lock the device when the user is away. Because the described techniques allow the electronic device to provide the user with useful feedback about available input modes, interactions may be more convenient and less frustrating because the user is aware of the input modes and can be confident about different ways in which the device can interact and receive input.</p>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">Consider an example smartphone that includes the described radar system. In this example, an application that has a capability to receive input through radar gestures is operating on the electronic device. This type of application will be referred to as a radar-gesture-subscribed application ("radar-gesture application"). Examples of radar-gesture applications include music players, media players, and applications or features of an electronic device that provide alerts or a reminder, such as a calendar. An interaction manager causes the electronic device to present a feedback indicator on a display of the device when the user's hand is within a gesture zone around the electronic device. The gesture zone is a volume around the electronic device within which the radar-gesture can be detected by the radar system. For example, the interaction manager can use radar data to determine that the user's hand is within a threshold distance (e.g., the gesture zone) from the electronic device. The threshold distance can be any suitable distance within which the radar system can recognize the user's hand, such as within three, five, seven, or nine inches. In some cases, the gesture zone may extend different threshold distances from the electronic device in different directions (e.g., it can have a wedged, oblong, ellipsoid, or asymmetrical shape). The size or shape of the gesture zone can also vary over time or be<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> based on other factors such as a state of the electronic device (e.g., battery level, orientation, locked or unlocked), or an environment (such as in a pocket or purse, in a car, or on a flat surface). Further, the gesture zone can have multiple sub-zones that correspond to different feedback indicators. For example, a primary feedback indicator can be presented when the user enters the outer limit of the gesture zone. Then as the user (e.g., the user's hand) gets closer to the electronic device, then a property of the feedback indicator can change <i>(e.g.,</i> it gets brighter, less or more transparent, changes color, changes size or shape). When the user withdraws, the feedback indicator can change in an inverse order.</p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">The feedback indicator is a user-perceivable element, such as a visual element that is presented on the display of the electronic device that indicates that the user's hand is within the gesture zone. This informs the user that radar gestures can be used to interact with a radar-gesture application. For example, when a radar-gesture application is running on the electronic device, the display may present an icon, a contrasted lighting area <i>(e.g.,</i> an area that is brighter or dimmer than the surrounding area), or an area of different or contrasting color. In some cases, the feedback indicator may be a combination of one or more of these features. Thus, in this example, when the electronic device determines that a radar-gesture application is running while the user's hand is in the gesture zone, an illuminated line appears at or near the top edge of the display. In some implementations, this indicator can move in some relationship with movements by the user or otherwise dynamically alter its appearance to approximately represent movements of the user's hand within the gesture zone.</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">Additionally, the amount and kind of radar gestures may vary at different distances from the electronic device. For example, a gesture that dismisses an alarm or silences a ringer, such as a "swipe" gesture (left-to-right, right-to-left, or up and down), may be available at a particular distance, such as three to five feet. At closer distances (e.g., seven, nine, or twelve inches), more-detailed fine-motion gestures may be available, such as rubbing two fingers together to adjust a volume or brightness in small increments. The feedback indicator can provide information regarding these differences, as well. For<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> example, in the described example, the feedback indicator may be smaller, less bright, or have a different color when only the "swipe" gesture is available (at around three feet from the electronic device). But, at the close distance, when more or different gestures are available, the feedback indicator can enlarge, brighten, or become a different color.</p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">The described techniques and systems employ a radar system, along with other features, to provide a useful and rewarding user experience that changes based on the user's presence or absence and the operation of a radar-gesture application on the electronic device. Rather than relying only on the user's knowledge and explicit user input, the electronic device can provide feedback to the user to indicate that the device is aware of the user's location and alert the user to the features and functionality that are available.</p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">Some conventional electronic devices may include sensors, such as cameras, proximity sensors (<i>e.g</i>., capacitive or infra-red sensors), or accelerometers to determine the location of the user and adjust various functions of the electronic device based on the proximity of the user. For example, the electronic device may provide additional privacy or aesthetic value by turning off a display unless the user is within a predetermined distance. The conventional electronic device, however, typically cannot provide a useful and rich ambient experience that can educate the user about the capabilities of the electronic device. These are but a few examples of how the described techniques and devices may be used to enable input methods for mobile devices, other examples and implementations of which are described throughout this document. The document now turns to an example operating environment, after which example devices, methods, and systems are described.</p>
<heading id="h0006"><b>Operating Environment</b></heading>
<p id="p0016" num="0016"><figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates an example environment 100 in which techniques enabling input methods for mobile devices can be implemented. The example environment 100 includes an electronic device 102, which includes, or is associated with, a radar system 104, a persistent radar-based interaction manager 106 (interaction manager 106), and, optionally, one or more non-radar sensors 108 (non-radar sensor 108). The term "persistent," with reference to the radar system 104 or the interaction manager 106, means<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> that no user interaction is required to activate the radar system 104 (which may operate in various modes, such as a dormant mode, an engaged mode, or an active mode) or the interaction manager 106. In some implementations, the "persistent" state may be paused or turned off (<i>e.g.,</i> by a user). In other implementations, the "persistent" state may be scheduled or otherwise managed in accordance with one or more parameters of the electronic device 102 (or another electronic device). For example, the user may schedule the "persistent" state such that it is only operational during daylight hours, even though the electronic device 102 is on both at night and during the day. The non-radar sensor 108 can be any of a variety of devices, such as an audio sensor (<i>e.g</i>., a microphone), a touch-input sensor (<i>e.g.,</i> a touchscreen), or an image-capture device (<i>e.g.,</i> a camera or video-camera).</p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">In the example environment 100, the radar system 104 provides a radar field 110 by transmitting one or more radar signals or waveforms as described below with reference to <figref idref="f0003 f0004 f0005 f0006">FIGS. 3-6</figref>. The radar field 110 is a volume of space from which the radar system 104 can detect reflections of the radar signals and waveforms (<i>e.g</i>., radar signals and waveforms reflected from objects in the volume of space). The radar field 110 may be configured in multiple shapes, such as a sphere, a hemisphere, an ellipsoid, a cone, one or more lobes, or an asymmetric shape (<i>e.g</i>., that can cover an area on either side of an obstruction that is not penetrable by radar). The radar system 104 also enables the electronic device 102, or another electronic device, to sense and analyze reflections from an object in the radar field 110. The radar field 110 may be used to provide a recognition zone. The recognition zone is a volume around the radar system 104 that may extend any of a variety of distances from the radar system 104, such as approximately three, seven, ten, or fourteen feet (or approximately one, two, three, or four meters). The recognition zone may be the same or less than a maximum extent of the radar field 110. The recognition zone may be a static size or shape that is predefined, user-selectable, or determined via another method <i>(e.g.,</i> based on power requirements, remaining battery life, or another factor). In some cases, the recognition zone may be dynamically and automatically adjustable by the interaction manager 106 based on various factors, such as the velocity or location of the electronic device 102, a time of day, or a state of an<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> application running on the electronic device 102. The threshold distance of the recognition zone can be determined based on a number of relevant factors, such as battery level, location of the electronic device, velocity of the electronic device, or data received from one or more of the radar system, other sensors, or applications running on the electronic device.</p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">Some implementations of the radar system 104 are particularly advantageous as applied in the context of smartphones, such as the electronic device 102, for which there is a convergence of issues such as a need for low power, a need for processing efficiency, limitations in a spacing and layout of antenna elements, and other issues, and are even further advantageous in the particular context of smartphones for which radar detection of fine hand gestures is desired. Although the implementations are particularly advantageous in the described context of the smartphone for which fine radar-detected hand gestures are required, it is to be appreciated that the applicability of the features and advantages of the present invention is not necessarily so limited, and other implementations involving other types of electronic devices (e.g., as described with reference to <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>) are also within the scope of the present teachings.</p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">The object may be any of a variety of objects from which the radar system 104 can sense and analyze radar reflections, such as wood, plastic, metal, fabric, a human body, or human body parts (<i>e.g</i>., a foot, hand, or finger of a user of the electronic device 102). As shown in <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, the object is a hand 112 of a user of the electronic device 102. Based on the analysis of the reflections, the radar system 104 can provide radar data that includes various types of information associated with the radar field 110 and the reflections from the hand 112, as described with reference to <figref idref="f0003 f0004 f0005 f0006">FIGS. 3-6</figref> (<i>e.g.,</i> the radar system 104 can pass the radar data to other entities, such as the interaction manager 106).</p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">The radar data can be continuously or periodically provided over time, based on the sensed and analyzed reflections from the object (<i>e.g</i>., the hand 112 in the radar field 110). A position of the hand 112 can change over time (<i>e.g.,</i> the hand 112 may move within the radar field 110) and the radar data can thus vary over time corresponding to the changed positions, reflections, and analyses. Because the radar data may vary over time,<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> the radar system 104 provides radar data that includes one or more subsets of radar data that correspond to different periods of time. For example, the radar system 104 can provide a first subset of the radar data corresponding to a first time-period, a second subset of the radar data corresponding to a second time-period, and so forth. In some cases, different subsets of the radar data may overlap, entirely or in part (<i>e.g.,</i> one subset of the radar data may include some or all of the same data as another subset).</p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">The electronic device 102 also includes a display 114 and an application manager 116. The display 114 can include any suitable display device, such as a touchscreen, a liquid crystal display (LCD), thin film transistor (TFT) LCD, an in-place switching (IPS) LCD, a capacitive touchscreen display, an organic light emitting diode (OLED) display, an active-matrix organic light-emitting diode (AMOLED) display, super AMOLED display, and so forth. The display 114 is used to display visual elements that are associated with various modes of the electronic device 102, which are described in further detail herein with reference to <figref idref="f0010 f0011 f0012 f0013 f0014 f0015">FIGS. 10-15</figref>. The application manager 116 can communicate and interact with applications operating on the electronic device 102 to determine and resolve conflicts between applications (<i>e.g</i>., processor resource usage, power usage, or access to other components of the electronic device 102). The application manager 116 can also interact with applications to determine the applications' available input modes, such as touch, voice, or radar gestures, and communicate the available modes to the interaction manager 106.</p>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">The interaction manager 106 can be used to interact with or control various components of the electronic device 102 (<i>e.g.</i>, modules, managers, systems, interfaces, or one or more of the non-radar sensors 108). For instance, the interaction manager 106 (independently or through the application manager 116) determines that an application operating on the electronic device has a capability to receive radar-gesture input <i>(e.g.,</i> a radar-gesture application). The radar-gesture input is based on the radar data and received through the radar system 104. The interaction manager 106, or the radar system 104, can also use one or more subsets of the radar data to determine that a portion of the user, such as the hand 112, is within a gesture zone 118 of the electronic device 102. The<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> gesture zone 118 is a region or volume around the electronic device 102 within which the radar system 104 (or another module or application) can detect radar gestures and determine the action associated with the radar gesture. For example, the interaction manager 106 can detect a user's reach toward the electronic device 102. To do this, the interaction manager 106 can determine that the hand 112 is within a threshold distance (the gesture zone 118) of the electronic device 102, such as within three, five, seven, or nine inches of the electronic device 102. While the radar system 104 can detect objects within the radar field 110 at greater distances, the gesture zone 118 helps the electronic device 102 and the radar-gesture applications to distinguish between intentional radar gestures by the user and other kinds of motions that may resemble radar gestures.</p>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">The gesture zone 118 may be, in some cases, a fixed volume around the electronic device that has a static size and/or shape that is predefined, user-selectable, or determined via another method (<i>e.g.,</i> based on power requirements, remaining battery life, or another factor). In other cases, the gesture zone 118 may be a volume around the electronic device that is dynamically and automatically adjustable by the interaction manager 106, based on factors such as the velocity or location of the electronic device 102, a time of day, a state of an application running on the electronic device 102, or another factor. The threshold distance or gesture zone 118 can be determined based on a number of relevant factors, such as battery level, location of the electronic device, velocity of the electronic device, or data received from one or more of the radar system, other sensors, or applications running on the electronic device. The size and shape of the gesture zone 118 may be symmetrical or asymmetrical and the extent of the gesture (<i>e.g</i>., the threshold distance from the electronic device) may be different in different directions from the electronic device.</p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">When the interaction manager 106 determines that the radar-gesture application is operating on the electronic device and that the hand 112 (or other portion of the user) is within the gesture zone 118 of the electronic device 102, the interaction manager 106, in response, causes the display 114 to present a feedback indicator 120. Similarly, when the interaction manager 106 determines that the hand 112 (or other portion<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> of the user) is outside the gesture zone 118 of the electronic device 102 and/or that the radar-gesture application is no longer operating on the electronic device, the interaction manager 106 can, in response, cause the display 114 to stop presenting the feedback indicator 120. The feedback indicator 120 is a user-perceivable element, such as a visual element that appears on an active area of the display 114. The appearance of the feedback indicator 120 indicates that the hand 112 (or another portion of the user) is within the gesture zone 118 and that the radar-gesture application has the capability to receive radar-gesture input. The feedback indicator 120 can also be (or include) a light element that is not on the display (<i>e.g</i>., a light-emitting diode (LED) or an LED array mounted on a housing or bezel of the electronic device), a haptic element (<i>e.g</i>., a vibration element), and/or an audio element (<i>e.g</i>., a user-perceivable sound).</p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">In some implementations, before the determinations that the radar-gesture application is operating on the electronic device 102 and that the hand 112 (or other portion of the user) is within the gesture zone 118, the electronic device can be in a state in which the electronic device 102 or applications on the electronic device are capable of receiving radar gestures, but the radar system 104 or the interaction manager 106 prevents the electronic device or the application from receiving the gestures (<i>e.g</i>., because the user is not within the gesture zone). In these implementations, the determinations that the radar-gesture application is operating and that the hand 112 is within the gesture zone 118 cause the electronic device 102 to enter a state in which radar gestures are permitted (<i>e.g.,</i> in which the radar system 104 or the interaction manager 106 permit the electronic device and/or the application to receive the radar gestures).</p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">The feedback indicator 120 may be presented at or along an edge of the display 114. In this document, the phrases "at an edge" and "along an edge" refer to being near or adjacent to an edge (<i>e.g</i>., adjacent to the edge with no gap or with a gap such as one pixel, two pixels, three pixels, and so forth). The feedback indicator 120 may have any of a variety of shapes, sizes, colors, and other visual parameters or properties. Examples of the other visual parameters or properties include luminosity, color, contrast, shape, saturation, or opaqueness. Luminosity refers to the perceived brightness of an<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> object by a human, and modifying the luminosity may include modifying luminance (e.g., brightness), contrast, and/or opaqueness.</p>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">In some cases, the visual element may have an area that is a portion of the active area of the display 114 that has a luminosity or other visual property that is different from a luminosity or other visual property of another portion of the display 114 that is proximate to the visual element. In this case, the visual element may also have a segment of an exterior border that is within a threshold distance from an edge of the active area of the display (e.g., adjacent to the edge with no gap or with a gap such as one pixel, two pixels, three pixels, one millimeter, two millimeters, three millimeters). While some of these examples describe the feedback indicator 120 as presented at or along an edge of the display 114, the feedback indicator 120 may appear at a location on the display 114 that is not an edge. For example, the edge of the display 114 may include an area beginning at a border of the active area of the display 114 and extending a distance from the border that is no more than approximately 15 percent of a total length of the border of the display 114.</p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">Consider an example illustrated in <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>. A detail view 100-1 shows the hand 112 within the gesture zone 118. In the detail view 100-1, an example of the feedback indicator 120 is presented on an example display 114-1 with a higher level of luminosity, to indicate that the interaction manager 106 has detected the hand 112 <i>(e.g.,</i> the interaction manager 106 has used one or more subsets of radar data to determine that the hand 112 is within the gesture zone 118) and that at least one radar-gesture application is operating on the electronic device 102. Another detail view 100-2 shows the hand 112 outside the gesture zone 118. In the detail view 100-2, a visual element 122 is presented on an example display 114-2. The visual element 122 is shorter than, and has a reduced luminosity (e.g., a 30 percent or 50 percent reduction of the luminosity) relative to, the feedback indicator 120 to indicate that the interaction manager 106 has determined that the hand 112 is outside the gesture zone 118 (and/or that no radar-gesture application is operating on the electronic device 102).</p>
<p id="p0029" num="0029">In the example shown in <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, the feedback indicator 120 and the visual element 122 are both shown as a line located at a top edge of the electronic device 102. In<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> other implementations, the feedback indicator 120 and/or the visual element 122 may be another size, another shape, or be presented at another location. Further, the interaction manager 106 may use one or more subsets of the radar data to enable the feedback indicator 120 to track small motions of the hand 112 and to dynamically adjust a position of the feedback indicator 120 on the display 114. The dynamic adjustments to the position of the feedback indicator 120 can correspond to movement of the user's hand 112 (or other portion of the user) that is within the gesture zone 118. In addition to, or instead of, adjustments of the position of the feedback indicator 120, the interaction manager 106 can adjust other visual properties of the feedback indicator 120 (e.g., luminosity, color, contrast, shape, saturation, and/or opaqueness) in a way that corresponds to the movement of the hand 112. This allows the user to see the feedback indicator 120 move or otherwise provide dynamically responsive visual feedback that corresponds to the movement of the user's hand 112 <i>(e.g.,</i> back and forth, up and down, and so forth).</p>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">According to the present invention, the feedback indicator 120 is presented as an adjustment to a visual element that is already being presented at or along the edge of the active area of the display (<i>e.g.,</i> a previously presented visual element indicating that the application operating on the electronic device 102 has the capability to receive radar-gesture input). For example, in the example shown in <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, the detail view 100-2 shows a visual element 122 already being presented on the example display 114-2. When the user's hand 112 moves back into the gesture zone 118, the visual element 122 may be adjusted to become the example feedback indicator 120, as shown in the detail view 100-1. In this case, the user may withdraw the hand 112 and, if the radar-gesture application is still running, the interaction manager 106 may stop presenting the feedback indicator 120 and resume presenting the visual element 122.</p>
<p id="p0031" num="0031">As shown in <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, the adjustment to the previously presented visual element 122 is an increase in a length and luminosity of the visual element 122. In other cases, the adjustment may be a change in a size of the previously presented visual element 122. For example, the change in size may be an enlargement of an area of the previously presented visual element 122. The enlargement may include extending the previously presented<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> visual element 122 in a direction parallel to the edge of the active area of the display, in a direction away from the edge of the active area of the display, or both in the direction parallel to the edge of the active area of the display and in the direction away from the edge of the active area of the display. In other implementations, the adjustment may also or instead be a change in another visual property, such as a luminosity, a color, a contrast, a shape, a saturation, and/or an opaqueness.</p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032">In some implementations, the luminosity (or other visual parameter) of the feedback indicator 120 may vary as the feedback indicator 120 extends across a distance from the edge of the active area of the display 114 <i>(e.g.,</i> have a luminosity at or along the edge of the display 114 that decreases as the shape extends away from the edge, or vice versa). For example, the feedback indicator 120 may be presented as an area of the display 114 that has a different luminosity than another area of the display 114 <i>(e.g.,</i> an area surrounding or near to the feedback indicator 120) and that is adjacent to the edge of the display 114. In another example, the feedback indicator 120 may be presented as a line, with a predetermined thickness, that has a different luminosity than the display 114 and that is adjacent to the edge of the display 114.</p>
<p id="p0033" num="0033">The color of the feedback indicator 120 may be any suitable color that can be visually differentiated from the background of the display 114 on which it is presented. The color of the feedback indicator 120 may change based on any of a variety of factors, such as an operational state of the electronic device 102 or an ambient background color of the display 114. In some implementations, the interaction manager 106 can determine a background color of a region of the display 114 on which the feedback indicator 120 is, or will be, displayed. In response to determining the background color, the interaction manager 106 can cause the display 114 to present the feedback indicator 120 in another color that is different from the background color. The different color of the feedback indicator 120 can provide human-discernable contrast between the feedback indicator 120 and the background color to make it easier for the user to see the feedback indicator 120. In some cases, the interaction manager 106 can continuously, automatically, and<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> dynamically adjust the color of the feedback indicator 120, based on changes to the background color.</p>
<p id="p0034" num="0034">The feedback indicator 120, in some implementations, may appear, at least in part, as a brief animation. For example, the feedback indicator 120 may appear at the edge of the active display and then grow or shrink before taking on a default appearance. Similarly, the color, luminosity, or shape may change as the feedback indicator 120 appears or disappears (<i>e.g</i>., if the radar-gesture application stops operating) before taking on the default appearance.</p>
<p id="p0035" num="0035">In some cases, the feedback indicator 120 may be an image that appears on the display 114, rather than an element that appears in a region of the display 114. The image may have visual parameters that are different from the parameters of an ambient background of the display 114, such as luminosity, saturation, color, and so forth. In other cases, the ambient background may be an image, and the feedback indicator 120 is the same image, with different visual parameters, such as luminosity, saturation, color, and so forth. In this way, the feedback indicator 120 can improve the user's experience by communicating to the user that the electronic device is operating in a mode in which radar gestures are available for interacting with the electronic device 102. Additional details and examples of the feedback indicator 120 are described with reference to <figref idref="f0008">FIG. 8</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">In some implementations, the location of the feedback indicator 120 may be determined based on an orientation of content on the display 114. For example, the interaction manager 106 may obtain the orientation of the content on the display 114 from the application manager 116 (or from another source). The interaction manager 106 can also determine, based on the orientation of the content, a direction of the radar-gesture input that can be used to interact with the content. Based on the direction of the radar-gesture input, the interaction manager 106 can cause the display to present the feedback indicator 120 at a particular edge of the active area of the display 114 that corresponds to the direction of the radar-gesture input. Thus, if the context of the displayed content is horizontal (<i>e.g</i>., the direction of the radar gesture would be left-to-right or right-to-left), the feedback indicator 120 is displayed at a top or bottom edge, to help indicate to the user<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> that the radar gestures are horizontal. Similarly, if the context of the displayed content is vertical (e.g., the direction of the radar gestures would be bottom-to-top or top-to-bottom), the feedback indicator 120 is displayed at a side edge, to help indicate to the user that the radar gestures are vertical.</p>
<p id="p0037" num="0037">Further, the interaction manager 106 may also be able to detect a change in an orientation of the electronic device 102 with respect to the user. For example, the user may rotate the device from a vertical to a horizontal orientation to watch a video or from a horizontal to a vertical orientation to read an article. Based on the change in orientation, the interaction manager 106 can cause the display 114 to present the feedback indicator 120 on a different edge of the active display. This different edge can maintain an orientation and location of the feedback indicator 120 with respect to the user (<i>e.g</i>., the feedback indicator 120 moves or relocates as the orientation of the user to the device changes). Thus, if the feedback indicator 120 is positioned on a top edge of the display 114 and the user rotates the electronic device 102, the location of the feedback indicator 120 changes from one edge to another so that it remains on "top" with reference to the user. As noted, the interaction manager 106 also takes into account the orientation of the content, and these features can be used in conjunction with each other to present the feedback indicator 120 on the display 114 at the location appropriate for the orientation of both the content on the display 114 and the orientation of the display 114 with respect to the user.</p>
<p id="p0038" num="0038">In some implementations, the interaction manager 106 can determine that the radar-gesture application on the electronic device 102 is operating in an immersive mode, such as a full-screen mode without any presented controls. In response to this determination, the interaction manager can cause the display 114 to periodically present the feedback indicator 120. For example, the display 114 can present the feedback indicator 120 for a presentation time duration and then stop presenting the feedback indicator 120 for a non-presentation time duration. Both the presentation time duration and the non-presentation time duration may be predetermined or selectable. In some cases, the time durations may be user-selectable (<i>e.g</i>., by the user) or selected by the interaction<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> manager 106 based on various factors, such as the type of radar-gesture application running in the immersive mode (<i>e.g.,</i> a game or a streaming media player), the status of the radar-gesture application, or the frequency with which the user employs a radar gesture.</p>
<p id="p0039" num="0039">In some implementations, the feedback indicator 120 may fade or disappear entirely when the user interacts with the electronic device 102 using input other than a radar gesture (<i>e.g.,</i> a touch or voice input). For example, while a radar-gesture application is operating on the electronic device 102, the user may decide to start another application using a touch command. In this case, the feedback indicator 120 may fade or disappear when the user picks up the electronic device 102 or touches the display 114. When the user stops touching the display 114 or puts down the electronic device 102, the feedback indicator 120 reappears (or brightens) if one or more radar-gesture applications are operating on the electronic device 102. The feedback indicator 120 may reappear or brighten immediately when the touch or voice input ends, or after a selectable time duration. Similarly, when the radar-gesture application is an application that provides an alert or notification, the feedback indicator 120 appears when the alert or notification is displayed, such as when a calendar reminder is displayed. When the user interacts with the alert or notification using a radar gesture (<i>e.g</i>., dismisses or resets the alert or notification), the feedback indicator 120 disappears, unless other gesture-subscribed apps are running.</p>
<p id="p0040" num="0040">The feedback indicator 120 may be presented while the electronic device 102 is in a locked state or an unlocked state. For example, the electronic device 102 may present the feedback indicator 120 (to indicate that the hand 112 is within the gesture zone 118 and that the radar-gesture application is running) when a user is nearby (e.g., within the recognition zone), but not authenticated, or when an authenticated user is nearby. The locked and unlocked states refer to a level of access to the electronic device 102. A locked state may be a state in which no user is authenticated and anyone using the device will have less than full rights or access (<i>e.g</i>., no access or rights, or limited access or rights). Examples of the locked state may include the aware and engaged modes of the electronic device 102 as described herein. Similarly, an unlocked state can be a state in which at least<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> one user is authenticated, and that user has full rights and/or access to the device. An example of the unlocked state is the active mode of the electronic device 102, as described herein. In some cases, the locked or unlocked state may have varying characteristics, depending on the type, configuration, or status (<i>e.g</i>., a battery level or a connectivity status) of the electronic device 102. Accordingly, characteristics of the locked and unlocked states for different devices or for the same device in different contexts may overlap, or include similar features, depending on those factors.</p>
<p id="p0041" num="0041">In more detail, consider <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>, which illustrates an example implementation 200 of the electronic device 102 (including the radar system 104, the interaction manager 106, the non-radar sensor 108, the display 114, and the application manager 116) that can implement the input methods for mobile devices. The electronic device 102 of <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> is illustrated with a variety of example devices, including a smartphone 102-1, a tablet 102-2, a laptop 102-3, a desktop computer 102-4, a computing watch 102-5, a gaming system 102-6, computing spectacles 102-7, a home-automation and control system 102-8, a smart refrigerator 102-9, and an automobile 102-10. The electronic device 102 can also include other devices, such as televisions, entertainment systems, audio systems, drones, track pads, drawing pads, netbooks, e-readers, home security systems, and other home appliances. Note that the electronic device 102 can be wearable, non-wearable but mobile, or relatively immobile (<i>e.g</i>., desktops and appliances).</p>
<p id="p0042" num="0042">In some implementations, exemplary overall lateral dimensions of the electronic device 102 can be approximately eight centimeters by approximately fifteen centimeters. Exemplary footprints of the radar system 104 can be even more limited, such as approximately four millimeters by six millimeters with antennas included. This requirement for such a limited footprint for the radar system 104 is to accommodate the many other desirable features of the electronic device 102 in such a space-limited package <i>(e.g.,</i> a fingerprint sensor, the non-radar sensor 108, and so forth). Combined with power and processing limitations, this size requirement can lead to compromises in the accuracy and efficacy of radar gesture detection, at least some of which can be overcome in view of the teachings herein.<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --></p>
<p id="p0043" num="0043">The electronic device 102 also includes one or more computer processors 202 and one or more computer-readable media 204, which includes memory media and storage media. Applications and/or an operating system (not shown) implemented as computer-readable instructions on the computer-readable media 204 can be executed by the computer processors 202 to provide some or all of the functionalities described herein. For example, the processors 202 can be used to execute instructions on the computer-readable media 204 to implement the radar-based interaction manager 106 and/or the application manager 116. The electronic device 102 may also include a network interface 206. The electronic device 102 can use the network interface 206 for communicating data over wired, wireless, or optical networks. By way of example and not limitation, the network interface 206 may communicate data over a local-area-network (LAN), a wireless local-area-network (WLAN), a personal-area-network (PAN), a wide-area-network (WAN), an intranet, the Internet, a peer-to-peer network, point-to-point network, or a mesh network.</p>
<p id="p0044" num="0044">Various implementations of the radar system 104 can include a System-on-Chip (SoC), one or more Integrated Circuits (ICs), a processor with embedded processor instructions or configured to access processor instructions stored in memory, hardware with embedded firmware, a printed circuit board with various hardware components, or any combination thereof. The radar system 104 can operate as a monostatic radar by transmitting and receiving its own radar signals.</p>
<p id="p0045" num="0045">In some implementations, the radar system 104 may also cooperate with other radar systems 104 that are within an external environment to implement a bistatic radar, a multistatic radar, or a network radar. Constraints or limitations of the electronic device 102, however, may impact a design of the radar system 104. The electronic device 102, for example, may have limited power available to operate the radar, limited computational capability, size constraints, layout restrictions, an exterior housing that attenuates or distorts radar signals, and so forth. The radar system 104 includes several features that enable advanced radar functionality and high performance to be realized in the presence of these constraints, as further described below with respect to <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref>. Note<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> that in <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>, the radar system 104 and the interaction manager 106 are illustrated as part of the electronic device 102. In other implementations, either or both of the radar system 104 and the interaction manager 106 may be separate or remote from the electronic device 102.</p>
<p id="p0046" num="0046">These and other capabilities and configurations, as well as ways in which entities of <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> act and interact, are set forth in greater detail below. These entities may be further divided, combined, and so on. The environment 100 of <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> and the detailed illustrations of <figref idref="f0002 f0003 f0004 f0005 f0006 f0007 f0008 f0009 f0010 f0011 f0012 f0013 f0014 f0015">FIG. 2 through FIG. 15</figref> illustrate some of many possible environments and devices capable of employing the described techniques. <figref idref="f0003 f0004 f0005 f0006">FIGS. 3-6</figref> describe additional details and features of the radar system 104. In <figref idref="f0003 f0004 f0005 f0006">FIGS. 3-6</figref>, the radar system 104 is described in the context of the electronic device 102, but as noted above, the applicability of the features and advantages of the described systems and techniques are not necessarily so limited, and other implementations involving other types of electronic devices may also be within the scope of the present teachings.</p>
<p id="p0047" num="0047"><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates an example implementation 300 of the radar system 104 that can be used to enable the input methods for mobile devices. In the example 300, the radar system 104 includes at least one of each of the following components: a communication interface 302, an antenna array 304, a transceiver 306, a processor 308, and a system media 310 (<i>e.g.,</i> one or more computer-readable storage media). The processor 308 can be implemented as a digital signal processor, a controller, an application processor, another processor (e.g., the computer processor 202 of the electronic device 102) or some combination thereof. The system media 310, which may be included within, or be separate from, the computer-readable media 204 of the electronic device 102, includes one or more of the following modules: an attenuation mitigator 314, a digital beamformer 316, an angle estimator 318, or a power manager 320. These modules can compensate for, or mitigate the effects of, integrating the radar system 104 within the electronic device 102, thereby enabling the radar system 104 to recognize small or complex gestures, distinguish between different orientations of the user, continuously monitor an external environment, or realize a target false-alarm rate. With these features,<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> the radar system 104 can be implemented within a variety of different devices, such as the devices illustrated in <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0048" num="0048">Using the communication interface 302, the radar system 104 can provide radar data to the interaction manager 106. The communication interface 302 may be a wireless or wired interface based on the radar system 104 being implemented separate from, or integrated within, the electronic device 102. Depending on the application, the radar data may include raw or minimally processed data, in-phase and quadrature (I/Q) data, range-Doppler data, processed data including target location information (e.g., range, azimuth, elevation), clutter map data, and so forth. Generally, the radar data contains information that is usable by the interaction manager 106 for the input methods for mobile devices.</p>
<p id="p0049" num="0049">The antenna array 304 includes at least one transmitting antenna element (not shown) and at least two receiving antenna elements (as shown in <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 4</figref>). In some cases, the antenna array 304 may include multiple transmitting antenna elements to implement a multiple-input multiple-output (MIMO) radar capable of transmitting multiple distinct waveforms at a time (<i>e.g.,</i> a different waveform per transmitting antenna element). The use of multiple waveforms can increase a measurement accuracy of the radar system 104. The receiving antenna elements can be positioned in a one-dimensional shape (<i>e.g.,</i> a line) or a two-dimensional shape for implementations that include three or more receiving antenna elements. The one-dimensional shape enables the radar system 104 to measure one angular dimension (<i>e.g</i>., an azimuth or an elevation) while the two-dimensional shape enables two angular dimensions to be measured (e.g., both azimuth and elevation). Example two-dimensional arrangements of the receiving antenna elements are further described with respect to <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0050" num="0050"><figref idref="f0004">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates example arrangements 400 of receiving antenna elements 402. If the antenna array 304 includes at least four receiving antenna elements 402, for example, the receiving antenna elements 402 can be arranged in a rectangular arrangement 404-1 as depicted in the middle of <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 4</figref>. Alternatively, a triangular arrangement 404-2<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> or an L-shape arrangement 404-3 may be used if the antenna array 304 includes at least three receiving antenna elements 402.</p>
<p id="p0051" num="0051">Due to a size or layout constraint of the electronic device 102, an element spacing between the receiving antenna elements 402 or a quantity of the receiving antenna elements 402 may not be ideal for the angles at which the radar system 104 is to monitor. In particular, the element spacing may cause angular ambiguities to be present that make it challenging for conventional radars to estimate an angular position of a target. Conventional radars may therefore limit a field of view (e.g., angles that are to be monitored) to avoid an ambiguous zone, which has the angular ambiguities, and thereby reduce false detections. For example, conventional radars may limit the field of view to angles between approximately -45 degrees to 45 degrees to avoid angular ambiguities that occur using a wavelength of 5 millimeters (mm) and an element spacing of 3.5 mm (<i>e.g.,</i> the element spacing being 70% of the wavelength). Consequently, the conventional radar may be unable to detect targets that are beyond the 45-degree limits of the field of view. In contrast, the radar system 104 includes the digital beamformer 316 and the angle estimator 318, which resolve the angular ambiguities and enable the radar system 104 to monitor angles beyond the 45-degree limit, such as angles between approximately -90 degrees to 90 degrees, or up to approximately -180 degrees and 180 degrees. These angular ranges can be applied across one or more directions (<i>e.g</i>., azimuth and/or elevation). Accordingly, the radar system 104 can realize low false-alarm rates for a variety of different antenna array designs, including element spacings that are less than, greater than, or equal to half a center wavelength of the radar signal.</p>
<p id="p0052" num="0052">Using the antenna array 304, the radar system 104 can form beams that are steered or un-steered, wide or narrow, or shaped (<i>e.g</i>., as a hemisphere, cube, fan, cone, or cylinder). As an example, the one or more transmitting antenna elements (not shown) may have an un-steered omnidirectional radiation pattern or may be able to produce a wide beam, such as the wide transmit beam 406. Either of these techniques enable the radar system 104 to illuminate a large volume of space. To achieve target angular accuracies and angular resolutions, however, the receiving antenna elements 402 and the digital<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> beamformer 316 can be used to generate thousands of narrow and steered beams (e.g., 2000 beams, 4000 beams, or 6000 beams), such as the narrow receive beam 408. In this way, the radar system 104 can efficiently monitor the external environment and accurately determine arrival angles of reflections within the external environment.</p>
<p id="p0053" num="0053">Returning to <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref>, the transceiver 306 includes circuitry and logic for transmitting and receiving radar signals via the antenna array 304. Components of the transceiver 306 can include amplifiers, mixers, switches, analog-to-digital converters, filters, and so forth for conditioning the radar signals. The transceiver 306 can also include logic to perform in-phase/quadrature (I/Q) operations, such as modulation or demodulation. The transceiver 306 can be configured for continuous wave radar operations or pulsed radar operations. A variety of modulations can be used to produce the radar signals, including linear frequency modulations, triangular frequency modulations, stepped frequency modulations, or phase modulations.</p>
<p id="p0054" num="0054">The transceiver 306 can generate radar signals within a range of frequencies <i>(e.g.,</i> a frequency spectrum), such as between 1 gigahertz (GHz) and 400 GHz, between 4 GHz and 100 GHz, or between 57 GHz and 63 GHz. The frequency spectrum can be divided into multiple sub-spectra that have a similar bandwidth or different bandwidths. The bandwidths can be on the order of 500 megahertz (MHz), 1 GHz, 2 GHz, and so forth. As an example, different frequency sub-spectra may include frequencies between approximately 57 GHz and 59 GHz, 59 GHz and 61 GHz, or 61 GHz and 63 GHz. Multiple frequency sub-spectra that have a same bandwidth and may be contiguous or non-contiguous may also be chosen for coherence. The multiple frequency sub-spectra can be transmitted simultaneously or separated in time using a single radar signal or multiple radar signals. The contiguous frequency sub-spectra enable the radar signal to have a wider bandwidth while the non-contiguous frequency sub-spectra can further emphasize amplitude and phase differences that enable the angle estimator 318 to resolve angular ambiguities. The attenuation mitigator 314 or the angle estimator 318 may cause the transceiver 306 to utilize one or more frequency sub-spectra to improve performance of the radar system 104, as further described with respect to <figref idref="f0005">FIGS. 5</figref> and <figref idref="f0006">6</figref>.<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --></p>
<p id="p0055" num="0055">A power manager 320 enables the radar system 104 to conserve power internally or externally within the electronic device 102. In some implementations, the power manager 320 communicates with the interaction manager 106 to conserve power within either or both of the radar system 104 or the electronic device 102. Internally, for example, the power manager 320 can cause the radar system 104 to collect data using a predefined power mode or a specific gesture-frame update rate. The gesture-frame update rate represents how often the radar system 104 actively monitors the external environment by transmitting and receiving one or more radar signals. Generally speaking, the power consumption is proportional to the gesture-frame update rate. As such, higher gesture-frame update rates result in larger amounts of power being consumed by the radar system 104.</p>
<p id="p0056" num="0056">Each predefined power mode can be associated with a particular framing structure, a particular transmit power level, or particular hardware (<i>e.g.</i>, a low-power processor or a high-power processor). Adjusting one or more of these affects the radar system's 104 power consumption. Reducing power consumption, however, affects performance, such as the gesture-frame update rate and response delay. In this case, the power manager 320 dynamically switches between different power modes such that gesture-frame update rate, response delay and power consumption are managed together based on the activity within the environment. In general, the power manager 320 determines when and how power can be conserved, and incrementally adjusts power consumption to enable the radar system 104 to operate within power limitations of the electronic device 102. In some cases, the power manager 320 may monitor an amount of available power remaining and adjust operations of the radar system 104 accordingly. For example, if the remaining amount of power is low, the power manager 320 may continue operating in a lower-power mode instead of switching to a higher-power mode.</p>
<p id="p0057" num="0057">The lower-power mode, for example, may use a lower gesture-frame update rate on the order of a few hertz (<i>e.g</i>., approximately 1 Hz or less than 5 Hz), and consume power on the order of a few milliwatts (mW) (<i>e.g</i>., between approximately 2 mW and 4 mW). The higher-power mode, on the other hand, may use a higher gesture-frame update<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> rate on the order of tens of hertz (Hz) (<i>e.g.,</i> approximately 20 Hz or greater than 10 Hz), which causes the radar system 104 to consume power on the order of several milliwatts (e.g., between approximately 6 mW and 20 mW). While the lower-power mode can be used to monitor the external environment or detect an approaching user, the power manager 320 may switch to the higher-power mode if the radar system 104 determines the user is starting to perform a gesture. Different triggers may cause the power manager 320 to dynamically switch between the different power modes. Example triggers include motion or the lack of motion, appearance or disappearance of the user, the user moving into or out of a designated region (<i>e.g.,</i> a region defined by range, azimuth, or elevation), a change in velocity of a motion associated with the user, or a change in reflected signal strength (<i>e.g.</i>, due to changes in radar cross section). In general, the triggers that indicate a lower probability of the user interacting with the electronic device 102 or a preference to collect data using a longer response delay may cause a lower-power mode to be activated to conserve power.</p>
<p id="p0058" num="0058">Each power mode can be associated with a particular framing structure. The framing structure specifies a configuration, scheduling, and signal characteristics associated with the transmission and reception of the radar signals. In general, the framing structure is set up such that the appropriate radar data can be collected based on the external environment. The framing structure can be customized to facilitate collection of different types of radar data for different applications (e.g., proximity detection, feature recognition, or gesture recognition). During inactive times throughout each level of the framing structure, the power-manager 320 can turn off the components within the transceiver 306 in <figref idref="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> to conserve power. The framing structure enables power to be conserved through adjustable duty cycles within each frame type. For example, a first duty cycle can be based on a quantity of active feature frames relative to a total quantity of feature frames. A second duty cycle can be based on a quantity of active radar frames relative to a total quantity of radar frames. A third duty cycle can be based on a duration of the radar signal relative to a duration of a radar frame.<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --></p>
<p id="p0059" num="0059">Consider an example framing structure (not illustrated) for the lower-power mode that consumes approximately 2 mW of power and has a gesture-frame update rate between approximately 1 Hz and 4 Hz. In this example, the framing structure includes a gesture frame with a duration between approximately 250 ms and 1 second. The gesture frame includes thirty-one pulse-mode feature frames. One of the thirty-one pulse-mode feature frames is in the active state. This results in the duty cycle being approximately equal to 3.2%. A duration of each pulse-mode feature frame is between approximately 8 ms and 32 ms. Each pulse-mode feature frame is composed of eight radar frames. Within the active pulse-mode feature frame, all eight radar frames are in the active state. This results in the duty cycle being equal to 100%. A duration of each radar frame is between approximately 1 ms and 4 ms. An active time within each of the active radar frames is between approximately 32 µs and 128 µs. As such, the resulting duty cycle is approximately 3.2%. This example framing structure has been found to yield good performance results. These good performance results are in terms of good gesture recognition and presence detection while also yielding good power efficiency results in the application context of a handheld smartphone in a low-power state. Based on this example framing structure, the power manager 320 can determine a time for which the radar system 104 is not actively collecting radar data. Based on this inactive time period, the power manager 320 can conserve power by adjusting an operational state of the radar system 104 and turning off one or more components of the transceiver 306, as further described below.</p>
<p id="p0060" num="0060">The power manager 320 can also conserve power by turning off one or more components within the transceiver 306 (<i>e.g.,</i> a voltage-controlled oscillator, a multiplexer, an analog-to-digital converter, a phase lock loop, or a crystal oscillator) during inactive time periods. These inactive time periods occur if the radar system 104 is not actively transmitting or receiving radar signals, which may be on the order of microseconds (µs), milliseconds (ms), or seconds (s). Further, the power manager 320 can modify transmission power of the radar signals by adjusting an amount of amplification provided by a signal amplifier. Additionally, the power manager 320 can control the use of different<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --> hardware components within the radar system 104 to conserve power. If the processor 308 comprises a lower-power processor and a higher-power processor (<i>e.g</i>., processors with different amounts of memory and computational capability), for example, the power manager 320 can switch between utilizing the lower-power processor for low-level analysis (<i>e.g</i>., implementing the idle mode, detecting motion, determining a location of a user, or monitoring the environment) and the higher-power processor for situations in which high-fidelity or accurate radar data is requested by the interaction manager 106 <i>(e.g.,</i> for implementing the aware mode, the engaged mode, or the active mode, gesture recognition or user orientation).</p>
<p id="p0061" num="0061">Further, the power manager 320 can determine a context of the environment around the electronic device 102. From that context, the power manager 320 can determine which power states are to be made available and how they are configured. For example, if the electronic device 102 is in a user's pocket, then although the user is detected as being proximate to the electronic device 102, there is no need for the radar system 104 to operate in the higher-power mode with a high gesture-frame update rate. Accordingly, the power manager 320 can cause the radar system 104 to remain in the lower-power mode, even though the user is detected as being proximate to the electronic device 102, and cause the display 114 to remain in an off or other lower-power state. The electronic device 102 can determine the context of its environment using any suitable non-radar sensor 108 (<i>e.g</i>., gyroscope, accelerometer, light sensor, proximity sensor, capacitance sensor, and so on) in combination with the radar system 104. The context may include time of day, calendar day, lightness/darkness, number of users near the user , surrounding noise level, speed of movement of surrounding objects (including the user) relative to the electronic device 102, and so forth).</p>
<p id="p0062" num="0062"><figref idref="f0005">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates additional details of an example implementation 500 of the radar system 104 within the electronic device 102. In the example 500, the antenna array 304 is positioned underneath an exterior housing of the electronic device 102, such as a glass cover or an external case. Depending on its material properties, the exterior housing may act as an attenuator 502, which attenuates or distorts radar signals that are transmitted<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --> and received by the radar system 104. The attenuator 502 may include different types of glass or plastics, some of which may be found within display screens, exterior housings, or other components of the electronic device 102 and have a dielectric constant (<i>e.g</i>., relative permittivity) between approximately four and ten. Accordingly, the attenuator 502 is opaque or semi-transparent to a radar signal 506 and may cause a portion of a transmitted or received radar signal 506 to be reflected (as shown by a reflected portion 504). For conventional radars, the attenuator 502 may decrease an effective range that can be monitored, prevent small targets from being detected, or reduce overall accuracy.</p>
<p id="p0063" num="0063">Assuming a transmit power of the radar system 104 is limited, and re-designing the exterior housing is not desirable, one or more attenuation-dependent properties of the radar signal 506 (<i>e.g.,</i> a frequency sub-spectrum 508 or a steering angle 510) or attenuation-dependent characteristics of the attenuator 502 (<i>e.g.,</i> a distance 512 between the attenuator 502 and the radar system 104 or a thickness 514 of the attenuator 502) are adjusted to mitigate the effects of the attenuator 502. Some of these characteristics can be set during manufacturing or adjusted by the attenuation mitigator 314 during operation of the radar system 104. The attenuation mitigator 314, for example, can cause the transceiver 306 to transmit the radar signal 506 using the selected frequency sub-spectrum 508 or the steering angle 510, cause a platform to move the radar system 104 closer or farther from the attenuator 502 to change the distance 512, or prompt the user to apply another attenuator to increase the thickness 514 of the attenuator 502.</p>
<p id="p0064" num="0064">Appropriate adjustments can be made by the attenuation mitigator 314 based on pre-determined characteristics of the attenuator 502 (e.g., characteristics stored in the computer-readable media 204 of the electronic device 102 or within the system media 310) or by processing returns of the radar signal 506 to measure one or more characteristics of the attenuator 502. Even if some of the attenuation-dependent characteristics are fixed or constrained, the attenuation mitigator 314 can take these limitations into account to balance each parameter and achieve a target radar performance. As a result, the attenuation mitigator 314 enables the radar system 104 to realize enhanced accuracy and larger effective ranges for detecting and tracking the user that is located on an opposite side of<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --> the attenuator 502. These techniques provide alternatives to increasing transmit power, which increases power consumption of the radar system 104, or changing material properties of the attenuator 502, which can be difficult and expensive once a device is in production.</p>
<p id="p0065" num="0065"><figref idref="f0006">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates an example scheme 600 implemented by the radar system 104. Portions of the scheme 600 may be performed by the processor 308, the computer processors 202, or other hardware circuitry. The scheme 600 can be customized to support different types of electronic devices and radar-based applications (e.g., the interaction manager 106), and also enables the radar system 104 to achieve target angular accuracies despite design constraints.</p>
<p id="p0066" num="0066">The transceiver 306 produces raw data 602 based on individual responses of the receiving antenna elements 402 to a received radar signal. The received radar signal may be associated with one or more frequency sub-spectra 604 that were selected by the angle estimator 318 to facilitate angular ambiguity resolution. The frequency sub-spectra 604, for example, may be chosen to reduce a quantity of sidelobes or reduce an amplitude of the sidelobes (e.g., reduce the amplitude by 0.5 dB, 1 dB, or more). A quantity of frequency sub-spectra can be determined based on a target angular accuracy or computational limitations of the radar system 104.</p>
<p id="p0067" num="0067">The raw data 602 contains digital information (e.g., in-phase and quadrature data) for a period of time, different wavenumbers, and multiple channels respectively associated with the receiving antenna elements 402. A Fast-Fourier Transform (FFT) 606 is performed on the raw data 602 to generate pre-processed data 608. The pre-processed data 608 includes digital information across the period of time, for different ranges <i>(e.g.,</i> range bins), and for the multiple channels. A Doppler filtering process 610 is performed on the pre-processed data 608 to generate range-Doppler data 612. The Doppler filtering process 610 may comprise another FFT that generates amplitude and phase information for multiple range bins, multiple Doppler frequencies, and for the multiple channels. The digital beamformer 316 produces beamforming data 614 based on the range-Doppler data 612. The beamforming data 614 contains digital information for a set of azimuths and/or<!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --> elevations, which represents the field of view for which different steering angles or beams are formed by the digital beamformer 316. Although not depicted, the digital beamformer 316 may alternatively generate the beamforming data 614 based on the pre-processed data 608 and the Doppler filtering process 610 may generate the range-Doppler data 612 based on the beamforming data 614. To reduce a quantity of computations, the digital beamformer 316 may process a portion of the range-Doppler data 612 or the pre-processed data 608 based on a range, time, or Doppler frequency interval of interest.</p>
<p id="p0068" num="0068">The digital beamformer 316 can be implemented using a single-look beamformer 616, a multi-look interferometer 618, or a multi-look beamformer 620. In general, the single-look beamformer 616 can be used for deterministic objects (e.g., point-source targets having a single phase center). For non-deterministic targets (e.g., targets having multiple phase centers), the multi-look interferometer 618 or the multi-look beamformer 620 are used to improve accuracies relative to the single-look beamformer 616. Humans are an example of a non-deterministic target and have multiple phase centers 622 that can change based on different aspect angles, as shown at 624-1 and 624-2. Variations in the constructive or destructive interference generated by the multiple phase centers 622 can make it challenging for conventional radars to accurately determine angular positions. The multi-look interferometer 618 or the multi-look beamformer 620, however, perform coherent averaging to increase an accuracy of the beamforming data 614. The multi-look interferometer 618 coherently averages two channels to generate phase information that can be used to accurately determine the angular information. The multi-look beamformer 620, on the other hand, can coherently average two or more channels using linear or non-linear beamformers, such as Fourier, Capon, multiple signal classification (MUSIC), or minimum variance distortion less response (MVDR). The increased accuracies provided via the multi-look beamformer 620 or the multi-look interferometer 618 enable the radar system 104 to recognize small gestures or distinguish between multiple portions of the user.</p>
<p id="p0069" num="0069">The angle estimator 318 analyzes the beamforming data 614 to estimate one or more angular positions. The angle estimator 318 may utilize signal-processing<!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --> techniques, pattern-matching techniques, or machine-learning. The angle estimator 318 also resolves angular ambiguities that may result from a design of the radar system 104 or the field of view the radar system 104 monitors. An example angular ambiguity is shown within an amplitude plot 626 (<i>e.g</i>., amplitude response).</p>
<p id="p0070" num="0070">The amplitude plot 626 depicts amplitude differences that can occur for different angular positions of the target and for different steering angles 510. A first amplitude response 628-1 (illustrated with a solid line) is shown for a target positioned at a first angular position 630-1. Likewise, a second amplitude response 628-2 (illustrated with a dotted line) is shown for the target positioned at a second angular position 630-2. In this example, the differences are considered across angles between -180 degrees and 180 degrees.</p>
<p id="p0071" num="0071">As shown in the amplitude plot 626, an ambiguous zone exists for the two angular positions 630-1 and 630-2. The first amplitude response 628-1 has a highest peak at the first angular position 630-1 and a lesser peak at the second angular position 630-2. While the highest peak corresponds to the actual position of the target, the lesser peak causes the first angular position 630-1 to be ambiguous because it is within some threshold for which conventional radars may be unable to confidently determine whether the target is at the first angular position 630-1 or the second angular position 630-2. In contrast, the second amplitude response 628-2 has a lesser peak at the second angular position 630-2 and a higher peak at the first angular position 630-1. In this case, the lesser peak corresponds to the target's location.</p>
<p id="p0072" num="0072">While conventional radars may be limited to using a highest peak amplitude to determine the angular positions, the angle estimator 318 instead analyzes subtle differences in shapes of the amplitude responses 628-1 and 628-2. Characteristics of the shapes can include, for example, roll-offs, peak or null widths, an angular location of the peaks or nulls, a height or depth of the peaks and nulls, shapes of sidelobes, symmetry within the amplitude response 628-1 or 628-2, or the lack of symmetry within the amplitude response 628-1 or 628-2. Similar shape characteristics can be analyzed in a phase response, which can provide additional information for resolving the angular<!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --> ambiguity. The angle estimator 318 therefore maps the unique angular signature or pattern to an angular position.</p>
<p id="p0073" num="0073">The angle estimator 318 can include a suite of algorithms or tools that can be selected according to the type of electronic device 102 (<i>e.g</i>., computational capability or power constraints) or a target angular resolution for the interaction manager 106. In some implementations, the angle estimator 318 can include a neural network 632, a convolutional neural network (CNN) 634, or a long short-term memory (LSTM) network 636. The neural network 632 can have various depths or quantities of hidden layers (e.g., three hidden layers, five hidden layers, or ten hidden layers) and can also include different quantities of connections (<i>e.g.</i>, the neural network 632 can comprise a fully-connected neural network or a partially-connected neural network). In some cases, the CNN 634 can be used to increase computational speed of the angle estimator 318. The LSTM network 636 can be used to enable the angle estimator 318 to track the target. Using machine-learning techniques, the angle estimator 318 employs non-linear functions to analyze the shape of the amplitude response 628-1 or 628-2 and generate angular probability data 638, which indicates a likelihood that the user or a portion of the user is within an angular bin. The angle estimator 318 may provide the angular probability data 638 for a few angular bins, such as two angular bins to provide probabilities of a target being to the left or right of the electronic device 102, or for thousands of angular bins (<i>e.g.,</i> to provide the angular probability data 638 for a continuous angular measurement).</p>
<p id="p0074" num="0074">Based on the angular probability data 638, a tracker module 640 produces angular position data 642, which identifies an angular location of the target. The tracker module 640 may determine the angular location of the target based on the angular bin that has a highest probability in the angular probability data 638 or based on prediction information (<i>e.g</i>., previously-measured angular position information). The tracker module 640 may also keep track of one or more moving targets to enable the radar system 104 to confidently distinguish or identify the targets. Other data can also be used to determine the angular position, including range, Doppler, velocity, or acceleration. In some cases,<!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --> the tracker module 640 can include an alpha-beta tracker, a Kalman filter, a multiple hypothesis tracker (MHT), and so forth.</p>
<p id="p0075" num="0075">A quantizer module 644 obtains the angular position data 642 and quantizes the data to produce quantized angular position data 646. The quantization can be performed based on a target angular resolution for the interaction manager 106. In some situations, fewer quantization levels can be used such that the quantized angular position data 646 indicates whether the target is to the right or to the left of the electronic device 102 or identifies a 90-degree quadrant the target is located within. This may be sufficient for some radar-based applications, such as user proximity detection. In other situations, a larger number of quantization levels can be used such that the quantized angular position data 646 indicates an angular position of the target within an accuracy of a fraction of a degree, one degree, five degrees, and so forth. This resolution can be used for higher-resolution radar-based applications, such as gesture recognition, or in implementations of the gesture zone, recognition zone, aware mode, engaged mode, or active mode as described herein. In some implementations, the digital beamformer 316, the angle estimator 318, the tracker module 640, and the quantizer module 644 are together implemented in a single machine-learning module.</p>
<p id="p0076" num="0076">These and other capabilities and configurations, as well as ways in which entities of <figref idref="f0001 f0002 f0003 f0004 f0005 f0006">FIG. 1-6</figref> act and interact, are set forth below. The described entities may be further divided, combined, used along with other sensors or components, and so on. In this way, different implementations of the electronic device 102, with different configurations of the radar system 104 and non-radar sensors, can be used to implement the input methods for mobile devices. The example operating environment 100 of <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> and the detailed illustrations of <figref idref="f0002 f0003 f0004 f0005 f0006">FIGS. 2-6</figref> illustrate but some of many possible environments and devices capable of employing the described techniques.</p>
<heading id="h0007"><b>Example Methods</b></heading>
<p id="p0077" num="0077"><figref idref="f0007">FIG. 7</figref> depicts example method 700, which enables input methods for mobile devices. The method 700 can be performed with an electronic device that includes, or is<!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --> associated with, a display, an application that is configured to receive input via radar gestures, and a radar system that can provide a radar field. The radar system and radar field can provide radar data, based on reflections of the radar field from objects in the radar field, such as a user of the electronic device. For example, the radar data may be generated by, and/or received through, the radar system 104, as described with reference to <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>. The radar data is used to determine interactions of the user with the electronic device, such as a presence of the user in the radar field, gestures made by the user in the radar field, and movement of the user relative to the electronic device. Based on the determination of the user's presence, movements, and gestures, the electronic device can enter and exit different modes of functionality and present different visual elements on a display. The visual elements provide feedback to the user to indicate the user's posture with respect to the device, the availability of different functionalities for the electronic device, and the user's interactions with the electronic device. Additional examples of the visual elements are described with respect to <figref idref="f0008 f0009 f0010 f0011 f0012">FIGS. 8-12</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0078" num="0078">The method 700 is shown as a set of blocks that specify operations performed but are not necessarily limited to the order or combinations shown for performing the operations by the respective blocks. Further, any of one or more of the operations may be repeated, combined, reorganized, or linked to provide a wide array of additional and/or alternate methods. In portions of the following discussion, reference may be made to the example operating environment 100 of <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> or to entities or processes as detailed in <figref idref="f0002 f0003 f0004 f0005 f0006">FIGS. 2-6</figref>, reference to which is made for example only. The techniques are not limited to performance by one entity or multiple entities operating on one device.</p>
<p id="p0079" num="0079">At 702, based on radar data that is received through the radar system, a portion of a user is determined to be within a gesture zone of the electronic device. For example, the interaction manager 106 or the radar system 104 can use the radar data from the radar system 104 to detect that the user's hand 112 is within the gesture zone of the electronic device 102, as described with reference to <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> (<i>e.g</i>., within three, five, seven, or nine inches).<!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --></p>
<p id="p0080" num="0080">At 704, it is determined that an application operating on the electronic device has a capability to receive radar-gesture input. The radar-gesture input (sometimes referred to as a radar gesture) is defined by radar data that is generated by a radar system. For example, an application manager, such as the application manager 116 or the interaction manager 106, can determine that an application operating on the electronic device (<i>e.g.,</i> the electronic device 102) has a capability to receive radar-gesture input (<i>e.g.,</i> is a radar-gesture application). The radar data on which the radar-gesture input is based may be generated by, and/or received through, the radar system 104, as described with reference to <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0081" num="0081">At 706, responsive to the determination that the portion of the user is within the gesture zone of the electronic device and the determination that the application operating on the electronic device has the capability to receive radar-gesture input, a feedback indicator is provided on the display of the electronic device, the feedback indicator indicating that the portion of the user is within the gesture zone and the application can receive radar-gesture input. For example, in response to determining that the hand 112 is within the gesture zone 118 and that the application operating on the electronic device 102 is a radar-gesture application, the interaction manager 106 can provide the feedback indicator 120 on the display 114. Similarly, when the feedback indicator is being provided, and the user's hand (or other portion of the user) is then determined to be outside the gesture zone (and/or that the radar-gesture application is no longer operating on the electronic device), the feedback indicator may cease being provided, even though another visual element may still be provided. Thus, when a user who is outside of the gesture zone reaches a hand toward the electronic device and into the gesture zone, the feedback indicator is displayed and when the user's hand is withdrawn, the feedback indicator is no longer displayed.</p>
<p id="p0082" num="0082">As described with reference to <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, the gesture zone is a region or volume around the electronic device 102 within which the radar system 104 (or another module or application) can detect the user's hand. The gesture zone can be any suitable distance within which the radar system can recognize the user's hand, such as within three, five,<!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --> seven, or nine inches. While the radar system 104 and interaction manager 106 may be able to recognize a radar gesture and determine an action associated with the radar gesture from greater distances, the gesture zone helps enable the electronic device to distinguish between intentional gestures and other user movements that are not intended to be used to interact with applications on the electronic device. Generally, the feedback indicator is a user-perceivable element, such as a visual element that appears on an active area of the display, that indicates that a part of the user, such as the user's hand 112, is close enough to the electronic device to use radar gestures to interact with the radar-gesture application (e.g., indicates that the user's hand is within the gesture zone). As noted with reference to <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, the gesture zone can have various sub-zones with different shapes and sizes within the gesture zone. The visual properties of the feedback indicator may vary in the different sub-zones (<i>e.g</i>., the feedback indicator may get brighter or bigger as the user's hand gets closer).</p>
<p id="p0083" num="0083">The feedback indicator may be provided at or along an edge of the display, as described with reference to <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, and may take any of a variety of shapes, sizes, colors, and other visual parameters or properties (<i>e.g</i>., luminosity, color, contrast, shape, saturation, or opaqueness). In some implementations, as described with reference to <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, the visual element may have an area that is a portion of the active area of the display that has a luminosity or other visual property that is different from a luminosity or other visual property of another portion of the display that is proximate to the visual element. In this case, the visual element may also have a segment of an exterior border that is within a threshold distance from an edge of the active area of the display (<i>e.g</i>., adjacent to the edge with no gap or with a gap such as one pixel, two pixels, three pixels, one millimeter, two millimeters, three millimeters). Additionally, the luminosity (or other visual parameter) of the feedback indicator may vary as the feedback indicator extends across a distance from the edge of the active area of the display (<i>e.g.</i>, have a luminosity at or along the edge of the display that decreases or increases as the shape extends away from the edge). In other implementations, the feedback indicator may appear at a location on the display that is not<!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --> an edge (e.g., the feedback indicator may be presented in an interior region of the display and not be adjacent to or touch an edge of the display).</p>
<p id="p0084" num="0084">Additionally, the feedback indicator may be used to provide visual feedback related to ongoing movements of the user's hand in the gesture zone. For example, as described with reference to <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, the interaction manager 106 may use one or more subsets of the radar data to enable the feedback indicator to track the movements of the user's hand and cause the feedback indicator to dynamically adjust a position of the feedback indicator on the display in a manner that corresponds to the movements of the user's hand (or other portion of the user) within the gesture zone. In addition to or instead of adjustments of the position of the feedback indicator, other visual properties of the feedback indicator (<i>e.g</i>., luminosity, color, contrast, shape, saturation, and/or opaqueness) can be adjusted in a way that corresponds to the movement of the user's hand. These adjustments allow the feedback indicator to provide dynamically responsive visual feedback that corresponds to the movement of the user's hand (<i>e.g</i>., back and forth, up and down, and so forth).</p>
<p id="p0085" num="0085">In an implementation of the method 700 according to the present invention, the feedback indicator is presented as an adjustment to a visual element that is already being presented at or along the edge of the active area of the display (<i>e.g.,</i> a previously presented visual element indicating that the application operating on the electronic device has the capability to receive radar-gesture input). For example, in the example shown in <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, the detail view 100-2 shows a visual element 122 already being presented on the example display 114-2. When the user's hand 112 moves back into the gesture zone 118, the visual element 122 may be adjusted to become the example feedback indicator 120, as shown in the detail view 100-1. In this case, the user may withdraw the hand 112 and, if the radar-gesture application is still running, the interaction manager 106 may stop presenting the feedback indicator 120 and resume presenting the visual element 122.</p>
<p id="p0086" num="0086">As noted with reference to <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, the adjustment to the previously presented visual element is an increase in a length and luminosity of the visual element. In other cases, the adjustment may be a change in a size of the previously presented visual element.<!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --> For example, the change in size may be an enlargement of an area of the previously presented visual element. The enlargement may include extending the previously presented visual element an increased distance in a direction parallel to the edge of the active area of the display, an increased distance in a direction away from the edge of the active area of the display, or both in the direction parallel to the edge of the active area of the display and in the direction away from the edge of the active area of the display. In other implementations, the adjustment may also or instead be a change in another visual property, such as a luminosity, a color, a contrast, a shape, a saturation, and/or an opaqueness.</p>
<p id="p0087" num="0087">The color of the feedback indicator may be any suitable color that can be visually differentiated from the background of the display on which it is presented. The color may change based on any of a variety of factors, as described with reference to <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>. In some implementations of the method 700, a component of the electronic device <i>(e.g.,</i> the interaction manager 106), can determine a background color of a region of the display on which the feedback indicator is displayed. In response to determining the background color, the feedback indicator may be presented in another color that is different from the background color, which provides human-discernable contrast between the feedback indicator and the background color, as described with reference to <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>. In some cases, the color of the feedback indicator can be continuously, automatically, and dynamically adjusted, based on changes to the background color.</p>
<p id="p0088" num="0088">The feedback indicator may appear, at least in part, as a brief animation. For example, the feedback indicator may appear at the edge of the active display and then grow or shrink before taking on a default appearance. Similarly, the color, luminosity, or shape may change as the feedback indicator appears or disappears (<i>e.g</i>., if the radar-gesture application stops operating) before taking on the default appearance. Further, the feedback indicator may be an image that appears on the display, rather than an element that appears in a region of the display. The image may have visual parameters that are different from the parameters of an ambient background of the display, such as luminosity, saturation, or color. In other cases, the ambient background may be an image, and the feedback indicator<!-- EPO <DP n="40"> --> is the same image, with different visual parameters, such as luminosity, saturation, color, and so forth. In this way, the feedback indicator can improve the user's experience by communicating to the user that a radar-gesture application is operating on the electronic device.</p>
<p id="p0089" num="0089">In some implementations of the method 700, the location of the feedback indicator may be determined based on an orientation of content on the display and/or a direction of the radar-gesture input that is used to interact with the content. For example, a component of the electronic device, such as the interaction manager 106, may obtain the orientation of the content on the display (e.g., from the application manager 116). Based on the orientation of the content, the display can determine the direction of the radar-gesture input that can be used to interact with the content and provide the feedback indicator at a particular edge of the active area of the display that corresponds to the direction of the radar input. Thus, as described with reference to <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, if the context of the displayed content is horizontal, the feedback indicator is displayed at a top edge and, if the context of the displayed content is vertical, the feedback indicator is displayed at a side edge.</p>
<p id="p0090" num="0090">Further, a change in an orientation of the electronic device with respect to the user may be detected and, based on the change in orientation, the feedback indicator may be provided on a different edge of the display, in order to maintain the orientation and location of the feedback indicator with respect to the user. For example, as described with reference to <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, the user may rotate the device from a vertical to a horizontal orientation to watch a video or from a horizontal to a vertical orientation to read an article. Based on the change in orientation, the interaction manager 106 can cause the display 114 to provide the feedback indicator 120 on a different edge of the active display, in order to maintain an orientation and location of the feedback indicator 120 with respect to the user. As noted, the orientation of the content may also be accounted for, and these features can be used in conjunction with each other to provide the feedback indicator on the display at the location appropriate for the orientation of both the content on the display and the orientation of the display with respect to the user.<!-- EPO <DP n="41"> --></p>
<p id="p0091" num="0091">In some cases, it can be determined that the radar-gesture application running on the electronic device is operating in an immersive mode (<i>e.g.,</i> in a full-screen mode without any presented controls). In response to this determination, the display can periodically provide the feedback indicator. For example, as described with reference to <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, the feedback indicator can be provided on the display for a presentation time duration and then stop being provided for a non-presentation time duration. Both the presentation time duration and the non-presentation time duration may be predetermined or selectable. The time durations may be selectable (<i>e.g</i>., by the user or by the interaction manager 106 based on various factors, such as the type of radar-gesture application running in the immersive mode, the status of the radar-gesture application, or the frequency with which the user employs a radar gesture).</p>
<p id="p0092" num="0092">The feedback indicator may fade or disappear entirely when the user interacts with the electronic device using input other than a radar gesture (<i>e.g</i>., a touch or voice input). For example, as described with reference to <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, the user may decide to start an application using a touch command on the electronic device, while a radar-gesture application is also running. In this case, the feedback indicator may fade or disappear when the user picks up the electronic device or touches the display. The feedback indicator restarts when the user stops touching the display or puts down the electronic device (if one or more radar-gesture applications are still operating). The feedback indicator may reappear or brighten immediately when the touch or voice input ends, or after a selectable default time duration. Similarly, when the radar-gesture application is an application that provides an alert or notification, the feedback indicator appears when an alert or notification is displayed and, when the user interacts with the alert or notification using a radar gesture, the feedback indicator disappears, unless other gesture-subscribed apps are running.</p>
<p id="p0093" num="0093">The feedback indicator can be provided while the electronic device 102 is in a locked state or an unlocked state. Thus, the electronic device may provide the feedback indicator when a part of the user is within the gesture zone (and a radar-gesture application is running), whether the user is authenticated or not authenticated. As described with<!-- EPO <DP n="42"> --> reference to <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, the locked and unlocked states refer to a level of access to the electronic device. A locked state may be a state in which no user is authenticated and anyone using the device will have less than full rights or access (<i>e.g.,</i> no access or rights, or limited access or rights). Examples of the locked state may include the aware and engaged modes of the electronic device as described herein. Similarly, an unlocked state can be a state in which at least one user is authenticated, and that user has full rights and/or access to the device. An example of the unlocked state is the active mode of the electronic device, as described herein.</p>
<p id="p0094" num="0094">These techniques for the input methods for mobile devices may be more secure than other authentication and feedback techniques. For example, a user's position, orientation, or use of radar gestures (especially user-defined gestures, micro-gestures, and posture or position-based gestures) are typically not duplicable or obtainable by an unauthorized person (unlike, for example, a password). Further, a radar image of the user (e.g., based on the radar data described above), even if it includes the user's face, does not visually identify the user like a photograph or video may do. Even so, further to the descriptions above, the user may be provided with controls allowing the user to make an election as to both whether and when any of the systems, programs, managers, modules, or features described in this document may enable collection of user information (<i>e.g.</i>, images of the user, radar data describing the user, information about a user's social network, social actions or activities, profession, a user's preferences, or a user's current location), and whether and when the user is sent content or communications from a server. In addition, certain data may be treated in one or more ways before it is stored or used, so that personally identifiable information is removed. For example, a user's identity may be treated so that no personally identifiable information can be determined for the user, or a user's geographic location may be generalized where location information is obtained (such as to a city, zip/postal code, or state level), so that a particular location of a user cannot be determined. Thus, the user may have control over what information is collected about the user, how that information is used, and what information is provided to or about the user.<!-- EPO <DP n="43"> --></p>
<heading id="h0008"><b>Example Visual Elements</b></heading>
<p id="p0095" num="0095">As noted, the techniques and systems described herein can enable the electronic device 102 to provide feedback and notification to make the user aware of an available radar-gesture input mode and, in some cases, provide additional feedback regarding the use and results of the radar gestures. The feedback and notification are provided by one or more user-perceivable elements, such as visual elements that are presented on the display 114. The techniques and systems can also enable a determination of the user's absence, presence, and location, which can be used to provide a more-responsive and more-efficient authentication process. For example, the techniques enable the electronic device to anticipate when the user is ready to be authenticated and to more-accurately determine when to lock the device when the user is away. The feedback, visual elements, and other features enable interactions that are more convenient and less frustrating because the user is aware of the input modes and can be confident about different ways in which the device can interact and receive input. <figref idref="f0008 f0009 f0010 f0011 f0012 f0013 f0014 f0015">FIGS. 8-15</figref> illustrate examples of the electronic device 102 running a radar-gesture application and describe examples of the visual elements that can be presented on the display to provide feedback to the user. Examples of the electronic device operating in multiple different modes and examples of the visual elements that can be presented on the display in the different modes are also described.</p>
<p id="p0096" num="0096">Consider <figref idref="f0008">FIG. 8</figref>, which illustrates generally, at 800, an example of a visual feedback element that can be used to indicate that a radar-gesture application is running on the electronic device 102. In <figref idref="f0008">FIG. 8</figref>, a detail view 800-1 shows an example display 114-3 to indicate a state of the electronic device 102 with no radar-gesture application running. Another state of the electronic device 102, in which at least one radar-gesture application is running, is shown on another example display 114-4. A visual element 802 at the top of the example display 114-4 indicates that the electronic device 102 can receive input through radar gestures, as described above. The visual element 802 is shown as an illuminated line, but, as noted above, may be presented at another location, at a different<!-- EPO <DP n="44"> --> illumination level (<i>e.g.,</i> only partially illuminated), or as another shape or type of element. For example, in another detail view 800-2, an example display 114-5 is shown to indicate the state of the electronic device 102 with no radar-gesture application running. Another state of the electronic device 102, in which at least one radar-gesture application is running, is shown on another example display 114-6. A visual element 804 at the top of the example display 114-6 indicates that the electronic device 102 can receive input through radar gestures, as described above. The visual element 804 is shown as an illuminated area (<i>e.g.,</i> a glowing area). As with the visual element 802, the visual element 804 could be presented at another location on the display 114-6, at a different illumination level (<i>e.g.,</i> more-illuminated or less-illuminated), or as another shape or type of element. Note that for clarity, no other elements (<i>e.g</i>., time, date, or application launch icons) are shown on the example displays 114-3 through 114-6. In other implementations, however, the visual elements 802 or 804 may be displayed along with other content on the display. Further, the visual elements 802 or 804 may be displayed while the electronic device 102 is in the aware mode, the engaged mode, the active mode, or another mode.</p>
<p id="p0097" num="0097">In some implementations, the electronic device 102 can also provide more-detailed visual feedback that is related to the availability of radar gestures. For example, the interaction manager 106 may cause the display 114 to present other visual elements that provide feedback regarding input received through radar-based radar gestures. <figref idref="f0009 f0010 f0011 f0012">FIGS. 9-12</figref> illustrate additional details of some of the ways that visual elements can be used to provide the feedback related to the use of radar gestures.</p>
<p id="p0098" num="0098">For instance, consider <figref idref="f0009">FIGS. 9A-9D</figref>, which illustrate generally, at 900, examples of the feedback indicator 120 that may be used to indicate that a user's hand is within a gesture zone that enables a radar-gesture application to receive radar-gesture input <i>(e.g.,</i> the gesture zone 118). The gesture zone 118 is an area around the electronic device 102 (or the radar system 104) within which the electronic device 102 can receive, interpret, and act on radar gestures, such as a swipe or a pinch. The gesture zone can extend any suitable distance from the electronic device 102 (<i>e.g</i>., approximately three, approximately five, approximately seven, or approximately nine inches).<!-- EPO <DP n="45"> --></p>
<p id="p0099" num="0099">In <figref idref="f0009">FIG. 9A</figref>, an example display 114-7 is shown in a state in which at least one radar-gesture application is running (e.g., similar to the example display 114-6 described with reference to <figref idref="f0008">FIG. 8</figref>). A user's hand 902 is shown near the example display 114-7, but outside the gesture zone 118 (the border of the gesture zone is shown as a dotted line 904). An example feedback indicator 906 (visual element 906) is shown as a glowing area <i>(e.g.,</i> an area or shape with varying brightness, color, or other properties) near the top of the example display 114-7 with a luminosity that changes with distance from the top. In other implementations, the visual element 906 could be presented at another location or as another shape or type of element (<i>e.g.</i>, a line, as shown in the detail view 800-1 of <figref idref="f0008">FIG. 8</figref>). In <figref idref="f0009">FIG. 9B</figref>, the user's hand 902 moves toward the electronic device and crosses the border 904 of the gesture zone, as shown by the arrow 908. In response to the electronic device detecting the movement 908, another visual element 910 replaces the visual element 906, as shown on an example display 114-8. In this example, the visual element 910 is a glowing area that is larger than the visual element 906 and has a different brightness or luminosity (e.g., less-, more-, or fully-illuminated). In other implementations, the visual element 910 could also be presented at another location or as another shape or type of element.</p>
<p id="p0100" num="0100">As shown in <figref idref="f0009">FIG. 9C</figref> (and described with reference to <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>), when the user's hand 902 is within the border 904 of the gesture zone, the visual element 910 can be used to provide feedback that indicates smaller, non-gesture motion of the user's hand 902, which are represented by a double-ended arrow 912. For example, as shown on an example display 114-9, the visual element can move to indicate the user's hand movements by moving back and forth with the user's hand, as shown by an arrow 914. In <figref idref="f0009">FIG. 9D</figref>, the user's hand 902 is withdrawn outside the border 904 of the gesture zone, as shown by an arrow 916. In response to the motion of the user's hand, the display 114 returns to the state as shown in the example display 114-7, in which the visual element 906 is displayed near the top edge of the display 114.</p>
<p id="p0101" num="0101">In some implementations (not shown in <figref idref="f0009">FIG. 9A-9D</figref>), the non-gesture motions can be represented by other visual elements or changes to the visual elements. For<!-- EPO <DP n="46"> --> example, a size and/or shape can change, or a center or focal point of the shape can move to represent the motions (while the shape itself remains stationary). Additionally or alternatively, changes to an intensity of the brightness or color can be used to represent the motion (<i>e.g.,</i> the brightness or color of the shape, or part of the shape, change in accordance with the non-gesture motions. The visual elements 906 and 910, along with the motion of the visual element 910, can help the user understand when gestures are available, and provide feedback that indicates the electronic device 102 is aware of the relative position of the user's hand, which can improve the user's experience with the electronic device 102. The embodiments shown in <figref idref="f0009">Fig. 9A-9D</figref> are examples 12-18 in which visual properties of the feedback indicator are dynamically adjusted corresponding to the distance to the electronic device and/or the movement of the portion of the user in the gesture zone.</p>
<p id="p0102" num="0102">As described with reference to <figref idref="f0009">FIG. 9C</figref>, the electronic device 102 can provide visual feedback to represent smaller, non-gesture motion of the user's hand in the gesture zone, such as moving a visual element back and forth on the display, corresponding to the motion of the user's hand. Similarly, when the user makes a radar gesture (e.g., a swiping gesture to skip a song or an omni-gesture to dismiss an alert or notification), the electronic device 102 can provide feedback to notify the user that the gesture has been successfully received or that a gesture attempt was received but it was not clear enough to be confirmed as a radar gesture. For example, <figref idref="f0010">FIG. 10</figref> illustrates generally, at 1000, a sequence of example visual elements that can be used to notify the user that a gesture has been successfully received.</p>
<p id="p0103" num="0103">In <figref idref="f0010">FIG. 10</figref>, an example display 114-10 is shown in a state in which at least one radar-gesture application is running and a user's hand 1002 is within a boundary of a gesture zone (<i>e.g.,</i> similar to the state represented by the example display 114-8 described with reference to <figref idref="f0009">FIG. 9B</figref>). The example display 114-10 is presenting a visual element 1004, shown as an illuminated line near the top of the example display 114-10, to indicate the availability of radar gestures and that the user's hand 1002 is within the gesture zone. In the example of <figref idref="f0010">FIG. 10</figref>, the user makes a sliding or swiping gesture from left to right, as shown by the arrow 1006. In response to the motion 1006 of the user's hand 1002, the<!-- EPO <DP n="47"> --> visual element 1004 also moves, as shown in a sequence 1008 (shown within a dashed-line rectangle). An example display 114-11 illustrates the beginning of the sequence 1008, as the visual element 1004 begins moving to the right, as shown by an arrow 1010.</p>
<p id="p0104" num="0104">The sequence 1008 continues in another example display 114-12, in which the visual element 1004 bends around a corner of the example display 114-12, as shown by an arrow 1012. The visual element 1004 can continue down a side of the display 114 for a variable distance (<i>e.g</i>., as soon as a trailing end of the visual element completes the bend or after the trailing end has traveled a particular distance along the side) and then disappear. Continuing the sequence 1008 in another example display 114-13, the visual element 1004 reappears or regenerates from the left side of the example display 114-13 and moves toward the center position, as shown by an arrow 1014. In some implementations, the visual element 1004 can reappear or regenerate at the initial position (as shown in the example display 114-10), rather than from the left side. When the sequence 1008 is complete, the display returns to the state as shown in the example display 114-10, with the visual element 1004 displayed near the top of the display 114 and may subtly track the user's hand 1002 while the hand remains within the boundary of the gesture zone. The motion of the visual element 1004 can help the user understand when radar gestures have been accepted and when the gesture is complete, which can improve the user's experience with the electronic device 102.</p>
<p id="p0105" num="0105">Consider an example in which a user is listening to music with a radar-gesture application on a smartphone (<i>e.g</i>., the electronic device 102). The user decides to skip a track and makes a radar gesture over the smartphone. The radar gesture may be a swipe in either direction (<i>e.g</i>., left-to-right to skip to the next track or right-to-left to restart the current track or skip to a previous track). When the user's hand enters the gesture zone, a visual element, such as the feedback indicator 120, is presented. As the user begins the radar gesture, the smartphone (<i>e.g</i>., through the interaction manager 106) presents the visual element in the sequence 1008, as described with reference to <figref idref="f0010">FIG. 10</figref>. In this way, the visual element can provide the user with feedback about the success of the radar gesture.<!-- EPO <DP n="48"> --></p>
<p id="p0106" num="0106">Note that the sequence 1008 begins when the user begins the gesture, but the gesture and the sequence 1008 may be completed at different times. Further, as described above, while the visual element 1004 is shown as an illuminated line near the top of the display 114, the visual element 1004 could be presented at another location or as another shape or type of element (<i>e.g</i>., as shown in <figref idref="f0009">FIGS. 9A-9D</figref> or in the detail view 800-2 of <figref idref="f0008">FIG. 8</figref>). The sequence 1008 could also begin at another location on the display 114 and proceed in another direction, such as right to left, top to bottom, or bottom to top <i>(e.g.,</i> if a radar gesture moved from right to left, top to bottom, or bottom to top). Another example of a sequence that shows a successful radar gesture (not shown in <figref idref="f0010">FIG. 10</figref>) includes a visual element that expands and brightens, then collapses on itself and briefly disappears, and then regenerates (e.g., from its original position). Other examples also include a visual element that bends or flexes (<i>e.g</i>., at one end, both ends, in the middle, or at another location) to show a successful radar gesture, such as a gesture made in a direction perpendicular to the display 114 or a gesture with a component that is perpendicular to the display 114. In other cases, the visual element 1004 may disappear at or before it reaches the corner, or it may continue down a side of the display 114 around the corner, or even move all the way around the display 114.</p>
<p id="p0107" num="0107">In some cases, as described herein, the visual element may be hidden even when radar gestures are available (<i>e.g</i>., because the user interacted with a voice or touch input, or in order to reduce the risk of screen burn-in). In this situation, the visual element, such as the visual element 1004, may still be shown when the user makes a successful radar gesture. Consider a variation of the music player example above, in which the visual element is hidden while the user is listening to music and using a voice input to open another application. In this example, the user performs a radar gesture to skip a song, and the display presents the sequence 1008 to notify the user that the radar gesture was successful.</p>
<p id="p0108" num="0108"><figref idref="f0011">FIG. 11</figref> illustrates generally, at 1100, a sequence of example visual elements that can be used to notify the user that a gesture has failed to be successfully made or received. In <figref idref="f0011">FIG. 11</figref>, an example display 114-14 is shown in a state in which at least one<!-- EPO <DP n="49"> --> radar-gesture application is running and in which a user's hand 1102 is within the boundary of a gesture zone (<i>e.g.,</i> similar to the state represented in the example display 114-8 described with reference to <figref idref="f0009">FIG. 9B</figref>). The example display 114-14 is presenting a visual element 1104, shown as an illuminated line near the top of the example display 114-14, to indicate the availability of radar gestures and that the user's hand 1102 is within the gesture zone. In the example of <figref idref="f0011">FIG. 11</figref>, assume that the user attempts to make a sliding or swiping gesture from left to right, but fails to meet sufficient standards for a swiping gesture or did not correspond to a radar gesture for a radar-gesture application on the electronic device. For example, as shown by a curved arrow 1106, the user's hand 1102 may fail to travel sufficient distance in a relevant direction before withdrawing. In this case, when the electronic device 102 (or the radar system 104) detects the motion 1106 of the user's hand 1102, which lacks sufficient definition to be successfully determined to be a radar gesture, the visual element 1104 moves as shown in a sequence 1108 (shown within a dashed-line rectangle). An example display 114-15 illustrates the beginning of the sequence 1108, as the visual element 1104 begins moving to the right, as shown by an arrow 1110.</p>
<p id="p0109" num="0109">Continuing the sequence 1108 in another example display 114-16, the visual element 1104 has stopped before reaching an opposite edge of the example display 114-16 and has shrunk (compared to its starting length as shown in the example display 114-14). The sequence 1108 continues in another example display 114-17, in which the visual element 1104 reverses direction and begins to move back toward its original location (the center in this example), as shown by another arrow 1112. The visual element 1104 also begins to grow back to its original length. In other implementations, rather than stopping and shrinking, the visual element 1104 may slow and bounce before reversing direction. When the sequence 1108 is complete, the display returns to the state as shown in the example display 114-14, with the visual element 1104 displayed near the top of the example display 114 and subtly tracking the user's hand 1102 while it remains within the boundary of the gesture zone (<i>e.g.,</i> as shown in <figref idref="f0009">FIG. 9A-9D</figref>). The motion of the visual element 1104 can help the user understand when a gesture has not been successfully completed so that the user can learn techniques for making successful radar gestures and<!-- EPO <DP n="50"> --> become aware when an attempted gesture fails (<i>e.g.,</i> so it can be attempted again, if necessary), which can improve the user's experience with the electronic device 102.</p>
<p id="p0110" num="0110">Note that the sequence 1108 may begin when the electronic device 102 (or the interaction manager 106) detects (<i>e.g</i>., using one or more subsets of the radar data) that the user has attempted a radar gesture, but also determines that the gesture fails to meet at least one criterion that is necessary for acceptance. Accordingly, the attempted gesture and the sequence 1108 may be completed at different times, depending on the nature of the attempted gesture and the speed of the sequence 1108. Further, as described above, while the visual element 1104 is shown as a partially illuminated line near the top of the display 114, the visual element 1104 may be presented at another location or as another shape or type of element (<i>e.g</i>., as shown in <figref idref="f0009">FIGS. 9A-9D</figref> or in the detail view 800-2 of <figref idref="f0008">FIG. 8</figref>). The sequence 1108 could also begin at another location on the display 114 and proceed in another direction, such as right to left, top to bottom, or bottom to top (<i>e.g.,</i> if an attempted radar gesture moved from right to left, top to bottom, or bottom to top). Other examples of sequences that show an unsuccessful radar gesture attempt include a visual element that partially collapses on itself, such as by briefly shrinking, and then returns to its original size and position.</p>
<p id="p0111" num="0111">In some implementations, the electronic device 102 includes a gesture-paused mode that can turn off or suspend the radar gesture capabilities of the electronic device 102 when conditions indicate that the system may be inefficient or ineffective at receiving or interpreting the gestures. For example, when the electronic device 102 is moving at a velocity above a threshold, or when the direction in which the electronic device 102 is moving changes rapidly and repeatedly, the electronic device can enter the gesture-paused mode and provide visual feedback to the user. The electronic device 102 may determine to enter the gesture-paused mode based on input from any of a variety of sensors, including a radar sensor (<i>e.g</i>., the radar system 104), an inertial measurement unit (IMU), a proximity sensor (<i>e.g</i>., an active infrared proximity sensor), and so forth. For example, if the user is walking and listening to audio content with the electronic device 102 in the user's hand, swinging back and forth, the motion may be similar to a radar-based swipe<!-- EPO <DP n="51"> --> gesture, but the user does not intend to skip tracks or adjust the volume. Accordingly, because the motion of the electronic device 102 can introduce ambiguity into the gesture interpretation process, the electronic device 102 may determine to enter the gesture-paused mode until the ambiguity is resolved (<i>e.g</i>., the user stops walking).</p>
<p id="p0112" num="0112">Consider <figref idref="f0012">FIG. 12</figref>, which illustrates generally, at 1200, example visual elements that may be used to indicate that a radar-gesture application is available to receive radar-gesture input, but that gestures are currently paused. The gesture-paused mode may be activated whenever radar gestures are available, whether the user's hand is in or out of the gesture zone. In <figref idref="f0012">FIG. 12</figref>, an example display 114-18 is shown in a state in which at least one radar-gesture application is running and a user's hand is within the boundary of a gesture zone (<i>e.g</i>., similar to the state represented in the example display 114-8 described with reference to <figref idref="f0009">FIG. 9B</figref>). The example display 114-18 is presenting a visual element 1202, shown as an illuminated line near the top of the example display 114-18, to indicate the availability of radar gestures and that the user's hand 1102 is within the gesture zone. If the user takes an action that causes the electronic device 102 to enter the gesture-paused mode <i>(e.g.,</i> the user's hand begins moving back and forth as the user is walking, as shown by an arrow 1204), the visual element 1202 can change, as shown in a sequence 1206 (within a dashed-line rectangle).</p>
<p id="p0113" num="0113">An example display 114-19 illustrates the beginning of the sequence 1206 as another visual element 1208 replaces the visual element 1202, in response to the electronic device 102 detecting the movement 1204. As shown on an example display 114-19, the visual element 1208 is another line that is shorter and dimmer than the visual element 1202. In implementations in which the visual element 1202 has a particular color, the visual element 1208 may have a different color from that of the visual element 1202 (<i>e.g.,</i> the color may change from the particular color to another color, such as grey or white). The sequence 1206 continues in another example display 114-20, in which the visual element 1208 begins moving to the right, as shown by an arrow 1210. Continuing the sequence 1206 in another example display 114-21, the visual element 1208 moves to the left as shown by an arrow 1212. In the sequence 1206, the visual element 1208 may stop and<!-- EPO <DP n="52"> --> reverse direction before it reaches a side of the display or go all the way to the edge before reversing direction. In some implementations, the visual element 1208 may further shrink when it stops to reverse directions and then return to another size when, after, or as, it begins moving in the opposite direction. Further, the oscillation of the visual element 1208 may match the condition upon which the gesture-paused mode is based. For example, in the case of the user's arms swinging, the velocity or frequency of the oscillation of the visual element 1208 may approximately match the velocity or frequency of the user's hand moving.</p>
<p id="p0114" num="0114">As described above, while the visual element 1208 is shown as an illuminated line near the top of the display 114, the visual element 1208 can be presented at another location or as another shape or type of element (<i>e.g.</i>, as shown in <figref idref="f0009">FIGS. 9A-9D</figref> or in the detail view 800-2 of <figref idref="f0008">FIG. 8</figref>). The sequence 1108 can also begin at another location on the display 114 and proceed in another direction, such as right to left, top to bottom, or bottom to top (<i>e.g.,</i> depending on the orientation of content on the display 114, the direction of the radar-gesture input, or another factor).</p>
<p id="p0115" num="0115">When the electronic device 102 exits the gesture-paused mode, the sequence 1206 is complete and the display 114 returns to an appropriate state, depending on whether there are radar-gesture applications running and on the location of the user's hand. The sequence 1206 of motion of the visual element 1208 can help the user understand when gestures may be paused and allow the user to adjust how the electronic device 102 is used to avoid or take advantage of the gesture-paused mode, which can improve the user's experience with the electronic device 102.</p>
<p id="p0116" num="0116">In some cases (not shown in <figref idref="f0012">FIG. 12</figref>), the user's motion may not introduce ambiguity, such as a situation in which the user walking with the electronic device and holding it steady in front of the user. In these cases, the electronic device does not enter the gesture-paused mode and the visual element 1202 may change one or more visual parameters to alert the user that radar gestures are available, even while the user and the electronic device are in motion. For example, the visual element 1202 may change from a default color to another color (<i>e.g.,</i> from grey to blue, grey to white, or white to blue).<!-- EPO <DP n="53"> --></p>
<p id="p0117" num="0117">In some implementations, the electronic device 102 can determine that the radar-gesture application running on the electronic device 102 is operating in an immersive mode <i>(e.g.,</i> in a full-screen mode without any presented controls). In response to this determination, the display can periodically provide the visual elements described with reference to <figref idref="f0008 f0009 f0010 f0011 f0012">FIGS. 8-12</figref> (<i>e.g</i>., the visual elements 802, 804, 906, 910, 1004, 1104, 1202, and/or 1208). For example, the visual element can be provided on the display for a time duration and then stop being provided for another time duration. The time durations may be selectable (e.g., by a user or by the electronic device 102, based on factors such as the type of radar-gesture application running in the immersive mode, the status of the radar-gesture application, or the frequency with which the user employs a radar gesture).</p>
<p id="p0118" num="0118">Note that the visual elements described above with reference to <figref idref="f0008 f0009 f0010 f0011 f0012">FIGS. 8-12</figref> (<i>e.g</i>., the visual elements 802, 804, 906, 910, 1004, 1104, 1202, 1208, and/or the feedback indicator 120), may be presented in any suitable color that can be visually differentiated from the background of the display on which it is presented. Further, the color of the visual elements may change based on any of a variety of factors, such as an operational state of the electronic device or an ambient background color of the display. For example, the interaction manager 106 (or another entity, module, or manager) can determine a background color of a region of the display on which the visual element is, or will be, displayed. In response to determining the background color, the visual element may be presented in another color that is different from the background color. The different color can provide human-discernable contrast between the visual element and the background color to make it easier for the user to see the visual element. In some cases, the color of the visual element can be continuously, automatically, and dynamically adjusted, based on changes to the background color.</p>
<p id="p0119" num="0119">The user's location and movements can also be used to detect user actions that are categorized as indications of the user's intention to interact (or not interact) with the electronic device. For example, the electronic device may have access to a library (e.g., in a memory device) of actions that are categorized as indicators of a user's intent to interact or not interact with the device (<i>e.g</i>., reaching for the electronic device, turning or<!-- EPO <DP n="54"> --> walking toward or away from the electronic device, leaning toward or looking at the electronic device). In some cases, the electronic device may also include machine-learning technology that can add, remove, or modify the actions stored in the library. Based on the detection of the user's presence, movements, and intention, the electronic device can cause the electronic device to enter and exit different modes of functionality and present different visual elements on a display, based on the modes. These modes can enable different functionalities for the electronic device, and help the user understand the mode the electronic device is operating in, and the services and functions that are available. <figref idref="f0013 f0014 f0015">FIGS. 13-15</figref> illustrate the electronic device operating in the multiple modes and describe examples of the visual elements that can be presented on the display in the different modes.</p>
<p id="p0120" num="0120">For instance, when the user is not detected near the electronic device (<i>e.g</i>., within the radar field 110 or the recognition zone), the device operates in a dormant mode. In the dormant mode, the display (<i>e.g</i>., the display 114) may present fewer visual elements than in other modes, or no visual elements and the display may be on or off. When the electronic device determines the presence of the user within the recognition zone (<i>e.g</i>., using radar data, or one or more subsets of the radar data, from the radar system 104), the electronic device exits the dormant mode and enters an aware mode. In the aware mode, the display presents one or more visual elements that can indicate a status or functionality level of the electronic device.</p>
<p id="p0121" num="0121">While the electronic device is in the aware mode, the electronic device can detect a user action that is categorized as an indication of a user intent to interact with the electronic device. In response to detecting this user action, the electronic device can prepare an authentication system to perform an authentication process. In some implementations, when the electronic device detects the indication of the user's intent to interact, the electronic device also exits the aware mode and enters an engaged mode. In the engaged mode, the display presents additional or alternate visual elements that can indicate changes in the status or functionality level of the electronic device. The electronic device can also detect a trigger event and, based on the trigger event, cause the authentication system to authenticate the user. In response to the user being authenticated,<!-- EPO <DP n="55"> --> the electronic device exits the aware or engaged mode and enters an active mode. In the active mode, the display presents additional or alternate visual elements that can indicate changes in the status or functionality level of the electronic device.</p>
<p id="p0122" num="0122"><figref idref="f0013">FIG. 13</figref> illustrates an example 1300 of an electronic device transitioning from the dormant mode to the aware mode. A detail view 1300-1 shows the electronic device 102 in the dormant mode while a user 1302 is outside of a recognition zone 1304. In this example, the recognition zone 1304 has a wedge shape, but as noted, the recognition zone 1304 can take any suitable shape or size. Continuing the example, in this case the display 114 is not presenting any visual elements in the dormant mode, as shown on an example display 114-22. In another detail view 1300-2, the user 1302 is closer to the electronic device 102, which has determined that the user 1302 has entered the recognition zone 1304. Based on this determination, the electronic device 102 exits the dormant mode and enters the aware mode, as shown by an arrow 1306.</p>
<p id="p0123" num="0123">In the detail view 1300-2, multiple visual elements are presented on an example display 114-23. For example, in the aware mode, the example display 114-23 presents a time-of-day element 1308 (a clock), a date element 1310, a connectivity status element 1312 <i>(e.g.,</i> Wi-Fi, cellular, or other network connectivity), and a battery-level indicator element 1314 (including a graphical element and a percentage indicator). In the detail view 1300-2, the remainder of the example display 114-23 is blank. In some implementations, however, additional elements may be displayed, including a background image, such as a wallpaper or other image. Though not shown in <figref idref="f0013">FIG. 13</figref>, if the user 1302 exits the recognition zone 1304, the electronic device 102 may stop displaying the visual elements and return to the dormant mode (immediately or after the user 1302 has been outside the recognition zone 1304 for a selectable predetermined amount of time).</p>
<p id="p0124" num="0124"><figref idref="f0014">FIG. 14</figref> illustrates an example 1400 of an electronic device transitioning from the aware mode to the optional engaged mode. A detail view 1400-1 shows the user 1302 within the recognition zone 1304 and the electronic device 102 in the aware mode, as described with reference to <figref idref="f0013">FIG. 13</figref>, including displaying multiple visual elements (1308, 1310, 1312, 1314) on an example display 114-24. Another detail view 1400-2<!-- EPO <DP n="56"> --> shows the user 1302 reaching for the electronic device 102. The electronic device 102 detects the reach (<i>e.g</i>., using one or more subsets of the radar data) as a user action that is an indication of a user intent to interact with the electronic device 102. In response to detecting this user action indicating intent, the electronic device 102 exits the aware mode and enters the engaged mode, as shown by an arrow 1402.</p>
<p id="p0125" num="0125">In the detail view 1400-2, additional visual elements are presented on an example display 114-25. For example, in the engaged mode, the example display 114-25 presents a background image 1404 (in this case, an image of the Golden Gate Bridge). The background image 1404 may have dynamic features that adjust with the context of the user, such as animation, or varying brightness or transparency levels that change depending on the distance or speed of the reach. While in the engaged mode, the electronic device 102 also prepares an authentication system to perform an authentication process (note that in some cases, the electronic device 102 does not enter the engaged mode and instead prepares the authentication system while in the aware mode, in response to the user action that indicates user intent). Accordingly, the example display 114-25 also presents a lock icon 1406, which indicates that full access to the electronic device 102 is unavailable until the user 1302 is authenticated. In some implementations, additional visual elements may be displayed on the example display 114-25, and some or all of the visual elements presented on the example display 114-24 may cease being presented. Though not shown in <figref idref="f0014">FIG. 14</figref>, if the user 1302 withdraws the reach gestures, the electronic device 102 may exit the engaged mode and return to the aware mode (immediately or after the reach has been withdrawn for a selectable predetermined amount of time).</p>
<p id="p0126" num="0126"><figref idref="f0015">FIG. 15</figref> illustrates an example 1500 of an electronic device transitioning from the engaged mode to the active mode after the user 1302 is authenticated (note that in some implementations, the electronic device can transition to the active mode from the aware mode). A detail view 1500-1 shows the user 1302 within the recognition zone 1304 and the electronic device 102 in the engaged mode, as described with reference to <figref idref="f0014">FIG. 14</figref>, including displaying multiple visual elements on an example display 114-26 (1308, 1310, 1312, 1314, 1404, 1406). As noted with reference to <figref idref="f0014">FIG. 14</figref>, when the user reaches for<!-- EPO <DP n="57"> --> the electronic device 102, the authentication system prepares to authenticate the user 1302. In <figref idref="f0015">FIG. 15</figref>, another detail view 1500-2 shows that the user 1302 has picked up the electronic device 102. The electronic device 102 determines that being picked up is a trigger event, as described above, and authenticates the user 1302. When the user 1302 is authenticated, the electronic device 102 exits the engaged mode (or the aware mode) and enters an active mode, as shown by an arrow 1502.</p>
<p id="p0127" num="0127">Additional visual elements associated with the active mode may also be presented on an example display 114-27, as shown in the detail view 1500-2. For example, in the active mode, the example display 114-27 continues to present the visual elements associated with the aware mode, but the background image 1404 (associated with the engaged mode) has changed to another background image 1504, a beach silhouette (note that because the background image 1504 has a different color scheme, some of the visual elements have changed contrast or color so that they remain visible to the user 1302). Additionally, the engaged mode lock icon 1406 has transitioned to an unlock icon 1506, which indicates that the user 1302 is authenticated. In some implementations, the unlock icon 1506 may be presented for a duration of time and then fade. While not illustrated in <figref idref="f0015">FIG. 15</figref>, additional visual elements may be displayed on the example display 114-27 after the unlock icon 1506 fades, such as an instruction (<i>e.g</i>., "Swipe or tap to open"), one or more application launch icons, or other visual elements available to the electronic device 102.</p>
<p id="p0128" num="0128">In some implementations, the user 1302 may remain authenticated as long as the user 1302 remains within the recognition zone (<i>e.g</i>., the recognition zone 1304) or within another defined area within which the radar system can detect the presence of the user 1302. In these implementations, the display 114 may remain powered and able to receive input and present content, or the screen may turn off to save battery power. Because the user 1302 remains authenticated, even if the screen is off, the user can access the electronic device 102 by touching the screen, picking up the device, or another action, without having to be re-authenticated. In this way, the user's enjoyment and experience with the electronic device 102 can be improved while preserving battery power.<!-- EPO <DP n="58"> --></p>
<p id="p0129" num="0129">Further, the described progression between modes (<i>e.g</i>., from the dormant mode, through the aware and engaged modes, to authentication and the active mode), may instead run in an opposite direction. For example, when the electronic device 102 is in the active mode and the user 1302 sets it down (e.g., another trigger event occurs), the electronic device may enter a locked state (<i>e.g</i>., de-authenticate the user 1302), and/or place the electronic device 102 in the engaged or aware mode, as described above. Accordingly, if the user's hand remains near the electronic device 102 (<i>e.g</i>., remains in a "reach" position), the electronic device 102 may remain in the engaged mode. Conversely, if the user's hand is withdrawn, the electronic device 102 may enter the aware mode. Then, as noted, the electronic device 102 may remain in the aware mode while the user is in the recognition zone. During this progression between zones, the display 114 may present the visual elements described above for each zone, to indicate the changing status of the electronic device 102 to the user 1302.</p>
<p id="p0130" num="0130">As noted, in some implementations, applications running on the electronic device 102 may be able to receive input through radar-based touch-independent gestures (radar gestures). In these cases, the radar system 104 may detect a reach by the user and perform actions, based on the context of the electronic device 102. For example, when the electronic device is in any of the modes described above, the user may receive a phone call, receive an alarm, alert, or notification, or play music through the electronic device. In these situations, the user may reach toward the electronic device to respond to the action. Thus, a reach may reduce or silence the ringer or notification during an incoming call or an alarm. Further, if the user notices an alert or notification is being displayed, and reaches toward the electronic device, the notification may be dismissed or become interactive. For example, upon detecting the user's reach, the electronic device may display the notification in a mode that allows the user to respond by dismissing or postponing the alert/notification, replying (in the case of a message or email notification), or in another manner. In some cases, the displayed notification may change color or size as well. In the example of the user listening to music, a reach may cause the electronic device to present a control screen for the music player, so that the user can control the track, volume, or other parameter.<!-- EPO <DP n="59"> --></p>
<p id="p0131" num="0131">Some or all of these features may be available in different modes, and which features are available may be user-selectable. For example, the user may allow volume silencing and music control in all modes but allow responding to alerts and notifications only in the active mode (<i>e.g</i>., when the user has been authenticated and has not left the recognition zone). Other combinations of features and permission levels may also be selected by the user.</p>
<p id="p0132" num="0132">Among the advantages of the described implementations, including implementations in which radar sensing is used to detect the presence of the user within a recognition zone, and further including implementations in which radar is used to detect user action that is categorized as an indication of a user intent to interact with the electronic device, either of which might alternatively be achievable using the on-device camera that is provided with most modern smartphones, is that the power usage of the radar facility is substantially less than the power usage of the camera facility, while the propriety of the results can often be better with the radar facility than with the camera facility. For example, using the radar facility described hereinabove, the desired user-state or user-intention detection can be achieved at average power ranging from single-digit milliwatts to just a few dozen milliwatts (<i>e.g</i>., 10 mW, 20 mW, 30 mW or 40 mW), even including the processing power for processing the radar vector data to make the determinations. At these low levels of power, it would be readily acceptable to have the radar facility in an always-on state. As such, for example, with the smartphone radar facility in the always-on state, the desired delightful and seamless experience presently described can still be provided for a user that has been sitting across the room from their smartphone for many hours.</p>
<p id="p0133" num="0133">In contrast, the optical cameras provided with most of today's smartphones typically operate at hundreds of milliwatts of power (<i>e.g</i>., an order of magnitude higher than 40 mW, which is 400 mW). At such power rates, optical cameras would be disadvantageous because they would significantly reduce the battery life of most of today's smartphones, so much so as to make it highly impractical, if not prohibitive, to have the optical camera in an always-on state. An additional advantage of the radar facility is that the field of view can be quite large, readily enough to detect a user walking up from any<!-- EPO <DP n="60"> --> direction even when lying flat and face-up on a table (for many typical implementations in which the radar chip is facing outward in the same general direction as the selfie camera) and, furthermore, by virtue of its Doppler processing ability can be highly effective (especially at operating frequencies near 60 GHz) in detecting even relatively subtle movements of moving bodies from the variety of directions.</p>
<p id="p0134" num="0134">Additionally, the radar facility can operate in environments in which the performance of the camera facility is reduced or restricted. For example, in lower-light environments, the camera facility may have a reduced ability to detect shape or movement. In contrast, the radar facility performs as well in lower-light as in full light. The radar facility can also detect presence and gestures through some obstacles. For instance, if the smartphone is in a pocket or a jacket or pair of pants, a camera facility cannot detect a user or a gesture. The radar facility, however, can still detect objects in its field, even through a fabric that would block the camera facility. An even further advantage of using a radar facility over an onboard video camera facility of a smartphone is privacy, because a user can have the advantages of the herein described delightful and seamless experiences while at the same time not needing to be worried that there is a video camera taking video of them for such purposes.</p>
<heading id="h0009"><b>Example Computing System</b></heading>
<p id="p0135" num="0135"><figref idref="f0016">FIG. 16</figref> illustrates various components of an example computing system 1600 that can be implemented as any type of client, server, and/or electronic device as described with reference to the previous <figref idref="f0001 f0002 f0003 f0004 f0005 f0006 f0007 f0008 f0009 f0010 f0011 f0012 f0013 f0014 f0015">FIGS. 1-15</figref> to implement input methods for mobile devices.</p>
<p id="p0136" num="0136">The computing system 1600 includes communication devices 1602 that enable wired and/or wireless communication of device data 1604 (<i>e.g</i>., radar data, authentication data, reference data, received data, data that is being received, data scheduled for broadcast, and data packets of the data). The device data 1604 or other device content can include configuration settings of the device, media content stored on the device, and/or information associated with a user of the device (<i>e.g</i>., an identity of a<!-- EPO <DP n="61"> --> person within a radar field or customized gesture data). Media content stored on the computing system 1600 can include any type of radar, biometric, audio, video, and/or image data. The computing system 1600 includes one or more data inputs 1606 via which any type of data, media content, and/or inputs can be received, such as human utterances, interactions with a radar field (<i>e.g</i>., a radar gesture), touch inputs, user-selectable inputs or interactions (explicit or implicit), messages, music, television media content, recorded video content, and any other type of audio, video, and/or image data received from any content and/or data source.</p>
<p id="p0137" num="0137">The computing system 1600 also includes communication interfaces 1608, which can be implemented as any one or more of a serial and/or a parallel interface, a wireless interface, any type of network interface, a modem, and as any other type of communication interface. The communication interfaces 1608 provide a connection and/or communication links between the computing system 1600 and a communication network by which other electronic, computing, and communication devices communicate data with the computing system 1600.</p>
<p id="p0138" num="0138">The computing system 1600 includes one or more processors 1610 (<i>e.g</i>., any of microprocessors, controllers, or other controllers) that can process various computer-executable instructions to control the operation of the computing system 1600 and to enable techniques for, or in which can be implemented, the input methods for mobile devices. Alternatively or additionally, the computing system 1600 can be implemented with any one or combination of hardware, firmware, or fixed logic circuitry that is implemented in connection with processing and control circuits, which are generally identified at 1612. Although not shown, the computing system 1600 can include a system bus or data transfer system that couples the various components within the device. The system bus can include any one or combination of different bus structures, such as a memory bus or memory controller, a peripheral bus, a universal serial bus, and/or a processor or local bus that utilizes any of a variety of bus architectures. Also not shown, the computing system 1600 can include one or more non-radar sensors, such as the non-radar sensors 108.<!-- EPO <DP n="62"> --></p>
<p id="p0139" num="0139">The computing system 1600 also includes computer-readable media 1614, such as one or more memory devices that enable persistent and/or non-transitory data storage (<i>e.g</i>., in contrast to mere signal transmission), examples of which include random access memory (RAM), non-volatile memory (<i>e.g</i>., any one or more of a read-only memory (ROM), flash memory, EPROM, EEPROM, etc.), and a disk storage device. A disk storage device may be implemented as any type of magnetic or optical storage device, such as a hard disk drive, a recordable and/or rewriteable compact disc (CD), any type of a digital versatile disc (DVD), and the like. The computing system 1600 can also include a mass storage media device (storage media) 1616.</p>
<p id="p0140" num="0140">The computer-readable media 1614 provides data storage mechanisms to store the device data 1604, as well as various device applications 1618 and any other types of information and/or data related to operational aspects of the computing system 1600. For example, an operating system 1620 can be maintained as a computer application with the computer-readable media 1614 and executed on the processors 1610. The device applications 1618 may include a device manager, such as any form of a control application, software application, signal-processing and control modules, code that is native to a particular device, an abstraction module, a gesture recognition module, and/or other modules. The device applications 1618 may also include system components, engines, modules, or managers to implement the input methods for mobile devices, such as the radar system 104, the interaction manager 106, or the application manager 116. The computing system 1600 may also include, or have access to, one or more machine-learning systems.<!-- EPO <DP n="63"> --></p>
<heading id="h0010"><b>Conclusion</b></heading>
<p id="p0141" num="0141">Although implementations of techniques for, and apparatuses enabling, input methods for mobile devices have been described in language specific to features and/or methods, it is to be understood that the subject of the appended claims is not necessarily limited to the specific features or methods described. Rather, the specific features and methods are disclosed as example implementations enabling the input methods for mobile devices. The scope of the present invention is defined only by the appended claims.</p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="64"> -->
<claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>A method implemented in an electronic device (102) that includes a display (114; 114-1 - 114-27) and a radar system (104), the method comprising:
<claim-text>determining, based on radar data received through the radar system (104), that a portion of a user is within a gesture zone (118) of the electronic device (102);</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining that an application operating on the electronic device (102) is configured to receive radar-gesture input; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>responsive to the determination that the portion of the user is within the gesture zone (118) of the electronic device (102) and the determination that the application operating on the electronic device (102) is configured to receive radar-gesture input, providing a feedback indicator (120) on the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27) of the electronic device (102), the providing of the feedback indicator (120) indicating that:
<claim-text>the portion of the user is within the gesture zone (118); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the application can receive the radar-gesture input,</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein
<claim-text>providing the feedback indicator (120) on the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27) of the electronic device (102) comprises adjusting a visual element (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406) that is already being presented at an edge of an active area of the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27) for indicating that the application operating on the electronic device (102) is configured to receive radar-gesture input; and wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>adjusting the visual element (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406) that is already being presented comprises enlarging<!-- EPO <DP n="65"> --> an area of the visual element (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406) that is already being presented.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>The method of claim 1, wherein the visual element (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406) includes:
<claim-text>an area that comprises a portion of the active area of the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a visual property, the visual property comprising a luminosity, a color, a contrast, a shape, a saturation, or an opaqueness that is different from the visual property of another portion of the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27) that is proximate to the visual element (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a segment of an exterior border that is within a threshold distance of the edge of the active area of the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>The method of claim 2, wherein the visual property of the visual element (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406) varies across the area of the visual element.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>The method of any of claims 1-3, wherein:
<claim-text>the portion of the user that is within the gesture zone (118) is a hand (112; 902; 1002; 1102) of the user; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining that the portion of the user is within the gesture zone (118) of the electronic device (102) comprises detecting a reach, by the hand (112; 902; 1002; 1102) of the user, toward the electronic device (102).</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="66"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>The method of claim 1, wherein enlarging the area of the visual element (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406) that is already being presented comprises:
<claim-text>extending the visual element (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406) that is already being presented in a direction parallel to the edge of the active area of the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27); or</claim-text>
<claim-text>extending the visual element (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406) that is already being presented in a direction away from the edge of the active area of the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>The method of any of claims 1, 4 or 5, further comprising: dynamically adjusting a visual property of the feedback indicator (120) corresponding to a distance of the portion of the user to the electronic device (102) and / or a movement of the portion of the user in the gesture zone (118).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>The method of claim 6, wherein:
<claim-text>the visual property is at least one of a luminosity, a brightness, or a visual intensity of the feedback indicator;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a measurement of the visual property increases as the distance approaches an amount corresponding to an improved radar-gesture-recognition efficacy of the radar system (104); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the measurement of the visual property of the feedback indicator (120) decreases as the distance approaches an amount corresponding to a reduced radar-gesture-recognition efficacy.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>The method of any of claims 1-7, further comprising dynamically adjusting<!-- EPO <DP n="67"> --> a position of the feedback indicator (120) on the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27), the<!-- EPO <DP n="68"> --> dynamic adjustment of the position of the feedback indicator (120) corresponding to a movement of the portion of the user that is within the gesture zone (118) of the electronic device (102), the movement of the portion of the user that is within the gesture zone (118) of the electronic device (102) based on a first subset of the radar data on which the determination that the portion of the user is within the gesture zone (118) of the electronic device (102) was based or on a second subset of the radar data, the second subset of the radar data received, by the radar system (104), after reception of the first subset of the radar data.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>The method of any of claims 1-8, further comprising:
<claim-text>determining, based on a first subset of the radar data on which the determination that the portion of the user is within the gesture zone (118) of the electronic device (102) was based or on a second subset of the radar data, the second subset of the radar data received, by the radar system (104), after reception of the first subset of the radar data, that the portion of the user is no longer within the gesture zone (118); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>responsive to the determination that the portion of the user is no longer within the gesture zone (118), ceasing to provide the feedback indicator (120) on the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27) of the electronic device (102).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>The method of any of claims 1-9, further comprising:
<claim-text>determining a background color of a region of the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27) on which the feedback indicator (120) is displayed; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>responsive to determining the background color of the region of the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27) on which the feedback indicator (120) is displayed, causing the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27) to provide the feedback indicator (120) in another color that is different from the background color, the different color effective to provide human-discernable contrast between the feedback indicator (120) and the region of the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27) on which the feedback indicator (120) is displayed.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="69"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>An electronic device (102) comprising:
<claim-text>a display (114; 114-1 - 114-27);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a radar system (104), implemented at least partially in hardware, configured to:
<claim-text>provide a radar field (110);</claim-text>
<claim-text>sense reflections from a user in the radar field (110);</claim-text>
<claim-text>analyze the reflections from the user in the radar field (110); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>provide, based on the analysis of the reflections, radar data;</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>a computer processor (202); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a computer-readable media (204) having instructions stored thereon that, responsive to execution by the computer processor (202), implement a radar-based interaction manager (106) configured to:
<claim-text>determine that an application operating on the electronic device (102) is configured to receive radar-gesture input;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determine, based on the radar data, that a portion of the user is within a gesture zone (118) of the electronic device (102); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>responsive to the determination that the application operating on the electronic device (102) is configured to receive radar-gesture input and the determination that the portion of the user is within the gesture zone (118) of the electronic device (102), cause the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27) to present a feedback indicator (120), the presentation of the feedback indicator (120) indicating that:
<claim-text>the portion of the user is within the gesture zone (118); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the application can receive the radar-gesture input,</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein
<claim-text>to cause the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27) to present the feedback indicator (120) comprises to cause the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27) to make an adjustment to a visual element (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406) that is already being presented at an edge of an active area of the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27) for<!-- EPO <DP n="70"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>indicating that the application operating on the electronic device (102) is configured to receive radar-gesture input; and wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>the adjustment to the visual element (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406) that is already being presented comprises at least enlarging an area of the visual element (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406) that is already being presented.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>The electronic device of claim 11, wherein the visual element (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406) includes:
<claim-text>an area that comprises a portion of the active area of the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a visual property, the visual property comprising a luminosity, a color, a contrast, a shape, a saturation, or an opaqueness that is different from the visual property of another portion of the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27) that is proximate to the visual element (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a segment of an exterior border that is within a threshold distance of the edge of the active area of the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>The electronic device of claim 12, wherein the visual property of the visual element (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406) varies across the area of the visual element.<!-- EPO <DP n="71"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>The electronic device of any of claims 11-13, wherein:
<claim-text>the portion of the user that is within the gesture zone (118) is a hand (112; 902; 1002; 1102) of the user; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the determination that the portion of the user is within the gesture zone of the electronic device is a determination of a reach, by the hand (112; 902; 1002; 1102) of the user, toward the electronic device (102).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0015" num="0015">
<claim-text>The electronic device of claim 11, wherein enlarging the area of the visual element (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406) that is already being presented comprises:
<claim-text>extending the visual element (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004: 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406) that is already being presented in a direction parallel to the edge of the active area of the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27); or</claim-text>
<claim-text>extending the visual element (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406) that is already being presented in a direction away from the edge of the active area of the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0016" num="0016">
<claim-text>The electronic device of claim 11, 14 or 15, wherein the radar-based interaction manager (106) is further configured to dynamically adjust a visual property of the feedback indicator (120) corresponding to a distance of the portion of the user to the electronic device (102) and/or a movement of the portion of the user in the gesture zone (118).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0017" num="0017">
<claim-text>The electronic device of claim 16, wherein:
<claim-text>the visual property is at least one of a luminosity, a brightness, or a visual intensity of the feedback indicator (120);<!-- EPO <DP n="72"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>a measurement of the visual property increases as the distance approaches an amount corresponding to an improved radar-gesture-recognition efficacy of the radar system (104); and<!-- EPO <DP n="73"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>the measurement of the visual property of the feedback indicator (120) decreases as the distance approaches an amount corresponding to a reduced radar-gesture-recognition efficacy.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0018" num="0018">
<claim-text>The electronic device of any of claims 11-17, wherein the radar-based interaction manager (106) is further configured to dynamically adjust a position of the feedback indicator (120) on the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27), the dynamic adjustment of the position of the feedback indicator (120) corresponding to a movement of the portion of the user that is within the gesture zone (118) of the electronic device (102), the movement of the portion of the user that is within the gesture zone (118) of the electronic device (102) based on a first subset of the radar data on which the determination that the portion of the user is within the gesture zone (118) of the electronic device (102) was based or a second subset of the radar data, the second subset of the radar data received, by the radar system (104), after reception of the first subset of the radar data.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0019" num="0019">
<claim-text>The electronic device of any of claims 11-18, wherein the radar-based interaction manager (106) is further configured to:
<claim-text>determine, based on a first subset of the radar data on which the determination that the portion of the user is within the gesture zone (118) of the electronic device (102) was based or on a second subset of the radar data, the second subset of the radar data received, by the radar system (104), after reception of the first subset of the radar data, that the portion of the user is no longer within the gesture zone (118); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>responsive to the determination that the portion of the user is no longer within the gesture zone (118), cause the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27) to cease to present the feedback indicator (120).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0020" num="0020">
<claim-text>The electronic device of any of claims 11-19, wherein the radar-based interaction manager (106) is further configured to:<!-- EPO <DP n="74"> -->
<claim-text>determine a background color of a region of the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27) on which the feedback indicator (120) is presented; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>responsive to the determination of the background color of the region of the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27) on which the feedback indicator (120) is presented, cause the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27) to present the feedback indicator (120) in another color that is different from the background color, the different color effective to provide human-discernable contrast between the feedback indicator (120) and the region of the display (114; 114-1 - 114-27) on which the feedback indicator (120) is presented.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims02" lang="de"><!-- EPO <DP n="75"> -->
<claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Verfahren, das in einer elektronischen Vorrichtung (102) implementiert ist, die eine Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27) und ein Radarsystem (104) beinhaltet, das Verfahren umfassend:
<claim-text>Ermitteln, basierend auf durch das Radarsystem (104) empfangenen Gestendaten, dass sich ein Teil eines Benutzers innerhalb einer Gestenzone (118) der elektronischen Vorrichtung (102) befindet;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Ermitteln, dass eine Anwendung, die auf der elektronischen Vorrichtung (102) betrieben wird, zum Empfangen von Radar-Gesteneingaben konfiguriert ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>in Reaktion auf das Ermitteln, dass sich der Teil des Benutzers innerhalb der Gestenzone (118) der elektronischen Vorrichtung (102) befindet, und das Ermitteln, dass die auf der elektronischen Vorrichtung (102) laufende Anwendung so konfiguriert ist, dass sie Radar-Gesteneingaben empfängt, Bereitstellen eines Feedback-Indikators (120) auf der Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27) der elektronischen Vorrichtung (102), wobei das Bereitstellen des Feedback-Indikators (120) angibt, dass:
<claim-text>sich der Teil des Benutzers innerhalb der Gestenzone (118) befindet; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>die Anwendung die Radar-Gesteneingabe empfangen kann, wobei</claim-text>
<claim-text>das Bereitstellen des Feedback-Indikators (120) auf der Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27) der elektronischen Vorrichtung (102) das Anpassen eines visuellen Elements (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406) umfasst, das bereits an einem Rand eines aktiven Bereichs der Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27) dargestellt wird, um anzugeben, dass die auf der elektronischen Vorrichtung (102) laufende Anwendung konfiguriert ist, die Radar-Gesteneingaben zu empfangen; und wobei</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>das Anpassen des visuellen Elements (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406), das bereits vorliegt, das Vergrößern eines Bereichs des visuellen Elements (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406), das bereits vorliegt, umfasst.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="76"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, wobei das visuelle Element (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406) beinhaltet:
<claim-text>einen Bereich, der einen Abschnitt des aktiven Bereichs der Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27) umfasst;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine visuelle Eigenschaft, wobei die visuelle Eigenschaft eine Leuchtkraft, eine Farbe, einen Kontrast, eine Form, eine Sättigung oder eine Opazität umfasst, die sich von der visuellen Eigenschaft eines anderen Abschnitts der Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27) unterscheidet, der sich in der Nähe des visuellen Elements (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406) befindet; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Segment einer Außengrenze, das sich innerhalb eines Schwellenabstands zum Rand des aktiven Bereichs der Anzeige befindet (114; 114-1 - 114-27).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 2, wobei die visuelle Eigenschaft des visuellen Elements (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406) über den Bereich des visuellen Elements variiert.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 1-3, wobei:
<claim-text>der Teil des Benutzers, der sich innerhalb der Gestenzone (118) befindet, eine Hand (112; 902; 1002; 1102) des Benutzers ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>das Ermitteln, dass sich der Teil des Benutzers innerhalb der Gestenzone (118) der elektronischen Vorrichtung (102) befindet, das Erkennen eines Greifens durch die Hand (112; 902; 1002; 1102) des Benutzers in Richtung der elektronischen Vorrichtung (102) umfasst.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, wobei das Vergrößern des Bereichs des visuellen Elements (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406), das bereits vorliegt, Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>Erweitern des visuellen Elements (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406), das<!-- EPO <DP n="77"> --> bereits vorliegt, in einer Richtung parallel zum Rand des aktiven Bereichs der Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27); oder</claim-text>
<claim-text>Erweitern des visuellen Elements (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406), das bereits vorliegt, in einer Richtung weg vom Rand des aktiven Bereichs der Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 1, 4 oder 5, ferner umfassend: dynamisches Anpassen einer visuellen Eigenschaft des Feedback-Indikators (120) entsprechend einem Abstand des Teils des Benutzers zu der elektronischen Vorrichtung (102) und/oder einer Bewegung des Teils des Benutzers in der Gestenzone (118).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 6, wobei:
<claim-text>die visuelle Eigenschaft zumindest eine von einer Leuchtkraft, einer Helligkeit oder einer visuellen Intensität des Feedback-Indikators ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Messung der visuellen Eigenschaft zunimmt, wenn sich der Abstand einem Betrag nähert, der einer verbesserten Wirksamkeit der Radargestenerkennung des Radarsystems (104) entspricht; und die Messung der visuellen Eigenschaft des Feedback-Indikators (120) abnimmt, wenn sich der Abstand einem Betrag nähert, der einer verringerten Wirksamkeit der Radargestenerkennung entspricht.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 1-7, ferner umfassend das dynamische Anpassen einer Position des Feedback-Indikators (120) auf der Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27), wobei das dynamische Anpassen der Position des Feedback-Indikators (120) einer Bewegung des Teils des Benutzers entspricht, der sich innerhalb der Gestenzone (118) der elektronischen Vorrichtung (102) befindet, die Bewegung des Teils des Benutzers, der sich innerhalb der Gestenzone (118) der elektronischen Vorrichtung (102) befindet, basierend auf einer ersten Teilmenge der Radardaten, auf denen das Ermitteln, dass sich der Teil des Benutzers innerhalb der Gestenzone (118) der elektronischen Vorrichtung (102) befindet, basierte, oder auf einer zweiten Teilmenge der Radardaten, wobei<!-- EPO <DP n="78"> --> die zweite Teilmenge der Radardaten von dem Radarsystem (104) nach dem Empfangen der ersten Teilmenge der Radardaten empfangen wird.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 1-8, ferner umfassend:
<claim-text>Ermitteln, basierend auf einer ersten Teilmenge der Radardaten, auf denen das Ermitteln, dass sich der Teil des Benutzers innerhalb der Gestenzone (118) der elektronischen Vorrichtung (102) befindet, basierte, oder auf einer zweiten Teilmenge der Radardaten, wobei die zweite Teilmenge der Radardaten von dem Radarsystem (104) nach dem Empfangen der ersten Teilmenge der Radardaten empfangen wurde, dass sich der Teil des Benutzers nicht mehr innerhalb der Gestenzone (118) befindet; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>in Reaktion auf das Ermitteln, dass sich der Teil des Benutzers nicht mehr innerhalb der Gestenzone (118) befindet, das Bereitstellen des Feedback-Indikators (120) auf der Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27) der elektronischen Vorrichtung (102) zu beenden.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 1-9, ferner umfassend:
<claim-text>Ermitteln einer Hintergrundfarbe eines Bereichs der Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27), auf dem der Feedback-Indikator (120) angezeigt wird; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>in Reaktion auf das Ermitteln der Hintergrundfarbe des Bereichs der Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27), auf dem der Feedback-Indikator (120) bereitgestellt wird, Veranlassen, dass die Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27) den Feedback-Indikator (120) in einer anderen Farbe bereitstellt, die sich von der Hintergrundfarbe unterscheidet, wobei die andere Farbe wirksam ist, um einen für den Menschen erkennbaren Kontrast zwischen dem Feedback-Indikator (120) und dem Bereich der Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27) bereitzustellen, auf dem der Feedback-Indikator (120) angezeigt wird.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>Elektronisches Gerät (102), umfassend:
<claim-text>eine Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27);<!-- EPO <DP n="79"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Radarsystem (104), das zumindest teilweise in Hardware implementiert ist, konfiguriert zum:
<claim-text>Bereitstellen eines Radarfeldes (110);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Erfassen von Reflexionen eines Benutzers in dem Radarfeld (110);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Analysieren der Reflexionen des Benutzers in dem Radarfeld (110); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Bereitstellen, basierend auf der Analyse der Reflexionen, von Radardaten;</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Computerprozessor (202); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein computerlesbares Medium (204) mit darauf gespeicherten Anweisungen, die, in Reaktion auf eine Ausführung durch den Computerprozessor (202), einen radarbasierten Interaktionsmanager (106) implementieren, der konfiguriert ist zum:
<claim-text>Ermitteln, dass eine Anwendung, die auf der elektronischen Vorrichtung (102) betrieben wird, zum Empfangen von Radar-Gesteneingaben konfiguriert ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Ermitteln, basierend auf den Radardaten, dass sich ein Teil des Benutzers innerhalb einer Gestenzone (118) der elektronischen Vorrichtung (102) befindet; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>in Reaktion auf das Ermitteln, dass die auf der elektronischen Vorrichtung (102) laufende Anwendung so konfiguriert ist, dass sie Radar-Gesteneingaben empfängt, und das Ermitteln, dass sich der Teil des Benutzers innerhalb der Gestenzone (118) der elektronischen Vorrichtung (102) befindet, Veranlassen, dass die Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27) einen Feedback-Indikator (120) präsentiert, wobei die Präsentation des Feedback-Indikators (120) angibt, dass:
<claim-text>sich der Teil des Benutzers innerhalb der Gestenzone (118) befindet; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>die Anwendung die Radar-Gesteneingabe empfangen kann,</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei
<claim-text>das Veranlassen der Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27), den Feedback-Indikator (120) darzustellen, das Veranlassen der Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27) umfasst, eine Anpassung an ein<!-- EPO <DP n="80"> --> visuelles Element (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406) vorzunehmen, das bereits an einem Rand eines aktiven Bereichs der Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27) dargestellt wird, um anzugeben, dass die Anwendung, die auf der elektronischen Vorrichtung (102) betrieben wird, zum Empfangen von Radar-Gesteneingaben konfiguriert ist; und wobei</claim-text>
<claim-text>das Anpassen des visuellen Elements (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406), das bereits vorliegt, zumindest das Vergrößern eines Bereichs des visuellen Elements (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406), das bereits vorliegt, umfasst.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>Elektronische Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 11, wobei das visuelle Element (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406) beinhaltet:
<claim-text>einen Bereich, der einen Abschnitt des aktiven Bereichs der Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27) umfasst;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine visuelle Eigenschaft, wobei die visuelle Eigenschaft eine Leuchtkraft, eine Farbe, einen Kontrast, eine Form, eine Sättigung oder eine Opazität umfasst, die sich von der visuellen Eigenschaft eines anderen Abschnitts der Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27) unterscheidet, der sich in der Nähe des visuellen Elements (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406) befindet; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Segment einer Außengrenze, das sich innerhalb eines Schwellenabstands zum Rand des aktiven Bereichs der Anzeige befindet (114; 114-1 - 114-27).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>Elektronische Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 12, wobei die visuelle Eigenschaft des visuellen Elements (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406) über den Bereich des visuellen Elements variiert.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>Elektronische Vorrichtung nach einem der Ansprüche 11-13, wobei:<!-- EPO <DP n="81"> -->
<claim-text>der Teil des Benutzers, der sich innerhalb der Gestenzone (118) befindet, eine Hand (112; 902; 1002; 1102) des Benutzers ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>das Ermitteln, dass sich der Teil des Benutzers innerhalb der Gestenzone der elektronischen Vorrichtung befindet, ein Ermitteln eines Erreichens durch die Hand (112; 902; 1002; 1102) des Benutzers in Richtung der elektronischen Vorrichtung (102) ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0015" num="0015">
<claim-text>Elektronische Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 11, wobei das Vergrößern des Bereichs des visuellen Elements (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406), das bereits vorliegt, Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>Erweitern des visuellen Elements (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406), das bereits vorliegt, in einer Richtung parallel zum Rand des aktiven Bereichs der Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27); oder</claim-text>
<claim-text>Erweitern des visuellen Elements (122; 802; 804; 906; 910; 1004; 1104; 1202, 1208; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314; 1404, 1406), das bereits vorliegt, in einer Richtung weg vom Rand des aktiven Bereichs der Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0016" num="0016">
<claim-text>Elektronische Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 11, 14 oder 15, wobei der radarbasierte Interaktionsmanager (106) ferner konfiguriert ist, um eine visuelle Eigenschaft des Feedback-Indikators (120) entsprechend einem Abstand des Teils des Benutzers zu der elektronischen Vorrichtung (102) und/oder einer Bewegung des Teils des Benutzers in der Gestenzone (118) dynamisch anzupassen.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0017" num="0017">
<claim-text>Elektronische Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 16, wobei:
<claim-text>die visuelle Eigenschaft zumindest eine von einer Leuchtkraft, einer Helligkeit oder einer visuellen Intensität des Feedback-Indikators (120) ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Messung der visuellen Eigenschaft zunimmt, wenn sich der Abstand einem Betrag nähert, der einer verbesserten Wirksamkeit der Radar-Gestenerkennung des Radarsystems (104) entspricht; und<!-- EPO <DP n="82"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>die Messung der visuellen Eigenschaft des Feedback-Indikators (120) abnimmt, wenn sich der Abstand einem Betrag nähert, der einer verringerten Wirksamkeit der Radar-Gestenerkennung entspricht.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0018" num="0018">
<claim-text>Elektronische Vorrichtung nach einem der Ansprüche 11-17, wobei der radarbasierte Interaktionsmanager (106) ferner konfiguriert ist, um eine Position des Feedback-Indikators (120) auf der Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27) einzustellen, wobei das dynamische Anpassen der Position des Feedback-Indikators (120) einer Bewegung des Teils des Benutzers entspricht, der sich innerhalb der Gestenzone (118) der elektronischen Vorrichtung (102) befindet, die Bewegung des Teils des Benutzers, der sich innerhalb der Gestenzone (118) der elektronischen Vorrichtung (102) befindet, basierend auf einer ersten Teilmenge der Radardaten, auf denen das Ermitteln, dass sich der Teil des Benutzers innerhalb der Gestenzone (118) der elektronischen Vorrichtung (102) befindet, basierte, oder auf einer zweiten Teilmenge der Radardaten, wobei die zweite Teilmenge der Radardaten von dem Radarsystem (104) nach dem Empfangen der ersten Teilmenge der Radardaten empfangen wird.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0019" num="0019">
<claim-text>Elektronische Vorrichtung nach einem der Ansprüche 11-18, wobei der radarbasierte Interaktionsmanager (106) ferner konfiguriert ist zum:
<claim-text>Ermitteln, basierend auf einer ersten Teilmenge der Radardaten, auf denen das Ermitteln, dass sich der Teil des Benutzers innerhalb der Gestenzone (118) der elektronischen Vorrichtung (102) befindet, basierte, oder auf einer zweiten Teilmenge der Radardaten, wobei die zweite Teilmenge der Radardaten von dem Radarsystem (104) nach dem Empfangen der ersten Teilmenge der Radardaten empfangen wurde, dass sich der Teil des Benutzers nicht mehr innerhalb der Gestenzone (118) befindet; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>in Reaktion auf das Ermitteln, dass sich der Teil des Benutzers nicht mehr innerhalb der Gestenzone (118) befindet, Veranlassen, dass die Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27) die Darstellung des Feedback-Indikators (120) beendet.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="83"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0020" num="0020">
<claim-text>Elektronische Vorrichtung nach einem der Ansprüche 11-19, wobei der radarbasierte Interaktionsmanager (106) ferner konfiguriert ist zum:
<claim-text>Ermitteln einer Hintergrundfarbe eines Bereichs der Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27), auf dem der Feedback-Indikator (120) dargestellt wird; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>in Reaktion auf das Ermitteln der Hintergrundfarbe des Bereichs der Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27), auf dem der Feedback-Indikator (120) dargestellt wird, Veranlassen, dass die Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27) den Feedback-Indikator (120) in einer anderen Farbe darstellt, die sich von der Hintergrundfarbe unterscheidet, wobei die andere Farbe wirksam ist, um einen für den Menschen erkennbaren Kontrast zwischen dem Feedback-Indikator (120) und dem Bereich der Anzeige (114; 114-1 - 114-27) bereitzustellen, auf dem der Feedback-Indikator (120) dargestellt wird.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims03" lang="fr"><!-- EPO <DP n="84"> -->
<claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Procédé mis en œuvre dans un dispositif électronique (102) qui inclut un affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27) et un système radar (104), le procédé comprenant :
<claim-text>la détermination, sur la base de données radar reçues par l'intermédiaire du système radar (104), qu'une partie d'un utilisateur se trouve au sein d'une zone de geste (118) du dispositif électronique (102) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>la détermination qu'une application fonctionnant sur le dispositif électronique (102) est configurée pour recevoir une entrée de geste radar ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>en réponse à la détermination que la partie de l'utilisateur se trouve au sein de la zone de geste (118) du dispositif électronique (102) et à la détermination que l'application fonctionnant sur le dispositif électronique (102) est configurée pour recevoir une entrée de geste radar, la fourniture d'un indicateur de rétroaction (120) sur l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27) du dispositif électronique (102), la fourniture de l'indicateur de rétroaction (120) indiquant que :
<claim-text>la partie de l'utilisateur est au sein de la zone de geste (118) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'application peut recevoir l'entrée de geste radar, dans lequel</claim-text>
<claim-text>la fourniture de l'indicateur de rétroaction (120) sur l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27) du dispositif électronique (102) comprend l'ajustement d'un élément visuel (122 ; 802 ; 804 ; 906 ; 910 ; 1004 ; 1104 ; 1202, 1208 ; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314 ; 1404, 1406) qui est déjà présenté au niveau d'un bord d'une zone active de l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27) pour indiquer que l'application fonctionnant sur le dispositif électronique (102) est configurée pour recevoir l'entrée de gestion radar ; et dans lequel</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>l'ajustement de l'élément visuel (122 ; 802 ; 804 ; 906 ; 910 ; 1004 ; 1104 ; 1202, 1208 ; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314 ; 1404, 1406) qui est déjà présenté comprend l'agrandissement d'une zone<!-- EPO <DP n="85"> --> d'élément visuel (122 ; 802 ; 804 ; 906 ; 910 ; 1004 ; 1104 ; 1202, 1208 ; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314 ; 1404, 1406) qui est déjà présenté.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, dans lequel l'élément visuel (122 ; 802 ; 804 ; 906 ; 910 ; 1004 ; 1104 ; 1202, 1208 ; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314 ; 1404, 1406) inclut :
<claim-text>une zone qui comprend une partie de la zone active de l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une propriété visuelle, la propriété visuelle comprenant une luminosité, une couleur, un contraste, une forme, une saturation ou une opacité qui est différente de la propriété visuelle d'une autre partie de l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27) qui est proche de l'élément visuel (122 ; 802 ; 804 ; 906 ; 910 ; 1004 ; 1104 ; 1202, 1208 ; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314 ; 1404, 1406) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un segment d'une bordure extérieure qui est au sein d'une distance seuil du bord de la zone active de l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 2, dans lequel la propriété visuelle de l'élément visuel (122 ; 802 ; 804 ; 906 ; 910 ; 1004 ; 1104 ; 1202, 1208 ; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314 ; 1404, 1406) varie sur la surface de l'élément visuel.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 3, dans lequel :
<claim-text>la partie de l'utilisateur qui se trouve au sein de la zone de geste (118) est une main (112 ; 902 ; 1002 ; 1102) de l'utilisateur ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la détermination que la partie de l'utilisateur est au sein de la zone de geste (118) du dispositif électronique (102) comprend la détection d'une portée, par la main (112 ; 902 ; 1002 ; 1102) de l'utilisateur, vers le dispositif électronique (102).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, dans lequel l'agrandissement de la zone de l'élément visuel (122 ; 802 ; 804 ; 906 ; 910 ; 1004 ; 1104 ; 1202, 1208 ; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314 ; 1404, 1406) qui est déjà présenté comprend :<!-- EPO <DP n="86"> -->
<claim-text>l'extension de l'élément visuel (122 ; 802 ; 804 ; 906 ; 910 ; 1004 ; 1104 ; 1202, 1208 ; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314 ; 1404, 1406) qui est déjà présenté dans une direction parallèle au bord de la zone active de l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27) ; ou</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'extension de l'élément visuel (122 ; 802 ; 804 ; 906 ; 910 ; 1004 ; 1104 ; 1202, 1208 ; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314 ; 1404, 1406) qui est déjà présenté dans une direction s'éloignant du bord de la zone active de l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1, 4 ou 5, comprenant en outre : l'ajustement dynamique d'une propriété visuelle de l'indicateur de rétroaction (120) correspondant à une distance de la partie de l'utilisateur au dispositif électronique (102) et/ou à un mouvement de la partie de l'utilisateur dans la zone de geste (118).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 6, dans lequel :
<claim-text>la propriété visuelle est au moins une parmi une luminosité, une luminance ou une intensité visuelle de l'indicateur de rétroaction ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une mesure de la propriété visuelle augmente à mesure que la distance approche d'une quantité correspondant à une efficacité améliorée de reconnaissance de geste radar du système radar (104) ; et la mesure de la propriété visuelle de l'indicateur de rétroaction (120) diminue à mesure que la distance approche d'une quantité correspondant à une efficacité réduite de reconnaissance de geste radar.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 7, comprenant en outre l'ajustement dynamique d'une position de l'indicateur de rétroaction (120) sur l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27), l'ajustement dynamique de la position de l'indicateur de rétroaction (120) correspondant à un mouvement de la partie de l'utilisateur qui se trouve au sein de la zone de geste (118) du dispositif électronique (102), le mouvement de la partie de l'utilisateur qui se trouve au sein de la zone de geste (118) du dispositif électronique (102) sur la base d'un premier sous-ensemble<!-- EPO <DP n="87"> --> des données radar sur lequel la détermination que la partie de l'utilisateur est au sein de la zone de geste (118) du dispositif électronique (102) était basée ou sur un second sous-ensemble des données radar, le second sous-ensemble des données radar reçues, par le système radar (104), après la réception du premier sous-ensemble des données radar.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 8, comprenant en outre :
<claim-text>la détermination, sur la base d'un premier sous-ensemble des données radar sur lequel la détermination que la partie de l'utilisateur se trouve au sein de la zone de geste (118) du dispositif électronique (102) était basée ou sur un second sous-ensemble des données radar, le second sous-ensemble des données radar reçues, par le système radar (104), après réception du premier sous-ensemble des données radar, que la partie de l'utilisateur ne se trouve plus au sein de la zone de geste (118) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>en réponse à la détermination que la partie de l'utilisateur ne se trouve plus au sein de la zone de geste (118), le fait de cesser de fournir l'indicateur de rétroaction (120) sur l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27) du dispositif électronique (102).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 9, comprenant en outre :
<claim-text>la détermination d'une couleur d'arrière-plan d'une région de l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27) sur laquelle l'indicateur de rétroaction (120) est affiché ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>en réponse à la détermination de la couleur d'arrière-plan de la région de l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27) sur lequel l'indicateur de rétroaction (120) est affiché, le fait d'amener l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27) à fournir l'indicateur de rétroaction (120) dans une autre couleur qui est différente de la couleur d'arrière-plan, la couleur différente efficace pour fournir un contraste humainement discernable entre l'indicateur de<!-- EPO <DP n="88"> --> rétroaction (120) et la région de l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27) sur lequel l'indicateur de rétroaction (120) est affiché.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>Dispositif électronique (102), comprenant :
<claim-text>un affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un système radar (104), mis en œuvre au moins partiellement dans du matériel, configuré pour :
<claim-text>fournir un champ radar (110) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>détecter des réflexions depuis un utilisateur dans le champ radar (110) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>analyser les réflexions depuis l'utilisateur dans le champ radar (110) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>fournir, sur la base de l'analyse des réflexions, des données radar ;</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>un processeur informatique (202) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un support lisible par ordinateur (204) ayant des instructions stockées sur celui-ci qui, en réponse à l'exécution par le processeur informatique (202), mettent en œuvre un gestionnaire d'interaction basé sur radar (106) configuré pour :
<claim-text>déterminer qu'une application fonctionnant sur le dispositif électronique (102) est configurée pour recevoir une entrée de geste radar ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>déterminer, sur la base des données radar, qu'une partie de l'utilisateur se trouve au sein d'une zone de geste (118) du dispositif électronique (102) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>en réponse à la détermination que l'application fonctionnant sur le dispositif électronique (102) est configurée pour recevoir une entrée de geste radar et à la détermination que la partie de l'utilisateur se trouve au sein de la zone de geste (118) du dispositif électronique (102), le fait d'amener l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27) à présenter un indicateur de rétroaction (120), la présentation de l'indicateur de rétroaction (120) indiquant que :
<claim-text>la partie de l'utilisateur est au sein de la zone de geste (118) ; et<!-- EPO <DP n="89"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>l'application peut recevoir l'entrée de geste radar,</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel
<claim-text>amener l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27) à présenter l'indicateur de rétroaction (120) comprend le fait d'amener l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27) à effectuer un ajustement sur un élément visuel (122 ; 802 ; 804 ; 906 ; 910 ; 1004 ; 1104 ; 1202, 1208 ; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314 ; 1404, 1406) qui est déjà présenté au niveau d'un bord d'une zone active de l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27) pour indiquer que l'application fonctionnant sur le dispositif électronique (102) est configurée pour recevoir l'entrée de gestion radar ; et dans lequel</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'ajustement de l'élément visuel (122 ; 802 ; 804 ; 906 ; 910 ; 1004 ; 1104 ; 1202, 1208 ; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314, 1404, 1406) qui est déjà présenté comprend au moins l'agrandissement d'une zone de l'élément visuel (122 ; 802 ; 804 ; 906 ; 910 ; 1004 ; 1104 ; 1202, 1208 ; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314 ; 1404, 1406) qui est déjà présenté.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>Dispositif électronique selon la revendication 11, dans lequel l'élément visuel (122 ; 802 ; 804 ; 906 ; 910 ; 1004 ; 1104 ; 1202, 1208 ; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314 ; 1404, 1406) inclut :
<claim-text>une zone qui comprend une partie de la zone active de l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une propriété visuelle, la propriété visuelle comprenant une luminosité, une couleur, un contraste, une forme, une saturation ou une opacité qui est différente de la propriété visuelle d'une autre partie de l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27) qui est proche de l'élément visuel (122 ; 802 ; 804 ; 906 ; 910 ; 1004 ; 1104 ; 1202, 1208 ; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314 ; 1404, 1406) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un segment d'une bordure extérieure qui est au sein d'une distance seuil du bord de la zone active de l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27).</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="90"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>Dispositif électronique selon la revendication 12, dans lequel la propriété visuelle de l'élément visuel (122 ; 802 ; 804 ; 906 ; 910 ; 1004 ; 1104 ; 1202, 1208 ; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314 ; 1404, 1406) varie sur la surface de l'élément visuel.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>Dispositif électronique selon l'une quelconque des revendications 11 à 13, dans lequel :
<claim-text>la partie de l'utilisateur qui se trouve au sein de la zone de geste (118) est une main (112 ; 902 ; 1002 ; 1102) de l'utilisateur ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la détermination que la partie de l'utilisateur se trouve au sein de la zone de geste du dispositif électronique est une détermination d'une portée, par la main (112 ; 902 ; 1002 ; 1102) de l'utilisateur, vers le dispositif électronique (102).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0015" num="0015">
<claim-text>Dispositif électronique selon la revendication 11, dans lequel l'agrandissement de la zone de l'élément visuel (122 ; 802 ; 804 ; 906 ; 910 ; 1004 ; 1104 ; 1202, 1208 ; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314 ; 1404, 1406) qui est déjà présenté comprend :
<claim-text>l'extension de l'élément visuel (122 ; 802 ; 804 ; 906 ; 910 ; 1004 ; 1104 ; 1202, 1208 ; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314 ; 1404, 1406) qui est déjà présenté dans une direction parallèle au bord de la zone active de l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27) ; ou</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'extension de l'élément visuel (122 ; 802 ; 804 ; 906 ; 910 ; 1004 ; 1104 ; 1202, 1208 ; 1308, 1310, 1312, 1314 ; 1404, 1406) qui est déjà présenté dans une direction s'éloignant du bord de la zone active de l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0016" num="0016">
<claim-text>Dispositif électronique selon la revendication 11, 14 ou 15, dans lequel le gestionnaire d'interaction basé sur radar (106) est en outre configuré pour ajuster dynamiquement une propriété visuelle de l'indicateur de rétroaction (120) correspondant à une distance de la partie de l'utilisateur au dispositif électronique (102) et/ou un mouvement de la partie de l'utilisateur dans la zone de geste (118).<!-- EPO <DP n="91"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0017" num="0017">
<claim-text>Dispositif électronique selon la revendication 16, dans lequel :
<claim-text>la propriété visuelle est au moins une parmi une luminosité, une luminance ou une intensité visuelle de l'indicateur de rétroaction (120) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une mesure de la propriété visuelle augmente à mesure que la distance s'approche d'une quantité correspondant à une efficacité améliorée de reconnaissance de geste radar du système radar (104) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la mesure de la propriété visuelle de l'indicateur de rétroaction (120) diminue à mesure que la distance s'approche d'une quantité correspondant à une efficacité réduite de reconnaissance de geste radar.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0018" num="0018">
<claim-text>Dispositif électronique selon l'une quelconque des revendications 11 à 17, dans lequel le gestionnaire d'interaction basé sur radar (106) est en outre configuré pour ajuster dynamiquement une position de l'indicateur de rétroaction (120) sur l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27), l'ajustement dynamique de la position de l'indicateur de rétroaction (120) correspondant à un mouvement de la partie de l'utilisateur qui se trouve au sein de la zone de geste (118) du dispositif électronique (102), le mouvement de la partie de l'utilisateur qui se trouve au sein de la zone de geste (118) du dispositif électronique (102) sur la base d'un premier sous-ensemble des données radar sur lequel la détermination que la partie de l'utilisateur est au sein de la zone de geste (118) du dispositif électronique (102) était basée ou un second sous-ensemble des données radar, le second sous-ensemble des données radar reçues, par le système radar (104), après la réception du premier sous-ensemble des données radar.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0019" num="0019">
<claim-text>Dispositif électronique selon l'une quelconque des revendications 11 à 18, dans lequel le gestionnaire d'interaction basé sur radar (106) est en outre configuré pour :
<claim-text>déterminer, sur la base d'un premier sous-ensemble des données radar sur lequel la détermination que la partie de l'utilisateur<!-- EPO <DP n="92"> --> se trouve au sein de la zone de geste (118) du dispositif électronique (102) était basée ou sur un second sous-ensemble des données radar, le second sous-ensemble des données radar reçues, par le système radar (104), après réception du premier sous-ensemble des données radar, que la partie de l'utilisateur ne se trouve plus au sein de la zone de geste (118) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>en réponse à la détermination que la partie de l'utilisateur ne se trouve plus au sein de la zone de geste (118), amener l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27) à cesser de présenter l'indicateur de rétroaction (120).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0020" num="0020">
<claim-text>Dispositif électronique selon l'une quelconque des revendications 11 à 19, dans lequel le gestionnaire d'interaction basé sur radar (106) est en outre configuré pour :
<claim-text>déterminer une couleur d'arrière-plan d'une région de l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27) sur laquelle l'indicateur de rétroaction (120) est présenté ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>en réponse à la détermination de la couleur d'arrière-plan de la région de l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27) sur lequel l'indicateur de rétroaction (120) est affiché, amener l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27) à présenter l'indicateur de rétroaction (120) dans une autre couleur qui est différente de la couleur d'arrière-plan, la couleur différente efficace pour fournir un contraste humainement discernable entre l'indicateur de rétroaction (120) et la région de l'affichage (114 ; 114-1 - 114-27) sur lequel l'indicateur de rétroaction (120) est présenté.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="93"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="156" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="94"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="148" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="95"> -->
<figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="140" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="96"> -->
<figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="161" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="97"> -->
<figure id="f0005" num="5"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="153" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="98"> -->
<figure id="f0006" num="6"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="150" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="99"> -->
<figure id="f0007" num="7"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="139" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="100"> -->
<figure id="f0008" num="8"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="140" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="101"> -->
<figure id="f0009" num="9A,9B,9C,9D"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="150" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="102"> -->
<figure id="f0010" num="10"><img id="if0010" file="imgf0010.tif" wi="157" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="103"> -->
<figure id="f0011" num="11"><img id="if0011" file="imgf0011.tif" wi="156" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="104"> -->
<figure id="f0012" num="12"><img id="if0012" file="imgf0012.tif" wi="160" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="105"> -->
<figure id="f0013" num="13"><img id="if0013" file="imgf0013.tif" wi="163" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="106"> -->
<figure id="f0014" num="14"><img id="if0014" file="imgf0014.tif" wi="159" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="107"> -->
<figure id="f0015" num="15"><img id="if0015" file="imgf0015.tif" wi="156" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="108"> -->
<figure id="f0016" num="16"><img id="if0016" file="imgf0016.tif" wi="125" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<ep-reference-list id="ref-list">
<heading id="ref-h0001"><b>REFERENCES CITED IN THE DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0001" num=""><i>This list of references cited by the applicant is for the reader's convenience only. It does not form part of the European patent document. Even though great care has been taken in compiling the references, errors or omissions cannot be excluded and the EPO disclaims all liability in this regard.</i></p>
<heading id="ref-h0002"><b>Patent documents cited in the description</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0002" num="">
<ul id="ref-ul0001" list-style="bullet">
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0001" dnum="US2019138109A1"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2019138109</doc-number><kind>A1</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0001">[0001]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0002" dnum="US2018164893A1"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2018164893</doc-number><kind>A1</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0002">[0002]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0003" dnum="US2017243389A1"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2017243389</doc-number><kind>A1</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0003">[0003]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0004" dnum="US2019162010A1"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2019162010</doc-number><kind>A1</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0004">[0004]</crossref></li>
</ul></p>
</ep-reference-list>
</ep-patent-document>
