<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP19890365A1" file="EP19890365NWA1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3888715" kind="A1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSKBAHRIS..MTNORSMESMMAKHTNMD..........</B001EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  1100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3888715</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT APPLICATION</B121><B121EP>published in accordance with Art. 153(4) EPC</B121EP></B120><B130>A1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>19890365.0</B210><B220><date>20191015</date></B220><B240><B241><date>20210630</date></B241></B240><B250>ko</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B300><B310>20180152804</B310><B320><date>20181130</date></B320><B330><ctry>KR</ctry></B330></B300><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B430></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>A61L  27/38        20060101AFI20200605BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="2"><text>A61L  27/26        20060101ALI20200605BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="3"><text>A61L  27/22        20060101ALI20200605BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="4"><text>A61L  27/24        20060101ALI20200605BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>A61L  27/24        20130101 LI20200625BCEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>A61L  27/38        20130101 LI20200625BCEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="3"><text>A61L  27/22        20130101 LI20200625BCEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="4"><text>A61L  27/26        20130101 LI20200625BCEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>ZUSAMMENSETZUNG ZUR TRANSPLANTATION EINES ORGANOIDS</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>COMPOSITION FOR TRANSPLANTATION OF ORGANOID</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>COMPOSITION POUR LA TRANSPLANTATION D'ORGANOÏDE</B542></B540><B590><B598>8b</B598></B590></B500><B700><B710><B711><snm>Organoidsciences, Ltd.</snm><iid>101905669</iid><irf>IPS-007 EP</irf><adr><str>302, 26, Yatap-ro, Bundang-gu 
Seongnam-si</str><city>Gyeonggi-do 13522</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B711></B710><B720><B721><snm>YOO, Jong Man</snm><adr><str>302, 26, Yatap-ro, Bundang-gu</str><city>Seongnam-si Gyeonggi-do 13522</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>JEE, Joo Hyun</snm><adr><str>302, 26, Yatap-ro, Bundang-gu</str><city>Seongnam-si Gyeonggi-do 13522</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>JUNG, Sang Yun</snm><adr><str>302, 26, Yatap-ro, Bundang-gu</str><city>Seongnam-si Gyeonggi-do 13522</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>KIM, Han Kyung</snm><adr><str>302, 26, Yatap-ro, Bundang-gu</str><city>Seongnam-si Gyeonggi-do 13522</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>LEE, Joong Woon</snm><adr><str>302, 26, Yatap-ro, Bundang-gu</str><city>Seongnam-si Gyeonggi-do 13522</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B740><B741><snm>Rückerl, Florian</snm><iid>101359438</iid><adr><str>Dehmel &amp; Bettenhausen 
Patentanwälte PartmbB 
Herzogspitalstraße 11</str><city>80331 München</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840><B844EP><B845EP><ctry>BA</ctry></B845EP><B845EP><ctry>ME</ctry></B845EP></B844EP><B848EP><B849EP><ctry>KH</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>MA</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>MD</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>TN</ctry></B849EP></B848EP><B860><B861><dnum><anum>KR2019013527</anum></dnum><date>20191015</date></B861><B862>ko</B862></B860><B870><B871><dnum><pnum>WO2020111507</pnum></dnum><date>20200604</date><bnum>202023</bnum></B871></B870></B800></SDOBI>
<abstract id="abst" lang="en">
<p id="pa01" num="0001">The present invention relates to a composition for biotransplantation comprising an organoid, and to a use thereof. According to one aspect of the present invention, when a collagen, gelatin and/or fibrin glue is used as a scaffold for organoid transplantation, the transplantation rate and survival rate of organoid are high, and the stability is also excellent.<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="130" he="77" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p>
</abstract>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<heading id="h0001"><b>[Technical Field]</b></heading>
<p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a composition for transplantation of an organoid, and a use of same.</p>
<heading id="h0002"><b>[Background Art]</b></heading>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">Organoids are considered basic experimental models, sources of implantable tissue, and physiologically relevant platforms for drug screening. In contrast to a culture of immortalized cells, intestinal organoids, for example, contain viable stem cells residing in crypt-like lobes, undergo a continuous cycle of regeneration and differentiation to produce multiple functional cell types and repeat key aspects of gut development and homeostasis.</p>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">Epithelial organoids can be formed from human colon, adenoma, and adenocarcinoma tissue and cultured from personalized medicine, patient-derived crypt or ex vivo and opened up possibilities for autologous transplantation using stem cells culture and proliferated in ex vivo. Despite an unmatched histological accuracy of the original tissues, stem cell-derived organoids from the gastrointestinal tract (GI tract) have several limitations, a main one of which is depending on Matrigel as a 3D scaffold.</p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">Matrigel is a widely used commercial product to provide a 3D scaffold for the growth of organoids of all cell types. It is used to grow intestine, retina, kidney, liver, stomach, prostate, breast, inner ear, cardiac muscle fibers, hepatic endothelium, pancreas, fallopian tubes, and cerebral organoids. It is also used for growing organoids from a variety of species including chickens, rats and humans. However, reliance on Matrigel or similar naturally derived biopolymer matrices as scaffolds for organoid growth poses several significant limitations to the study and use of the resulting organoids. Matrigel is derived from basement membrane of ECM-rich mouse sarcoma and therefore carries a high risk of transmitting immunogens or pathogens when given to a patient, particularly problematic in the field of serious patient death and morbidity related to infection following immunosuppression and it is known to promote angiogenesis and cancer development.</p>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">In addition, the batch-to-batch variability of Matrigel can lead to inconsistent cell behavior<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> introducing unknown and potentially confounding variables that complicate the interpretation of both basic and translational research. Moreover, although Matrigel is a crucial element of the current organoid culture model, its role in organoid formation has not been elucidated.</p>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">Therefore, a development of a scaffold for human injection that is effective enough to replace Matrigel in the field of organoids and suitable for in vivo transplantation is needed.</p>
<heading id="h0003"><b>[Description of the Invention]</b></heading>
<heading id="h0004"><b>[Technical Problem]</b></heading>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">One aspect of the present invention is to provide a composition for biotransplantation comprising an organoid, and a gelatin, collagen, fibrin glue, or a combination of thereof.</p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">Another aspect of the present invention is to provide a method for organoid transplantation comprising a step of mixing gelatin, collagen, fibrin glue, or a combination thereof with an organoid and a step of administering the mixture to a subject.</p>
<heading id="h0005"><b>[Technical Solution]</b></heading>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">One aspect of the present invention provides a composition for biotransplantation comprising organoid, and a gelatin, collagen, fibrin glue, or a combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">The term "organoid" as used herein refers to a cell mass having a 3D three-dimensional structure and refers to a miniaturized and simplified version of an organ prepared through an artificial culture process that is not collected or acquired from animals. The origin of the cells constituting the organoid is not limited. Organoids can be derived from tissues, stem cells, for example, embryonic stem cells or induced pluripotent stem cells, and may be cultured in three dimensions from their self-renewal and differentiation ability. The organoid may have an environment that is allowed to interact with the surrounding environment during the cell growth process. Accordingly, the 3D organoid in the present invention almost completely mimics the organs that interact in vivo and can be an excellent model for observing the development of therapeutic agents for diseases. It can similarly reproduce the physiologically active function of the human body, and by constructing an organ analogue from the patient's tissue, disease modeling based on the patient's genetic information and drug screening through repeated tests are possible. For this function, it is required to have excellent transplantation rate, transplantation efficiency, survival rate and stability when transplanted into a living body. The<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> term "gelatin" as used herein refers to a kind of a protein obtained by decomposing and purifying natural proteins composed in animal skin, cartilage, tendon, etc.</p>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">The term "collagen" as used herein refers to a protein that is most widely distributed in the human body, and although it is a main component of connective tissues, mainly in bones and skin, it is a component distributed throughout our body, such as joints, membranes of each organ, and hair. A hard protein may also be called 'collagen'.</p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">The term "fibrin glue" as used herein refers to a tissue adhesive composed of fibrinogen, thrombin, calcium chloride, and inhibitors of anti-fibrinolytic enzyme, and is used for hemostasis in patients with lacerations. When a tissue is wounded, it refers to a substance that forms fibrin by leaking fibrinogen together with blood components from the capillaries around the cut.</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">The term "fibrin glue" as used herein refers to a tissue adhesive composed of fibrinogen, thrombin, calcium chloride, and inhibitors of anti-fibrinolytic enzyme, that is used for suturing peripheral nerves, suturing microvessels, cranial nerve surgery, orthopedic surgery such as bone adhesion, and hemostasis of patients with lacerations. When a tissue is wounded, it refers to a substance that forms fibrin by leaking fibrinogen together with blood components from the capillaries around the cut.</p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">The gelatin, collagen, and fibrin glue all have excellent biocompatibility and stability in the body.</p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">The term "biotransplanting" or "bio implanting", as used herein refers to a phenomenon in which a composition for biotransplantation is administered to a subject and settle at the implantation site.</p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">For biotransplantation, it is required that the transplanted site is not affected, and to have a high survival rate and transplantation rate.</p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">The organoid is not limited thereto as long as it is an organoid that can be implanted using gelatin, collagen, fibrin glue, or a combination thereof as a scaffold. Specifically, the organoids may be selected from a group of intestinal organoids, retinal organoids, kidney organoids, liver organoids, gastric organoids, prostate organoids, breast organoids, inner ear organoids, cardiac muscle fiber organoids, liver endothelial organoids, pancreas organoids, fallopian tube<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> organoids, and cerebral organoids.</p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">Gelatin may be comprised in an amount of about 2.5 to 10% (w/v) based on the total weight of the composition. If the gelatin is more than about 10% (w/v), cytotoxicity may occur to the transplanted organoids due to the endotoxicity of the gelatin.</p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">Collagen may be comprised in an amount of about 10 to 20% (v/v) based on the total weight of the composition.</p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">Fibrin glue may be comprised in an amount of about 10 to 15% (v/v) based on the total weight of the composition. If the fibrin glue is more than about 15% (v/v), the composition may harden too quickly and the transplantation rate of the organoid may be reduced.</p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">The gelatin, collagen, or fibrin glue may be used by purchasing commercially available ones, separating those existing in nature, or synthesizing them.</p>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">The composition may further comprise a material that may be conventionally included when transplanting and culturing organoids.</p>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">In the composition, the organoid, gelatin, collagen, or fibrin glue may be in a form attached to a medical device for transplantation. The medical device may be selected from the group consisting of, for example, but not limited to, stents, pins, stitches, splits, pacemakers, artificial skin, and rods.</p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">The composition according to one embodiment of the present invention may include a pharmaceutically acceptable carrier and/or additive. For example, sterile water, physiological saline, conventional buffers (phosphoric acid, citric acid, other organic acids, etc.), stabilizers, salts, antioxidants (ascorbic acid, etc.), surfactants, suspending agents, isotonic agents, or preservatives, etc. For topical administration, organic materials such as biopolymers, inorganic materials such as hydroxyapatite, specifically collagen matrix, polylactic acid polymers or copolymers, polyethylene glycol polymers or copolymers and chemical derivatives thereof, etc. may also be combined for topical administration.</p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">Another aspect of the present invention provides a cell therapy product comprising an organoid, and a gelatin, collagen, fibrin glue, or a combination of thereof.</p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">The term "cell therapy product" or "cell therapy agent" as used herein refers to a pharmaceutical manufactured through separation, culture, and special manipulation of human cells and tissues<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> used for the purpose of treatment, diagnosis, and prevention through a series of actions such as proliferating and selecting allogeneic or xenogeneic cells in vitro, or changing the biological properties of cells in other ways.</p>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">According to one aspect of the invention, the cell therapy agent may be used to treat a condition in which the mucosa itself is lost, such as inflammatory bowel disease or damage to the mucous membrane.</p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">Another aspect of the present invention provides a method for organoid transplantation comprising a step of mixing gelatin, collagen, fibrin glue, or a combination thereof with an organoid and a step of administering the mixture to a subject.</p>
<p id="p0029" num="0029">Gelatin, collagen, fibrin glue, and organoids are as described above.</p>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">The subject may be a subject that needs to be formed by transplanting an organoid.</p>
<p id="p0031" num="0031">The subject includes humans and mammals, and specifically includes humans, monkeys, mice, rats, rabbits, sheep, cattle, dogs, horses, pigs.</p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032">The terms "administering," "introducing," and "transplanting" as used herein can be used interchangeably and, according to one embodiment of the present invention may refer to a method that results in at least partial localization of the composition to a desired site or a placement of a composition according to a route into a subject in one embodiment. Administration may be by any suitable route that delivers at least a portion of a cell or cellular component of a composition according to one embodiment to a desired location in a living subj ect.</p>
<p id="p0033" num="0033">In the above method, administration may be administered to a lesion site requiring transplantation of an organoid. Endoscopy equipment may be used for administration, but is not limited thereto. For example, administration to the esophagus, stomach, duodenum, large intestine, or colon using an endoscope is typical, and in addition, all organs in the body through surgical operations, such as salivary glands, lacrimal glands, muscles, lungs, liver, pancreas, kidney, uterus, prostate, etc. can be administered. For example, when the mucous membrane itself is lost, such as inflammatory bowel disease or damage to the mucous membrane, it can be used to replace the damaged mucosa by transplanting organoids.</p>
<p id="p0034" num="0034">The method uses collagen, gelatin, or fibrin glue as a scaffold for organoid transplantation, thereby exhibiting transplant stability and transplant efficiency similar to those of<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> conventionally used matrigel, and is also clinically applicable safely.</p>
<p id="p0035" num="0035">As mentioned above, organoids can be differentiated into organoids with adult-like characteristics even in vitro, and above all, because they utilize the patient's own adult cells, there are no technical issues such as immunogenicity, and ethical problems which become obstacles in future use as a tissue therapy.</p>
<heading id="h0006"><b>[Effects]</b></heading>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">According to one aspect of the present invention, when collagen, gelatin, or fibrin glue is used as a scaffold for organoid transplantation, the transplantation rate and survival rate of organoids are high, and stability is also excellent.</p>
<heading id="h0007"><b>[Brief Description of Figures]</b></heading>
<p id="p0037" num="0037">
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
<li><figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a photograph of measuring the GFP signal emitted from an organoid transplanted into the colon tissue on the 7th day after transplanting the colon organoid for each scaffold.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0001">FIG. 2</figref> is a graph showing the area of an organoid transplanted to the colon tissue on the 7th day after transplanting the colon organoid.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">FIG. 3</figref> is a photograph showing the result of observing a colon tissue section on the 7th day after transplanting colon organoids.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 4</figref> is a photograph showing the morphology of a colon transplanted with an organoid on the 7th day after transplanting the colon organoid.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 5</figref> is a graph showing the result of calculating the weight/length of a colon transplanted with an organoid on the 7th day after transplanting the colon organoid.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0004">FIG. 6</figref> is a photograph of the result of confirming the GFP signal after forming a secondary organoid after transplanting the colon organoid.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0004">FIG. 7</figref> is a graph showing the results of measuring a correlation with an engraftment area by measuring a number of GFP-expressing organoids after forming a secondary organoid after transplanting a colonic organoid.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0005">FIG. 8a</figref> is a schematic diagram showing the manufacturing process of the acute colon injury<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> model induced by EDTA.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0005">FIG. 8b</figref> is a schematic diagram illustrating a transplantation process of an organoid according to one embodiment.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0005">FIG. 8c</figref> is a result showing the tissue analysis result after transplantation of the organoid according to one embodiment.</li>
</ul></p>
<heading id="h0008"><b>[Examples]</b></heading>
<p id="p0038" num="0038">Hereinafter, it will be described in more detail through examples. However, these examples are for illustrative purposes of one or more embodiments, and the scope of the present invention is not limited to these examples.</p>
<heading id="h0009"><b>Reference 1. Preparation and culture of colon organoids</b></heading>
<p id="p0039" num="0039">Colon tissue was separated from EGFP mice, and colonic crypt was isolated using an enzyme, and matrigel and medium for colon organoids were mixed in a 1:1 ratio and inoculated into an uncoated 48-well plate. It was placed in an incubator, and after 20 minutes, it was confirmed that the matrigel was hardened. And then, a medium for colon organoids was added and cultured for 5 days to prepare colon organoids for biotransplantation to be used below.</p>
<heading id="h0010"><b>Example 1. Preparation and transplantation of organoids for biotransplantation</b></heading>
<heading id="h0011"><b>1.1. Colon tissue damage model construction</b></heading>
<p id="p0040" num="0040">A colon tissue damage model to produce organoids was prepared as follows. Wild-type mice to be transplanted with colon organoids were exposed to 0.5M EDTA for 5 minutes, and physical damage was applied to remove the crypts of the colonic lining for 2 minutes with an electric toothbrush.</p>
<heading id="h0012"><b>1.2. Preparation and transplantation of organoids for biotransplantation</b></heading>
<p id="p0041" num="0041">A colon organoid was prepared so that the colon organoid prepared above expresses GFP. All colon organoids were treated with 10 µM of Y-27632 in the organoid medium one day before transplantation to maximize the survival rate. In addition, the matrix used during culture was completely removed by treatment with a cell recovery solution.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></p>
<p id="p0042" num="0042">Thereafter, the following three scaffolds were mixed under the conditions described below and transplanted in a volume of 50 µl into the anus of the colon tissue damage mouse model prepared in 1.1.
<ol id="ol0001" compact="compact" ol-style="">
<li>1) Gelatin: GFP+ colon organoids were mixed in PBS with 5% gelatin dissolved in gelatin : organoid = 1 : 2 ratio of medium and transplanted. At this time, the medium containing the organoids contains 10 µM of Y-27632.</li>
<li>2) Collagen: GFP+ colon organoids were mixed in 100% collagen stock solution dissolved in collagen : organoid = 1 : 9 ratio of medium and transplanted. At this time, the medium containing the organoids contains 10 µM of Y-27632.</li>
<li>3) Fibrin Glue: a colonoid solution was prepared by mixing GFP+ colon organoids with 45 µl of colonoid culture medium containing 10 µM of Y-27632, and fibrin was mixed with a ratio of 1:1 in a solution in which thrombin is diluted 1:100 in PBS to make 5 µl of the solution totally. And then, 5 µl of the solution were mixed with the prepared 45 µl of colonoid solution and transplanted.</li>
</ol></p>
<p id="p0043" num="0043">Matrigel was used as a control group.</p>
<p id="p0044" num="0044">Matrigel was transplanted by mixing it in a colonoid culture medium containing organoids at a concentration of 10%. At this time, the medium containing the organoids contains 10 µM of Y-27632.</p>
<p id="p0045" num="0045">After transplantation, the anus was closed using 10 µl of 3M Vetbond, and the suture was released 14 hours later to induce normal bowel activity.</p>
<heading id="h0013"><b>Example 2. Evaluation of transplantation rate of organoids</b></heading>
<p id="p0046" num="0046">In order to evaluate the transplantation rate according to the scaffold of the colon organoid transplanted in Example 1, it was carried out as follows.</p>
<p id="p0047" num="0047">On the 7th day after transplantation of colon organoids, the colon tissue was autopsied to measure GFP signals released from the transplanted organoids. Specifically, the organoid-implanted colon tissue was vertically incised to create a planar structure, and this tissue was spread thinly on a slide glass and a glass cover was covered thereon. At this time, the crypt was directed downward. The prepared slide glass was placed on the stage of a fluorescence microscope to observe the region where GFP fluorescence was expressed.</p>
<p id="p0048" num="0048"><figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a photograph of measuring the GFP signal emitted from the organoid transplanted into the colon tissue on the 7th day after transplantation of the colon organoid for each scaffold.<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></p>
<p id="p0049" num="0049"><figref idref="f0001">FIG. 2</figref> is a graph showing the area of the organoid transplanted into the colon tissue on the 7th day after transplantation of the colon organoid.</p>
<p id="p0050" num="0050">As shown in <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1 and 2</figref>, in the absence of a scaffold, it was confirmed that the GFP signal was the weakest and the transplantation rate was low. On the other hand, it was confirmed that when gelatin, collagen, and fibrin glue were used as scaffolds, the transplantation rate and transplanted area were similar to those when Matrigel, a positive control, was used as a scaffold. Therefore, when gelatin, collagen, or fibrin glue is used as a scaffold for organoid transplantation, the transplantation rate of organoids is significantly increased.</p>
<heading id="h0014"><b>Example 3. Evaluation of survival rate and engraftment ratio of organoids</b></heading>
<p id="p0051" num="0051">In order to evaluate the survival rate and engraftment ratio according to the scaffold of the colon organoid transplanted in Example 1, it was carried out as follows. 10 to 13 animals were used for each scaffold experimental group, and tissue autopsy was performed one week after transplantation of GFP organoids into the colon. The final engraftment ratio was calculated by calculating the percentage of the number of transplanted animals out of the total number of animals by classifying those expressing GFP in the colon as those with engraftment successes, and those without GFP expression as those with engraftment failed. And the final survival rate was calculated by counting the animals who died within 7 days after transplantation.</p>
<p id="p0052" num="0052">The results are shown in Table 1 below.
<tables id="tabl0001" num="0001">
<table frame="all">
<title>[Table 1]</title>
<tgroup cols="7">
<colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="18mm"/>
<colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="32mm"/>
<colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="31mm"/>
<colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="23mm"/>
<colspec colnum="5" colname="col5" colwidth="13mm"/>
<colspec colnum="6" colname="col6" colwidth="22mm"/>
<colspec colnum="7" colname="col7" colwidth="28mm"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry align="center" valign="middle"/>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Number of transplantation</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Engraftment successes</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Engraftment failed</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Dead</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Survival rate (%)</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Engraftment ratio (%)</entry></row></thead>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">No scaffold</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">13</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">8</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">1</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">2</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">84.62</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">61.54</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Matrigel</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">10</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">9</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">0</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">1</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">90.00</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">90.00</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Gelatin</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">13</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">9</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">1</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">3</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">76.92</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">69.23</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Collagen</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">10</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">9</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">1</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">0</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">100.00</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">90.00</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Fibrin glue</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">10</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">9</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">0</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">1</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">90.00</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">90.00</entry></row></tbody></tgroup>
</table>
</tables></p>
<p id="p0053" num="0053">As shown in Table 1, when gelatin, collagen, and fibrin glue were used as scaffolds, the survival rates were 76.92, 100, and 90%, respectively, and the engraftment ratio was confirmed as high<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> as 69.23, 90, and 90%, respectively. Therefore, it was confirmed that the survival rate and engraftment ratio were excellent. This was at a level similar to that in the case of using Matrigel, a positive control. <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 3</figref> is a photograph showing the results of observing the colon tissue section on the 7th day after transplantation of colon organoids.</p>
<p id="p0054" num="0054">As shown in <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 3</figref>, when gelatin, collagen, and fibrin glue were used as scaffolds, it was confirmed that the organoids were successfully settled to form colonic crypts.</p>
<heading id="h0015"><b>Example 4. Stability evaluation</b></heading>
<p id="p0055" num="0055">In order to evaluate the stability of the colon organoid transplanted in Example 1, an autopsy was performed on the 7th day after transplantation, and the shape of the autopsied tissue and the occurrence of lesions were checked.</p>
<p id="p0056" num="0056"><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 4</figref> is a photograph showing the shape of the colon transplanted with the organoid on the 7th day after transplantation of the colon organoid.</p>
<p id="p0057" num="0057">As shown in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 4</figref>, when gelatin, collagen, or fibrin glue was used as a scaffold, an edema or bloody stool that may appear in the colon transplanted with organoid was not observed in the autopsy tissue.</p>
<p id="p0058" num="0058"><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 5</figref> is a graph showing the result of calculating the weight/length of the colon transplanted with the organoid on the 7th day after transplantation of the colon organoid.</p>
<p id="p0059" num="0059">As shown in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 5</figref>, the volume of edema that may appear when inflammation occurred was checked by calculating the weight/length of the colon transplanted with organoid. As a result, there was no significant difference compared with the control group using Matrigel.</p>
<p id="p0060" num="0060">Therefore, it was confirmed that when the organoid was transplanted using gelatin, collagen, or fibrin glue as a scaffold, the stability was excellent.</p>
<heading id="h0016"><b>Example 5. Evaluation of Normal Organoid Formation from Transplanted Tissue</b></heading>
<p id="p0061" num="0061">In order to evaluate whether normal organoids are formed from the colonic organoids transplanted in Example 1, a second colonic organoid (secondary organoid) was formed from the transplanted colonic tissue.</p>
<p id="p0062" num="0062">Specifically, after checking the GFP of the transplanted colon tissue with a fluorescence<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> microscope, it was cut with surgical scissors, put in a tube containing crypt chelating buffer, and reacted in a shaking incubator at 37 °C for 20 minutes. And then, it was put in a 10 ml syringe equipped with an 18 gage needle, and crypt is separated by grinding 20 times. The separated crypt was centrifuged, collected, filtered through a 70 µm filter, mixed with Y-27632-added medium and matrigel at a 1:1 ratio, and inoculated at a concentration of 20 µl/well in a 48-well plate. After hardening the matrigel by putting it in an incubator at 37 °C for 30 minutes, a medium supplemented with Y-27632 was added and cultured for 5 days. On the 5th day of culture, colonic organoids expressing GFP were followed up.</p>
<p id="p0063" num="0063"><figref idref="f0004">FIG. 6</figref> is a photograph of the result of confirming the GFP signal after forming a secondary organoid after transplantation of the colon organoid.</p>
<p id="p0064" num="0064">As shown in <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 6</figref>, when gelatin, collagen, or fibrin glue was used as a scaffold, secondary organoids expressing GFP were effectively formed. This was confirmed to be at a level similar to that of the positive control using matrigel.</p>
<p id="p0065" num="0065"><figref idref="f0004">FIG. 7</figref> is a graph showing the results of measuring the correlation with the engraftment area by measuring the number of GFP-expressing organoids after forming a secondary organoid after transplantation of colonic organoids.</p>
<p id="p0066" num="0066">As shown in <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 7</figref>, it was confirmed that the number and area of secondary organoids increased in proportion.</p>
<p id="p0067" num="0067">Therefore, it indicates that gelatin, collagen, and fibrin glue do not significantly affect normal organoid formation.</p>
<p id="p0068" num="0068">According to one aspect of the present invention, when collagen, gelatin, or fibrin glue is used as a scaffold for organoid transplantation, the transplantation rate and survival rate of the organoid is high and the stability is also excellent, therefore the composition comprising the same can be used usefully for biotransplantation in vivo.</p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="12"> -->
<claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>A composition for biotransplantation comprising organoid; and gelatin, collagen, fibrin glue, or a combination thereof.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>The composition for biotransplantation according to claim 1, wherein the organoid is selected from the group consisting of intestinal organoid, retinal organoid, kidney organoid, liver organoid, gastric organoid, prostate organoid, breast organoid, inner ear organoid, cardiac muscle fiber organoid, hepatic endothelial organoid, pancreatic organoids, fallopian tube organoids, and cerebral organoids.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>The composition for biotransplantation according to claim 1, wherein the gelatin is comprised in an amount of 2.5 to 10% (w/v) based on the total weight of the composition.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>The composition for biotransplantation according to claim 1, wherein the collagen is comprised in an amount of 10 to 20% (w/v) based on the total weight of the composition.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>The composition for biotransplantation according to claim 1, wherein the fibrin glue is comprised in an amount of 10 to 15% (w/v) based on the total weight of the composition.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>A method for transplanting an organoid comprising mixing gelatin, collagen, fibrin glue, or a combination thereof with the organoid; and administering the mixture to a subject.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1,2"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="165" he="206" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="3"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="117" he="155" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> -->
<figure id="f0003" num="4,5"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="111" he="231" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> -->
<figure id="f0004" num="6,7"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="137" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> -->
<figure id="f0005" num="8a,8b,8c"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="161" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<search-report-data id="srep" lang="en" srep-office="EP" date-produced=""><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="153" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="153" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0003" file="srep0003.tif" wi="153" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0004" file="srep0004.tif" wi="153" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data>
</ep-patent-document>
