<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP19850716B1" file="EP19850716NWB1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3680539" kind="B1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSK..HRIS..MTNORS..SM..................</B001EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  2100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3680539</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT SPECIFICATION</B121></B120><B130>B1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>19850716.2</B210><B220><date>20190827</date></B220><B240><B241><date>20200224</date></B241></B240><B250>zh</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B300><B310>201811456240</B310><B320><date>20181130</date></B320><B330><ctry>CN</ctry></B330></B300><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20200715</date><bnum>202029</bnum></B430><B450><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B450><B452EP><date>20210520</date></B452EP></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>F16M  11/04        20060101AFI20210331BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="2"><text>F16M  13/00        20060101ALI20210331BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="3"><text>G09F   9/302       20060101ALI20210331BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="4"><text>F16M  13/02        20060101ALI20210331BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="5"><text>E05C   9/04        20060101ALI20210331BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>F16M  11/041       20130101 LI20201016BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>F16M  13/02        20130101 FI20200911BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="3"><text>F16M2200/02        20130101 LA20201016BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="4"><text>G09F   9/3026      20130101 LI20200911BHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>ANZEIGEBILDSCHIRM</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>DISPLAY SCREEN</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>ÉCRAN D'AFFICHAGE</B542></B540><B560><B561><text>CN-A- 107 387 512</text></B561><B561><text>CN-A- 107 393 427</text></B561><B561><text>CN-A- 109 751 489</text></B561><B561><text>CN-U- 202 939 922</text></B561><B561><text>CN-U- 203 535 911</text></B561><B561><text>CN-U- 205 842 158</text></B561><B561><text>GB-A- 2 558 858</text></B561><B561><text>US-A- 4 142 747</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2015 163 928</text></B561><B565EP><date>20201028</date></B565EP></B560></B500><B700><B720><B721><snm>HAO, Zongchao</snm><adr><str>Building 18A, 3rd NanGang Industrial Park
Tangtou, ShiyanTown, Baoan District</str><city>Shenzhen, Guangdong 518100</city><ctry>CN</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>LIU, Qiuhe</snm><adr><str>Building 18A, 3rd NanGang Industrial Park
Tangtou, ShiyanTown, Baoan District</str><city>Shenzhen, Guangdong 518100</city><ctry>CN</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>HU, Rihao</snm><adr><str>Building 18A, 3rd NanGang Industrial Park
Tangtou, ShiyanTown, Baoan District</str><city>Shenzhen, Guangdong 518100</city><ctry>CN</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B730><B731><snm>Shenzhen Infiled Electronics Co., Ltd</snm><iid>101854079</iid><irf>P20/0308</irf><adr><str>Building 18A, 3rd NanGang Industrial Park</str><city>Tangtou, ShiyanTown, Baoan District
Shenzhen
Guangdong 518100</city><ctry>CN</ctry></adr></B731></B730><B740><B741><snm>Kayahan, Senem</snm><iid>101838273</iid><adr><str>Yalciner Patent and Consulting Ltd. 
Tunus Cad. No: 85/3-4 
Kavaklidere Cankaya</str><city>06680 Ankara</city><ctry>TR</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840><B860><B861><dnum><anum>CN2019102684</anum></dnum><date>20190827</date></B861><B862>zh</B862></B860><B870><B871><dnum><pnum>WO2020107968</pnum></dnum><date>20200604</date><bnum>202023</bnum></B871></B870></B800></SDOBI>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<heading id="h0001"><b>TECHNICAL FIELD</b></heading>
<p id="p0001" num="0001">The present disclosure relates to the field of display devices, in particular to a display screen.</p>
<heading id="h0002"><b>BACKGROUND</b></heading>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">In the field of display devices, most of the large display screens are formed by assembling at least two display modules. However, the quality of display modules is inconsistent due to imperfect packaging of lamp beads and deficient manufacturing such as subsequent patching. These defective display modules then must be replaced.</p>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">At present, the display modules are fixed by screw fixation mode or magnetic adsorption. There are advantages and disadvantages to screw fixation and magnetic adsorption. Display modules fixed by screws are relatively firm, but are inconvenient for maintenance and replacement. Display modules fixed by magnetic adsorption can be disassembled quickly without removing screws, but are not resistant to wind, as a result it easier for the displays fixed by magnetic adsorption to fall under windy conditions. Some display manufacturers add a safety rope behind the display modules as a safety precaution but this solution may be unsightly.</p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="CN203535911U"><text>CN 203 535 911 U</text></patcit> discloses a module with a locking system comprising a through hole, gear and locking bar which does not provide a smooth operating of the locking system. Also, a gear locking system is disclosed din <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="GB2558585A"><text>GB 2 558 585 A</text></patcit>.</p>
<p id="p0005" num="0005"><patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="US4142747A"><text>US 4 142 747 A</text></patcit> discloses doors or windows having glass panes, with a hinged locking system. It does not relate to a display screen and does not provide feature to ensure accurate functioning of the locking system.</p>
<heading id="h0003"><b>SUMMARY</b></heading>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">In order to overcome the shortcomings of the prior art, the present application discloses a display screen, so as to solve the problems of troublesome replacement and unstable connections of the existing display modules.</p>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">The technical solution of the present application is as follows.<br/>
A display screen, including a display frame, a detachable display module connected to the display frame, and a locking mechanism mounted on the back of the display module for locking the display module to the display frame. The display frame has at least two frame bars arranged in a row and at intervals, and any two adjacent frame bars are provided with at least two engaged grooves spaced opposite to each other. The locking mechanism includes two telescopic rods and a drive assembly for the two telescopic rods to be inserted into or pulled out from the engaged grooves<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> arranged on the two frame bars, respectively. The drive assembly is installed on the back of the display module and connected to the two telescopic rods.</p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">Preferably, the drive assembly is a knob assembly arranged on the back of the display module. One end of each of the two telescopic rods is hinged to a side of the knob assembly. The knob assembly includes a knob and a rotating member with one end connected to the knob. One end of each of the two telescopic rods is hinged to a side of the rotating member. The rotating member includes a plate body, a first bulge disposed on a side of the plate body, and a second bulge arranged on the other side of the plate body. The first bulge is connected to the knob. A limiting hole is arranged on the back of the display module, and the second bulge is mounted in the limiting hole and capable of rotating therein. One end of each of the two telescopic rods is hinged to a side of the plate body. The plate body is respectively provided with a first through hole on both sides, where the first through holes are arranged oppositely in the extension direction of the first bulge, and one end of each of the two telescopic rods is provided with a second through hole. The locking mechanism further includes two pins, and the telescopic rods are hinged with the plate body by means of the pins penetrating the first through hole and the second through hole. The display module is provided with two arc-shaped holes on the side of the limiting hole at an interval along a circumferential direction, and one end of each pin away from the knob is arranged in the arc-shaped hole and capable of sliding therein; and/or,<br/>
the display module includes a module bracket and a lamp panel mounted on the module bracket. The locking mechanism is arranged on the back of the module bracket, and the module bracket is provided with the limiting hole. The second bulge is provided with an inner hexagonal hole, and the lamp panel is provided with a disassembly hole in alignment with the limiting hole penetrating the lamp panel.</p>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">Preferably, each telescopic rod includes a first rod portion with one end<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> extending into the engaged groove and a second rod portion with one end hinged with the other end of the first rod portion. One end of each second rod portion away from the first rod portion is hinged with the plate body.</p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">Preferably, the locking mechanism further includes a cover plate mounted on the back of the display module. A receiving cavity is formed between the cover plate and the display module. The side of the cover plate away from the display module is provided with a knob hole. A part of the knob is installed in the receiving cavity, and the other part of the knob protrudes out of the receiving cavity through the knob hole. The cover plate is provided with a third bulge on both sides of the knob hole opposite to each other, respectively. The opposite faces of the two third bulges are each provided with a first groove for locating the knob when the telescopic rod is extended into the engaged groove. Both sides of the knob opposite to each other are each provided with a fourth bulge engaged in the first groove.</p>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">Preferably, the back of the display module is concavely provided with a second groove, and the bottom surface of the second groove are convexly provided with two bumps at an interval for connecting with the cover plate. The side surface of the bump facing the cover plate is concavely provided with a first through groove, and the side surface of the cover plate connected to the bump is concavely provided with a second through groove. The first through groove and the second through groove surround to form a through hole for the telescopic rods to pass through. The second groove is divided by two bumps into a first groove portion and second groove portions located on both sides of the first groove portion opposite to each other. Two blocks are arranged on the two frame bars, respectively, and the two blocks are partially engaged in the second groove portions, respectively. The two engaged grooves are arranged on the two blocks, respectively.</p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">Preferably, the display module further includes a plurality of first magnets. The back of the display module is further provided with a plurality of installation slots for mounting the first magnets. The face of the display frame matched with the display module is provided with a plurality of second magnets in alignment with the first magnets, or metal parts magnetically attached to the first magnets. Alternatively, the<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> display frame is a metal frame body and magnetically attached to the first magnets; and/or,<br/>
the number of the display modules is at least two. The number of the locking mechanisms is equal to the number of the display modules, and the number of the engaged grooves is twice the number of the display modules. Each display module is locked to the display frame through the locking mechanism, respectively.</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">Compared to the prior art, the advantages of the present application are as follows.</p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">According to the display screen of the present application, a locking mechanism is arranged on the back of a display module, and the locking mechanism includes two telescopic rods and a drive assembly. The drive assembly is arranged on the back of the display module and connected to the two telescopic rods for driving the two telescopic rods to be extended into or pulled out from the engaged grooves, respectively. When the display module needs to be installed on a display frame, the user can drive the two telescopic rods to be engaged in two engaged grooves arranged opposite to each other on the display frame through the drive assembly, so that the display module can be firmly installed on the display frame and is less likely to fall in windy conditions. When the display module needs to be removed from the display frame, the operator only needs to pull out the two telescopic rods from the two engaged grooves and remove the display module through the drive assembly. In summary, this design facilitates the disassembly and assembly of the display module, and improves the installation efficiency.</p>
<heading id="h0004"><b>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</b></heading>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li><figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic diagram showing the structure of the display screen disclosed in an embodiment of the present application;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> is an enlarged view showing part A in <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">FIG. 3</figref> is an enlarged view showing part B in <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 4</figref> is a schematic diagram showing a cooperation of the display module and the locking mechanism disclosed in an embodiment of the present application;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0004">FIG. 5</figref> is an exploded view of the display module and the locking mechanism<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> disclosed in an embodiment of the present application;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0005">FIG. 6</figref> is an enlarged view showing part C in <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 5</figref>;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0006">FIG. 7</figref> is an exploded view of a first perspective of the locking mechanism disclosed in an embodiment of the present application;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0007">FIG. 8</figref> is an enlarged view showing part D in <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 7</figref>;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0007">FIG. 9</figref> is an enlarged view showing part E in <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 7</figref>;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0008">FIG. 10</figref> is an exploded view of a second perspective of the locking mechanism disclosed in an embodiment of the present application;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0009">FIG. 11</figref> is a schematic diagram showing the structure of the lamp plate disclosed in an embodiment of the present application; and</li>
<li><figref idref="f0010">FIG. 12</figref> is an enlarged view showing part F in <figref idref="f0009">FIG. 11</figref>.</li>
</ul></p>
<heading id="h0005"><b>DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS</b></heading>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">The present application is further described hereinafter in combination with the drawings and specific embodiments. It should be noted that under the premise of no conflict, the following embodiments or technical features can be arbitrarily combined to form a new embodiment.</p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">Referring to <figref idref="f0001 f0002 f0003 f0004">FIGS. 1 to 5</figref>, the embodiment of the present application discloses the display screen 100, including the display frame 10, the display module 20 detachably connected to the display frame 10, and the locking mechanism 30 mounted on the back of the display module 20 for locking the display module 20 on the display frame 10. The display frame 10 has at least two frame bars 11 arranged in a row and at intervals, and any two adjacent frame bars 11 are provided with at least two engaged grooves 111 spaced opposite to each other. The locking mechanism 30 includes two telescopic rods 31 and the drive assembly 32 for driving the two telescopic rods 31 to be inserted into or pulled out from the engaged grooves 111 arranged on the two frame bars 11, respectively. The drive assembly 32 is installed on the back of the display module 20 and connected to the two telescopic rods 31.</p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">In this design, the locking mechanism 30 is arranged on the back of the display module 20, and the locking mechanism 30 includes two telescopic rods 31 and the drive assembly 32. The drive assembly 32 is arranged on the back of the display<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> module 20 and connected to the two telescopic rods 31 for driving the two telescopic rods 31 to be extended into or pulled out from the two engaged grooves 111, respectively. When the display module 20 needs to be installed on the display frame 10, the user can drive the two telescopic rods 31 to be engaged in the two engaged grooves 111 arranged opposite to each other on the display frame 10 through the drive assembly 32, so that the display module 20 can be firmly installed on the display frame 10 and is not likely to fall in windy conditions. When the display module 20 needs to be removed from the display frame 10, the operator only needs to pull out the two telescopic rods 31 from the two engaged grooves 111 through the drive assembly 32 and remove the display module 20. To sum up, this kind of design facilitates the disassembly and installation of the display module 20, and the installation efficiency can be effectively improved.</p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">Referring to <figref idref="f0005 f0006 f0007 f0008">FIGS. 6 to 10</figref>, the drive assembly 32 is a knob assembly arranged on the back of the display module, and one end of each of the two telescopic rods 31 is hinged with a side of the knob assembly 32, respectively. The knob assembly 32 includes the knob 321 and the rotating member 322 with one end connected to the knob 321, and one end of each of the two telescopic rods 31 is hinged with a side of the rotating member 322. The rotating member 322 includes the plate body 3221, the first bulge 3222 disposed on one side of the plate body 3221, and the second bulge 3223 arranged on the other side of the plate body 3221. The first bulge 3222 is connected to the knob 321. The limiting hole 21 is arranged on the back of the display module 20, and the second bulge 3223 is mounted in the limiting hole 21 and capable of rotating therein. One end of each of the two telescopic rods 31 is hinged with a side of the plate body 3221. Specifically, the side of the knob 321 near the rotating member 322 is provided with the long waist-shaped hole 3211, and the cross section of the first bulge 3222 is in a runway shape matching the shape of the waist-shaped hole 3211. The first bulge 3222 is arranged in the long waist-shaped hole 3211 by means of penetration. Understandably, the knob 321 and the rotating member 322 may also be integrally formed. The second bulge 3223 is installed in the limiting hole 21 and<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> capable of rotating therein, and the limiting hole 21 limits the operation of the rotating member 322, that is, the rotating member 322 does not deflect left and right in the process of pulling the telescopic rods 31, and the rotating member 322 rotates smoothly. The rotating member 322 is stressed uniformly, which can prolong the service life of the locking mechanism 20. The plate body 3221 is respectively provided with the first through hole 3224 on both sides, where the first through holes are arranged oppositely in the extension direction of the first bulge 3222, and one end of each of the two telescopic rods 31 is provided with the second through hole 311. The locking mechanism 30 further includes two pins 33, and the telescopic rods 31 are hinged with the plate body 3221 by means of the pins 33 penetrating the first through hole 3224 and the second through hole 311. Preferably, the pin 33 includes a pin cap, a first pin rod portion and a second pin rod portion, wherein the pin cap, the first pin rod portion and the second pin rod portion are connected sequentially. The outer wall of the first pin rod portion is smooth, the outer wall of the second pin rod portion is provided with screw threads, and the telescopic rod 31 is sleeved outside the first pin rod portion. The first through hole 3224 is a threaded hole, and the plate body 3221 is in screw-threaded fit with the second pin rod portion. The display module 20 is provided with two arc-shaped holes 22 on the side of the limiting hole 21 at an interval along the circumferential direction, and one end of each pin 33 away from the knob 321 is arranged in the arc-shaped hole 22 and capable of sliding therein. The two arc-shaped holes 22 limit the rotation of the knob 321. Here, the sliding arrangement means that the part of the pin 33 penetrating through the arc-shaped hole 22 can slide along the track of the arc-shaped hole 22.</p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">Preferably, each telescopic rod 31 includes the first rod portion 312 with one end extending into the engaged groove 111 and the second rod portion 313 with one end hinged with the other end of the first rod portion 312. One end of each second rod portion 313 away from the first rod portion 312 is hinged with the plate body 3221. Preferably, one end of each first rod portion 312 away from the second rod portion 313 is provided with the notch 3121 facing the back of the display module 20, and the<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> telescopic rod 31 is arranged in the engaged groove 111 of the frame bar 11 by the notch 3121.</p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">Preferably, the locking mechanism 30 further includes the cover plate 34 mounted on the back of the display module 20. A receiving cavity is formed between the cover plate 34 and the display module 20. The side of the cover plate 34 away from the display module 20 is provided with the knob hole 341. A part of the knob 321 is installed in the receiving cavity, and the other part of the knob 321 protrudes out of the receiving cavity through the knob hole 341. The cover plate 34 is provided with the third bulge 342 on both sides of the knob hole 341 opposite to each other, respectively. The opposite faces of the two third bulges 342 are each provided with the first groove 343 for locating the knob 321 when the telescopic rod 31 is extended into the engaged groove 111. Both sides of the knob 321 opposite to each other are each provided with the fourth bulge 3212 for being engaged in the first groove 3411. The first groove 343 is arranged on the third bulge 342, and both sides of the knob 321 opposite to each other are each provided with the fourth bulge 3212 for being engaged in the first groove 3411, so that when the locking mechanism 30 is in a locked state, the two third bulges 342 can fix the knob 321 through the first groove 343, thereby preventing the knob 321 from rotating due to contact, preventing the locking mechanism 30 from unlocking and preventing the display module 20 from falling off.</p>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">Preferably, the back of the display module 20 is concavely provided with the second groove 231, and the bottom surface of the second groove 231 are convexly provided with two bumps 232 at an interval for connecting with the cover plate 34. The second groove 231 is divided, by the two bumps 232, into the first groove portion 2311 and the second groove portions 2312 located on both sides of the first groove portion 2311 opposite to each other. The two blocks 112 are arranged on the two frame bars 11, respectively, and the two blocks 112 are partially engaged in the second groove portion 2312, respectively. The two engaged grooves 111 are arranged on the two blocks 112, respectively. The surface of the bump 232 facing the cover plate 34 is concavely provided with a first through groove, and the surface of the<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> cover plate 34 connected to the bumps 232 is concavely provided with a second through groove. When the cover plate 34 is connected to the bumps 232, the first through groove and the second through groove surround to form a through hole for the telescopic rods 31 to pass through.</p>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">Preferably, the display module 20 further includes a plurality of the first magnets 25. The back of the display module 20 is further provided with a plurality of installation slots 26 for mounting the first magnets 25. The face of the display frame 10 matched with the display module 20 is provided with a plurality of second magnets in alignment with the first magnets 25, or metal parts that can be magnetically attached to the first magnets 25. Alternatively, the display frame 10 is a metal frame body which can be magnetically attached to the first magnets 25. In this design, the display module 20 can be attached and fixed on the display frame 10 by the first magnets 25. In the actual installation process, the display module 20 is first attached on the display frame 10 through the first magnets 25, and then the display module 20 is locked on the display frame 10 through the locking mechanism 30, which makes the installation convenient. At the same time, the display module 20 and the display frame 10 are firmly connected, and the display module 20 does not fall off in case of windy conditions. Understandably, the first magnets 25 are not necessary, and the display module 20 can be fixed on the display frame 10 only through the locking mechanism 30.</p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">Preferably, the number of the display modules 20 is at least two. The number of the locking mechanisms 30 is equal to the number of the display modules 20, and the number of the engaged grooves 111 is twice the number of the display modules 20. Each display module 20 is locked to the display frame 10 through one locking mechanism 30.</p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">Referring to <figref idref="f0003">FIGS. 4</figref>, <figref idref="f0005">6</figref>, <figref idref="f0009">11</figref> and <figref idref="f0010">12</figref>, preferably, the display module 20 includes the module bracket 23 and the lamp panel 24 mounted on the module bracket 23. The locking mechanism 30 is arranged on the back of the module bracket 23, and the module bracket 23 is provided with the limiting hole 21. The second bulge 3223 is provided with the inner hexagonal hole 3225, and the lamp panel 24 is provided with<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> the disassembly hole 241 in alignment with the limiting hole 21 penetrating the lamp panel 24. By setting the inner hexagonal hole 3225, the user can unlock the locking mechanism 30 from the front of the lamp panel 24 with a hexagon wrench, and then remove the display module 20 from the front of the lamp panel 24. When the display module 20 is not convenient to be disassembled from the rear of the display screen 100, the inner hexagonal hole 3225 and the disassembly hole 241 are provided to facilitate maintenance from the front.</p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">The implementation modes described above are only the preferred implementations of the present application and cannot be used to limit the protective scope of the present application. Any non-substantive changes and replacements made by those skilled in the art on the basis of the present application shall fall within the protective scope claimed by the present application.</p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="11"> -->
<claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>A display screen (100), comprising a display frame (10), a display module (20) detachably connected to the display frame, and a locking mechanism (30) mounted on a back of the display module for locking the display module on the display frame; wherein the display frame has at least two frame bars (11) arranged in a row and at intervals, and any two adjacent frame bars are provided with at least two engaged grooves (111) spaced opposite to each other; the locking mechanism comprises two telescopic rods (31) and a drive assembly (32) for driving the two telescopic rods to be inserted into or pulled out from the engaged grooves arranged on the two frame bars, respectively; the drive assembly is installed on the back of the display module and connected to the two telescopic rods.;
<claim-text>wherein, the drive assembly is a knob assembly arranged on the back of the display module, and one end of each of the two telescopic rods is hinged with a side of the knob assembly;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, the knob assembly comprises a knob (321) and a rotating member (322) with one end connected to the knob, and the one end of each of the two telescopic rods is hinged with a side of the rotating member;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, the rotating member comprises a plate body (3221), a first bulge (3222) disposed on a side of the plate body, and a second bulge (3223) arranged on the other side of the plate body; the first bulge is connected to the knob; a limiting hole (21) is arranged on the back of the display module, and the second bulge is mounted in the limiting hole and capable of rotating in the limiting hole;</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>characterized in that</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>the one end of each of the two telescopic rods is hinged with a side of the plate body; the plate body is respectively provided with a first through hole (3224) on both sides, the first through holes are oppositely arranged in an extension direction of the first bulge, and one end of each of the two telescopic rods is provided with a second through hole (311); the locking mechanism further comprises two pins (33), and the telescopic rods are hinged with the plate body by means of the pins penetrating the first through hole and the second through hole:<br/>
and
<claim-text>the display module is provided with two arc-shaped holes (22) on a side of the limiting hole at an interval along a circumferential direction, and one end of each pin away from the<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> knob is arranged in the arc-shaped hole and capable of sliding in the arc-shaped hole; and/or,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the display module comprises a module bracket (23) and a lamp panel (24) mounted on the module bracket; the locking mechanism is arranged on a back of the module bracket, and the module bracket is provided with the limiting hole; the second bulge is provided with an inner hexagonal hole (3225), and the lamp panel is provided with a disassembly hole (241) in alignment with the limiting hole penetrating the lamp panel.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>The display screen according to claim 1, wherein, each telescopic rod comprises a first rod portion (312) with one end extending into the engaged groove and a second rod portion (313) with one end hinged with the other end of the first rod portion; one end of each second rod portion away from the first rod portion is hinged with the plate body.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>The display screen according to claim 1, wherein, the locking mechanism further comprises a cover plate (34) mounted on the back of the display module; a receiving cavity is formed between the cover plate and the display module; a side of the cover plate away from the display module is provided with a knob hole (341); a part of the knob is installed in the receiving cavity, and the other part of the knob protrudes out of the receiving cavity through the knob hole; the cover plate is provided with a third bulge (342) on both sides of the knob hole opposite to each other, respectively; the opposite faces of the two third bulges are each provided with a first groove (343) for locating the knob when the telescopic rod is extended into the engaged groove; both sides of the knob opposite to each other are each provided with a fourth bulge (3212) for being engaged in the first groove.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>The display screen according to claim 3, wherein, the back of the display module is concavely provided with a second groove (231), and a bottom surface of the second groove are convexly provided with two bumps (232) at an interval for connecting with the cover plate; a side surface of the bump facing the cover plate is concavely provided with a first through groove, and a side surface of the cover plate connected to the bump is concavely provided with a second through groove; the first through groove and the second through groove surround to form a through hole for the telescopic rods to pass through; the second groove is divided, by the two bumps, into a first groove portion (2311) and second groove portions (2312) located on both sides of the first groove portion opposite to each other; two blocks are arranged on the two frame bars, respectively, and the two blocks are partially engaged in the second groove portion; the two engaged grooves are arranged on the two blocks, respectively.<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>The display screen according to claim 1, wherein, the display module further comprises a plurality of first magnets (25); the back of the display module is further provided with a plurality of installation slots (26) for mounting the plurality of first magnets; a face of the display frame matched with the display module is provided with a plurality of second magnets in alignment with the first magnets, or metal parts magnetically attached to the first magnets; alternatively, the display frame is a metal frame body magnetically attached to the first magnets; and/or,<br/>
a number of the display modules is at least two; a number of the locking mechanisms is equal to the number of the display modules, and a number of the engaged grooves is twice the number of the display modules; each display module is locked to the display frame through the locking mechanism.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims02" lang="de"><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> -->
<claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Ein Anzeigebildschirm (100), der einen Anzeigerahmen (10), ein abnehmbares, mit dem Anzeigerahmen verbundenes Anzeigemodul (20) und einen auf einer Rückseite des Anzeigemoduls angebrachten Verriegelungsmechanismus (30) zum Verriegeln des Anzeigemoduls auf dem Anzeigerahmen umfasst; wobei der Anzeigerahmen mindestens zwei in einer Reihe, in Abständen angeordnete Rahmenstangen (11) aufweist und beliebige zwei benachbarte Rahmenstangen mit mindestens zwei einander gegenüberliegenden Eingriffsnuten (111) vorgesehen sind; der Verriegelungsmechanismus umfasst zwei Teleskopstangen (31) und eine Antriebsbaugruppe (32), sodass die beiden Teleskopstangen in die Eingriffsnuten, die auf den beiden Rahmenstangen angeordnet sind, eingeführt bzw. herausgezogen werden können; die Antriebsbaugruppe ist auf der Rückseite des Anzeigemoduls installiert und mit den beiden Teleskopstangen verbunden;
<claim-text>wobei die Antriebsbaugruppe eine Knopfbaugruppe ist, die auf der Rückseite des Anzeigemoduls angeordnet ist, und das jeweils eine Ende beider Teleskopstangen durch ein Gelenk mit einer Seite der Knopfbaugruppe beweglich verbunden ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei die Knopfanordnung einen Knopf (321) und ein Drehelement (322) umfasst, dessen eines Ende mit dem Knopf verbunden ist, und das jeweils eine Ende beider Teleskopstangen durch ein Gelenk mit einer Seite des Drehelements beweglich verbunden ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei das Drehelement einen Plattenkörper (3221), eine erste Ausbuchtung (3222), die auf einer Seite des Plattenkörpers angebracht ist, und eine zweite Ausbuchtung (3223), die auf der anderen Seite des Plattenkörpers angebracht ist, umfasst; die erste Ausbuchtung ist mit dem Knopf verbunden; ein Begrenzungsloch (21) ist auf der Rückseite des Anzeigemoduls angebracht und die zweite Ausbuchtung ist in dem Begrenzungsloch angebracht und kann sich in dem Begrenzungsloch drehen;</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>das jeweils eine Ende beider Teleskopstangen mit einer Seite des Plattenkörpers durch<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> ein Gelenk beweglich verbunden ist; der Plattenkörper jeweils mit einem ersten Durchgangsloch (3224) auf beiden Seiten vorgesehen ist, die ersten Durchgangslöcher in einer Erstreckungsrichtung der ersten Ausbuchtung gegenüberliegend angeordnet sind und das jeweils eine Ende beider Teleskopstangen mit einem zweiten Durchgangsloch (311) vorgesehen ist; der Verriegelungsmechanismus ferner zwei Stifte (33) umfasst und die Teleskopstangen mit dem Plattenkörper mittels der Stifte durch ein Gelenk beweglich verbunden sind, die das erste Durchgangsloch und das zweite Durchgangsloch durchdringen:<br/>
und
<claim-text>das Anzeigemodul mit zwei bogenförmigen Löchern (22) auf einer Seite des Begrenzungslochs in einem Abstand entlang einer Umfangsrichtung vorgesehen ist, und ein Ende jedes Stifts entfernt von dem Knopf in dem bogenförmigen Loch angeordnet ist und in dem bogenförmigen Loch gleiten kann; und/oder,</claim-text>
<claim-text>das Anzeigemodul eine Modulhalterung (23) und eine an der Modulhalterung angebrachte Lampenplatte (24) umfasst; der Verriegelungsmechanismus auf einer Rückseite der Modulhalterung angeordnet ist und die Modulhalterung mit dem Begrenzungsloch vorgesehen ist; die zweite Ausbuchtung mit einem inneren sechseckigen Loch (3225) vorgesehen ist und die Lampenplatte mit einem Demontageloch (241) in Ausrichtung mit dem Begrenzungsloch, das die Lampenplatte durchdringt, vorgesehen ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Anzeigebildschirm nach Anspruch 1, wobei jede Teleskopstange einen ersten Stangenabschnitt (312), dessen eines Ende sich in die Eingriffsnut erstreckt, und einen zweiten Stangenabschnitt (313) umfasst, dessen eines Ende mit dem anderen Ende des ersten Stangenabschnitts gelenkig verbunden ist; ein vom ersten Stangenabschnitt entferntes Ende jedes zweiten Stangenabschnitts ist mit dem Plattenkörper gelenkig verbunden.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Anzeigebildschirm nach Anspruch 1, wobei der Verriegelungsmechanismus ebenfalls eine Abdeckplatte (34) umfasst, die auf der Rückseite des Anzeigemoduls angebracht ist; ein Aufnahmehohlraum zwischen der Abdeckplatte und dem Anzeigemodul<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> gebildet wird; eine vom Anzeigemodul abgewandte Seite der Abdeckplatte mit einem Loch (341) vorgesehen ist; sich ein Teil des Knopfes in dem Aufnahmehohlraum befindet und der andere Teil des Knopfes durch das Knopfloch aus dem Aufnahmehohlraum herausragt; die Abdeckplatte mit einer dritten Ausbuchtung (342) auf beiden Seiten des Lochs vorgesehen ist, die einander gegenüberliegen; die gegenüberliegenden Flächen der beiden dritten Ausbuchtungen jeweils mit einer ersten Nut (343) zum Anordnen des Knopfes vorgesehen sind, wenn die Teleskopstange in die Eingriffsnut ausgefahren ist; beide Seiten des Knopfes, die einander gegenüberliegen, jeweils mit einer vierten Ausbuchtung (3212) vorgesehen sind, um in die erste Nut einzugreifen.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Anzeigebildschirm nach Anspruch 3, wobei die Rückseite des Anzeigemoduls konkav mit einer zweiten Nut (231) vorgesehen ist und eine Bodenfläche der zweiten Nut konvex mit zwei Höckern (232) in einem Abstand zur Verbindung mit der Abdeckplatte vorgesehen ist; eine Seitenfläche des Höckers, die der Abdeckplatte zugewandt ist, konkav mit einer ersten Durchgangsnut vorgesehen ist, und eine Seitenfläche der Abdeckplatte, die mit dem Höcker verbunden ist, konkav mit einer zweiten Durchgangsnut vorgesehen ist; die erste Durchgangsnut und die zweite Durchgangsnut sich umschließen und damit ein Durchgangsloch bilden, durch das sich die Teleskopstangen hindurchführen lassen; die zweite Nut durch die beiden Höcker in einen ersten Nutabschnitt (2311) und zweite Nutabschnitte (2312) unterteilt ist, die auf beiden Seiten des ersten Nutabschnitts einander gegenüberliegend angeordnet sind; zwei Blöcke jeweils an den beiden Rahmenstangen angeordnet sind, und die beiden Blöcke teilweise in dem zweiten Nutabschnitt in Eingriff stehen; die beiden in Eingriff stehenden Nuten jeweils an den beiden Blöcken angebracht sind.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Anzeigebildschirm nach Anspruch 1, wobei das Anzeigemodul weiter eine Vielzahl von ersten Magneten (25) umfasst; die Rückseite des Anzeigemoduls ferner mit einer Vielzahl von Installationsschlitzen (26) zum Anbringen der Vielzahl von ersten Magneten vorgesehen ist; eine mit dem Anzeigemodul zusammenpassende Fläche des Anzeigerahmens mit einer Vielzahl von zweiten Magneten in Ausrichtung mit den ersten Magneten oder Metallteilen vorgesehen ist, die magnetisch an den ersten Magneten befestigt sind; alternativ der Anzeigerahmen ein Metallrahmenkörper ist, der magnetisch an den ersten Magneten befestigt ist; und/oder,<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> -->eine Anzahl der Anzeigemodule mindestens zwei beträgt; die Anzahl der Verriegelungsmechanismen gleich der Anzahl der Anzeigemodule ist und die Anzahl der ineinandergreifenden Rillen doppelt so groß ist wie die Anzahl der Anzeigemodule; jedes Anzeigemodul durch den Verriegelungsmechanismus mit dem Anzeigerahmen verriegelt ist.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims03" lang="fr"><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> -->
<claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Ecran d'affichage (100), comprenant un cadre d'affichage (10), un module d'affichage (20) connecté de manière détachable au cadre d'affichage, et un mécanisme de verrouillage (30) monté sur un dos du module d'affichage pour verrouiller le module d'affichage sur le cadre d'affichage ; dans lequel le cadre d'affichage a au moins deux barres de cadre (11) disposées en une rangée et à intervalles, et deux barres de cadre adjacentes quelconques sont pourvues d'au moins deux rainures engagées (111) espacées et opposées l'une à l'autre ; le mécanisme de verrouillage comprend deux tiges télescopiques (31) et un ensemble d'entraînement (32) pour entraîner les deux tiges télescopiques afin qu'elles soient insérées dans les rainures d'engagement disposées sur les deux barres du cadre, ou retirées de celles-ci, respectivement ; l'ensemble d'entraînement est installé sur le dos du module d'affichage et relié aux deux tiges télescopiques ;
<claim-text>dans lequel, l'ensemble d'entraînement est un ensemble de boutons disposé sur le dos du module d'affichage, et une extrémité de chacune des deux tiges télescopiques est articulée avec un côté de l'ensemble de boutons ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel, l'ensemble de boutons comprend un bouton (321) et un élément rotatif (322) avec une extrémité reliée au bouton, et la première extrémité de chacune des deux tiges télescopiques est articulée avec un côté de l'élément rotatif ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel, l'élément rotatif comprend un corps de plaque (3221), un premier renflement (3222) disposé sur un côté du corps de plaque, et un second renflement (3223) disposé sur l'autre côté du corps de plaque ; le premier renflement est relié au bouton ; un trou de limitation (21) est disposé sur le dos du module d'affichage, et le second renflement est monté dans le trou de limitation et capable de tourner dans le trou de limitation ;</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>caractérisé en ce que</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>la première extrémité de chacune des deux tiges télescopiques est articulée avec un côté du corps de plaque ; le corps de plaque est respectivement pourvu d'un premier trou traversant (3224) sur les deux côtés, les premiers trous traversants sont agencés de manière opposée dans une direction d'extension du premier renflement, et une extrémité de chacune des deux tiges télescopiques est pourvue d'un second trou traversant (311) ; le mécanisme de verrouillage comprend en outre deux broches (33), et les tiges télescopiques sont articulées avec le corps de plaque au moyen des broches pénétrant dans le premier trou traversant et le second trou traversant :<br/>
et<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> -->
<claim-text>le module d'affichage est pourvu de deux trous en forme d'arc (22) sur un côté du trou de limitation à un intervalle le long d'une direction circonférentielle, et une extrémité de chaque broche éloignée du bouton est disposée dans le trou en forme d'arc et capable de coulisser dans le trou en forme d'arc ; et/ou,</claim-text>
<claim-text>le module d'affichage comprend un support de module (23) et un panneau de lampe (24) monté sur le support de module ; le mécanisme de verrouillage est disposé sur un dos du support de module, et le support de module est pourvu du trou de limitation ; le second renflement est pourvu d'un trou hexagonal intérieur (3225), et le panneau de lampe est pourvu d'un trou de démontage (241) en alignement avec le trou de limitation pénétrant dans le panneau de lampe.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Ecran d'affichage selon la revendication 1, dans lequel, chaque tige télescopique comprend une première partie de tige (312) avec une extrémité s'étendant dans la rainure engagée et une seconde partie de tige (313) avec une extrémité articulée avec l'autre extrémité de la première partie de tige ; une extrémité de chaque seconde partie de tige éloignée de la première partie de tige est articulée avec le corps de plaque.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Ecran d'affichage selon la revendication 1, dans lequel, le mécanisme de verrouillage comprend en outre une plaque de couverture (34) montée à l'arrière du module d'affichage ; une cavité de réception est formée entre la plaque de couverture et le module d'affichage ; un côté de la plaque de couverture éloigné du module d'affichage est pourvu d'un trou de bouton (341) ; une partie du bouton est installée dans la cavité de réception, et l'autre partie du bouton fait saillie hors de la cavité de réception à travers le trou de bouton ; la plaque de recouvrement est pourvue d'un troisième renflement (342) sur les deux côtés du trou de bouton opposés l'un à l'autre, respectivement ; les faces opposées des deux troisièmes renflements sont chacune pourvues d'une première rainure (343) pour positionner le bouton lorsque la tige télescopique est étendue dans la rainure engagée ; les deux côtés du bouton opposés l'un à l'autre sont chacun pourvus d'un quatrième renflement (3212) pour être engagé dans la première rainure.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Ecran d'affichage selon la revendication 3, dans lequel, l'arrière du module d'affichage est pourvu de manière concave d'une seconde rainure (231), et une surface inférieure de la seconde rainure est pourvue de manière convexe de deux bosses (232) à un intervalle pour la connexion avec la plaque de couverture ; une surface latérale de la bosse faisant face à la<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> plaque de couverture est pourvue de manière concave d'une première rainure traversante, et une surface latérale de la plaque de couverture connectée à la bosse est pourvue de manière concave d'une seconde rainure traversante ; la première rainure traversante et la seconde rainure traversante s'entourent pour former un trou traversant pour le passage des tiges télescopiques ; la seconde rainure est divisée, par les deux bosses, en une première partie de rainure (2311) et des secondes parties de rainure (2312) situées sur les deux côtés de la première partie de rainure opposés l'un à l'autre ; deux blocs sont disposés sur les deux barres de cadre, respectivement, et les deux blocs sont partiellement engagés dans la seconde partie de rainure ; les deux rainures engagées sont disposées sur les deux blocs, respectivement.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Ecran d'affichage selon la revendication 1, dans lequel, le module d'affichage comprend en outre une pluralité de premiers aimants (25) ; l'arrière du module d'affichage est en outre pourvu d'une pluralité de fentes d'installation (26) pour monter la pluralité de premiers aimants ; une face du cadre d'affichage appariée au module d'affichage est pourvue d'une pluralité de seconds aimants en alignement avec les premiers aimants, ou de parties métalliques fixées magnétiquement aux premiers aimants ; en variante, le cadre d'affichage est un corps de cadre métallique fixé magnétiquement aux premiers aimants ; et/ou,<br/>
un nombre de modules d'affichage est au moins deux ; un nombre de mécanismes de verrouillage est égal au nombre de modules d'affichage, et un nombre de rainures engagées est deux fois le nombre de modules d'affichage ; chaque module d'affichage est verrouillé au cadre d'affichage par le mécanisme de verrouillage.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="121" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="2,3"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="99" he="204" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> -->
<figure id="f0003" num="4"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="101" he="227" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> -->
<figure id="f0004" num="5"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="109" he="206" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> -->
<figure id="f0005" num="6"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="147" he="128" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="26"> -->
<figure id="f0006" num="7"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="165" he="128" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> -->
<figure id="f0007" num="8,9"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="95" he="187" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="28"> -->
<figure id="f0008" num="10"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="165" he="123" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="29"> -->
<figure id="f0009" num="11"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="112" he="193" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="30"> -->
<figure id="f0010" num="12"><img id="if0010" file="imgf0010.tif" wi="111" he="103" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<ep-reference-list id="ref-list">
<heading id="ref-h0001"><b>REFERENCES CITED IN THE DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0001" num=""><i>This list of references cited by the applicant is for the reader's convenience only. It does not form part of the European patent document. Even though great care has been taken in compiling the references, errors or omissions cannot be excluded and the EPO disclaims all liability in this regard.</i></p>
<heading id="ref-h0002"><b>Patent documents cited in the description</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0002" num="">
<ul id="ref-ul0001" list-style="bullet">
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0001" dnum="CN203535911U"><document-id><country>CN</country><doc-number>203535911</doc-number><kind>U</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0001">[0004]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0002" dnum="GB2558585A"><document-id><country>GB</country><doc-number>2558585</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0002">[0004]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0003" dnum="US4142747A"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>4142747</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0003">[0005]</crossref></li>
</ul></p>
</ep-reference-list>
</ep-patent-document>
