<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP15465507B1" file="EP15465507NWB1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3073810" kind="B1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSK..HRIS..MTNORS..SM..................</B001EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  2100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3073810</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT SPECIFICATION</B121></B120><B130>B1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>15465507.0</B210><B220><date>20150326</date></B220><B240><B241><date>20170328</date></B241><B242><date>20190425</date></B242></B240><B250>en</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20160928</date><bnum>201639</bnum></B430><B450><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B450><B452EP><date>20210624</date></B452EP></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>H05K   5/00        20060101AFI20151001BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>H05K   5/0047      20130101 FI20150928BHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>ELEKTRONISCHE STEUEREINHEIT MIT GEHÄUSESTABILISIERUNGSELEMENT UND GEHÄUSE FÜR ELEKTRONISCHE STEUEREINHEIT</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>ELECTRONIC CONTROL UNIT WITH A HOUSING STABILIZING ELEMENT AND HOUSING FOR ELECTRONIC CONTROL UNIT</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>UNITÉ DE COMMANDE ÉLECTRONIQUE AVEC UN ÉLÉMENT DE STABILISATION DE BOÎTIER ET BOÎTIER POUR UNITÉ DE COMMANDE ÉLECTRONIQUE</B542></B540><B560><B561><text>EP-A2- 2 429 273</text></B561><B561><text>DE-A1- 19 712 099</text></B561><B561><text>DE-A1-102009 043 177</text></B561><B561><text>DE-A1-102009 054 758</text></B561><B561><text>DE-A1-102013 203 986</text></B561><B561><text>JP-A- H08 316 662</text></B561><B561><text>JP-A- 2014 120 677</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2011 315 580</text></B561></B560></B500><B700><B720><B721><snm>Kang, Alan</snm><adr><str>3833 Cherrywood Ln</str><city>48309, Rochester Hills, MI Michigan</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>Riepl, Thomas</snm><adr><str>Thomas-Mann-Str. 22</str><city>93077 Bad Abbach</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>Tarnovetchi, Marius</snm><adr><str>Cal. Sagului 81C</str><city>300516 Timisoara</city><ctry>RO</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B730><B731><snm>Vitesco Technologies GmbH</snm><iid>101844986</iid><irf>2013P03155EP</irf><adr><str>Vahrenwalder Straße 9</str><city>30165 Hannover</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B731></B730></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840></B800></SDOBI>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<heading id="h0001"><u>Field of the invention</u></heading>
<p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a housing for an electronic control unit, for example for automotive applications, and to an electronic control unit.</p>
<heading id="h0002"><u>Art Background</u></heading>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">Electronic components, for example printed circuit boards, of an electronic control unit normally need to be protected from the surrounding environment which could be dangerous for the normal functioning of the electronic components, for example due to the presence of pollutants, such as dust, water or oil. For this reason electronic components may be contained in the inner volume of a housing, which is sealed to prevent contact with the external environment.</p>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">Conventional housings for electronic control units comprise a main body and a cover which are joined together along a border. Along the border area of contact between the main body and the cover, the housing comprises a sealing element, for example constituted by a gasket, an O-ring or a viscous dispensed material. The sealing element prevents pollutants, such as dust, water or oil from entering the housing through the border area.</p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">The housing is normally subject to temperature variations, due to both self-heating of the electronic control unit and to variations in the climate conditions of the external environment. Accelerated tests to which electronic control units are subjected create even harsher temperature conditions. Differences in temperature between the sealed inner volume of the housing and the external environment may in turn cause pressure differences between a gas inside the housing and the ambient atmosphere surrounding the housing.</p>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">Due to differences in the coefficients of thermal expansion of the main body and of the cover and to positive or negative differences between internal and external pressure (overpressure or under-pressure, respectively), the housing is subject to<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> mechanical stress. Such stress may cause deformation of the parts, in particular the cover, which are thinner in comparison with other parts, in particular the main body. As a result, this may cause stress on the sealing element between the main body and the cover, which may result into an adhesion or a cohesion sealant failure.</p>
<p id="p0006" num="0006"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="DE102013203986A1"><text>DE 102013203986 A1</text></patcit> relates to an arrangement for fixing a carrier plate for an electronic circuit inside a housing. The housing has a lower housing part, a housing cover, and a seal which is arranged between the lower housing part and the housing cover. Fixing elements are arranged between the carrier plate and the housing cover, which are connected to the seal.</p>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">The housing for controllers in motor vehicles disclosed by <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="DE102009054758A1"><text>DE 102009054758 A1 </text></patcit> has a printed circuit board, temporarily connected with an element expanding with respect to volume such that the carrier element is force-subjected with contact force against a housing element during expansion of the element. The volume is temperature-dependent and a relative motion of the housing element and another housing element to the carrier element is compensated by the volume such that the force is maintained, where the motion takes place during temperature change. The latter housing element is made of plastic.</p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">The device of <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="EP2429273A2"><text>EP 2429273 A2</text></patcit> has a cooling element provided as a housing lid of an electrical device. An electronic circuit is arranged on a printed circuit board. A pressing pin is arranged above a power loss producing element of the electronic circuit so that mechanical and thermal contacts to the board are ensured. The pressing-pin is manufactured by an injection molding process. The pressing-pin is produced as a seal for a lower housing part and the housing lid made of liquid-silicone. The pressing-pin is pressed with pressing force of 100 to 200 Newton after a mounting step.</p>
<p id="p0009" num="0009"><patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="JPH08316662A"><text>JP H08-316662 A</text></patcit> discloses an electronic apparatus wherein the head of an attaching screw, connected to ground potential in a printed wiring board, for attaching the printed wiring board to a housing body, is electrically connected to an electrically conductive body electrically covering the printed wiring board.</p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010"><patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="JP2014120677A"><text>JP 2014-120677 A</text></patcit> relates to an electronic apparatus which includes a circuit board which is fixed to the side of an apparatus body; a conductive cover member which is attached to the side of the apparatus body while covering the circuit<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> board; and conductive rubber which is provided lying astride the circuit board and the cover member so that the circuit board and the cover member are electrically conducted.</p>
<heading id="h0003"><u>Summary of the Invention</u></heading>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">It is an object of the present invention to provide a control unit with a housing which has a particularly small risk of damage to the sealing element between the cover and the main body of the housing due to mechanical stress.</p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">The object is achieved by an electronic control unit according to the independent claim. The dependent claims describe advantageous developments and modifications of the invention.</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">According to the present invention, an electronic control unit is disclosed. The electronic control unit comprises a sealed housing including a main body and a cover fixed to one another and a sealing element in contact with one and/or the other of the main body and the cover. In particular the sealing element is in contact with both, the main body and the cover. The sealing element is preferably positioned at an interface of the main body with the cover for sealing the interface. The main body and/or the cover may have a groove for accommodating the sealing element at least in part.</p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">Further, the electronic control unit comprises a circuit board arrangement in the housing. The circuit board arrangement comprises a circuit board. The circuit board is for example a printed circuit board.</p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">The sealed housing further comprises at least one housing stabilizing element in contact with the circuit board arrangement and the cover.</p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">The housing stabilizing element(s) between the circuit board arrangement inside the housing and the housing itself provide(s) an additional fixation to the housing assembly, thus limiting deformation and therefore preventing adhesion or a cohesion sealant failure of the sealing element which is provided between the main body and the cover. As a further advantage, the housing described above is characterized by a high degree of stiffness, showing improved vibration performances.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">As a consequence, additional fixations between the cover and the main body of the housing, provided to avoid permanent deformations and to limit the displacements to the elastic domain, can be advantageously be dispensed with. For example, additional internal walls or posts of the housing rising from the main body and supporting the cover within the inner volume of the housing can be omitted. The presence of additional internal walls or posts would reduce the space available for the electronic circuit inside the inner volume. In addition, the presence of additional internal walls makes the main body of the housing more complex and therefore more expensive.</p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">Additional fixation means between the cover and the main body - such as screws, rivets or the like can also be omitted. The presence of additional fixations between the sheet metal cover and the main body of the housing makes the coupling of the cover to the main body longer. Such additional fixation means can also increase the risk for reliability issues, e.g. due to the additional sealing area required in the regions where they penetrate for example from the outside through the cover into the main body.</p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">In one embodiment, the housing stabilizing element(s) overlap(s) the circuit board in top view on a main surface of the circuit board. In this way, the housing stabilizing element is particularly space saving.</p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">According to the invention, the circuit board arrangement comprises one or more fixing elements for fixing the circuit board to the main body. The housing stabilizing element or at least one of the housing stabilizing elements is interposed between and in mechanical contact with the fixing elements and the cover</p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">According to the invention, the fixing elements are screws and the housing stabilizing element is interposed between said other one of the main body and the cover and a head of one of the screws.</p>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">The fixing elements protrude from the circuit board, for example the heads of the screws for fixing circuit boards protrude from the circuit board, thus reducing the gap which the housing stabilizing element has to bridge to contact the housing at a side remote from the circuit board arrangement. Therefore, the thickness of the housing stabilizing element(s) may be particularly small.</p>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">According to the invention, the circuit board is fixed to the main body and the housing stabilizing element is interposed between the circuit board and the cover<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> of the sealed housing. Advantageously, this facilitates an easy assembly of the electronic control unit. In a method for producing the electronic control unit, the circuit board can be fixed on the main body first, one or more housing stabilizing elements can be provided on the circuit board arrangement and finally the cover can be fixed to the main body.</p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">The fixing elements fix the circuit board to the main body and the housing stabilizing element or at least one of the housing stabilizing elements is interposed between the cover and one of the fixing elements. The fixing elements are screws and a housing stabilizing element is interposed between the cover and at least one head of said screws. Advantageously, this allows providing the housing stabilizing elements over stiffening elements, i.e. over fixing elements which have to be present to assure the fixing of the circuit board to the main body of the housing.</p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">The cover comprises at least one indentation protruding towards the printed circuit board. The housing stabilizing element or at least one of the housing stabilizing elements is interposed between the indentation and the circuit board. In other words, the housing stabilizing element(s) is/are sandwiched between the circuit board arrangement and the indentation(s). In particular, at least one of the housing stabilizing elements is interposed between the indentation and a respective head of a respective screw, fixing the circuit board to the main body of the housing. Advantageously, indentations further help in achieving a particularly small gap between the circuit board and the cover of the housing, thus a particularly small thickness of the housing stabilizing element(s) is achievable.</p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">According to the invention, the at least one indentation further comprises a first linear segment inclined with respect to a top surface of the cover and protruding towards an inner volume of the sealed housing, the first segment being linked to the top surface by means of a first corner. The at least one indentation further comprises a second linear segment parallel to the top surface and linked to the first linear segment by a second corner. The at least one indentation further comprises a third linear segment linked to the second linear segment by means of a third corner and linked to the top surface by means of a fourth corner, wherein the at least one of the housing stabilizing elements is interposed between and in mechanical contact with the second linear segment and the head of the screw.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">According to further embodiments, the fixing elements or at least one fixing element in contact with a respective housing stabilizing element is positioned in correspondence to the portions of the sealed housing having the highest deformability. For example, the fixing element may be positioned in correspondence to an area lacking mechanical fixation - for example a center area<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> of the cover in top view on a main surface of the circuit board - thus improving stiffness and vibration performances. According to a further embodiment, the fixing element or at least one fixing element in contact with a respective housing stabilizing element is positioned close to the border portion of the sealed housing. For example, it is positioned adjacent to an edge region of the circuit board. Advantageously, this improves the resistance of the assembly in case of drop.</p>
<heading id="h0004"><u>Brief Description of the Drawings</u></heading>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">The aspects defined above and further aspects of the present invention are apparent from the examples of embodiment to be described hereinafter and are explained with reference to the exemplary embodiments. The invention will be described in more detail hereinafter with reference to exemplary embodiments to which the invention is not limited. The scope of the invention is defined by the claims.
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
<li><figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is a sectional view of an electronic control unit according to a first exemplary embodiment of the present invention,</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> is a sectional view of an electronic control unit according to a second exemplary embodiment the present invention,</li>
</ul></p>
<heading id="h0005"><u>Detailed Description</u></heading>
<p id="p0029" num="0029"><figref idref="f0001"><b>Fig. 1</b></figref> shows an electronic control unit 1 according to a first exemplary embodiment of the present invention. The electronic control unit 1 comprises a housing 10 and a circuit board arrangement inside the housing 10.</p>
<p id="p0030" num="0030"><figref idref="f0002"><b>Fig. 2</b></figref> shows an electronic control unit 1 according to a second exemplary embodiment of the present invention. The electronic control unit 1 according to the second embodiment corresponds in<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> general to the electronic control unit 1 according to the first embodiment. Differences between the two embodiments are discussed below.</p>
<p id="p0031" num="0031">The circuit board arrangement comprises a printed circuit board 20 and a plurality of fixing elements 23 which fix the circuit board 20 to the housing 10.</p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032">The housing 10 comprises a main body 11 and a cover 12 joined together. The main body 11 is made of a plastic or metal material. It may be a molded part. The cover 12 is typically made of a metal sheet, of the same or of a different material with respect to the main body 11. The housing 10 comprises a connector (not shown) for connecting the printed circuit board 20 inside the housing 10 to an external source of connection -such as a wire harness - for providing power and/or data exchange.</p>
<p id="p0033" num="0033">The main body 11 has a base 15 and a perimeter wall 18 rising from the base 15. The base 15, seen from a top or bottom view (not shown) orthogonal to the sectional views of <figref idref="f0001">figures 1</figref> and <figref idref="f0002">2</figref>, may of rectangular shape, circular shape or other shapes. The perimeter wall 18 is orthogonal to the base 15. According to different embodiments of the present invention (not shown) the perimeter wall 18 may be otherwise inclined and/or curved with respect to the base 15.</p>
<p id="p0034" num="0034">The cover 12 has a top surface 16 and a perimeter wall 17 protruding from the top surface 16. The perimeter wall 17 is orthogonal to the top surface 16. According to different embodiments of the present invention (not shown) the perimeter wall 17 of the cover 12 may be otherwise inclined and/or curved with respect to the top surface 16. According to different embodiments of the present invention (not shown) the perimeter wall 17 of the cover 12 may not be present.</p>
<p id="p0035" num="0035">On top of the perimeter wall 18, the cover 12 is supported and fixed in order to create a hollow structure with an inner volume 30 extending between the base 15, the perimeter wall 18 and the<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> cover 12. The inner volume 30 is subject to house the printed circuit board 20. The inner volume 30 may house a plurality of further electronic components (not shown).</p>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">On top of the perimeter wall 18, a planar border portion 21a is defined for the coupling with a correspondent planar border portion 21b at the end of the perimeter wall 17 of the cover 12. In embodiments where the perimeter wall 17 of the cover 12 are not present, the planar border portion 21b is provided directly along the border of top surface 16 of the cover 12.</p>
<p id="p0037" num="0037">Border portions 21a, 21b, which are not planar are also conceivable. However, also non-planar border portions 21a, 21b may expediently be configured for establishing a form-fit connection between the main body 11 and the cover 12.</p>
<p id="p0038" num="0038">On the border portion 21a the perimeter wall 18 of the main body 11 includes a seat 19 for a perimeter sealing element 40 made of a sealant material. For example, the sealing element 40 may be constituted by an O-ring or a formed-in-place gasket made from a fluid sealing compound. The seat 19 and the sealing element 40 are trapezoidal in cross-sectional shape, but other shapes are in general also possible, for example shapes as a circular sector or a rectangle.</p>
<p id="p0039" num="0039">When the main body 11 and the cover 12 are joined together, the sealing element 40 is interposed between the top of the perimeter wall 18 and the cover 12, preventing contamination, for example dust or other pollutants, to the inner volume 30 from the external environment.</p>
<p id="p0040" num="0040">The main body 11 has a plurality of supports 13 rising from the base 15 for supporting the printed boarded circuit 20. In each of the supports 13 a coupling element 14 for one of the fixing elements 23 is provided. When the printed circuit board 20 is supported on the supports 13, the coupling of the fixing elements 23 to the respective coupling elements 14 assures that the printed<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> boarded circuit 20 is fixed to the main body 11 of the housing 10.</p>
<p id="p0041" num="0041">In the embodiments of <figref idref="f0001">figures 1</figref> and <figref idref="f0002">2</figref>, the fixing elements 23 are screws and coupling elements 14 are threaded holes. Each screw 23 comprises a head 24, protruding from the printed boarded circuit 20 in a direction away from the supports 13 when the printed boarded circuit 20 is fixed to the main body 11 of the housing 10. In other words, the supports 13, the circuit board 20 and the heads 24 follow one another in this order in a direction normal to a main surface of the circuit board 20 towards the cover 12.</p>
<p id="p0042" num="0042">In <figref idref="f0001">figure 1</figref>, two supports 13 are shown, laterally adjacent to the border portion 21a, 21b. In the more stiffened embodiment of <figref idref="f0002">figure 2</figref>, three supports 13 are shown. The additional support 13 - with respect to the supports 13 shown in <figref idref="f0001">figure 1</figref> - is placed in a central area 16a of the top surface 16 of the cover 12, where no other mechanical fixation is present, i.e. the portion of the top surface 16 having the highest deformability. The additional support 13 provides improved stiffness and response to vibrations, for applications where this may be desirable. In general, according to other embodiments of the present invention, any number of supports may be foreseen for reaching the desired level of stiffness.</p>
<p id="p0043" num="0043">The printed circuit board 20 comprises a top main surface 20a, opposite to a bottom main surface 20b, which is subject to contact the supports 13. Between the top main surface 20a and the cover 12, one or more housing stabilizing element 50 are interposed between the printed circuit board 20 and the cover 12 of the sealed housing 10.</p>
<p id="p0044" num="0044">As shown in the embodiments of <figref idref="f0001">figures 1</figref> and <figref idref="f0002">2</figref>, each housing stabilizing element 50 is interposed between the cover 12 and one of the fixing elements 23, in particular between the cover 12 and a respective head 24 of a respective screw 23. Specifically, opposite sides of the housing stabilizing elements 50 are in<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> direct mechanical contact with the cover 12 and the corresponding heads 24, respectively. The housing stabilizing elements 50 are made of adhesive glue or of a sealant material formed-in-place gasket made from a fluid sealing compound. The housing stabilizing elements 50 - as well as the heads 24 - laterally overlap the circuit board 20 and also the supports 13 in top view of the top main surface 20a.</p>
<p id="p0045" num="0045">The cover 12 comprises one or more indentations 22, protruding, when the electronic control unit 1 is assembled, towards the printed circuit board 20. According to possible embodiments of the present invention, each of the housing stabilizing elements 50 are interposed between a respective indentation 22 and the circuit board 20. In particular, in the embodiments of <figref idref="f0001">figures 1</figref> and <figref idref="f0002">2</figref>, each of the housing stabilizing elements 50 are interposed between and in mechanical contact with a respective indentation 22 and a respective head 24 of a respective screw 23. Each indentation 22 laterally overlaps a corresponding housing stabilizing element 50, a corresponding screw head 24, the circuit board 20 and a corresponding support 13 in top view onto the top main surface 20a.</p>
<p id="p0046" num="0046">The indentation 22 has a trapezoidally shaped cross-section, comprising three consecutive linear segments 25 and four corners 26, linking the segments 25 with one another and with the other portions of the cover 12, for example, in the embodiment of <figref idref="f0001">figure 1</figref>, central area 16a of the top surface 16. The trapezoidally shaped section of each indentation 22 comprises:
<ul id="ul0002" list-style="dash" compact="compact">
<li>a first segment 25 (i.e. a sidewall) inclined with respect to the top surface 16 towards the inner volume 30 and linked to the top surface 16 by means of a first corner 26,</li>
<li>a second segment 25 (i.e. a bottom wall) parallel to the top surface 16 and linked to the first segment 25 by means of a second corner 26,</li>
<li>a third segment 25 (i.e. a further sidewall) linked to the second segment 25 by means of a third corner 26 and linked to the top surface 16 by means of a fourth corner 26.</li>
</ul><!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></p>
<p id="p0047" num="0047">The bottom wall 25 of each indentation 22 is directly in contact with a respective housing stabilizing element 50.</p>
<p id="p0048" num="0048">In an example not covered by the claimed invention any other shape, for example a curved shape, may be used in the indentations 22 of the cover 12 for obtaining an area which, in the assembly of the electronic control unit 1 is closer to the printed boarded circuit 20, thus permitting to control the gap between the cover 12 and the printed boarded circuit 20 and consequently the thickness of the housing stabilizing elements 50.</p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> -->
<claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>An electronic control unit (1) comprising:
<claim-text>- a sealed housing (10) including a main body (11) and a cover (12) fixed to one another and a sealing element (40) in contact with one and/or the other of the main body (11) and the cover (12),</claim-text>
<claim-text>- a circuit board arrangement in the housing (10), the circuit board arrangement comprising a circuit board (20) being fixed to the main body (11) and one or more fixing elements (23) for fixing the circuit board (20) to the main body (11), wherein the one or more fixing elements (23) are screws having a head (24),</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>the sealed housing (10) further comprises at least one housing stabilizing element (50) in contact with the circuit board arrangement and the cover (12), the housing stabilizing element (50) being interposed between the circuit board (20) and the cover (12) of the sealed housing (10),</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>the housing stabilizing element (50) is interposed between and in mechanical contact with one of the fixing elements (23) and the cover (12),</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>characterized in that</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>the cover (12) comprises at least one indentation (22) protruding towards the printed circuit board (20),</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one of the housing stabilizing elements (50) being interposed between the indentation (22) and the circuit board (20),</claim-text>
<claim-text>the at least one indentation (22) further comprising
<claim-text>a first linear segment (25) inclined with respect to a top surface (16) of the cover (12) and protruding towards an inner volume (30) of the sealed housing (10), the first segment (25) being linked to the top surface (16) by means of a first corner (26)</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second linear segment (25) parallel to the top surface (16) and linked to the first linear segment (25) by a second corner (26), and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third linear segment (25) linked to the second linear segment (25) by means of a third corner (26) and linked to the top surface (16) by means of a fourth corner (26), wherein<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>the at least one of the housing stabilizing elements (50) is interposed between and in mechanical contact with the second linear segment (25) and the head (24) of the screw.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Electronic control unit (1) according to claim 1, wherein the fixing elements (23) in contact with the housing stabilizing elements (50) are positioned in correspondence to portions of the sealed housing (10) having the highest deformability.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Electronic control unit (1) according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein the fixing elements (23) in contact with the housing stabilizing elements (50) are positioned close to the border portion (21a, 21b) of the sealed housing (10).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Electronic control unit (1) according to any of the preceding claims, wherein the housing stabilizing elements (50) are made of adhesive glue or of a sealant material.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims02" lang="de"><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> -->
<claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Elektronische Steuereinheit (1), umfassend:
<claim-text>ein abgedichtetes Gehäuse (10) einschließlich eines Hauptkörpers (11) und einer Abdeckung (12), die aneinander befestigt sind, und eines Dichtungselements (40) in Kontakt mit einem und/oder dem anderen vom Hauptkörper (11) und der Abdeckung (12),</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Leiterplattenanordnung im Gehäuse (10), wobei die Leiterplattenanordnung eine Leiterplatte (20), die am Hauptkörper (11) befestigt ist, und ein oder mehrere Befestigungselemente (23) zum Befestigen der Leiterplatte (20) am Hauptkörper (11) umfasst, wobei das eine oder die mehreren Befestigungselemente (23) Schrauben mit einem Kopf (24) sind,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei</claim-text>
<claim-text>das abgedichtete Gehäuse (10) ferner mindestens ein Gehäusestabilisierungselement (50) umfasst, das mit der Leiterplattenanordnung und der Abdeckung (12) in Kontakt steht, wobei sich das Gehäusestabilisierungselement (50) zwischen der Leiterplatte (20) und der Abdeckung (12) des abgedichteten Gehäuses (10) befindet,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei</claim-text>
<claim-text>das Gehäusestabilisierungselement (50) sich zwischen und in mechanischem Kontakt mit einem der Befestigungselemente (23) und der Abdeckung (12) befindet,</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>die Abdeckung (12) mindestens eine Einbuchtung (22) umfasst, die in Richtung der Leiterplatte (20) vorsteht,</claim-text>
<claim-text>mindestens eines der Gehäusestabilisierungselemente (50) sich zwischen der Einbuchtung (22) und der Leiterplatte (20) befindet,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei die mindestens eine Einbuchtung (22) ferner umfasst:
<claim-text>ein erstes lineares Segment (25), das in Bezug auf eine obere Fläche (16) der Abdeckung (12) geneigt ist und in Richtung eines Innenvolumens (30) des abgedichteten Gehäuses (10) vorsteht, wobei das erste Segment (25) mit der oberen Fläche (16) mittels einer ersten Ecke (26) verbunden ist,</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein zweites lineares Segment (25), das parallel zur oberen Fläche (16) verläuft und über eine zweite Ecke (26) mit dem ersten linearen Segment (25) verbunden ist, und</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein drittes lineares Segment (25), das mit dem zweiten linearen Segment (25) mittels einer dritten Ecke (26) verbunden ist und mit der oberen Fläche (16) mittels einer vierten Ecke (26) verbunden ist, wobei das mindestens eine der Gehäusestabilisierungselemente (50) sich zwischen und in mechanischem Kontakt mit dem zweiten linearen Segment (25) und dem Kopf (24) der Schraube befindet.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Elektronische Steuereinheit (1) nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Befestigungselemente (23), die mit den Gehäusestabilisierungselementen (50) in Kontakt stehen, in Übereinstimmung mit Abschnitten des abgedichteten Gehäuses (10) angeordnet sind, die die höchste Verformbarkeit aufweisen.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Elektronische Steuereinheit (1) nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei die Befestigungselemente (23), die mit den Gehäusestabilisierungselementen (50) in Kontakt stehen, nahe dem Randabschnitt (21a, 21b) des abgedichteten Gehäuses (10) angeordnet sind.<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Elektronische Steuereinheit (1) nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei die Gehäusestabilisierungselemente (50) aus Klebstoff oder aus einem Dichtungsmaterial bestehen.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims03" lang="fr"><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> -->
<claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Unité (1) de commande électronique comportant :
<claim-text>- un boîtier étanche (10) comprenant un corps principal (11) et un couvercle (12) fixés l'un à l'autre et un élément (40) d'étanchéité en contact avec l'un et/ou l'autre du corps principal (11) et du couvercle (12),</claim-text>
<claim-text>- un agencement de carte à circuit dans le boîtier (10), l'agencement de carte à circuit comportant une carte (20) à circuit qui est fixée au corps principal (11) et un ou plusieurs éléments (23) de fixation servant à fixer la carte (20) à circuit au corps principal (11), l'élément ou les éléments (23) de fixation étant des vis dotées d'une tête (24),</claim-text>
<claim-text>le boîtier étanche (10) comportant en outre au moins un élément (50) de stabilisation de boîtier en contact avec l'agencement de carte à circuit et le couvercle (12), l'élément (50) de stabilisation de boîtier étant interposé entre la carte (20) à circuit et le couvercle (12) du boîtier étanche (10),</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'élément (50) de stabilisation de boîtier étant interposé entre, et en contact mécanique avec, un des éléments (23) de fixation et le couvercle (12), <b>caractérisé en ce que</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>le couvercle (12) comporte au moins une indentation (22) faisant saillie vers la carte (20) à circuit imprimé,</claim-text>
<claim-text>au moins un des éléments (50) de stabilisation de boîtier étant interposé entre l'indentation (22) et la carte (20) à circuit,<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>l'indentation ou les indentations (22) comportant en outre</claim-text>
<claim-text>un premier segment linéaire (25) incliné par rapport à une surface supérieure (16) du couvercle (12) et faisant saillie vers un volume intérieur (30) du boîtier étanche (10), le premier segment (25) étant lié à la surface supérieure (16) au moyen d'un premier coin (26),</claim-text>
<claim-text>un deuxième segment linéaire (25) parallèle à la surface supérieure (16) et lié au premier segment linéaire (25) par un deuxième coin (26), et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un troisième segment linéaire (25) lié au deuxième segment linéaire (25) au moyen d'un troisième coin (26) et lié à la surface supérieure (16) au moyen d'un quatrième coin (26),</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'élément ou les éléments parmi les éléments (50) de stabilisation de boîtier étant interposés entre, et en contact mécanique avec, le deuxième segment linéaire (25) et la tête (24) de la vis.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Unité (1) de commande électronique selon la revendication 1, les éléments (23) de fixation en contact avec les éléments (50) de stabilisation de boîtier étant positionnés en correspondance avec des parties du boîtier étanche (10) présentant la plus grande déformabilité.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Unité (1) de commande électronique selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, les éléments (23) de fixation en contact avec les éléments (50) de stabilisation de boîtier étant positionnés près de la partie (21a, 21b) de bordure du boîtier étanche (10).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Unité (1) de commande électronique selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, les éléments (50) de stabilisation de boîtier étant constitués d'une colle adhésive ou d'un matériau d'étanchéité.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="129" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="130" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<ep-reference-list id="ref-list">
<heading id="ref-h0001"><b>REFERENCES CITED IN THE DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0001" num=""><i>This list of references cited by the applicant is for the reader's convenience only. It does not form part of the European patent document. Even though great care has been taken in compiling the references, errors or omissions cannot be excluded and the EPO disclaims all liability in this regard.</i></p>
<heading id="ref-h0002"><b>Patent documents cited in the description</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0002" num="">
<ul id="ref-ul0001" list-style="bullet">
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0001" dnum="DE102013203986A1"><document-id><country>DE</country><doc-number>102013203986</doc-number><kind>A1</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0001">[0006]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0002" dnum="DE102009054758A1"><document-id><country>DE</country><doc-number>102009054758</doc-number><kind>A1</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0002">[0007]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0003" dnum="EP2429273A2"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2429273</doc-number><kind>A2</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0003">[0008]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0004" dnum="JPH08316662A"><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>H08316662</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0004">[0009]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0005" dnum="JP2014120677A"><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2014120677</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0005">[0010]</crossref></li>
</ul></p>
</ep-reference-list>
</ep-patent-document>
