<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP20185603A1" file="EP20185603NWA1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3889732" kind="A1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSKBAHRIS..MTNORSMESMMAKHTNMD..........</B001EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  1100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3889732</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT APPLICATION</B121></B120><B130>A1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>20185603.6</B210><B220><date>20200714</date></B220><B240><B241><date>20210825</date></B241></B240><B250>en</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B300><B310>PCT/KR2020/004594</B310><B320><date>20200403</date></B320><B330><ctry>WO</ctry></B330></B300><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B430></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>G06F   1/16        20060101AFI20210616BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="2"><text>H04M   1/02        20060101ALI20210616BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>H04M   1/0268      20130101 LI20210310BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>H04M   1/0237      20130101 LA20210412BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="3"><text>G06F   1/1656      20130101 LI20210611BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="4"><text>G06F   1/1624      20130101 FI20210310BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="5"><text>G06F   1/1652      20130101 LI20210310BHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>FLEXIBLE ANZEIGEVORRICHTUNG</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>FLEXIBLE DISPLAY DEVICE</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>AFFICHEUR SOUPLE</B542></B540><B590><B598>2B</B598></B590></B500><B700><B710><B711><snm>LG Electronics Inc.</snm><iid>101862914</iid><irf>AD2747 EP</irf><adr><str>128, Yeoui-daero 
Yeongdeungpo-gu</str><city>07336 SEOUL</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B711></B710><B720><B721><snm>CHOI, Hak-HO</snm><adr><str>19, Yangjae-daero 11-gil, Seocho-gu</str><city>06772 Seoul</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>SEOL, Seounghwan</snm><adr><str>19, Yangjae-daero 11-gil, Seocho-gu</str><city>06772 Seoul</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>KIM, Sung Do</snm><adr><str>19, Yangjae-daero 11-gil, Seocho-gu</str><city>06772 Seoul</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>YANG, Ji Woong</snm><adr><str>19, Yangjae-daero 11-gil, Seocho-gu</str><city>06772 Seoul</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>PARK, Sangwook</snm><adr><str>19, Yangjae-daero 11-gil, Seocho-gu</str><city>06772 Seoul</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>YOM, Jeeho</snm><adr><str>19, Yangjae-daero 11-gil, Seocho-gu</str><city>06772 Seoul</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B740><B741><snm>Vossius &amp; Partner 
Patentanwälte Rechtsanwälte mbB</snm><iid>100751388</iid><adr><str>Siebertstrasse 3</str><city>81675 München</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840><B844EP><B845EP><ctry>BA</ctry></B845EP><B845EP><ctry>ME</ctry></B845EP></B844EP><B848EP><B849EP><ctry>KH</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>MA</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>MD</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>TN</ctry></B849EP></B848EP></B800></SDOBI>
<abstract id="abst" lang="en">
<p id="pa01" num="0001">A flexible display device is disclosed. The flexible display device includes a first body, a second body, a flexible display, and a first cover. The second body performs reciprocating movement between a first position and a second position relative to the first body. The flexible display includes a first region, a first connected region, and a second connected region. When the second body is at the first position, the first cover covers the second connected region and forms a rear surface of the flexible display device. When switching between the first position and the second position is made, the user may hold the flexible display device in contact with the first region and the first cover.
<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="78" he="91" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p>
</abstract>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<heading id="h0001">BACKGROUND</heading>
<heading id="h0002">1. Technical Field</heading>
<p id="p0001" num="0001">The present disclosure relates to a device including a flexible display, and more particularly, a portable and variable-sized device.</p>
<heading id="h0003">2. Description of Related Art</heading>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">With the development of flexible displays that are bendable while displaying image information thereon, studies are being conducted and developments are being made regarding a foldable type device in which a flexible display is applied to a device having two bodies and folding structures (for example, hinge units). In such a device, since the flexible display may be entirely disposed on the two bodies via a folding structure, a large sized display may be implemented in the device.</p>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">As another device using a flexible display, a rollable device having a structure in which a display is rolled has been studied and developed. In such a device, as the flexible display is rolled, the total size or area of the display may be reduced. Conversely, as the flexible display is unrolled, the size or area of the display may be increased.</p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">As still another device using a flexible display, a device has been introduced in which, as the two bodies perform sliding movement relative to each other, the flexible display having a U-shape according to a curved middle part is modified such that an area of the display viewed from either side changes.</p>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">As one prior document using a flexible display in this regard, Korean Patent Registration No. <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="KR1107127"><text>1107127</text></patcit> (hereinafter referred to as 'Related Art') discloses a mobile terminal that includes a terminal body, a sliding member, a flexible display, and a rotation axis.</p>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">The mobile terminal according to the Related Art may be maintained in a relatively small size in a state in which the sliding member is not withdrawn from the terminal body,<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> but may form a display of a relatively large screen by being maintained in a relatively large size in a state in which the sliding member is withdrawn from the terminal body.</p>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">Smartphones, which constitute the majority of mobile phones, are configured to have various functions. For this, smartphones include, for example, various sensors including a touch sensor, and cameras. In recent years, various smartphones including a flexible display have also been introduced.</p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">The display may need to continue to be used even while a screen is extending. To this end, the flexible display should be able to display continuous visual information to the user. However, in the case of the mobile terminal according to the above-mentioned Related Art, the flexible display is modified by movement of a sliding member while the user holds the terminal body, that is, movement (and modification) of the flexible display relative to the terminal body is made. As a result, even if an image is displayed on the flexible display, since the image moves while being displayed, the concentration of the user may deteriorate, which may lead to the user not properly recognizing visual information.</p>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">Moreover, the touch sensor may need to be used even in a device in which the screen is extended, and in particular, the touch sensor may need to be operated while the screen is being extended. However, in the case of the mobile terminal according to the above-mentioned Related Art, the flexible display is modified by movement of a sliding member while the user holds the terminal body, that is, movement (and modification) of the flexible display relative to the terminal body is made. As a result, even if the touch sensor is formed on the flexible display, it will be impossible or very difficult to perform touch input while the flexible display is being modified.</p>
<heading id="h0004">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">The present disclosure is directed to providing a flexible display device configured such that when a flexible display is modified by moving two bodies relative to each other, a user can stably hold any one body of the flexible display device, and a part of the flexible display that is in front of the body held by the user can maintain a fixed state.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">The present disclosure is further directed to providing a flexible display device configured such that, in a device in which a flexible display is modified by moving two bodies relative to each other, since a part of the flexible display that is in front of the body held by the user does not perform relative movement while the flexible display is being modified, touch input can be performed.</p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">The present disclosure is still further directed to providing a flexible display device configured such that photographing by a camera can be performed stably while a flexible display is being modified by moving two bodies relative to each other</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">The present disclosure is still further directed to providing a flexible display device equipped with a means for preventing foreign matter from entering therein.</p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">The present disclosure is still further directed to providing a flexible display device that is easy to maintain in consideration of its characteristics as a variable device.</p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">A flexible display device according to an embodiment of the present disclosure is made to be carried and held by a user.</p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">The flexible display device includes a first body, a second body, a flexible display, and a first cover.</p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">The flexible display device may further include a second cover.</p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">The second body may be configured to move relative to the first body between a first position and a second position. The first position is a relative position of the second body relative to the first body, and the second position is also a relative position of the second body relative to the first body.</p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">When the second body is at the first position relative to the first body, the state of the flexible display device is referred to as a first state. Further, when the second body is at the second position relative to the first body, the state of the flexible display device is referred to as a second state. Accordingly, in the description of the present disclosure, "the first position" may be used in the same sense as "the first state of the flexible display device", and "the second position" may be used in the same sense as "the second state of the flexible display device".</p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">The second body is provided with a support.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">The flexible display may include a first region and a second region.</p>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">The second region may include a first connected region and a second connected region.</p>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">The first region may be positioned in front of the first body to face forward. The first region may form a front surface of the flexible display device.</p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">The first connected region extends from the first region.</p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">The second connected region extends from the first connected region.</p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">When the second body is at the first position, the first connected region may be curved around the support, and the second connected region may be parallel to the first region and be facing backward.</p>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">When the second body is at the second position, the first connected region may form the same plane with the first region, and a part of the second connected region may be curved around the support.</p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">The first cover is coupled to the back of the first body so as not to move relative to the first region, and covers the second connected region to form a rear surface of the flexible display device when the second body is at the first position.</p>
<p id="p0029" num="0029">An area of the first cover may be formed to be greater than or equal to that of the second connected region.</p>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">The second cover may be located in front of the first cover, and may be coupled to the back of the second body to cover the second connected region when the second body is at the first position. The second cover, with the first cover, may form a rear surface of the flexible display device.</p>
<p id="p0031" num="0031">When switching between the first position and the second position is made, the first and second covers may at least partially overlap each other.</p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032">The flexible display device may further include a filter.</p>
<p id="p0033" num="0033">The filter is disposed between the first cover and the second cover and configured to prevent intrusion of foreign matter between the first cover and the second cover. The filter may be made of at least one of a brush, a cloth, a non-woven fabric, a sponge, or paper, and may be formed to be coupled to one of the first cover or the second cover and to<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> contact the other one of the first cover or the second cover.</p>
<p id="p0034" num="0034">The first body may include a first edge portion that forms a first edge of the flexible display device and is in close contact with or adjacent to the first cover.</p>
<p id="p0035" num="0035">The second body may include a second edge portion that is disposed outside the support and forms a second edge of the flexible display device on the opposite side of the first edge portion.</p>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">When the second body is at the first position, the first cover may be in close contact with or adjacent to the second edge portion. When the second body is at the second position, the first cover is separated from the second edge portion.</p>
<p id="p0037" num="0037">At least a portion of the first cover may be made transparent. When the second body is at the first position, the second connected region may be visually seen at a back side of the flexible display device through the transparent first cover.</p>
<p id="p0038" num="0038">At least a portion of each of the first cover and the second cover may be made transparent. When the second body is at the first position, the second connected region may be visually seen at a back side of the flexible display device through the transparent first and second covers.</p>
<p id="p0039" num="0039">The transparent portions of the first and second covers may have different colors.</p>
<p id="p0040" num="0040">The first cover may be detachably coupled to the first body.</p>
<p id="p0041" num="0041">A first latching portion may be formed on an inner surface of the first cover.</p>
<p id="p0042" num="0042">The first body may include a movable rod, a second latching portion, and a first elastic body.</p>
<p id="p0043" num="0043">The movable rod may be configured to perform reciprocating movement in a direction parallel to the inner surface of the first cover.</p>
<p id="p0044" num="0044">The second latching portion may be formed on the movable rod to be caught on or released from the first latching portion depending on the movement of the movable rod.</p>
<p id="p0045" num="0045">The first elastic body may be configured to provide an elastic force to the movable rod such that the first latching portion and the second latching portion are caught on each other.</p>
<p id="p0046" num="0046">The first body may further include a pusher and a second elastic body.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p>
<p id="p0047" num="0047">The pusher is configured to move toward the inner surface of the first cover.</p>
<p id="p0048" num="0048">The second elastic body is configured to provide elastic force to the first cover away from the first body via a pusher.</p>
<p id="p0049" num="0049">The flexible display device may further include a touch panel, a first terminal, and a second terminal.</p>
<p id="p0050" num="0050">The touch panel may be coupled to the first cover along a surface of the first cover.</p>
<p id="p0051" num="0051">The first terminal may be coupled to the first body to be electrically connected to the flexible display.</p>
<p id="p0052" num="0052">The second terminal may be coupled to the inner surface of the first cover to be electrically connected to the touch panel, and may contact the first terminal upon coupling of the first cover and the first body.</p>
<p id="p0053" num="0053">The first cover may include a transparent region and a non-transparent region.</p>
<p id="p0054" num="0054">When the second body is at the first position, the transparent region may form a region corresponding to the second connected region on the first cover.</p>
<p id="p0055" num="0055">The non-transparent region may form a region other than the transparent region on the first cover.</p>
<p id="p0056" num="0056">The touch panel may be formed in the transparent region, and the second terminal may be formed in the non-transparent region.</p>
<p id="p0057" num="0057">The flexible display device may further include a camera.</p>
<p id="p0058" num="0058">The camera is mounted on a rear surface of the first body away from the support,</p>
<p id="p0059" num="0059">A camera hole may be formed in the first cover detachably coupled to the first body, and the camera may be mounted in the camera hole.</p>
<p id="p0060" num="0060">In the flexible display device according to the embodiments of the present disclosure, the first cover is coupled to the back of the first body so as not to move relative to the first region, and covers the second connected region to form a rear surface of the flexible display device when the second body is at the first position. When switching from the first position to the second position is made, the user may hold the flexible display device in contact with both the first cover forming the rear surface and the first region forming the front surface. Accordingly, when switching from the first position to the<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> second position is made, the user may stably hold the flexible display device, and continue to view the image information displayed on the first region at the same position.</p>
<p id="p0061" num="0061">In the flexible display device according to the embodiments of the present disclosure, when the second body is at the first position, the first region forms the front surface of the flexible display device and the first cover forms the rear surface of the flexible display device. Accordingly, when switching from the first position to the second position is made, the user may perform touch input through the first region while holding the first body to which the first cover and the first region are fixed.</p>
<p id="p0062" num="0062">In the flexible display device according to the embodiments of the present disclosure, the camera is fixed to the rear surface of the first body. When switching from the first position to the second position is made, since the user may hold the first body to which the first cover and the first region are fixed, and the camera fixed to the first body may face a subject from the same point and direction, photographing by the camera can be stably performed.</p>
<p id="p0063" num="0063">Since the flexible display device according to the embodiments of the present disclosure may include a filter, the entry of foreign matter into the flexible display device can be prevented.</p>
<p id="p0064" num="0064">The flexible display device according to the embodiments of the present disclosure is switched between the first position and the second position, and the first cover is detachably coupled to the first body. Accordingly, even when foreign matter such as dust enters the flexible display device, the foreign matter can be easily removed through separation of the first cover from the first body.</p>
<p id="p0065" num="0065">Since the flexible display device according to the embodiments of the present disclosure includes the first latching portion, the movable rod, the second latching portion, and the first elastic body, the first cover can be easily detached from the first body. In addition, since the flexible display device according to the embodiments of the present disclosure includes the pusher and the second elastic body, the first cover can be perfectly coupled to the second body so as not to be loosened.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></p>
<heading id="h0005">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p0066" num="0066">
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li><figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram for explaining a mobile terminal.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2A</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a first state of a flexible display device, and <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 2B</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a second state in which the flexible display device illustrated in <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2A</figref> is modified.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0004">FIG. 3A</figref> is a rear perspective view illustrating the flexible display device illustrated in <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2A</figref>, and <figref idref="f0005">FIG. 3B</figref> is a rear perspective view illustrating the flexible display device illustrated in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 2B</figref>.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0006">FIG. 4A</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a flexible display separated from the flexible display device in a first state, and <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 4B</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a modified state (the second state) of the flexible display illustrated <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 4A</figref>.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0007">FIG. 5A</figref> is a cross-sectional view taken along line A-A' of <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 3A</figref>, and schematically illustrates a flexible display device. <figref idref="f0007">FIG. 5B</figref> is a cross-sectional view taken along line B-B' of <figref idref="f0005">FIG. 3B</figref>, and schematically illustrates a flexible display device.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0007">FIG. 6A</figref> is a cross-sectional view illustrating a flexible display separated from the flexible display device illustrated in <figref idref="f0007">FIG. 5A</figref>, and <figref idref="f0008">FIG. 6B</figref> is a cross-sectional view illustrating the flexible display separated from the flexible display device illustrated in <figref idref="f0007">FIG. 5B</figref>.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0008">FIG. 7A</figref> is a cross-sectional view schematically illustrating a flexible display device. <figref idref="f0008">FIG. 7B</figref> is a cross-sectional view schematically illustrating a state in which the flexible display device illustrated in <figref idref="f0008">FIG. 7A</figref> is modified.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0009">FIG. 8</figref> is a cross-sectional view schematically illustrating a part of a flexible display device.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0010">FIG. 9</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a state in which a first cover and a second cover are separated from the flexible display device.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0011">FIG. 10A</figref> is a view illustrating an inner surface of a first cover, and <figref idref="f0012">FIG. 10B</figref> is a view illustrating a rear surface of a first body from which the first cover is separated.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0013">FIG. 11A</figref> is a view illustrating an inner surface of a first cover, and <figref idref="f0014">FIG. 11B</figref> is a view illustrating a rear surface of a first body from which the first cover is separated.<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></li>
<li><figref idref="f0015">FIG. 12A</figref> is a cross-sectional view schematically illustrating a state in which a first cover and a first body are separated from each other, and <figref idref="f0015">FIG. 12B</figref> is a cross-sectional view schematically illustrating a state in which the first cover and the first body are combined.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0016">FIG. 13A</figref> is a rear view schematically illustrating a flexible display device with a first cover and a second cover removed, and <figref idref="f0017">FIG. 13B</figref> is a rear view illustrating a state in which the flexible display device illustrated in <figref idref="f0016">FIG. 13A</figref> is modified. In <figref idref="f0016">FIG. 13A</figref>, a second body is represented by a dotted line.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0018">FIG. 14A</figref> is a rear view schematically illustrating a flexible display device with a first cover 215 and a second cover 225 removed, <figref idref="f0019">FIG. 14B</figref> is a cross-sectional view schematically illustrating a state in which a first body, a second body, and a third region are separated from each other, and <figref idref="f0019">FIG. 14C</figref> is a cross-sectional view schematically illustrating a state in which the first body, the second body, and the third region illustrated in <figref idref="f0019">FIG. 14B</figref> are combined.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0020">FIG. 15</figref> is an exploded perspective view illustrating a tension generator.</li>
</ul></p>
<heading id="h0006">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p0067" num="0067">Hereinafter, Hereinafter, exemplary embodiments disclosed herein will be described in detail with reference to the accompanying drawings, and like reference numerals designate like elements, and redundant description thereof will be omitted. Suffixes "module" and "unit or portion" for elements used in the following description are merely provided for facilitation of preparing this specification, and thus they are not granted a specific meaning or function. Wherever possible, the same reference numbers will be used throughout the drawings to refer to the same or like parts. In the following description, known functions or structures, which may confuse the substance of the present disclosure, are not explained. The accompanying drawings are used to help easily explain various technical features and it should be understood that the embodiments presented herein are not limited by the accompanying drawings. As such, the present disclosure should be construed to extend to any alterations, equivalents and substitutes in addition to<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> those which are particularly set out in the accompanying drawings.</p>
<p id="p0068" num="0068">Although the terms first, second, and the like, may be used herein to describe various elements, these elements should not be limited by these terms. These terms are generally only used to distinguish one element from another.</p>
<p id="p0069" num="0069">When an element or layer is referred to as being "on," "engaged to," "connected to," or "coupled to" another element or layer, it may be directly on, engaged, connected, or coupled to the other element or layer, or intervening elements or layers may be present. In contrast, when an element is referred to as being "directly on," "directly engaged to," "directly connected to," or "directly coupled to" another element or layer, there may be no intervening elements or layers present.</p>
<p id="p0070" num="0070">The singular expressions include plural expressions unless the context clearly dictates otherwise.</p>
<p id="p0071" num="0071">It should be understood that the terms "comprises," "comprising," "includes," "including," "containing," "has," "having" or any other variation thereof specify the presence of stated features, integers, steps, operations, elements, and/or components, but do not preclude the presence or addition of one or more other features, integers, steps, operations, elements, and/or components.</p>
<p id="p0072" num="0072">A flexible display device (hereinafter, referred to as a 'display device') described in the present specification may include a mobile terminal such as a portable phone, a smartphone, a laptop computer, a digital broadcasting terminal, a personal digital assistant (PDA), a portable multimedia player (PMP), a navigation, a slate PC, a tablet PC, an ultra-book, a wearable device, a smart watch, a smart glass, a head mounted display (HMD), and the like.</p>
<p id="p0073" num="0073">It will be apparent to those skilled in the art that the configuration according to the embodiment disclosed in the present specification may be applied to a fixed terminal such as a digital TV, a desktop computer, a digital signage except for an example that is applied only to a mobile terminal. Hereinafter, in the present disclosure, for the convenience of description, the mobile terminal will be first described as an example of the display device.</p>
<p id="p0074" num="0074"><figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram for explaining a mobile terminal 100 according to the<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p0075" num="0075">The mobile terminal 100 may include, for example, a wireless transceiver 110, an input interface 120, a sensor 140, an output interface 150, an interface 160, a memory 170, a controller 180, and a power supply 190. The components shown in <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> are not essential to implement the mobile terminal, and the mobile terminal described in the present disclosure may include more or fewer components than the components described above.</p>
<p id="p0076" num="0076">More specifically, the wireless transceiver 110 may include one or more modules that enable wireless communication between the mobile terminal 100 and a wireless communication system, between the mobile terminal 100 and another mobile terminal 100, or between the mobile terminal 100 and an external server. Further, the wireless transceiver 110 may include one or more modules that connect the mobile terminal 100 to one or more networks.</p>
<p id="p0077" num="0077">The wireless transceiver 110 may include at least one of a broadcast receiving module 111, a mobile communication module 112, a wireless internet module 113, a near field communication module 114, or a position information module 115.</p>
<p id="p0078" num="0078">The input interface 120 may include a camera 121 or an image input interface that inputs an image signal, a microphone 122 or an audio input interface that inputs an audio signal, and a user input interface 123 (for example, a touch key or a mechanical key) that receives information from a user. Voice data or image data collected by the input interface 120 may be analyzed and processed as a control command of the user.</p>
<p id="p0079" num="0079">The sensor 140 may include one or more sensors that sense at least one of information in the mobile terminal, surrounding environment information around the mobile terminal, or user information. For example, the sensor 140 may include at least one of a proximity sensor 141, an illumination sensor 142, a touch sensor, an acceleration sensor, a magnetic sensor, a G-sensor, a gyroscope sensor, a motion sensor, an RGB sensor, an infrared (IR) sensor, a finger scan sensor, an ultrasonic sensor, an optical sensor (for example, a camera 121), a microphone 122, a battery gauge, an environment sensor (for example, a barometer, a hygrometer, a thermometer, a radiation sensor, a thermal sensor, a<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> gas sensor, etc.), or a chemical sensor (for example, an electronic nose, a healthcare sensor, and a biometric sensor). Further, the mobile terminal disclosed in the present specification may combine and utilize information sensed by at least two sensors from the above-mentioned sensors.</p>
<p id="p0080" num="0080">The output interface 150 generates outputs related to visual, auditory, or tactile senses, and may include at least one of a display 151, a sound output interface 152, a haptic module 153, or an optical output interface 154. The display 151 forms a mutual layered structure with a touch sensor, or is formed integrally to be implemented as a touch screen. The touch screen simultaneously may serve as a user input interface 123 that provides an input interface between the mobile terminal 100 and the user while providing an output interface between the mobile terminal 100 and the user.</p>
<p id="p0081" num="0081">The interface 160 serves as a passage between the mobile terminal 100 and various types of external devices that are connected to the mobile terminal 100. The interface 160 may include at least one of a wired/wireless headset port, an external charger port, a wired/wireless data port, a memory card port, a port for connecting a device equipped with an identification module, an audio input/output (I/O) port, a video input/output (I/O) port, or an earphone port. As the external device is connected to the interface 160, the mobile terminal 100 may perform appropriate control on the connected external device.</p>
<p id="p0082" num="0082">Further, the memory 170 may store data that supports various functions of the mobile terminal 100. The memory 170 may store a plurality of application programs (or applications) driven in the mobile terminal, and data and commands for operations of the mobile terminal 100. At least some of the application programs may be downloaded from an external server through wireless communication. Further, at least some of the application programs for the basic functions of the mobile terminal 100 (for example, functions for receiving and making calls and receiving and sending messages) may be provided in the mobile terminal 100 from the time of manufacture. The application programs may be stored in the memory 170, and may be installed on the mobile terminal 100 so as to be driven by the controller 180 to perform operations (or functions) of the mobile terminal.<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></p>
<p id="p0083" num="0083">In addition to the operations related to the application programs, the controller 180 may generally control overall operation of the mobile terminal 100. The controller 180 may process a signal, data, or information that is inputted or outputted through the above-described components or drive the application programs stored in the memory 170 to provide or process appropriate information or functions to the user.</p>
<p id="p0084" num="0084">Further, in order to drive the application programs stored in the memory 170, the controller 180 may control at least some of components described with reference to <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>. Moreover, the controller 180 may combine and operate at least two of components included in the mobile terminal 100 to drive the application programs.</p>
<p id="p0085" num="0085">Under the control of the controller 180, the power supply 190 may be supplied with external power or internal power, and supply power to each component included in the mobile terminal 100. The power supply 190 includes a battery, which may be a built-in battery or a replaceable battery.</p>
<p id="p0086" num="0086">At least some of the above-described components may operate in cooperation with each other to implement the operation, the control, or the control method of the mobile terminal according to various embodiments which will be described below. Further, the operation, the control, or the control method of the mobile terminal may be implemented on the mobile terminal by driving at least one application program stored in the memory 170.</p>
<p id="p0087" num="0087">Hereinafter, prior to describing various embodiments implemented by the mobile terminal 100 described above, the above-mentioned components will be described in more detail with reference to <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0088" num="0088">The broadcast receiving module 111 of the wireless transceiver 110 receives a broadcast signal and/or broadcast-related information from an external broadcast management server through a broadcast channel. The broadcast channel may include a satellite channel and a ground wave channel. Two or more broadcast receiving modules for simultaneous broadcast reception or broadcast channel switching for at least two broadcast channels may be provided to the mobile terminal 100.</p>
<p id="p0089" num="0089">The broadcast management sever may refer to a server that generates and<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> transmits a broadcast signal and/or broadcast-related information or a server that is supplied with the previously generated broadcast signal and/or broadcast-related information to transmit the broadcast signal and/or the broadcast-related information to the terminal. The broadcast signal may include not only a TV broadcast signal, a radio broadcast signal, and a data broadcast signal, but also a broadcast signal obtained by combining the TV broadcast signal or the radio broadcast signal with the data broadcast signal.</p>
<p id="p0090" num="0090">The broadcast signal may be encoded according to at least one of technical standards (or broadcast schemes, for example, ISO, IEC, DVB, or ATSC) for transmitting and receiving a digital broadcast signal, and the broadcast receiving module 111 may receive the digital broadcast signal using an appropriate method for the technical specification defined by the technical standards.</p>
<p id="p0091" num="0091">The broadcast-related information may refer to information related to a broadcast channel, a broadcast program, or a broadcast service provider. The broadcast-related information may also be provided over the mobile communication network. In this case, the broadcast-related information may be received by the mobile communication module 112.</p>
<p id="p0092" num="0092">The broadcast-related information may exist in various types, such as an electronic program guide (EPG) of a digital multimedia broadcast (DMB) or an electronic service guide (ESG) of a digital video broadcast-handheld (DVB-H). The broadcast signal and/or the broadcast-related information received by the broadcast receiving module 111 may be stored in the memory 170.</p>
<p id="p0093" num="0093">The mobile communication module 112 may transmit/receive a wireless signal to/from at least one of a base station, an external terminal, or a server over a mobile communication network established according to the technical standards or communication methods for mobile communication (for example, Global System for Mobile communication (GSM), Code Division Multi Access (CDMA), Code Division Multi Access 2000 (CDMA2000), Enhanced Voice-Data Optimized or Enhanced Voice-Data Only (EV-DO), Wideband CDMA (WCDMA), High Speed Downlink Packet Access<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> (HSDPA), High Speed Uplink Packet Access (HSUPA), Long Term Evolution (LTE), and Long Term Evolution-Advanced (LTE-A).)</p>
<p id="p0094" num="0094">The wireless signal may include a voice call signal, a video call signal, or various types of data in accordance with transmission or reception of a text/multimedia message.</p>
<p id="p0095" num="0095">The wireless internet module 113 refers to a module for wireless internet connection, and may be embodied in the mobile terminal 100 or installed at the outside of the mobile terminal 100. The wireless internet module 113 may be configured to transmit/receive a wireless signal over a communication network according to wireless internet technologies.</p>
<p id="p0096" num="0096">The wireless internet technologies include, for example, wireless LAN (WLAN), wireless fidelity (Wi-Fi), Wi-Fi direct, digital living network alliance (DLNA), wireless broadband (WiBro), world interoperability for microwave access (WiMAX), high speed downlink packet access (HSDPA), high speed uplink packet access (HSUPA), long term evolution (LTE), and long term evolution-advanced (LTE-A). The wireless internet module 113 may transmit or receive data in accordance with at least one wireless internet technology within a range including internet technology that have not been described above.</p>
<p id="p0097" num="0097">From the viewpoint that the wireless internet connection through, for example, WiBro, HSDPA, HSUPA, GSM, CDMA, WCDMA, LTE, and LTE-A is performed over the mobile communication network, the wireless internet module 113 that performs the wireless internet connection over the mobile communication network may be understood as a type of the mobile communication module 112.</p>
<p id="p0098" num="0098">The near field communication module 114 is for short range communication, and may support the short range communication using at least one of Bluetooth™, radio frequency identification (RFID), infrared data association (IrDA), ultra-wideband (UWB), ZigBee, Near Field Communication (NFC), wireless fidelity (Wi-Fi), Wi-Fi Direct, or Wireless Universal Serial Bus (Wireless USB). The near field communication module 114 may support wireless communication between the mobile terminal 100 and the wireless communication system, between the mobile terminal 100 and the other mobile terminal<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> 100, or between the mobile terminal 100 and a network in which the other mobile terminal 100 (or external server) is located, over the wireless local area network. The wireless local area network may be a wireless personal area network.</p>
<p id="p0099" num="0099">Here, the other mobile terminal 100 may be a wearable device (for example, a smart watch, a smart glass, or a head mounted display (HMD)) that is capable of exchanging data (or interworking) with the mobile terminal 100 according to the present disclosure. The near field communication module 114 may detect (or recognize) the wearable device that is capable of communicating with the mobile terminal 100, in the vicinity of the mobile terminal 100. Moreover, when the detected wearable device is authenticated to communicate with the mobile terminal 100 according to the present disclosure, the controller 180 may transmit at least a portion of data processed in the mobile terminal 100 to the wearable device through the near field communication module 114. Therefore, the user of the wearable device may use the data processed in the mobile terminal 100, through the wearable device. For example, according to this, when a phone call is received by the mobile terminal 100, the user may make a phone call through the wearable device, or when a message is received by the mobile terminal 100, the user may check the received message through the wearable device.</p>
<p id="p0100" num="0100">The position information module 115 is a module for obtaining a position (or a current position) of a mobile terminal, and its representative examples include a global positioning system (GPS) module or a wireless fidelity (Wi-Fi) module. For example, when the GPS module is utilized, the mobile terminal may obtain the position of the mobile terminal using a signal transmitted from the GPS satellite. As another example, when the Wi-Fi module is utilized, the mobile terminal may obtain the position of the mobile terminal based on information on a wireless access point (AP) that transmits and receives wireless signals with the Wi-Fi module. If necessary, the position information module 115 may alternatively or additionally perform a function of another module of the wireless transceiver 110 to obtain data on the position of the mobile terminal. The position information module 115 is a module used to obtain the position (or the current position) of the mobile terminal, and is not limited to a module that directly calculates or obtains the<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> position of the mobile terminal.</p>
<p id="p0101" num="0101">Next, the input interface 120 is for inputting video information (or signal), audio information (or signal), data, or information inputted by the user, and the mobile terminal 100 may include one or a plurality of cameras 121 to input the video information. The camera 121 processes an image frame such as a still or moving image obtained by an image sensor in a video call mode or a photographing mode. The processed image frame may be displayed on the display 151 or stored in the memory 170. Further, the plurality of cameras 121 included in the mobile terminal 100 may be arranged to form a matrix structure, and a plurality of pieces of image information having various angles or focal points may be inputted to the mobile terminal 100 through the cameras 121 that form the matrix structure. Further, the plurality of cameras 121 may be arranged to form a stereo structure to obtain left and right images used to implement a stereoscopic image.</p>
<p id="p0102" num="0102">The microphone 122 processes an external sound signal as electrical speech data. The processed voice data may be utilized in various manners in accordance with the function (or an application program that is being executed) that is being performed by the mobile terminal 100. Various noise removal algorithms for removing noise generated during the process of receiving the external sound signal may be implemented in the microphone 122.</p>
<p id="p0103" num="0103">The user input interface 123 is for receiving information from the user, and when the information is inputted through the user input interface 123, the controller 180 may control the operation of the mobile terminal 100 so as to correspond to the inputted information. The user input interface 123 may include a mechanical input interface (or a mechanical key, for example, a button located on a front, rear, or side surface of the mobile terminal 100, a dome switch, a jog wheel, a jog switch, etc.) and a touch type input interface. For example, the touch type input interface may be formed as a virtual key, a soft key, or a visual key that is displayed on the touch screen through a software process, or a touch key that is disposed on a part other than the touch screen. The virtual key or visual key may be displayed on the touch screen in various shapes, and, for example, may be formed as graphics, text, icons, video, or a combination thereof.<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></p>
<p id="p0104" num="0104">The sensor 140 senses at least one of information in the mobile terminal, surrounding environment information around the mobile terminal, or user information, and generates a sensing signal corresponding to the information. The controller 180 may control the driving or the operation of the mobile terminal 100 or perform data processing, functions, or operations related to the application program installed in the mobile terminal 100, based on the sensing signal. Representative sensors among various sensors that may be included in the sensor 140 will be described in more detail below.</p>
<p id="p0105" num="0105">First, the proximity sensor 141 refers to a sensor that senses the presence of an object approaching a predetermined sensing surface or nearby objects, using an electromagnetic field force or infrared ray without any mechanical contact. The proximity sensor 141 may be disposed in an internal area of the mobile terminal that is enclosed by the above-described touch screen or in the vicinity of the touch screen.</p>
<p id="p0106" num="0106">Examples of the proximity sensor 141 may include, for example, a transmission type photoelectric sensor, a direct reflection type photoelectric sensor, a mirror reflection type photoelectric sensor, a high frequency oscillation type proximity sensor, a capacitive proximity sensor, a magnetic proximity sensor, and an infrared proximity sensor. When the touch screen is a capacitive type, the proximity sensor 141 may be configured to detect the proximity of an object with a change in the electric field in accordance with the proximity of the object having conductivity. In this case, the touch screen (or the touch sensor) itself may be classified as a proximity sensor.</p>
<p id="p0107" num="0107">For convenience of description, when the object approaches the touch screen without contacting the touch screen, and it is recognized that the object is located over the touch screen, it is referred to as a "proximity touch". When the object actually touches the touch screen, it is referred to as a "contact touch". A position at which the object proximately touches the touch screen refers to a position at which the object vertically corresponds to the touch screen when the object proximately touches the touch screen. The proximity sensor 141 may sense the proximity touch and a proximity touch pattern (for example, a proximate touch distance, a proximate touch direction, a proximate touch speed, a proximate touch time, a proximate touch position, and a proximate touch movement<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> state). As described above, the controller 180 may process data (or information) corresponding to the proximate touch operation and the proximate touch pattern sensed by the proximity sensor 141, and may further display visual information corresponding to the processed data on the touch screen. Furthermore, the controller 180 may control the mobile terminal 100 to process different operations or data (or information) depending on whether the touch on the same point on the touch screen is the proximity touch or the contact touch.</p>
<p id="p0108" num="0108">The touch sensor senses a touch (or a touch input) applied to the touch screen (or the display 151) using at least one of various touch types such as a resistive film type, a capacitive type, an infrared type, an ultrasonic type, and a magnetic field type.</p>
<p id="p0109" num="0109">For example, the touch sensor may be configured to convert a change in a pressure applied to a specific portion of the touch screen, or a capacitance generated in a specific portion, into an electrical input signal. The touch sensor may be configured to detect a position and area where a touch subject that applies a touch onto the touch screen is touched on the touch sensor, and a pressure and capacitance at the time of the touch. Here, the touch subject is an object that applies a touch to the touch sensor, and may include, for example, a finger, a touch pen, a stylus pen, and a pointer.</p>
<p id="p0110" num="0110">As described above, when there is the touch input to the touch sensor, corresponding signal(s) is transmitted to a touch controller. The touch controller processes the signal(s) and then transmits corresponding data to the controller 180. By doing this, the controller 180 may confirm which area of the display 151 is touched. Here, the touch controller may be a separate component from the controller 180, or may be the controller 180 itself.</p>
<p id="p0111" num="0111">The controller 180 may perform different control or the same control depending on a type of a touch subject that touches the touch screen (or a touch key provided other than the touch screen). Whether to perform the different or the same control depending on the type of touch subject may be determined in accordance with an operating state of the current mobile terminal 100 or an application program that is being executed.</p>
<p id="p0112" num="0112">The touch sensor and the proximity sensor that are described above may, independently or in combination, sense various types of touches on the touch screen, such<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> as a short (or tap) touch, a long touch, a multi touch, a drag touch, a flick touch, a pinch-in touch, a pinch-out touch, a swipe touch, or a hovering touch.</p>
<p id="p0113" num="0113">The ultrasonic sensor may recognize position information on a sensing object using an ultrasonic wave. The controller 180 may calculate a position of a wave generating source by using information sensed by the optical sensor and the plurality of ultrasonic sensors. The position of the wave generating source may be calculated using the property that light is much faster than the ultrasonic wave, that is, the time in which light reaches the optical sensor is much faster than the time in which the ultrasonic wave reaches the ultrasonic sensor. More specifically, the position of the wave generating source may be calculated using a time difference of the time of arrival of the ultrasonic wave with respect to light that serves as a reference signal.</p>
<p id="p0114" num="0114">As seen from the configuration of the input interface 120, the camera 121 includes at least one of a camera sensor (for example, a CCD and a CMOS), a photo sensor (or an image sensor), or a laser sensor.</p>
<p id="p0115" num="0115">The camera 121 and the laser sensor may be combined to sense a touch of a sensing object for a three-dimensional stereoscopic image. The photo sensor, which may be stacked on a display element, is configured to scan a motion of the sensing object proximate to the touch screen. More specifically, the photo sensor includes photo diodes and transistors (TR) in rows/columns so as to scan contents disposed on the photo sensor by using an electrical signal that changes in accordance with an amount of light applied to the photo diode. That is, the photo sensor calculates coordinates of the sensing object in accordance with a changed amount of light, and position information on the sensing object may be obtained through the coordinates.</p>
<p id="p0116" num="0116">The display 151 displays (outputs) information processed in the mobile terminal 100. For example, the display 151 may display execution screen information on an application program driven in the mobile terminal 100 and user interface (UI), or graphic user interface (GUI) information in accordance with the execution screen information.</p>
<p id="p0117" num="0117">Further, the display 151 may be configured as a stereoscopic display that displays a stereoscopic image.<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --></p>
<p id="p0118" num="0118">A three-dimensional display type such as a stereoscopic type (a glass type), an autostereoscopic type (a glass-free type), and a projection type (a holographic type) may be applied to the stereoscopic display.</p>
<p id="p0119" num="0119">The sound output interface 152 may output audio data received from the wireless transceiver 110 or stored in the memory 170 in, for example, a call signal reception mode, a phone-call mode, a recording mode, a voice recognition mode, and a broadcasting reception mode. The sound output interface 152 may also output a sound signal (for example, a call signal reception sound and a message reception sound) related to a function performed in the mobile terminal 100. Such a sound output interface 152 may include, for example, a receiver, a speaker, and a buzzer.</p>
<p id="p0120" num="0120">The haptic module 153 may generate various tactile effects that the user may feel. A representative example of the tactile effect generated by the haptic module 153 may be vibration. For example, an intensity and pattern of the vibration generated in the haptic module 153 may be controlled by the selection of the user or a setting of the controller 180. For example, the haptic module 153 may compose different vibrations to output the composed vibrations, or sequentially output the different vibrations.</p>
<p id="p0121" num="0121">In addition to the vibration, the haptic module 153 may generate various tactile effects, such as effects by, for example, a pin arrangement that vertically moves to a contact skin surface, an injection force or a suction force of air through an injection port or a suction port, grazing on a skin surface, electrode contact, and stimulation of an electrostatic force or effects of reproducing a cold or hot sensation using a heat absorbing or heat emitting element.</p>
<p id="p0122" num="0122">The haptic module 153 may not only transmit a tactile effect by means of direct contact, but may also be implemented to allow the user to feel a tactile effect by muscular sensation of a finger or an arm. Two or more haptic modules 153 may be provided in accordance with a configuration aspect of the mobile terminal 100.</p>
<p id="p0123" num="0123">The optical output interface 154 outputs a signal for notifying occurrence of an event by using light from a light source of the mobile terminal 100. Examples of events generated in the mobile terminal 100 may include message reception, call signal reception,<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> missed call, alarm, schedule notification, email reception, and information reception through an application.</p>
<p id="p0124" num="0124">The signal outputted from the optical output interface 154 is implemented as the mobile terminal emits single color or a plurality of color light on a front surface or a rear surface. When the mobile terminal senses the event confirmation of the user, the signal output may be completed.</p>
<p id="p0125" num="0125">The interface 160 serves as a passage with all external devices that are connected to the mobile terminal 100. The interface 160 receives data from the external device or is supplied with power from the external device to supply power to each component in the mobile terminal 100, or transmits data in the mobile terminal 100 to the external device. For example, the interface 160 may include, for example, a wired/wireless headset port, an external charger port, a wired/wireless data port, a memory card port, a port that connects a device equipped with an identification module, an audio input/output (I/O) port, a video input/output (I/O) port, and an earphone port.</p>
<p id="p0126" num="0126">The identification module is a chip in which various pieces of information for authenticating a usage right of the mobile terminal 100 is stored, and may include, for example, a user identity module (UIM), a subscriber identity module (SIM), and a universal subscriber identity module (USIM). A device (hereinafter, referred to as "identification device") equipped with the identification module may be manufactured as a smart card. Therefore, the identification device may be connected to the terminal 100 through the interface 160.</p>
<p id="p0127" num="0127">When the mobile terminal 100 is connected to an external cradle, the interface 160 may serve as a passage through which power is supplied from the cradle to the mobile terminal 100 or a passage through which various command signals inputted to the cradle by a user are transmitted to the mobile terminal 100. Various command signals or power inputted from the cradle may operate a signal for recognizing that the mobile terminal 100 is precisely mounted in the cradle.</p>
<p id="p0128" num="0128">The memory 170 may store a program for an operation of the controller 180, or temporarily store inputted/outputted data (for example, a phone book, a message, a still<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> image, and a moving image). The memory 170 may store data related to vibrations or sounds of various patterns outputted when the touch is inputted onto the touch screen.</p>
<p id="p0129" num="0129">The memory 170 may include at least one type of storage medium of a flash memory type, a hard disk type, a solid state disk (SSD) type, a silicon disk drive (SDD) type, a multimedia card micro type, and card type memories (for example, SD or XD memory), a random access memory (RAM), a static random access memory (SRAM), a read-only memory (ROM), an electrically erasable programmable read-only memory (EEPROM), a programmable read only memory (PROM), a magnetic memory, a magnetic disk, or an optical disk. The mobile terminal 100 may operate in association with a web storage that performs a storage function of the memory 170 on the Internet.</p>
<p id="p0130" num="0130">As described above, the controller 180 may control an operation related to the application program and an overall operation of the mobile terminal 100. For example, when the state of the mobile terminal satisfies a predetermined condition, the controller 180 may execute or release a locking state that restricts an input of a control command of a user regarding the applications.</p>
<p id="p0131" num="0131">Further, the controller 180 may perform control and processing related to, for example, voice call, data communication, and video call, or may perform a pattern recognition process that may recognize a handwriting input or a picture drawing input performed on the touch screen as a text or an image, respectively. Moreover, the controller 180 may control any one or a combination of a plurality of components described above to implement various embodiments which will be described below, in the mobile terminal 100 according to the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p0132" num="0132">Under the control of the controller 180, the power supply 190 is supplied with an external power or an internal power, and supplies power required for operating the components. The power supply 190 includes a battery, and the battery may be a chargeable embedded battery and be detachably coupled to a terminal body to be charged.</p>
<p id="p0133" num="0133">Further, the power supply 190 may include a connection port, and the connection port may be configured as one example of an interface 160 to which an external charger which supplies power to charge a battery is electrically connected.<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --></p>
<p id="p0134" num="0134">As another example, the power supply 190 may be configured to wirelessly charge the battery without using the connection port. In this case, the power supply 190 may receive power from an external wireless power transmission device by using one or more of an inductive coupling scheme based on a self-induction phenomenon or a magnetic resonance coupling scheme based on an electromagnetic resonance phenomenon.</p>
<p id="p0135" num="0135">Various embodiments below may be implemented in a recording medium readable by a computer or a similar device using hardware, software, or a combination thereof, for example.</p>
<p id="p0136" num="0136">The display 151 displays (outputs) information processed in the mobile terminal 100. For example, the display 151 may display execution screen information on an application program driven in the mobile terminal 100 and user interface (UI), or graphic user interface (GUI) information in accordance with the execution screen information.</p>
<p id="p0137" num="0137">The display 151 may include at least one of a liquid crystal display (LCD), a thin film transistor liquid crystal display (TFT LCD), an organic light emitting diode (OLED), a flexible display, a three-dimensional display (3D display), or an electronic ink display (e-ink display).</p>
<p id="p0138" num="0138">Further, two or more displays 151 may be provided in accordance with an implementation type of the mobile terminal 100. In this case, a plurality of displays may be disposed to be spaced apart from each other or integrally disposed on one surface of the mobile terminal 100 or may be disposed on different surfaces.</p>
<p id="p0139" num="0139">The display 151 may include a touch sensor that senses a touch on the display 151 so as to receive the control command by the touch method. Therefore, when the touch is made on the display 151, the touch sensor senses the touch, and based on the touch, the controller 180 may generate a control command corresponding to the touch. Contents inputted by the touch method may be, for example, letters or numbers, or instructions or designated menu items in various modes.</p>
<p id="p0140" num="0140">The microphone 122 is configured to receive a voice of the user, or other sounds. The microphone 122 may be provided in a plurality of locations to receive stereo sounds.</p>
<p id="p0141" num="0141">The interface 160 serves as a passage through which the mobile terminal 100 is<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> connected to the external device. For example, the interface 160 may be at least one of a connection terminal for connection with other devices (for example, an earphone or an external speaker), a port for near field communication (for example, an infrared port (IrDA port), a Bluetooth port, and a wireless LAN port) or a power supply terminal for supplying power to the mobile terminal 100. The interface 160 may be implemented as a socket type which accommodates an external card, such as a subscriber identity module (SIM), a user identity module (UIM), and a memory card for information storage.</p>
<p id="p0142" num="0142">At least one antenna for wireless communication may be provided in a terminal body. The antenna may be embedded in the terminal body or formed in a case. For example, the antenna which forms a part of the broadcast receiving module 111 (see <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>) may be configured to be withdrawn from the terminal body. Alternatively, the antenna may be formed to be a film type to be attached onto an inner surface of a housing, or a case including a conductive material may serve as an antenna.</p>
<p id="p0143" num="0143">The terminal body includes the power supply 190 (see <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>) which supplies power to the mobile terminal 100. The power supply 190 may be embedded in the terminal body, or may include a battery 191 which is configured to be detachable at the outside of the terminal body.</p>
<p id="p0144" num="0144">The battery 191 may be configured to be supplied with power through a power cable connected to the interface 160. Further, the battery 191 may be configured to be wirelessly chargeable by a wireless charging device. The wireless charging may be implemented by a self-induction scheme or a resonance scheme (magnetic resonance scheme).</p>
<p id="p0145" num="0145">An accessory which protects an outer appearance of the mobile terminal 100 or supports or extends the function thereof may be added to the mobile terminal 100. An example of the accessory may include a cover or a pouch which covers at least one surface of the mobile terminal 100 or accommodates the mobile terminal 100. The cover or the pouch may interwork with the display 151 to extend the function of the mobile terminal 100. Another example of the accessory may include a touch pen which supports or extends a touch input on the touch screen.<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --></p>
<p id="p0146" num="0146"><figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2A</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a first state of a flexible display device 1, and <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 2B</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a second state in which the flexible display device illustrated in <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2A</figref> is modified.</p>
<p id="p0147" num="0147"><figref idref="f0004">FIG. 3A</figref> is a rear perspective view illustrating the flexible display device 1 illustrated in <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2A</figref>, and <figref idref="f0005">FIG. 3B</figref> is a rear perspective view illustrating the flexible display device 1 illustrated in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 2B</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0148" num="0148">The flexible display device 1 may include a body 200, a flexible display 300, and a first cover 215. The flexible display device 1 may further include a second cover 225. The body 200 may include a first body 210, a second body 220, and a support 230.</p>
<p id="p0149" num="0149">In describing embodiments of the present disclosure, a first direction (X direction), a second direction (Y direction), and a third direction (Z direction) shown in the drawings are directions perpendicular to each other.</p>
<p id="p0150" num="0150">The flexible display device 1 may include two surfaces 1a and 1b which are opposite to each other. The flexible display device 1 may include a first surface 1a and a second surface 1b. The facing direction of the first surface 1a (direction perpendicular to or substantially perpendicular to the first surface 1a) is opposite to the facing direction of the second surface 1b (direction perpendicular to or substantially perpendicular to the second surface 1b). The flexible display device 1 may be disposed such that the first surface 1a faces the third direction (Z direction) while the second surface 1b faces the direction opposite to the third direction (Z direction). When the first surface 1a corresponds to a front surface of the flexible display device 1, the second surface 1b may correspond to a rear surface of the flexible display device 1.</p>
<p id="p0151" num="0151">Hereinafter, unless otherwise specified, a front direction of the flexible display device 1 is referred to as the third direction (Z direction), and a rear direction of the flexible display device 1 refers to the direction opposite to the third direction (Z direction).</p>
<p id="p0152" num="0152">The body 200 may form the overall shape of the flexible display device 1. The body 200 may form a frame of the flexible display device 1. The body 200 may be made of a relatively hard material, for example, plastic, carbon, metal, or a combination thereof. Other components constituting the flexible display device 1 may be coupled to the body<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --> 200.</p>
<p id="p0153" num="0153">The body 200 may be formed in various shapes to support other components coupled thereto.</p>
<p id="p0154" num="0154">The body 200 may be flat overall, or may be curved like a curved surface. The interior of the body 200 may be completely filled, or a part thereof may not be filled.</p>
<p id="p0155" num="0155">For example, when viewed from the front (Z direction), the body 200 may be formed in a quadrangular shape overall, and may be flat overall.</p>
<p id="p0156" num="0156">The body 200 may be divided into two or more parts. The body 200 may include a first body 210 and a second body 220, and the first body 210 and the second body 220 may move relative to each other (See <figref idref="f0002">FIGS. 2A</figref>, <figref idref="f0003">2B</figref>, <figref idref="f0004">3A</figref>, and <figref idref="f0005">3B</figref>).</p>
<p id="p0157" num="0157">The second body 220 may perform sliding movement and reciprocating movement relative to the first body 210. Accordingly, when viewed from the front (Z direction), the total area occupied by the body 200 may change.</p>
<p id="p0158" num="0158">The second body 220 may perform reciprocating movement relative to the first body 210 between a first position and a second position.</p>
<p id="p0159" num="0159">When viewed from the front (Z direction), when the second body 220 is at the first position, the total area occupied by the body 200 (the area of the body 200 projected in the Z direction) may be the smallest (see, for example, <figref idref="f0002">FIGS. 2A</figref> and <figref idref="f0004">3A</figref>), and when the second body 220 is at the second position, the total area occupied by the body 200 (the area of the body 200 projected in the Z direction) may be the largest (see, for example, <figref idref="f0003">FIGS. 2B</figref> and <figref idref="f0005">3B</figref>).</p>
<p id="p0160" num="0160">When viewed from the front (Z direction), when the second body 220 is at the first position, the overlapping area of the first body 210 and the second body 220 may be the largest (see, for example, <figref idref="f0002">FIGS. 2A</figref> and <figref idref="f0004">3A</figref>), and when the second body 220 is at the second position, the overlapping area between the first body 210 and the second body 220 may be the smallest (see, for example, <figref idref="f0003">FIGS. 2B</figref> and <figref idref="f0005">3B</figref>).</p>
<p id="p0161" num="0161">A movement direction of the second body relative to the first body may be parallel to the first direction (X direction).</p>
<p id="p0162" num="0162">The first body 210 may have a predetermined length in the first direction (X<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --> direction), and may also have a predetermined length in the second direction (Y direction) orthogonal to the first direction. The first body 210 may have a predetermined length in the third direction (Z direction) orthogonal to the first and second directions, but the length of first body 210 in the third direction may be sufficiently smaller than the length thereof in the first and second directions. Accordingly, the first body 210 may be flat or substantially flat in the first and second directions.</p>
<p id="p0163" num="0163">The first body 210 may be formed in the shape of a plate.</p>
<p id="p0164" num="0164">The second body 220 may have a predetermined length in the first and second directions. The second body 220 may have a predetermined length in the third direction, but the length of the second body 220 in the third direction may be sufficiently smaller than the length thereof in the first and second directions. Accordingly, the second body 220 may be flat or substantially flat in the first and second directions.</p>
<p id="p0165" num="0165">The second body 220 may be formed in the shape of a plate.</p>
<p id="p0166" num="0166">The first body 210 and the second body 220 may be formed in the shape of plates that are parallel to each other.</p>
<p id="p0167" num="0167">The support 230 may be coupled to, formed on, or fixed to the second body 220. The support 230, together with the second body 220, may move relative to the first body 210.</p>
<p id="p0168" num="0168">The support 230 may be provided inside the flexible display device 1.</p>
<p id="p0169" num="0169">The support may cause the flexible display 300 to be curved to change direction. That is, the flexible display 300 formed in the first direction may be curved to form a curved surface on the support 230, and may extend in the direction opposite to the first direction while passing the support 230.</p>
<p id="p0170" num="0170">The support 230 may form a U- or C-shaped path through which the flexible display 300 moves, or may support an inner surface of the flexible display 300.</p>
<p id="p0171" num="0171">When supporting the inner surface of the flexible display 300, the support 230 may extend in the second direction (Y direction).</p>
<p id="p0172" num="0172">At least a portion of the support 230 may have a uniform cross-section in the second direction (Y direction). The outer circumferential surface of the support 230 that<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --> meets or contacts the flexible display 300 may form a curved surface, and the cross-section of the support 230 may be formed in, for example, a circular or semi-circular shape.</p>
<p id="p0173" num="0173">In an embodiment, the support 230 may be formed in a cylindrical shape having a uniform cross-section in the second direction (Y direction). In addition, the support 230 may be formed in the shape of a roller which is capable of rotating in both directions about the central axis 231 parallel to the second direction. That is, the support 230 may be coupled to the second body 220 in a state in which the support 230 is capable of rotating by using the central axis 231 as a rotation axis (see <figref idref="f0017">FIG. 13B</figref>).</p>
<p id="p0174" num="0174"><figref idref="f0006">FIG. 4A</figref> is a perspective view illustrating the flexible display 300 separated from the flexible display device 1 in the first state, and <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 4B</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a modified state (second state) of the flexible display 300 illustrated in <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 4A</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0175" num="0175"><figref idref="f0006">FIG. 4A</figref> may illustrate the state in which the second body 220 is at the above-described first position relative to the first body 210, and <figref idref="f0006">FIGS. 4B and 4C</figref> may illustrate the state in which the second body 220 is at the above-described second position relative to the first body 210, respectively.</p>
<p id="p0176" num="0176">The flexible display 300 may be configured like the display 151 described above.</p>
<p id="p0177" num="0177">The flexible display 300 may be formed in the shape of a thin film, and may have an outer surface and an inner surface. The outer surface of the flexible display 300 is a surface facing the outside of the flexible display device 1, and the inner surface thereof is a surface facing the inside of the flexible display device 1. An image may be displayed on at least a portion of the outer surface of the flexible display 300.</p>
<p id="p0178" num="0178">Since at least a portion of the flexible display 300 may be formed to be curved, when the second body 220 moves relative to the first body 210, the flexible display 300 may change in shape. When switching from the first position to the second position is made, the middle part of the flexible display 300 is curved around the support 230, and the flexible display 300 changes in shape by being pushed by the support 230.</p>
<p id="p0179" num="0179">The flexible display 300 may include a first region 310 and a second region 320 that are coupled to each other.</p>
<p id="p0180" num="0180">The flexible display 300 may include a first region 310, a second region 320, and a<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --> third region 330 that are sequentially connected to each other.</p>
<p id="p0181" num="0181">When the flexible display 300 is not coupled to the body 200 and is extended to be flat overall, the first region 310, the second region 320, and the third region 330 may all form the same plane.</p>
<p id="p0182" num="0182">In <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 2B</figref>, the dotted line b1 is an imaginary line indicating the boundary between the first region 310 and the second region 320 (a first connected region 321).</p>
<p id="p0183" num="0183">The first region 310 may have a predetermined area, and may be coupled to the body 200 at either side of the body 200. The first region 310 may be coupled to the first body 210, or may be fixed to the first body 210. That is, the first region 310 may not move relative to the first body 210.</p>
<p id="p0184" num="0184">The first region 310 may be parallel to the first and second directions. The first region 310 may be fixed in front of the first body 210. The first region 310 may be fixed in front of the first body 210 based on the third direction. The first region 310 and the first body 210 may be parallel to each other.</p>
<p id="p0185" num="0185">In an embodiment of the present disclosure, the first region 310 may form a curved surface overall. In this case, the curvature of the first region 310 may be smaller than the curvature of the first connected region 321 described below, and the radius of curvature of the first region 310 may be greater than the radius of curvature of the first connected region 321. The radius of curvature of the first region 310 may be sufficiently greater than the radius of curvature of the first connected region 321. For example, when the radius of curvature of the first connected region 321 is "a", the radius of curvature of the first region 310 may be "10<sup>∗</sup>a" or greater.</p>
<p id="p0186" num="0186">In another embodiment of the present disclosure, the first region 310 may form a flat surface overall. The first region 310 may form an outer surface that is a flat surface, and may be disposed on the front surface of the body 200. The first region 310 may have a uniform cross-section in the first and second directions.</p>
<p id="p0187" num="0187">Hereinafter, the flexible display device 1 will be described on the assumption that the first region 310 is formed in a flat surface.</p>
<p id="p0188" num="0188">The facing direction of the first region 310 (the facing direction of the outer<!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --> surface of the first region 310) may be the third direction. The first region 310 may form a part or the entirety of the first surface 1a of the flexible display device 1.</p>
<p id="p0189" num="0189">The flexible display 300 may further include a fourth region 340.</p>
<p id="p0190" num="0190">The fourth region 340 may be configured to extend from the first region 310, and may form an end of the flexible display 300. The fourth region 340 may have a uniform cross-section and be curved, in the second direction. An image may be displayed on the fourth region 340.</p>
<p id="p0191" num="0191">The second region 320 is configured to extend from the first region 310, and a part of second region 320 is curved around the support 230. The second region 320 may have a uniform cross-section in the second direction.</p>
<p id="p0192" num="0192">The second region 320 may include the first connected region 321 and a second connected region 322.</p>
<p id="p0193" num="0193">The first connected region 321 may be directly coupled to the first region 310, and the second connected region 322 may be directly coupled to the first connected region 321 and the third region 330.</p>
<p id="p0194" num="0194">When the second body 220 is at the first position, the first connected region 321 is curved around the support 230 along the outer circumferential surface of the support 230. When the second body 220 is at the first position, the first connected region 321 may form an outer surface that is curved about a curvature center line L1. When the second body 220 is at the first position, the curvature center line L1 is an imaginary straight line that forms a center of curvature of the first connected region 321, and is parallel to the second direction.</p>
<p id="p0195" num="0195">When the second body 220 is at the first position, a cross-section of the first connected region 321 may form a semicircular shape.</p>
<p id="p0196" num="0196">The curvature center line L1 may coincide with the central axis 231 of the support 230.</p>
<p id="p0197" num="0197">When the second body 220 is at the second position, the curvature center line L1 may form a center of curvature of the curved second connected region 322.</p>
<p id="p0198" num="0198">An image may be displayed on the first connected region 321 and the first region 310.<!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --></p>
<p id="p0199" num="0199">The area of the first region 310 may be larger than that of the first connected region 321.</p>
<p id="p0200" num="0200">When the second body 220 is at the first position, the second connected region 322 may form an outer surface that is an opposite surface of the first region 310. That is, when the second body 220 is at the first position, when the first region 310 faces the third direction (Z direction), the second connected region 322 may face the direction opposite to the third direction (Z direction). An image may be displayed on the second connected region 322.</p>
<p id="p0201" num="0201">The second connected region 322 may have a uniform cross-section in the second direction. When the second body 220 is at the first position, the second connected region 322 may have a uniform cross-section in the first direction.</p>
<p id="p0202" num="0202">The flexible display 300 is configured such that the first region 310, the first connected region 321, and the second connected region 322 are sequentially connected to each other, and when the second body 220 is at the first position, the first region 310, the first connected region 321, and the second connected region 322 may be formed in a U-shape overall.</p>
<p id="p0203" num="0203">In an embodiment of the present disclosure, when the second body 220 is at the first position, the second connected region 322 may form a curved surface overall. In this case, the curvature of the second connected region 322 may be smaller than the curvature of the first connected region 321, and the radius of curvature of the second connected region 322 may be greater than the radius of curvature of the first connected region 321. The radius of curvature of the second connected region 322 may be sufficiently greater than the radius of curvature of the first connected region 321. For example, when the radius of curvature of the first connected region 321 is "a", the radius of curvature of the second connected region 322 may be "10<sup>∗</sup>a" or greater.</p>
<p id="p0204" num="0204">In another embodiment of the present disclosure, when the second body 220 is at the first position, the second connected region 322 may form a flat surface overall. In addition, the second connected region 322 may be parallel to the first region 310. Hereinafter, the flexible display device 1 will be described on the assumption that when the<!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --> second body 220 is at the first position, the second connected region 322 is formed in a flat surface and is parallel to the first region 310.</p>
<p id="p0205" num="0205">The third region 330 is configured to extend from the second region 320 on the opposite side of the first region 310. The third region 330 may be configured to extend from the second connected region 322, and may form an end of the flexible display 300.</p>
<p id="p0206" num="0206">In the flexible display 300, an image may be displayed on the surfaces of the first region 310, the second region 320, and the fourth region 340, but not on the surface of the third region 330. In the flexible display 300, the third region 330 may form an extended part of a display substrate, and may form a dummy part on which an image is not displayed.</p>
<p id="p0207" num="0207">The third region 330 may be formed separately from the flexible display 300 and then be coupled to the flexible display 300, or may be integrally formed with the flexible display 300 in the manufacturing process of the flexible display 300. The third region 330 may be formed as a substrate of the flexible display 300.</p>
<p id="p0208" num="0208">The third region may be formed in the shape of a plastic film, and may be flexibly curved.</p>
<p id="p0209" num="0209">The third region 330 may include a first end region 331 and a second end region 332.</p>
<p id="p0210" num="0210">When the second body 220 is at the first position, when viewed from the third direction, the first end region 331 may be formed in the same line as the camera 121 in the second direction, and may have a uniform width in the second direction.</p>
<p id="p0211" num="0211">When viewed from the third direction, the second end region 332 may be formed in the same line as the camera 121 in the first direction, may have a uniform width in the second direction, and may be coupled to the first end region 331.</p>
<p id="p0212" num="0212"><figref idref="f0007">FIG. 5A</figref> is a cross-sectional view taken along line A-A' of <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 3A</figref>, and schematically illustrates the flexible display device 1. <figref idref="f0007">FIG. 5B</figref> is a cross-sectional view taken along line B-B' of <figref idref="f0005">FIG. 3B</figref>, and schematically illustrates the flexible display device 1.</p>
<p id="p0213" num="0213"><figref idref="f0007">FIG. 6A</figref> is a cross-sectional view illustrating the flexible display 300 separated from the flexible display device 1 illustrated in <figref idref="f0007">FIG. 5A</figref>, and <figref idref="f0008">FIG. 6B</figref> is a cross-sectional view illustrating the flexible display 300 separated from the flexible display device 1<!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --> illustrated in <figref idref="f0007">FIG. 5B</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0214" num="0214">In the flexible display device 1 according to an embodiment of the present disclosure, an inner plate 350 may be stacked on an inner surface of the flexible display 300 to be coupled to the flexible display 300.</p>
<p id="p0215" num="0215">The inner plate 350 may be formed as an elastic metal plate. The inner plate 350 may be made of a super-elastic metal. The inner plate 350 may be formed in the shape of a relatively thin plate. The inner plate 350 may be made to have a thickness in the range of 0.05 to 0.2 mm, for example, 0.1 mm.</p>
<p id="p0216" num="0216">In an embodiment of the present disclosure, the inner plate 350 may be formed in the same size and shape as or a similar size and shape to the flexible display 300 such that the inner plate 350 may be coupled to an entire inner surface of the flexible display 300.</p>
<p id="p0217" num="0217">In another embodiment of the present disclosure, the inner plate 350 may be formed in the same size and shape as or a similar size and shape to the second region 320 such that the inner plate 350 may be coupled to an inner surface of the second region 320.</p>
<p id="p0218" num="0218">The inner plate 350 facilitates elastic modification and recovery of the flexible display 300.</p>
<p id="p0219" num="0219">The flexible display device 1 according to an embodiment of the present disclosure may include a chain 360.</p>
<p id="p0220" num="0220">The chain 360 may be made of a hard material to maintain the original shape of the chain 360. The chain 360 may be made of metal, plastic, or a combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p0221" num="0221">The chain 360 includes a plurality of links 361 that are coupled to each other. Each of the links extend in the second direction (Y direction), have a uniform cross-section in the second direction (Y direction), and are coupled to each other so as to be able to rotate about a rotation axis parallel to the second direction (Y direction) (see <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 2B</figref>).</p>
<p id="p0222" num="0222">The chain 360 may contact or be coupled to the inner surface of the second region 320 of the flexible display 300 to support the second region 320. When the inner plate 350 is provided, the chain 360, the inner plate 350, and the second region 320 may be sequentially stacked.</p>
<p id="p0223" num="0223">The second region 320 may be maintained in a stable state by means of the chain<!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --> 360. In particular, when the second region 320 is formed as a touch screen to perform touch input, the second region 320 may be stably supported by means of the chain 360.</p>
<p id="p0224" num="0224">At least one camera 121 is fixed to a rear surface of the body 200. The camera 121 may be coupled to the body 200 to face the opposite direction of the third direction (Z direction).</p>
<p id="p0225" num="0225">The camera 121 may be fixed to a rear surface of the first body 210.</p>
<p id="p0226" num="0226">The camera 121 may be fixed to the body 200 away from the support 230. That is, when the support 230 is coupled to the body 200 on the left side of the flexible display device 1, the camera 121 is coupled to the body 200 on the right side of the flexible display device 1. The camera 121 may be fixed adjacent to an edge of the first body 210 farthest from the support 230.</p>
<p id="p0227" num="0227">Two or more cameras 121 may be arranged in the second direction.</p>
<p id="p0228" num="0228"><figref idref="f0008">FIG. 7A</figref> is a cross-sectional view schematically illustrating the flexible display device 1. <figref idref="f0008">FIG. 7B</figref> is a cross-sectional view schematically illustrating a state in which the flexible display device 1 illustrated in <figref idref="f0008">FIG. 7A</figref> is modified.</p>
<p id="p0229" num="0229">The flexible display device 1 according to an embodiment of the present disclosure may include a plurality of support bars 370. The plurality of support bars 370 may be coupled to the inner surface of the second region 320 of the flexible display 300 to support the second region 320.</p>
<p id="p0230" num="0230">The support bars 370 may be made of a relatively hard material, for example, plastic or metal, to support the flexible display 300.</p>
<p id="p0231" num="0231">The support bars 370 may extend in the second direction (Y direction), and may have a uniform cross-section of a trapezoidal shape in the second direction (Y direction) (that is, the width of the cross-section of each of the support bars 370 becomes narrower as the cross-section is farther away from the rear surface of the flexible display).</p>
<p id="p0232" num="0232">When the plurality of successively arranged support bars 370 form a plane parallel to the first region 310, the support bars 370 have a predetermined thickness such that the second region 320 supported by means of the support bars 370 is maintained stably like the first region 310.<!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --></p>
<p id="p0233" num="0233">The second region 320 may be maintained in a stable state by means of the support bars 370. In particular, when the second region 320 is formed as a touch screen to perform touch input, the second region 320 may be stably supported by means of the support bars 370.</p>
<p id="p0234" num="0234">The first cover 215 may have a predetermined length in the first direction (X direction) and the second direction (Y direction).</p>
<p id="p0235" num="0235">The first cover 215 may be formed in the shape of a plate substantially parallel to the first direction (X direction) and the second direction (Y direction). The first cover 215 may be parallel to or substantially parallel to the first region 310.</p>
<p id="p0236" num="0236">The first cover 215 may form the rear surface of the first body 210. The first cover 215 may be fixedly or detachably coupled to the first body 210. The first cover 215 may be made transparent or non-transparent.</p>
<p id="p0237" num="0237">When the second body 220 is at the first position, an area of the first cover 215 (an area inside a border of the first cover 215) may be equal to or larger than that of the second connected region 322.</p>
<p id="p0238" num="0238">When the second body 220 is at the first position, the area of the first cover 215 (the area inside a border of the first cover 215) may be equal to or equivalent to that of the first region 310.</p>
<p id="p0239" num="0239">The first cover 215 may form a part or the entirety of the second surface 1b of the flexible display device 1. That is, the first cover 215 may form a part or the entirety of the rear surface of the flexible display device 1.</p>
<p id="p0240" num="0240">The first cover 215 may form half or more of the second surface 1b of the flexible display device 1. That is, the first cover 215 may form half or more of the rear surface of the flexible display device 1.</p>
<p id="p0241" num="0241">The second cover 225 may have a predetermined length in the first direction (X direction) and the second direction (Y direction).</p>
<p id="p0242" num="0242">The second cover 225 may be formed in the shape of a plate substantially parallel to the first direction (X direction) and the second direction (Y direction). The second cover 225 may be parallel to or substantially parallel to the first region.<!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --></p>
<p id="p0243" num="0243">The second cover 225 may form the rear surface of the second body 220. The second cover 225 may be fixedly or detachably coupled to the second body 220. The first cover 225 may be made transparent or non-transparent.</p>
<p id="p0244" num="0244">When the second body 220 is at the first position, an area of the second cover 225 (an area inside a border of the second cover 225) may be equal to or larger than that of the second connected region 322.</p>
<p id="p0245" num="0245">When the second body 220 is at the first position, the second cover 225 is located inside the first cover 215, and an outer surface of the second cover 225 faces an inner surface of the first cover 215. When the second body 220 is at the first position, the second cover 225 may be located inside a region formed by the first cover 215.</p>
<p id="p0246" num="0246">When the second body 220 is at the first position, the first cover 215 and the second cover 225 overlap each other. However, when switching from the first position to the second position is made, the first cover 215 and the second cover 225 perform sliding movement relative to each other.</p>
<p id="p0247" num="0247">When the second body 220 is at the second position, the first cover 215 and the second cover 225 may form a rearmost surface of the flexible display device 1. When the second body 220 is at the second position, the second cover 225 may form a part of the second surface 1b of the flexible display device 1.</p>
<p id="p0248" num="0248">The first body 210 may include a first edge portion 216.</p>
<p id="p0249" num="0249">The first edge portion 216 forms a border on either side of the flexible display device 1. The first edge portion 216 may form any one of four sides of the flexible display device 1 having a rectangular shape.</p>
<p id="p0250" num="0250">The first edge portion 216 is fixed to the first body 210. The first edge portion 216 may be integrally formed with the first body 210, or may be formed separately from the first body 210 and be fixed thereto.</p>
<p id="p0251" num="0251">The first edge portion 216 extends in the second direction (Y direction).</p>
<p id="p0252" num="0252">At least a portion of the first edge portion 216 may have a uniform cross-section in the second direction (Y direction). The outer surface of the first edge portion 216 may form a convex curved surface, and the cross-section of the first edge portion 216 may be formed<!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --> in, for example, a semi-circular shape.</p>
<p id="p0253" num="0253">The fourth region 340 may be fixed to the first edge portion 216.</p>
<p id="p0254" num="0254">The first edge portion 216 and the first cover 215 may be coupled so as not to move relative to each other, and the first edge portion 216 may be in close contact with or adjacent to the first cover 215.</p>
<p id="p0255" num="0255">The second body may include a second edge portion 226.</p>
<p id="p0256" num="0256">The second edge portion 226 forms the border of the flexible display device on the opposite side to the first edge portion 216. When the first edge portion 216 forms a left border of the flexible display device 1, the second edge portion 226 forms a right border of the flexible display device 1.</p>
<p id="p0257" num="0257">The second edge portion 226 is disposed outside the support 230.</p>
<p id="p0258" num="0258">A gap 226b is provided between the second edge portion 226 and the support 230, and the flexible display 300 that may be curved is moved through the gap 226b.</p>
<p id="p0259" num="0259">The second edge portion 226 is fixed to the second body 220. The second edge portion 226 may be integrally formed with the second body 220, or may be formed separately from the second body 220 and be fixed thereto.</p>
<p id="p0260" num="0260">The second edge portion 226 extends in the second direction (Y direction).</p>
<p id="p0261" num="0261">At least a portion of the second edge portion 226 may have a uniform cross-section in the second direction (Y direction). The outer surface of the second edge portion 226 may form a convex curved surface, and the cross-section of the second edge portion 226 may be formed in, for example, a semi-circular shape.</p>
<p id="p0262" num="0262">The second edge portion 226 and the second cover 225 may be coupled so as not to move relative to each other.</p>
<p id="p0263" num="0263">When the second body 220 is at the first position, an edge of the first cover 215 may be in close contact with or adjacent to the second edge portion 226.</p>
<p id="p0264" num="0264">A cover-close contacted portion 226a may be formed on one side of the second edge portion 226. The cover-close contacted portion 226a extends in the second direction (Y direction). When the second body 220 is at the first position, the cover-close contacted portion 226a is in close contact with an edge of the first cover 215. The cover-close<!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --> contacted portion 226a may be made of the same material as the first cover 215.</p>
<p id="p0265" num="0265">When the second body 220 is at the first position, the second cover 225 is located inside the first cover 215 forming the rear surface of the flexible display device 1, and the second connected region 322 is located inside the second cover 225.</p>
<p id="p0266" num="0266">When the second body 220 is at the second position, the first connected region 321 may form the same plane with the first region 310, and at least a portion of the second connected region 322 may be curved around the support 230 in the circumferential direction of the support 230. When the second body 220 is at the second position, a part of the second connected region 322 may form the same plane with the first region 310.</p>
<p id="p0267" num="0267">When the second body 220 is at the second position, the first connected region 321 may be located in front of the second body 220, and a part of the second connected region 322 may also be located in front of the second body 220.</p>
<p id="p0268" num="0268">Accordingly, a significant portion of the second region 320 located behind the second body 220 when the second body 220 is at the first position may move to the front of the second body 220 when the second body 220 is at the second position. In addition, an area of the second region 320 located in front of the second body 220 may be larger when the second body 220 is at the second position than when the second body 220 is at the first position.</p>
<p id="p0269" num="0269">When the second body 220 is at the second position, based on the third direction, the third region 330 may be located behind the support 230. When the second body 220 is at the second position, a part of the third region 330 may be curved around the support 230 and a remaining part thereof may be parallel to the first region 310.</p>
<p id="p0270" num="0270">When the second body 220 performs reciprocating movement relative to the first body 210 between the first position and the second position, an area of the flexible display 300 viewed from the third direction (Z direction) may be increased or reduced.</p>
<p id="p0271" num="0271">In the flexible display device 1, when viewed from the third direction (Z direction), a projection area of the flexible display 300 may be larger when the second body 220 is at the second position than when the second body 220 is at the first position.</p>
<p id="p0272" num="0272">When the second body 220 is at the first position, the first connected region 321<!-- EPO <DP n="40"> --> may be curved to form a curved surface around the support 230, the second connected region 322 may be parallel to the first region 310, and the third region 330 may be located in the same line as the camera 121 in the second direction when viewed from the third direction.</p>
<p id="p0273" num="0273">When the second body 220 moves relative to the first body 210 such that switching from the first position to the second position is made, the first connected region 321 may form the same plane with the first region 310, and a part of the second connected region 322 may be curved to form a curved surface around the support 230.</p>
<p id="p0274" num="0274">In addition, when the second body 220 is at the second position, the third region 330 may be located in the same line as the support 230 in the second direction when viewed from the third direction.</p>
<p id="p0275" num="0275">In order to achieve a stable modification of the flexible display 300 when switching back from the second position to the first position is made, as will be described below, the third region 330 may be coupled to a tension generator 400, and at least a portion of the third region 330 is located behind the support 230 based on the third direction.</p>
<p id="p0276" num="0276">When the second body 220 moves relative to the first body 210 such that switching from the second position to the first position is made, the first connected region 321 may be curved around the support 230 again, and the second connected region 322 may form a plane parallel to the first region 310.</p>
<p id="p0277" num="0277">When switching from the first position to the second position is made, the third region 330 moves relative to the second body 220, and, based on the first body 210, the movement distance of the third region 330 is twice the movement distance of the second body 220.</p>
<p id="p0278" num="0278">In the flexible display device 1, when the second body 220 is at the first position, based on the first direction, the distance from the support to an end of the third region 330 is equal to or greater than the distance from the support 230 to a center of the camera 121, and when the second body 220 is at the second position, the third region 330 may move to the support 230.<!-- EPO <DP n="41"> --></p>
<p id="p0279" num="0279">Accordingly, when the second body 220 is at the second position, the first connected region 321 may form the same plane with the first region 310, as well as maximizing the size (area) of the second region 320 forming the same plane with the first region 310.</p>
<p id="p0280" num="0280">According to an embodiment of the present disclosure, since the flexible display device 1 may be configured such that the camera 121 may be mounted on the rear surface thereof and an exposed area of the flexible display 300 on the front surface thereof may continuously change, the exposed area of the flexible display 300 on the front surface of the flexible display device 1 can be further increased.</p>
<p id="p0281" num="0281">In the flexible display device 1 according to an embodiment of the present disclosure, the first cover 215 is coupled to the back of the first body 210 so as not to move relative to the first region 310, and covers the second connected region 322 to form a rear surface of the flexible display 1 device when the second body 220 is at the first position.</p>
<p id="p0282" num="0282">When the second body 220 is at the first position, a user may hold the first body 210 by means of the first cover 215 forming the entirety or a significant portion of the rear surface of the flexible display device 1, and may view an image displayed on the first region 310 forming the entirety or a significant portion of the front surface of the flexible display device 1.</p>
<p id="p0283" num="0283">In this case, even when switching from the first position to the second position is made, the user may stably hold the flexible display device 1 in contact with both the first cover 215 and the first region 310, and continue to view the image information displayed on the first region 310 at the same position.</p>
<p id="p0284" num="0284">In addition, when the first region 310 is formed as a touch screen including a touch sensor, when switching from the first position to the second position is made, the user may perform touch input through the first region 310 while holding the first body 210 to which the first cover 215 and the first region 310 are fixed, and the flexible display device 1 may be stably used even during switching between the first state and the second state.</p>
<p id="p0285" num="0285"><figref idref="f0009">FIG. 8</figref> is a cross-sectional view schematically illustrating a part of the flexible<!-- EPO <DP n="42"> --> display device 1.</p>
<p id="p0286" num="0286">The flexible display device 1 may include a filter 280 that is disposed between the first cover 215 and the second cover 225.</p>
<p id="p0287" num="0287">The filter 280 is formed to be fixed to one of the first cover 215 or the second cover 225 and to contact the other one of the first cover 215 or the second cover 225. Accordingly, the filter 280 may have a predetermined length in the third direction.</p>
<p id="p0288" num="0288">The filter 280 may be made of a soft material. That is, the filter 280 may be made of at least one of a brush, a cloth, a non-woven fabric, a sponge, or paper.</p>
<p id="p0289" num="0289">The filter 280 may extend in the direction parallel to the second direction. The filter 280 may be formed over the entire area of the first cover 215 or the second cover 225 in a direction parallel to the second direction. That is, the filter 280 may be formed to have a length crossing the first cover 215 or the second cover 225 in a direction parallel to the second direction.</p>
<p id="p0290" num="0290">The filter 280 may prevent foreign matter such as dust from entering the gap between the first cover 215 and the second cover 225.</p>
<p id="p0291" num="0291"><figref idref="f0010">FIG. 9</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a state in which the first cover 215 and the second cover 225 are separated from the flexible display device 1.</p>
<p id="p0292" num="0292">The first cover 215 and the second cover 225 may together form the rear surface of the flexible display device 1. That is, when viewed from the direction opposite to the third direction, both the first cover 215 and the second body 225 may be seen.</p>
<p id="p0293" num="0293">At least a portion of the first cover 215 may be made transparent. Accordingly, stacked components inside the first cover 215 may be visually exposed to the outside (back).</p>
<p id="p0294" num="0294">At least a portion of the second cover 225 may also be made transparent. Accordingly, stacked components inside the second cover 225 may be visually exposed to the outside (back).</p>
<p id="p0295" num="0295">The first cover 215 may include a first transparent region 215a and a first non-transparent region 215b. When the second body 220 is at the first or second position, the first transparent region 215a and the first non-transparent region 215b form the rear surface<!-- EPO <DP n="43"> --> of the flexible display device 1.</p>
<p id="p0296" num="0296">The first transparent region 215a may be made transparent using materials such as transparent plastic and glass. When the second body 220 is at the first position, when viewed from the third direction (Z direction), the first transparent region 215a may overlap the second region 320, and may overlap the second connected region 322.</p>
<p id="p0297" num="0297">The first non-transparent region 215b is made non-transparent. When the second body 220 is at the first position, when viewed from the third direction (Z direction), the first non-transparent region 215b may overlap the third region 330.</p>
<p id="p0298" num="0298">The third region 330 may be formed in a dummy form so as not to display an image, and the first non-transparent region 215b may overlap the third region 330 to prevent unnecessary exposure of the inside of the flexible display device 1.</p>
<p id="p0299" num="0299">The second cover 225 may include a second transparent region 225a and a second non-transparent region 225b. When the second body 220 is at the second position, the second transparent region 225a and the second non-transparent region 225b may form the rear surface of the flexible display device 1.</p>
<p id="p0300" num="0300">The second transparent region 225a may be made transparent using materials such as transparent plastic and glass. When the second body 220 is at the first position, when viewed from the third direction (Z direction), the second transparent region 225a may overlap the second region 320, and may overlap the second connected region 322.</p>
<p id="p0301" num="0301">The second non-transparent region 225b is made non-transparent. When the second body 220 is at the first position, when viewed from the third direction (Z direction), the second non-transparent region 225b may overlap the third region 330. As described above, the third region 330 may be formed in a dummy form so as not to display an image, and the second non-transparent region 225b may overlap the third region 330 to prevent unnecessary exposure of the inside of the flexible display device 1.</p>
<p id="p0302" num="0302">The flexible display 300 (the second region 320 and the third region 330) is formed to move inside the first cover 215 and the second cover 225.</p>
<p id="p0303" num="0303">As described above, the first transparent region 215a and the second transparent region 225a may be made transparent to cause the second region 320 to be visually<!-- EPO <DP n="44"> --> exposed to the outside (back). Accordingly, an image on the second region 320 may be viewed from behind the flexible display device 1, through the first transparent region 215a and the second transparent region 225a.</p>
<p id="p0304" num="0304">When the first body 210 includes the first transparent region 215a and the second body 220 includes the second transparent region 225a, the flexible display device 1 may include a touch panel 240. In this case, the touch panel 240 may be coupled to the first transparent region 215a by being stacked thereon, or may be coupled to the outer or inner surface of the first transparent region 215a. The touch panel 240 may be formed as a touch sensor (see <figref idref="f0011">FIG. 10A</figref>).</p>
<p id="p0305" num="0305">In addition, the touch panel 240 may have the same area as the first transparent region 215A so as to be perfectly coupled thereto. When the second body 220 is at the first position, the second connected region 322, the second transparent region 225a, the first transparent region 215a, and the touch panel 240 may be arranged to overlap each other, the second region 320 and the touch panel 240 may be combined to form a touch screen, and touch input (information input) may be performed through the second region 320.</p>
<p id="p0306" num="0306">In an embodiment of the present disclosure, the transparent portions of the first cover 215 and the second cover 225 may have different colors. The first transparent region 215a and the second transparent region 225a may have different colors.</p>
<p id="p0307" num="0307">When the first transparent region 215a and the second transparent region 225a have different colors, when the second body 220 is at the second position, the first transparent region 215a and the second transparent region 225a may be shown to the user in different colors, respectively. However, when the second body 220 is at the first position, the first transparent region 215a and the second transparent region 225a may overlap and be shown to the user in different colors from the original colors of the two regions 215a and 225a, respectively.</p>
<p id="p0308" num="0308">For example, when the first transparent region 215a is yellow and the second transparent region 225a is blue, when the second body 220 is at the first position, the first transparent region 215a and the second transparent region 225a may overlap and be shown to the user in green.<!-- EPO <DP n="45"> --></p>
<p id="p0309" num="0309">Accordingly, depending on whether the second body 220 is at the first position, at the second position, or at a position between the first position and the second position, the first transparent region 215a and the second transparent region 225a may be shown to the user in various colors, respectively, and may exhibit various colors even when an image is displayed on the second connected region.</p>
<p id="p0310" num="0310"><figref idref="f0011">FIG. 10A</figref> is a view illustrating the inner surface of the first cover 215, and <figref idref="f0012">FIG. 10B</figref> is a view illustrating the rear surface of the first body 210 from which the first cover 215 is separated.</p>
<p id="p0311" num="0311">The flexible display device 1 according to an embodiment of the present disclosure may be switched between the first position and the second position, and the first cover 215 may be detachably coupled to the first body 210. Accordingly, even when foreign matter such as dust enters the flexible display device 1, the foreign matter can be easily removed through separation of the first cover 215 from the first body 210.</p>
<p id="p0312" num="0312">When the first cover 215 is detachably coupled to the first body 210 and the touch panel 240 is provided on the first cover 215, the flexible display device 1 includes a first terminal 242 and a second terminal 241.</p>
<p id="p0313" num="0313">The first terminal 242 is coupled to the first body 210 to be electrically connected to the flexible display 300. The first terminal 242 may be electrically connected to the second connected region 322. The first terminal 242 is formed to be fixed to the outer surface (rear surface) of the first body.</p>
<p id="p0314" num="0314">The second terminal 241 is coupled to the inner surface of the first cover 215 to be electrically connected to the touch panel 240. The second terminal 241 may be fixed on the first non-transparent region 215b.</p>
<p id="p0315" num="0315">When the first cover 215 is coupled to the first body 210, since the first terminal 242 and the second terminal 241 are connected in contact with each other, the touch panel 240 and the second connected region 322 may be combined to form a touch screen.</p>
<p id="p0316" num="0316">When the first cover 215 is detachably coupled to the first body 210, a camera hole 215c may be formed in the first cover 215. The camera hole 215c may be formed in the shape of a hole through the first cover 215. When the first cover 215 is coupled to the<!-- EPO <DP n="46"> --> first body 210, the camera 121 may be mounted inside the camera hole 215c.</p>
<p id="p0317" num="0317"><figref idref="f0013">FIG. 11A</figref> is a view illustrating the inner surface of the first cover 215, and <figref idref="f0014">FIG. 11B</figref> is a view illustrating the rear surface of the first body 210 from which the first cover 215 is separated.</p>
<p id="p0318" num="0318"><figref idref="f0015">FIG. 12A</figref> is a cross-sectional view schematically illustrating a state in which the first cover 215 and the first body 210 are separated from each other, and <figref idref="f0015">FIG. 12B</figref> is a cross-sectional view schematically illustrating a state in which the first cover 215 and the first body 210 are combined.</p>
<p id="p0319" num="0319">The flexible display device 1 according to an embodiment of the present disclosure includes a first latching portion 215d, a movable rod 291, a second latching portion 292, and a first elastic body 293,</p>
<p id="p0320" num="0320">The first latching portion 215d and the second latching portion 292 have a shape such that the first latching portion 215d and the second latching portion 292 are caught on each other.</p>
<p id="p0321" num="0321">In an embodiment of the present disclosure, the first latching portion 215d may have a bent end in order to have an L-shape, and the second latching portion 292 may be formed in the shape of a hole provided with a catching protrusion such that the first latching portion 215d may be inserted into the hole and then be caught on the catching protrusion.</p>
<p id="p0322" num="0322">Two or more first latching portions 215d and second latching portions 292 may be provided, respectively.</p>
<p id="p0323" num="0323">The movable rod 291 may be coupled to the first body 210 such that the movable rod 291 performs reciprocating movement relative to the first body 210 in the direction parallel to the inner surface of the first cover 215.</p>
<p id="p0324" num="0324">The movable rod 291 may be formed in the shape of a rod extending in the second direction, and may be coupled to the first body 210 on the first edge portion 216. Moreover, the movable rod 291 may be coupled to the first body 210 to perform reciprocating movement in the direction parallel to the second direction.</p>
<p id="p0325" num="0325">The second latching portion 292 is formed in the movable rod 291. Depending on<!-- EPO <DP n="47"> --> the movement of the movable rod, the first latching portion 215d and the second latching portion 292 are caught on or released from each other.</p>
<p id="p0326" num="0326">The first elastic body 293 is coupled to the first body 210, and elastically supports the movable rod 291 such that the first latching portion 215d and the second latching portion 292 are caught on each other. The first elastic body 293 may be formed in the shape of a spring that stores elastic restoring force while being elastically modified. Accordingly, the first elastic body 293 may elastically support the movable rod 291 such that the movable rod 291 moves in the direction for causing the first latching portion 215d and the second latching portion 292 to be caught on each other.</p>
<p id="p0327" num="0327">Unless there is a separate external force, the first latching portion 215d or the second latching portion 292 continue to be caught on each other such that the first cover 215 is fixed to the first body 210. However, when the movable rod 291 moves in the direction in which the first elastic body 293 is modified in compressed form by an external force, the first latching portion 215d and the second latching portion 292 may be released such that the user may separate the first cover 215 from the first body 210.</p>
<p id="p0328" num="0328">The flexible display device 1 may include a pusher 294 and a second elastic body 295.</p>
<p id="p0329" num="0329">The pusher 294 is coupled to the first body 210 to perform reciprocating movement toward the inner surface of the first cover 215. The pusher 294 is configured to perform reciprocating movement in the direction parallel to the third direction.</p>
<p id="p0330" num="0330">The pusher 294 may be coupled to the first edge portion 216. The pusher 294 may be configured to perform reciprocating movement relative to the first edge portion 216 in the third direction, and may protrude more than the first edge portion 216 in the direction opposite to the third direction.</p>
<p id="p0331" num="0331">The second elastic body 295 elastically supports the pusher 294 toward the first cover 215.</p>
<p id="p0332" num="0332">The second elastic body 295 is coupled to the first body 210, and elastically supports the pusher 294 such that the pusher 294 protrudes in the direction opposite to the third direction. The second elastic body 295 may be formed in the shape of a spring that<!-- EPO <DP n="48"> --> stores elastic restoring force while being elastically modified.</p>
<p id="p0333" num="0333">Unless there is a separate external force, the pusher 294 pressed by the second elastic body 295 is in contact with the inner surface of the first cover 215. Accordingly, a force is applied to the first cover 215 and the first body in the direction to space them away from each other. That is, an external force is applied to the first cover 215 in the direction opposite to the third direction. As a result, since the first latching portion 215d and the second latching portion 292 continue to be more strongly caught on each other, the first cover 215 may be prevented from being loosened relative to the first body 210.</p>
<p id="p0334" num="0334">Furthermore, when the movable rod 291 moves in the direction in which the first elastic body 293 is modified in compressed form by the external force (for example, when the movable rod 291 moves in the direction opposite to the second direction), the first latching portion 215d and the second latching portion 292 may be released, and the pusher 294 pushes the first cover 215 to facilitate separation of the first cover 215 from the first body 210.</p>
<p id="p0335" num="0335">The flexible display device 1 may include a tension generator 400.</p>
<p id="p0336" num="0336">The tension generator 400 is configured to pull the flexible display 300 to apply tension to the flexible display 300 (see <figref idref="f0007">FIGS. 5B</figref>, <figref idref="f0018">14A</figref>, and <figref idref="f0020">15</figref>).</p>
<p id="p0337" num="0337">The tension generator 400 may be coupled to the body 200 to be connected to the second region 320 of the flexible display 300, and may increase the tension applied to the flexible display 300, when switching from the first position to the second position is made.</p>
<p id="p0338" num="0338">In an embodiment, the tension generator 400 may include a spring.</p>
<p id="p0339" num="0339">When the flexible display 300 includes the third region 330, the tension generator 400 may be configured to couple the first body 210 to the third region 330, and to apply an external force to the flexible display 300 to cause the third region 330 to move away from the support 230 again, when the third region 330 approaches the support 230 in the first direction. That is, the tension generator 400 may be configured to pull the third region 330 to cause the third region 330 to be close to the camera 121 in the first direction.</p>
<p id="p0340" num="0340">When the flexible display 300 includes the third region 330, the tension generator 400 may be configured to couple the second body 220 to the third region 330, and to apply<!-- EPO <DP n="49"> --> an external force to the flexible display 300 to cause the third region 330 to move away from the support 230 again, when the third region 330 approaches the support 230 in the first direction. That is, the tension generator 400 may be configured to pull the third region 330 to cause the third region 330 to be close to the camera 121 in the first direction.</p>
<p id="p0341" num="0341"><figref idref="f0016">FIG. 13A</figref> is a rear view schematically illustrating the flexible display device 1 with the first cover 215 and the second cover 225 removed, and <figref idref="f0017">FIG. 13B</figref> is a rear view illustrating a state in which the flexible display device 1 illustrated in <figref idref="f0016">FIG. 13A</figref> is modified. In <figref idref="f0016">FIG. 13A</figref>, the second body 220 is represented by a dotted line, and in <figref idref="f0017">FIGS. 13B</figref>, the support 230 is represented by a dotted line.</p>
<p id="p0342" num="0342">In order to enable the first body 210 and the second body 220 to perform relative movement (sliding movement), the flexible display device 1 may be configured to further include a first rail 261, a second rail 262, a first slider 263, and a second slider 264.</p>
<p id="p0343" num="0343">The first rail 261 extends in the first direction, and is fixed to the second body. The first rail 261 may have a uniform cross-section in the first direction.</p>
<p id="p0344" num="0344">The second rail 262 extends in the first direction, and is fixed to the second body. The second rail 262 may be symmetric with the first rail 261 and may be the same as the first rail 261. The second rail 262 may have a uniform cross-section in the first direction.</p>
<p id="p0345" num="0345">The first rail and the second rail are spaced parallel to each other. When the first rail is coupled adjacent to the bottom of the second body, the second rail may be coupled adjacent to the top of the second body.</p>
<p id="p0346" num="0346">The first slider 263 is coupled to the first rail 261 to perform sliding movement along the first rail 261, and is fixed to the first body 210. Based on the first slider 263, the first rail 261 performs reciprocating movement in the first direction.</p>
<p id="p0347" num="0347">The first slider 264 is coupled to the second rail 262 to perform sliding movement along the second rail 262, and is fixed to the first body 210. Based on the second slider 264, the second rail 262 performs reciprocating movement in the first direction.</p>
<p id="p0348" num="0348">The first slider 263 and the second slider 264 are fixed to the first body 210 away from the camera 121. For example, when the camera 121 is coupled to the first body 210 on the right side of the flexible display device 1, the first slider 263 and the second slider<!-- EPO <DP n="50"> --> 264 are coupled to the first body 210 on the left side of the flexible display device 1.</p>
<p id="p0349" num="0349"><figref idref="f0018">FIG. 14A</figref> is a rear view schematically illustrating the flexible display device 1 with the first cover 215 and the second cover 225 removed, <figref idref="f0019">FIG. 14B</figref> is a cross-sectional view schematically illustrating a state in which the first body 210, the second body 220, and the third region 330 are separated from each other, and <figref idref="f0019">FIG. 14C</figref> is a cross-sectional view schematically illustrating a state in which the first body 210, the second body 220, and the third region 330 illustrated in <figref idref="f0019">FIG. 14B</figref> are combined.</p>
<p id="p0350" num="0350"><figref idref="f0020">FIG. 15</figref> is an exploded perspective view illustrating the tension generator 400, 400a, and 400b.</p>
<p id="p0351" num="0351">In order to enable the second body 220 and the third region 330 of the flexible display 300 to perform relative movement (sliding movement), the flexible display device 1 may be configured to further include a third rail 228, a fourth rail 229, a third slider 351, and a fourth slider 352.</p>
<p id="p0352" num="0352">The third rail 228 is configured to extend on the second body 220 in the first direction. The third rail 228 may have a uniform cross-section in the first direction, and may have a groove shape on a rear surface of the second body 220.</p>
<p id="p0353" num="0353">The fourth rail 229 extends on the second body 220 in the first direction. The third rail 228 may have a uniform cross-section in the first direction, and may have a groove shape on a rear surface of the second body 220.</p>
<p id="p0354" num="0354">The third rail 228 and the fourth rail 229 may have the same cross-section.</p>
<p id="p0355" num="0355">The third rail 228 and the fourth rail 229 may be spaced apart from each other to be parallel to each other. When the third rail 228 is provided on the lower side of the second body 220, the fourth rail 229 may be provided on the upper side of the second body 220.</p>
<p id="p0356" num="0356">The third slider 351 is coupled to the third rail 228 to perform sliding movement in a longitudinal direction of the third rail 228, and is fixed to the flexible display 300. The third slider 351 may be fixed to the third region 330.</p>
<p id="p0357" num="0357">When the third rail 228 has a groove shape, the third slider 351 may be inserted into and coupled to the third rail 228 by having a protruding shape, and may be bound to<!-- EPO <DP n="51"> --> the third rail 228 such that movement of the third slider 351 in a direction other than the first direction is prevented.</p>
<p id="p0358" num="0358">The fourth slider 352 is coupled to the fourth rail 229 to perform sliding movement in the longitudinal direction of the fourth rail 229, and is fixed to the flexible display 300. The fourth slider 352 may be fixed to the third region 330.</p>
<p id="p0359" num="0359">When the fourth rail 229 has a groove shape, the fourth slider 352 may be inserted into and coupled to the fourth rail 229 by having a protruding shape, and may be bound to the fourth rail 229 such that movement the fourth slider 352 in a direction other than the first direction is prevented.</p>
<p id="p0360" num="0360">In the flexible display device 1, the tension generator 400 may include a first tension generator 400a and a second tension generator 400b. The first tension generator 400a and the second tension generator 400b may respectively be configured like the tension generator 400 described above.</p>
<p id="p0361" num="0361">The first tension generator 400a may be configured to couple the first body 210 to the first end region 331, and when the second body 220 is at the second position, to apply tension to the flexible display 300.</p>
<p id="p0362" num="0362">The second tension generator 400b may be configured to couple the first body 210 to the second end region 332, and when the second body 220 is at the second position, to apply tension to the flexible display 300.</p>
<p id="p0363" num="0363">The tension generator 400, the first tension generator 400a, and the second tension generator 400b may be configured to include a tension body 410, a spool 420, a spiral spring 430, and a wire 440, respectively.</p>
<p id="p0364" num="0364">In addition, the tension generator 400, the first tension generator 400a, and the second tension generator 400b may be configured to include a tension housing 450 for receiving the spiral spring 430, respectively.</p>
<p id="p0365" num="0365">Furthermore, the tension generator 400, the first tension generator 400a, and the second tension generator 400b may be configured to include a pulley 460 around which the wire 440 may be wound so as to change the direction of the wire 440.</p>
<p id="p0366" num="0366">The tension body 410 is fixed to the first body 210 so as not to rotate relative to<!-- EPO <DP n="52"> --> the first body 210.</p>
<p id="p0367" num="0367">The spool 420 is coupled to the tension body 410 so as to be able to rotate about a rotation axis 401, and the wire 440 is wound around the spool 420.</p>
<p id="p0368" num="0368">The spiral spring 430 may be received within the tension housing 450, and have one end 431 fixed to the tension body 410 and the other end 432 fixed to the spool 420. Accordingly, the spiral spring 430 elastically supports the spool 420 on the tension body 410. That is, when the spool 420 is rotated relative to the tension body 410 by applying an external force to the spool 420, the spiral spring 430 is elastically deformed and accordingly stores elastic energy, and when the external force is released, the rotation direction of the spool 420 on the tension body 410 is reversed.</p>
<p id="p0369" num="0369">One end 441 of the wire 440 is fixed to and wound around the spool 420 and the other end 442 of the wire 440 is coupled to the third region 330. The wire 440 of the first tension generator 400a is coupled to the first end region 331 of the third region 330, and the wire 440 of the second tension generator 400b is coupled to the second end region 332 of the third region 330.</p>
<p id="p0370" num="0370">When an external force is applied to the flexible display device 1 to cause the second body 220 to switch from the first position to the second position relative to the first body 210, the third region 330 is close to the support 230 in the first direction, and the spiral spring 430 is elastically deformed and stores elastic energy accordingly as the wire 440 is unwound from the spool 420. Accordingly, a predetermined tension is applied to the flexible display 300.</p>
<p id="p0371" num="0371">When the external force applied to the flexible display device 1 is removed, the wire 440 is again wound around the spool 420 by the elastic restoring force of the spiral spring 430, such that the tension generators 400, 400a, and 400b pull the third region 330 to cause the third region 330 to be close to the camera 121 in the first direction.</p>
<p id="p0372" num="0372">In the foregoing, while specific embodiments of the present disclosure have been described for illustrative purposes, the scope of the present disclosure is not limited thereto, it will be understood by those skilled in the art that various changes and modifications can be made to other specific embodiments without departing from the scope of the present<!-- EPO <DP n="53"> --> disclosure. Therefore, the scope of the present disclosure should be defined not by the above-described embodiments but by the technical idea defined in the following claims.</p>
<p id="p0373" num="0373">The flexible display device according to an embodiment of the present disclosure is industrially applicable in that, when switching between the first position and the second position is made, the user can easily use the flexible display device while holding the flexible display device in contact with the first region and the first cover.</p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="54"> -->
<claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>A flexible display device, comprising:
<claim-text>a first body (210);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second body (220) configured to move between a first position and a second position relative to the first body (210) and comprising a support (230);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first cover (215); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a flexible display (300) comprising:
<claim-text>a first region (310) positioned in front of the first body (210);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first connected region (321) extending from the first region (310); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second connected region (322) extending from the first connected region (321),</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein when the second body (220) is at the first position, a portion of the first connected region (321) is curved around the support (230) and the second connected region (322) is parallel to the first region (310) and faces backward,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein when the second body (220) is at the second position, the first connected region (321) is co-planar with the first region (310) and a portion of the second connected region (322) is curved around the support (230), and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first cover (215) is coupled to a rear of the first body (210) to form a rear surface of the flexible display device and configured to cover the second connected region (322) when the second body (220) is at the first position.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>The flexible display device of claim 1, wherein an area of the first cover (215) is formed to be greater than or equal to an area of the second connected region (322).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>The flexible display device of claim 1 or 2, further comprising a second cover (225) coupled to a rear of the second body (220) to cover the second connected region (322) when the second body (220) is at the first position,<br/>
wherein the first cover (215) and the second cover (225) at least partially overlap when switching between the first position and the second position.<!-- EPO <DP n="55"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>The flexible display device according to claim 3, further comprising a filter (280) disposed between the first cover (215) and the second cover (225) and configured to prevent intrusion of foreign matter between the first cover (215) and the second cover (225).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>The flexible display device of one of claims 1 to 4, wherein the first body (210) comprises a first edge portion (216) that forms a first edge of the flexible display device,<br/>
wherein the second body (220) comprises a second edge portion (226) that forms a second edge of the flexible display device opposite the first edge, and<br/>
wherein the first cover (215) is adjacent to the second edge portion (226) when the second body (220) is at the first position and separated from the second edge portion (226) when the second body (220) is at the second position.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>The flexible display device of one of claims 1 to 5, wherein the first cover (215) is transparent such that the second connected region (322) is visible at a rear of the flexible display device when the second body (220) is at the first position.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>The flexible display device of claim 3 or 4, wherein at least a portion of each of the first cover (215) and the second cover (225) is transparent such that the second connected region (322) is visible at a rear of the flexible display device when the second body (220) is at the first position.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>The flexible display device according to claim 7, wherein a transparent portion of the first cover (215) is a different color than a transparent portion of the second cover (225).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>The flexible display device of claim 1 or 2, further comprising a second cover (225) coupled to a rear of the second body (220) to cover the second connected region (322) when the second body (220) is at the first position,<br/>
wherein the first cover (215) is detachably coupled to the first body (210).<!-- EPO <DP n="56"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>The flexible display device according to claim 9, further comprising:
<claim-text>a first latching portion (215d) formed on an inner surface of the first cover (215);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second latching portion (292) formed on a movable rod (291) disposed in the first body (210); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first elastic body (293) configured to provide an elastic force to the movable rod (291),</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first latching portion (215d) and the second latching portion (292) are configured to engage with each other to secure the first cover (215) to the first body (210).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>The flexible display device according to claim 10, wherein the first body (210) comprises<br/>
a second elastic body (295) configured to provide an elastic force to the first cover (215) away from the first body (210) via a pusher (294).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>The flexible display device according to claim 9, further comprising:
<claim-text>a touch panel (240) disposed at a surface of the first cover (215);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first terminal (242) coupled to the first body (210) and electrically connected to the flexible display (300); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second terminal (241) coupled to an inner surface of the first cover (215) and electrically connected to the touch panel (240), wherein the second terminal (241) contacts the first terminal (242) upon coupling of the first cover (215) and the first body (210).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>The flexible display device according to claim 12, wherein the first cover (215) comprises:
<claim-text>a transparent region (215a) corresponding to the second connected region (322) when the second body (220) is at the first position; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a non-transparent region (215b),</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the touch panel (240) is formed at the transparent region(215a), and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second terminal (241) is covered by the non-transparent region(215b).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>A flexible display device, comprising:<!-- EPO <DP n="57"> -->
<claim-text>a first body (210);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a flexible display (300) comprising a first region (310) forming a front surface of the flexible display device, a first connected region (321) extending from the first region (310), and a second connected region (322) extending from the first connected region (321), wherein the first region (310) is coupled to the first body (210);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second body (220) configured to slide between a first position and a second position relative to the first body (210) and comprising a support (230);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first cover (215) coupled to the first body (210) to form a rear surface of the flexible display device; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second cover (225) coupled to the second body (220) and located underneath the first cover (215) when the second body (220) is at the first position,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein when the second body (220) is at the first position, the first connected region (321) is curved around the support (230), and the second connected region (322) is located underneath the first cover (215) and the second cover (225), and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein when the second body (220) is at the second position, the first connected region (321) is co-planar with the first region (310), a portion of the second connected region (322) is curved around the support (230), and the second cover (225) is partially overlapped by the first cover (215).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0015" num="0015">
<claim-text>The flexible display device according to claim 14, wherein at least a portion of each of the first cover (215) and the second cover (225) is transparent such that the second connected region (322) is visible at a rear of the flexible display device when the second body (220) is at the first position.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="58"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="137" he="205" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="59"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="2A"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="100" he="163" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="60"> -->
<figure id="f0003" num="2B"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="130" he="150" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="61"> -->
<figure id="f0004" num="3A"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="103" he="163" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="62"> -->
<figure id="f0005" num="3B"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="129" he="172" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="63"> -->
<figure id="f0006" num="4A,4B"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="125" he="185" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="64"> -->
<figure id="f0007" num="5A,5B,6A"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="130" he="179" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="65"> -->
<figure id="f0008" num="6B,7A,7B"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="135" he="181" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="66"> -->
<figure id="f0009" num="8"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="114" he="82" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="67"> -->
<figure id="f0010" num="9"><img id="if0010" file="imgf0010.tif" wi="130" he="164" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="68"> -->
<figure id="f0011" num="10A"><img id="if0011" file="imgf0011.tif" wi="104" he="173" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="69"> -->
<figure id="f0012" num="10B"><img id="if0012" file="imgf0012.tif" wi="104" he="172" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="70"> -->
<figure id="f0013" num="11A"><img id="if0013" file="imgf0013.tif" wi="103" he="163" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="71"> -->
<figure id="f0014" num="11B"><img id="if0014" file="imgf0014.tif" wi="100" he="215" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="72"> -->
<figure id="f0015" num="12A,12B"><img id="if0015" file="imgf0015.tif" wi="136" he="130" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="73"> -->
<figure id="f0016" num="13A"><img id="if0016" file="imgf0016.tif" wi="98" he="164" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="74"> -->
<figure id="f0017" num="13B"><img id="if0017" file="imgf0017.tif" wi="126" he="167" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="75"> -->
<figure id="f0018" num="14A"><img id="if0018" file="imgf0018.tif" wi="129" he="141" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="76"> -->
<figure id="f0019" num="14B,14C"><img id="if0019" file="imgf0019.tif" wi="145" he="108" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="77"> -->
<figure id="f0020" num="15"><img id="if0020" file="imgf0020.tif" wi="125" he="214" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<search-report-data id="srep" lang="en" srep-office="EP" date-produced=""><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="151" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="151" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0003" file="srep0003.tif" wi="157" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0004" file="srep0004.tif" wi="157" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0005" file="srep0005.tif" wi="157" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0006" file="srep0006.tif" wi="157" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0007" file="srep0007.tif" wi="150" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0008" file="srep0008.tif" wi="150" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data><search-report-data date-produced="20210611" id="srepxml" lang="en" srep-office="EP" srep-type="ep-Rule63partial-sr" status="n"><!--
 The search report data in XML is provided for the users' convenience only. It might differ from the search report of the PDF document, which contains the officially published data. The EPO disclaims any liability for incorrect or incomplete data in the XML for search reports.
 -->

<srep-info><file-reference-id>AD2747 EP</file-reference-id><application-reference><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>20185603.6</doc-number></document-id></application-reference><applicant-name><name>LG Electronics Inc.</name></applicant-name><srep-established srep-established="yes"/><srep-unity-of-invention><p id="pu0001" num="">1. claims: 1-5<br/>The subject-matter of claims 1 to 5 is directed to a flexible display device comprising a first body and a second body capable of sliding in and out of the first body and that comprises a support, a flexible display that comprises a first region fixed to the front of the first body, a first connected portion extending from the first fixed portion and a second connected portion that extends from the first extending portion, wherein in a first position the second body is positioned in the first body, the first connected portion of the flexible display is curved around the support and the second connected portion is parallel to the first region fixed and faces backwards, wherein the second body slides out to a second position in which the first connected portion of the flexible display is flat with the first region and the second connected portion is curved around the support, the flexible display device further comprises a cover coupled to a rear of the first body to form a rear surface of the flexible display device and to cover the second connected region when the second body is at the first position, the flexible display device further characterised by comprisinga filter disposed between the first cover and a second cover coupled to the rear of the second body, the filter configured to prevent intrusion of foreign matter.</p><p id="pu0002" num="">2. claims: 6-8<br/>The subject-matter of claims 6 to 8 is directed to a flexible display device comprising a first body and a second body capable of sliding in and out of the first body and that comprises a support, a flexible display that comprises a first region fixed to the front of the first body, a first connected portion extending from the first fixed portion and a second connected portion that extends from the first extending portion, wherein in a first position the second body is positioned in the first body, the first connected portion of the flexible display is curved around the support and the second connected portion is parallel to the first region fixed and faces backwards, wherein the second body slides out to a second position in which the first connected portion of the flexible display is flat with the first region and the second connected portion is curved around the support, the flexible display device further comprises a cover coupled to a rear of the first body to form a rear surface of the flexible display device and to cover the second connected region when the second body is at the first position, the flexible display device further characterised in that the first cover is transparent such that the second connected region is visible at the rear.</p><p id="pu0003" num="">3. claims: 9-13<br/>The subject-matter of claims 9-13 is directed to a flexible display device comprising a first body and a second body capable of sliding in and out of the first body and that comprises a support, a flexible display that comprises a first region fixed to the front of the first body, a first connected portion extending from the first fixed portion and a second connected portion that extends from the first extending portion, wherein in a first position the second body is positioned in the first body, the first connected portion of the flexible display is curved around the support and the second connected portion is parallel to the first region fixed and faces backwards, wherein the second body slides out to a second position in which the first connected portion of the flexible display is flat with the first region and the second connected portion is curved around the support, the flexible display device further comprises a cover coupled to a rear of the first body to form a rear surface of the flexible display device and to cover the second connected region when the second body is at the first position, the flexible display device further characterised in that the first cover is detachably coupled to the first body.</p><srep-search-fees><srep-fee-1/></srep-search-fees></srep-unity-of-invention><srep-invention-title title-approval="yes"/><srep-abstract abs-approval="yes"/><srep-figure-to-publish figinfo="by-applicant"><figure-to-publish><fig-number>2B</fig-number></figure-to-publish></srep-figure-to-publish><srep-info-admin><srep-office><addressbook><text>MN</text></addressbook></srep-office><date-search-report-mailed><date>20210622</date></date-search-report-mailed></srep-info-admin></srep-info><srep-for-pub><srep-fields-searched><minimum-documentation><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr><text>G06F</text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr><text>H04M</text></classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr></minimum-documentation></srep-fields-searched><srep-citations><citation id="sr-cit0001"><patcit dnum="WO2019153818A1" id="sr-pcit0001" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=WO2019153818&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2019153818</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>XIAN ZHONGXING NEW SOFTWARE CO LTD [CN]</name><date>20190815</date></document-id></patcit><category>X</category><rel-claims>1-3</rel-claims><category>Y</category><rel-claims>6-13</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* figures 1-22 *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0002"><patcit dnum="JP2010178188A" id="sr-pcit0002" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=JP2010178188&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2010178188</doc-number><kind>A</kind><name>SOFTBANK MOBILE CORP</name><date>20100812</date></document-id></patcit><category>X</category><rel-claims>1,2,5</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* figures 1-5 *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0003"><patcit dnum="JP2005309086A" id="sr-pcit0003" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=JP2005309086&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2005309086</doc-number><kind>A</kind><name>FUJI PHOTO FILM CO LTD</name><date>20051104</date></document-id></patcit><category>X</category><rel-claims>1-3</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* figures 2,3 *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0004"><patcit dnum="EP3525430A1" id="sr-pcit0004" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=EP3525430&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>3525430</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>GUANGDONG OPPO MOBILE TELECOMMUNICATIONS CORP LTD [CN]</name><date>20190814</date></document-id></patcit><category>A</category><rel-claims>4</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* figures 1-8 *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0005"><patcit dnum="US2013058063A1" id="sr-pcit0005" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=US2013058063&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2013058063</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>O'BRIEN PAUL M [US]</name><date>20130307</date></document-id></patcit><category>Y</category><rel-claims>6-8</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* paragraph [0026]; figures 1,2 *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0006"><patcit dnum="WO2016018300A1" id="sr-pcit0006" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=WO2016018300&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2016018300</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>HEWLETT PACKARD DEVELOPMENT CO [US]</name><date>20160204</date></document-id></patcit><category>A</category><rel-claims>6-8</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* paragraph [0059]; figure 8 *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0007"><patcit dnum="US2017012254A1" id="sr-pcit0007" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=US2017012254&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2017012254</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>TAKAHASHI DAISUKE [JP] ET AL</name><date>20170112</date></document-id></patcit><category>Y</category><rel-claims>9</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* paragraph [0020] - paragraph [0044]; figures 1-4 *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0008"><patcit dnum="US2014037372A1" id="sr-pcit0008" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=US2014037372&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2014037372</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>CHANG FANG-TA [TW] ET AL</name><date>20140206</date></document-id></patcit><category>Y</category><rel-claims>10,11</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* paragraph [0033] - paragraph [0057]; figures 1-8b *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0009"><patcit dnum="WO2019139371A1" id="sr-pcit0009" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=WO2019139371&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2019139371</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>SAMSUNG ELECTRONICS CO LTD [KR]</name><date>20190718</date></document-id></patcit><category>Y</category><rel-claims>12,13</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* paragraph [0068] - paragraph [0078]; figures 3a-4 *</passage></rel-passage></citation></srep-citations><srep-incomplete-search><limitation-of-search reason-type="reasonobscurity" sequence="1"><claims-searched>1-13</claims-searched><claims-not-searched>14, 15</claims-not-searched><reason-limited-search><heading>Reason for the limitation of the search:</heading><p num="1">The search has been restricted to the subject-matter of claims 1-13 as indicated by the applicant in his letter of 19-01-2021 filed in reply to the invitation pursuant to Rule 62a(1) EPC.</p></reason-limited-search></limitation-of-search></srep-incomplete-search><srep-admin><examiners><primary-examiner><name>Alonso Nogueiro, M</name></primary-examiner></examiners><srep-office><addressbook><text>Munich</text></addressbook></srep-office><date-search-completed><date>20210611</date></date-search-completed></srep-admin><!--							The annex lists the patent family members relating to the patent documents cited in the above mentioned European search report.							The members are as contained in the European Patent Office EDP file on							The European Patent Office is in no way liable for these particulars which are merely given for the purpose of information.							For more details about this annex : see Official Journal of the European Patent Office, No 12/82						--><srep-patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2019153818</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20190815</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>CN</country><doc-number>108259649</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20180706</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2021044683</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20210211</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2019153818</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20190815</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2010178188</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20100812</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>5302027</doc-number><kind>B2</kind><date>20131002</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2010178188</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20100812</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2005309086</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20051104</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>4713845</doc-number><kind>B2</kind><date>20110629</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2005309086</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20051104</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>3525430</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20190814</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>CN</country><doc-number>207926663</doc-number><kind>U</kind><date>20180928</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>3525430</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20190814</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2019253533</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20190815</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2019153846</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20190815</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2013058063</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20130307</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>CN</country><doc-number>102902308</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20130130</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2751639</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20140709</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>ES</country><doc-number>2616031</doc-number><kind>T3</kind><date>20170609</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>HK</country><doc-number>1178634</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20130913</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>6151253</doc-number><kind>B2</kind><date>20170621</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2014531796</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20141127</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>KR</country><doc-number>20140059274</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20140515</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>KR</country><doc-number>20190077107</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20190702</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>TW</country><doc-number>201315196</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20130401</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2013058063</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20130307</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2014211399</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140731</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2013033479</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20130307</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2016018300</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20160204</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>CN</country><doc-number>106663392</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20170510</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>3175440</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20170607</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2017212556</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20170727</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2016018300</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20160204</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2017012254</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20170112</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>6149323</doc-number><kind>B2</kind><date>20170621</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2016122590</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20160707</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2017012254</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20170112</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2016104162</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20160630</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2014037372</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140206</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>CN</country><doc-number>103576768</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20140212</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>TW</country><doc-number>201407313</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20140216</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2014037372</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140206</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2019139371</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20190718</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>DE</country><doc-number>202019005676</doc-number><kind>U1</kind><date>20210611</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>3709609</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20200916</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>KR</country><doc-number>20190086305</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20190722</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2020371558</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20201126</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2019139371</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20190718</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family></srep-patent-family></srep-for-pub></search-report-data>
<ep-reference-list id="ref-list">
<heading id="ref-h0001"><b>REFERENCES CITED IN THE DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0001" num=""><i>This list of references cited by the applicant is for the reader's convenience only. It does not form part of the European patent document. Even though great care has been taken in compiling the references, errors or omissions cannot be excluded and the EPO disclaims all liability in this regard.</i></p>
<heading id="ref-h0002"><b>Patent documents cited in the description</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0002" num="">
<ul id="ref-ul0001" list-style="bullet">
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0001" dnum="KR1107127"><document-id><country>KR</country><doc-number>1107127</doc-number></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0001">[0005]</crossref></li>
</ul></p>
</ep-reference-list>
</ep-patent-document>
