<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP19889754A1" file="EP19889754NWA1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3889004" kind="A1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSKBAHRIS..MTNORSMESMMAKHTNMD..........</B001EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  1100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3889004</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT APPLICATION</B121><B121EP>published in accordance with Art. 153(4) EPC</B121EP></B120><B130>A1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>19889754.8</B210><B220><date>20191122</date></B220><B240><B241><date>20210625</date></B241></B240><B250>zh</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B300><B310>201811416723</B310><B320><date>20181126</date></B320><B330><ctry>CN</ctry></B330></B300><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B430></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>B62D   5/04        20060101AFI20200605BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>B62D   6/003       20130101 FI20210707BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>B62D   6/008       20130101 LA20210707BHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>HILFSSTEUERUNGSSYSTEM UND -VERFAHREN FÜR EIN FAHRZEUG</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>AUXILIARY CONTROL SYSTEM AND METHOD FOR A VEHICLE</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>SYSTÈME ET PROCÉDÉ DE COMMANDE AUXILIAIRE POUR UN VÉHICULE</B542></B540><B590><B598>1</B598></B590></B500><B700><B710><B711><snm>Great Wall Motor Company Limited</snm><iid>101712581</iid><irf>K93998-4ch</irf><adr><str>No.2266 Chaoyang South St.</str><city>Baoding, Hebei 071000</city><ctry>CN</ctry></adr></B711></B710><B720><B721><snm>NIU, Xiaofeng</snm><adr><str>2266 Chaoyang South Street</str><city>Baoding, Hebei 071000</city><ctry>CN</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>KONG, Fanmao</snm><adr><str>2266 Chaoyang South Street</str><city>Baoding, Hebei 071000</city><ctry>CN</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>SUN, Yu</snm><adr><str>2266 Chaoyang South Street</str><city>Baoding, Hebei 071000</city><ctry>CN</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>WANG, Binbin</snm><adr><str>2266 Chaoyang South Street</str><city>Baoding, Hebei 071000</city><ctry>CN</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>ZHANG, Huijun</snm><adr><str>2266 Chaoyang South Street</str><city>Baoding, Hebei 071000</city><ctry>CN</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>ZHOU, Wenguo</snm><adr><str>2266 Chaoyang South Street</str><city>Baoding, Hebei 071000</city><ctry>CN</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B740><B741><snm>Klunker IP 
Patentanwälte PartG mbB</snm><iid>101636152</iid><adr><str>Destouchesstraße 68</str><city>80796 München</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840><B844EP><B845EP><ctry>BA</ctry></B845EP><B845EP><ctry>ME</ctry></B845EP></B844EP><B848EP><B849EP><ctry>KH</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>MA</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>MD</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>TN</ctry></B849EP></B848EP><B860><B861><dnum><anum>CN2019120308</anum></dnum><date>20191122</date></B861><B862>zh</B862></B860><B870><B871><dnum><pnum>WO2020108406</pnum></dnum><date>20200604</date><bnum>202023</bnum></B871></B870></B800></SDOBI>
<abstract id="abst" lang="en">
<p id="pa01" num="0001">The embodiment of the invention relates to an auxiliary control system and method for vehicles, and belongs to the field of vehicles. The system may comprise a DSA module and an EPS module, wherein the DSA module is used for performing the following steps: detecting whether the vehicle is in a special working condition; calculating the assist steering torque for the current working condition of the vehicle if the vehicle is in a special working condition; generating a torque overlay request comprising the assist steering torque; and sending the torque overlay request to the EPS module; and the EPS module is used for regulating the steering wheel torque according to the assist steering torque in the torque overlay request. The vehicle can always be in a stable and controllable state through the system so that the vehicle safety and driving comfort are improved.<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="110" he="24" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p>
</abstract>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<heading id="h0001"><b>Technical</b> Field</heading>
<p id="p0001" num="0001">The invention relates to the field of vehicles, and more particularly, to an auxiliary control system and method for vehicles.</p>
<heading id="h0002"><b>Background</b></heading>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">The Electronic Stability Program (ESP) system is able to quickly intervene in the operation of the engines and braking systems in emergency situation where the vehicle is about to be out of control, so that the vehicle can be kept stabilized quickly to ensure the safety of the driver and the vehicle.</p>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">The ESP system mainly consists of three control modules: Antilock Brake System (ABS) module, Traction Control System (TCS) module and Vehicle Dynamic Control (VDC) module.</p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">However, in interactive systems among different Electronic Control Units (ECU) on the vehicle, the ESP system seldom interacts with other systems and usually act as a subsystem, for example the ESP system applies emergency brake for Adaptive Cruise Control system(ACC), and identifies wheel rotating direction and wheel speed for Auto Parking Assistance System (APA).</p>
<heading id="h0003"><b>Summary</b></heading>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">The embodiment of the invention aims to provide an auxiliary control system and method for vehicles, used for at least improving the control strategy of the ESP system.</p>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">In order to achieve the aforementioned purposes, the embodiment of the invention aims to provide an auxiliary control system and method for vehicles. The system comprises a Dynamic Stability Assistant (DSA) module and an Electric Power Steering (EPS) module, wherein, the DSA module is used for performing the<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> following steps: detecting whether the vehicle is in a special working condition; calculating the assist steering torque for the current working condition of the vehicle if the vehicle is in a special working condition; generating a torque overlay request comprising the assist steering torque; and sending the torque overlay request to the EPS module; and the EPS module is used for regulating the steering wheel torque according to the assist steering torque in the torque overlay request.</p>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">Optionally, the DSA module is used for periodically performing the steps; and/or the special working conditions include one or more of the following items: oversteer, understeer, braking on split-mu surface, accelerating on split-mu surface, and cornering with the lateral acceleration which is higher than a predetermined acceleration.</p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">Optionally, the EPS module regulates the steering wheel torque according to the assist steering torque and the gradient of the assist steering torque.</p>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">Optionally, the EPS module is used for: under the condition that the number of accumulated anomalies of the assist steering torque and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque is smaller than the predetermined number, performing the following steps: superimposing the assist steering torque on the steering wheel torque if the assist steering torque and the gradient are normal; calculating the current torque to be superimposed according to the preset gradient value and the latest superimposed torque if the assist steering torque is normal and the gradient is abnormal; and superimposing the preset torque on the steering wheel torque if the assist steering torque is abnormal, but the gradient is normal or abnormal, wherein the superposition direction of the preset torque is the same as that of the assist steering torque; under the condition that the assist steering torque is in the preset torque range, it is determined that the assist steering torque is normal; under the condition that the gradient does not exceed the preset gradient value, it is determined that the gradient is normal; under the condition that the number of accumulated anomalies of the assist steering torque and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque is smaller than the predetermined number, the steering wheel torque does not need to be superimposed.</p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">Optionally, the EPS module calculates the number of accumulated anomalies<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> according to the following steps: if the assist steering torque is abnormal and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque is abnormal, the number of accumulated anomalies is increased by the predetermined value; if the assist steering torque and the gradient of the assist steering torque are both normal, the number of accumulated anomalies is decreased by the predetermined value; wherein, when the assist steering torque and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque shows abnormality for the first time, the number of accumulated anomalies will start to be counted.</p>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">Optionally, in one or more of the followings: under the condition that the number of accumulated anomalies of the assist steering torque and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque is smaller than the predetermined number, the EPS module is kept in the active state, or the EPS module is transferred to the active state from the ready-for-control state; under the condition that the number of accumulated anomalies of the assist steering torque and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque is equal to the predetermined number, the EPS module is transferred to the permanent failure state from the active state; and the preset toque is the maximum or the minimum value of the preset torque range.</p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">Optionally, the EPS module is further used for outputting its current state to the DSA module, and the DSA module is used for sending the torque overlay request to the EPS module under the condition that the EPS module is in either the active state or ready-for-control state.</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">Correspondingly, the embodiment of the invention further provides an auxiliary control method for vehicles. The method comprises: the DSA module performs the following steps: detecting whether the vehicle is in a special working condition; calculating the assist steering torque for the current working condition of the vehicle if the vehicle is in a special working condition; generating a torque overlay request comprising the assist steering torque; and sending the torque overlay request to the EPS module; and the EPS module regulates the steering wheel torque according to the assist steering torque based on the torque overlay request.</p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">Optionally, the DSA module is used for periodically performing the steps; and/or the special working conditions include one or more of the following items:<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> oversteer, understeer, braking on split-mu surface, accelerating on split-mu surface, cornering with the lateral acceleration which is higher than the predetermined acceleration.</p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">Optionally, the EPS module regulates the steering wheel torque according to the assist steering torque and the gradient of the assist steering torque.</p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">Optionally, under the condition that the number of accumulated anomalies of the assist steering torque and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque is smaller than the predetermined number, the EPS module performs the following steps: superimposing the assist steering torque on the steering wheel torque if the assist steering torque and the gradient are normal; calculating the current torque to be superimposed according to the preset gradient value and the latest superimposed torque if the assist steering torque is normal and the gradient is abnormal; and superimposing the preset torque on the steering wheel torque if the assist steering torque is abnormal while the gradient is normal or abnormal, wherein the superposition direction of the preset torque is the same as that of the assist steering torque; under the condition that the assist steering torque is in the preset torque range, it is determined that the assist steering torque is normal; under the condition that the gradient does not exceed the preset gradient value, it is determined that the gradient is normal; under the condition that the number of accumulated anomalies of the assist steering torque and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque is smaller than the predetermined number, the EPS module will not superimpose the steering wheel torque.</p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">Optionally, the EPS module calculates the number of accumulated anomalies: if the assist steering torque and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque is abnormal, the number of accumulated anomalies is increased by the predetermined value; if the assist steering torque and the gradient of the assist steering torque are both normal, the number of accumulated anomalies is decreased by the predetermined value; wherein, when the assist steering torque and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque shows abnormality for the first time, the number of accumulated anomalies start to be counted.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">Optionally, in one or more of the followings: under the condition that the number of accumulated anomalies of the assist steering torque and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque is smaller than the predetermined number, the EPS module is kept in the active state, or the EPS module is transferred to the active state from the ready-for-control state; under the condition that the number of accumulated anomalies of the assist steering torque and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque is equal to the predetermined number, the EPS module is transferred to the permanent failure state from the active state; and the preset toque is the maximum or the minimum value of the preset torque range.</p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">Optionally, the method further comprises the following steps: the EPS module outputs its current state to the DSA module; and the DSA module sends the torque overlay request to the EPS module under the condition that the EPS module is in the active state or ready-for-control state.</p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">Through the aforementioned technical solution, the DSA module calculates the assist steering torque for the special working condition where the vehicle is detected to be under; the ESP module assists the driver in operating the vehicle through the assist steering torque and correcting the dynamic change of the vehicle, so that the vehicle can always be in a stable and controllable state; therefore, the vehicle safety and the ride comfort are improved.</p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">Other characteristics and advantages of the embodiment of the invention will be described in the Detailed Description of the Preferred Embodiments in detail.</p>
<heading id="h0004"><b>Brief Description of the Figures</b></heading>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">The figures provide more details about the embodiments of the invention, and form a part of the description. Such figures, together with the Detailed Description of the Preferred Embodiments below, are used for explaining the embodiments of the invention, but do not constitute the limitation to the embodiments of the invention. In those figures:
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li><figref idref="f0001">FIG.1</figref> shows a structural block diagram of the auxiliary control system for vehicles according to the embodiment of the invention;<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></li>
<li><figref idref="f0001">FIG.2</figref> shows a state transition diagram of the EPS module in the embodiment; and</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">FIG.3</figref> shows a process diagram of the auxiliary control method for vehicles according to the embodiment of the invention.</li>
</ul></p>
<heading id="h0005">Definitions of the markings in figures</heading>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">
<tables id="tabl0001" num="0001">
<table frame="none">
<tgroup cols="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="11mm"/>
<colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="23mm"/>
<colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="11mm"/>
<colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="23mm"/>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry>110</entry>
<entry>DSA module</entry>
<entry>120</entry>
<entry>EPS module</entry></row></tbody></tgroup>
</table>
</tables></p>
<heading id="h0006"><b>Detailed Description of the Preferred Embodiments</b></heading>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">The detailed description of the embodiments of the present invention is given below in combination with the figures. It should be understood that the detailed description explained here is used for describing and explaining the embodiments of the invention only, not for limiting the embodiments of the invention.</p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">When the vehicle runs on a split-mu surface (that is, the left wheels of the vehicle run on a low-mu section while the right wheels run on a high-mu section, or the right wheels run on the low-mu section while the left wheels run on the high-mu section), since the adhesion coefficients of the right and left wheels of the vehicle on the roads are inconsistent, the following two conditions may occur when the vehicle is braked or accelerated on such special roads:
<ol id="ol0001" compact="compact" ol-style="">
<li>(1) In case of braking on the split-mu surface, the brake pressure generated on the high-mu section is higher than that generated on the low-mu section, and consequently the vehicle is subjected to a yaw torque of rotation toward the high-mu section; the yaw torque is increased as the difference in the adhesion coefficients is increased, and the yaw velocity is increased as the braking speed is increased; when the yaw torque and the yaw velocity reach large values, ordinary drivers are hard to control the vehicle steadily;</li>
<li>(2) In case of acceleration on the split-mu surface, the driving force generated on the high-mu section is higher than that generated on the low-mu section, and consequently the vehicle is subjected to the yaw torque of rotation toward the high-mu section and tended to move towards the low-mu section, and the driver needs<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> to correct the steering wheel to ensure that the vehicle runs linearly.</li>
</ol></p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">Under the special conditions, the yaw torque of the vehicle can be reduced with pressure of low friction side of a front axle by the ESP system through control over pressurization and pressure reduction of high friction side of the front axle; in addition, the rear axle can be limited to a certain pressure so as to reduce the risk that the vehicle drifts and assist the vehicle in stabilizing. But under the condition of high-speed braking of the vehicle, the driver still needs to make accurate judgment in advance, and correct the steering wheel to control the vehicle in combination with the ESP system; only through cooperation of the ESP system and the driver, the risk that the vehicle gets out of control can be reduced finally.</p>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">Based on this, the embodiment of the invention provides an auxiliary control systems and method for vehicles, used for assisting the driver in operating the vehicle and correcting the dynamic change of the vehicle under the special working condition, so that the vehicle can always be in a stable and controllable state; therefore, the vehicle safety is improved.</p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028"><figref idref="f0001">FIG.1</figref> shows a structure diagram of the auxiliary control system for the vehicle according to the embodiment of the invention. As shown in <figref idref="f0001">FIG.1</figref>, the embodiment of the invention provides an auxiliary control system for vehicles. The system may comprise a Dynamic Stability Assistant (DSA) module 110 and an Electric Power Steering (EPS) module 120.</p>
<p id="p0029" num="0029">The DSA module 110 can be an internal module of the vehicle ESP system, and the DSA module 110 can be further developed based on hardware of the ESP system. The logical function of the DSA module 110 may be an additional function designed based on the VDC module, ABS module and TCS module in the ESP system, and it can further improve the control strategy of the ESP system.</p>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">In the vehicle running process, the DSA module 110 may detect whether the vehicle is under a special working condition in real time or periodically. The special working conditions comprise one or more of the following items: oversteer, understeer, braking on split-mu surface, accelerating on split-mu surface, and cornering with the lateral acceleration which is higher than the predetermined<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> acceleration.</p>
<p id="p0031" num="0031">The DSA module can identify whether the vehicle is under a special working condition according to the vehicle speed, master cylinder braking pressure, target yaw angle and body slip angle calculated by the ESP system and in combination with the VDS control threshold and TCS trigger threshold. The DSA module may calculate the assist steering torque for the current working condition of the vehicle when detecting that the vehicle is under a special working condition. Specifically, the DSA module 110 can receive the lateral acceleration, steering wheel angle, body yaw angle and other parameters sent by a body sensor; the EPS module 120 can send the detected driver-input torque to the DSA module 110; and the DSA module 110 can calculate the assist steering torque on the basis of the lateral acceleration, steering wheel angle, body yaw angle and driver input torque. For example, a database is established according to the three parameters, namely the lateral acceleration, steering wheel angle and body yaw angle, and a dynamic index is evaluated according to the database. The dynamic index may be used for evaluating the current vehicle stability; the larger the dynamic index is, the more unstable the vehicle will be at present, and the larger torque value is required to assist the driver in operating the vehicle. The required steering wheel torques corresponding to the dynamic indexes one by one can be stored in the DSA module 110. The larger the dynamic index is, the larger the required steering wheel torque is. After the required steering wheel torque is determined according to the dynamic index, the assist steering torque for the current working condition of the vehicle can be calculated in combination with the driver input torque. The calculated assist steering torque can comprise "+" and "-", wherein "+" can be set to show the counterclockwise direction, and "-" shows the clockwise direction; for example, the assist steering torque -1NM indicates that the steering wheel is expected to rotate clockwise with 1NM.</p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032">After the assist steering torque is calculated, the torque overlay request including the assist steering torque is generated. Optionally, the corresponding assist steering torque range can be stored for each special working condition in the DSA module 110, and the torque overlay request is generated under the condition that the<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> calculated assist steering torque is within the corresponding steering torque range. Under the condition that the calculated assist steering torque is beyond the corresponding steering torque range, the torque overlay request is not generated, and the DSA module 110 continues detecting the working condition of the vehicle.</p>
<p id="p0033" num="0033">The DSA module 110 may sends the generated torque overlay request to the ESP module 120; for example, the torque overlay request can be sent to the ESP module 120 through a CAN bus. The EPS module 120 may regulate the steering wheel torque according to the assist steering torque included in the torque overlay request. Optionally, the torque overlay request further includes a torque overlay command request flag. The EPS module 120 may regulate the steering wheel torque based on the assist steering torque under the condition that the torque overlay request comprises the torque overlay command request flag and the assist steering torque. The steering wheel torque is regulated based on the assist steering torque to assist the driver in operating the vehicle and correcting the dynamic change of the vehicle, so that the vehicle can always be in a stable and controllable state; therefore, the vehicle safety is improved.</p>
<p id="p0034" num="0034">Optionally, the function of the DSA module can be enabled and disabled through a switch; for example, the function of the DSA module can be enabled and disabled by the driver. The switch of the DSA module can be a button arranged on a vehicle operating panel, and the driver can enable and disable the DSA module through the button. Or, an option for enabling and disabling the DSA module can be set on a touch screen of the vehicle host system, so as to facilitate the driver to enable and disable the DSA module.</p>
<p id="p0035" num="0035"><figref idref="f0001">FIG.2</figref> shows a state transition diagram of the EPS module in the embodiment. As shown in <figref idref="f0001">FIG.2</figref>, after powering on, the EPS module is firstly initialized; if the initialization is failed, the EPS module will be in the permanent failure state; wherein, under the condition that the EPS module is in the permanent failure state, the EPS module can report an error for anomaly. In the initializing process, the EPS module is in the temporarily prohibited state; if the initialization succeeds, the EPS module turns to the ready-for-control state, and then goes into the<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> active state through effective trigger. The EPS module can be switched to the corresponding state through the switching condition of an internal state machine. The EPS module may transmit its current state to the DSA module; for example, the current state can be represented through "EPS_DSA_ControlSts", and the data transmission between the EPS module and the DSA module is performed through the CAN bus.</p>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">Under the condition that the current state of the EPS module is in the ready-for-control state or the active state, the DSA module sends the torque overlay request to the ESP module. "DSA_Torque_Request" may be used for representing the assist steering torque calculated through the DSA module in the superposition request, and "DSA_Active" is used for representing the torque overlay command request flag. The EPS module will regulate the steering wheel torque according to the received assist steering torque and the gradient of the assist steering torque.</p>
<p id="p0037" num="0037">Specifically, the EPS module may regulate the steering wheel torque according to the situation whether the received assist steering torque is normal, the gradient of the assist steering torque is normal, and the number of accumulated anomalies of the gradient of the assist steering torque. Under the condition that the assist steering torque is in the preset torque range, it is determined that the assist steering torque is normal; Under the condition that the assist steering torque is beyond the preset torque range, it is determined that the assist steering torque is abnormal; wherein, the preset torque range can be set to any proper values according to the actual conditions; for example, the preset torque range can be set to -3Nm∼+3Nm, wherein the two endpoints -3Nm and +3Nm are included. Under the condition that the gradient does not exceed the preset gradient value, it is determined that the gradient is normal; under the condition that the gradient exceeds the preset gradient value, it is determined that the gradient is abnormal, wherein the preset gradient value can be set to any proper value according to the actual conditions, and the preset gradient value of the different types of vehicle can be different. For example, the preset gradient value can be set to 10Nm/s. The difference between the assist steering torque received currently and the assist steering torque received previously can be obtained by<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> subtracting the assist steering torque received previously from the assist steering torque received currently, and then the difference divided by the time difference between the assist steering torque received currently and the assist steering torque received previously equals to the gradient of the assist steering torque, or the difference between the assist steering torque received currently and the torque superimposed on the steering wheel through the EPS module previously can be obtained by subtracting the torque superimposed on the steering wheel previously from the assist steering torque received currently, and then the difference divided by the time difference between the assist steering torque received currently and the assist steering torque received previously equals to the gradient of the assist steering torque.</p>
<p id="p0038" num="0038">The anomaly monitoring and counting function can be enabled through the EPS module for monitoring the number of accumulated anomalies, that is, the EPS module is in the active or ready-for-control state, since the assist steering torque and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque received by the DSA module is abnormal, the number of accumulated anomalies start to be counted.</p>
<p id="p0039" num="0039">When the assist steering torque and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque shows abnormality for the first time, the number of accumulated anomalies start to be counted; for example, in case of anomaly for the first time, the number of accumulated anomalies can be recorded and is equal to 1. In the accumulation process, if the assist steering torque is abnormal and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque is abnormal, the number of accumulated anomalies is increased by the predetermined value; if the assist steering torque and the gradient of the assist steering torque are both normal, the number of accumulated anomalies is decreased by the predetermined value. Wherein, the predetermined value can be set to any proper value according to the requirements, and examples are given in the embodiment of the invention by taking the predetermined value as 1.</p>
<p id="p0040" num="0040">The following is an illustration for calculation of the number of accumulated anomalies by taking the predetermined value as 1.</p>
<p id="p0041" num="0041">When the EPS module monitors and detects that either the assist steering torque or the gradient of the assist steering torque received from the DSA module<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> shows abnormality for the first time, the number of accumulated anomalies start to be counted and at the moment, the number of accumulated anomalies is recorded as 1. The EPS module continuously monitors the assist steering torque and the gradient of the assist steering torque received from the DSA module.</p>
<p id="p0042" num="0042">When the EPS module monitors that either the assist steering torque or the gradient of the assist steering torque received from the DSA module shows abnormality once more, the number of accumulated anomalies is recorded as 1+1=2. When either the assist steering torque or the gradient of the assist steering torque shows abnormality for the third time, the number of accumulated anomalies is recorded as 1+1+1=3, and so on; wherein, as long as any one of the assist steering torque and the gradient of the assist steering torque shows abnormality, the number of accumulated anomalies is accounted. When the EPS module monitors that the assist steering torque and the gradient of the assist steering torque received from the DSA module are both abnormal, the number of accumulated anomalies is recorded as 1+1+1-1=2.</p>
<p id="p0043" num="0043">The number of accumulated anomalies can be increased or decreased through the EPS module according to the aforementioned control strategies and whether the assist steering torque and the gradient of the assist steering torque received from the DSA module currently is abnormal or normal.</p>
<p id="p0044" num="0044">Under the condition that the number of accumulated anomalies is smaller than the predetermined number, according to the situation whether the assist steering torque and the gradient of the assist steering torque received from the DSA module currently is abnormal or normal, different steps can be performed through the EPS module.</p>
<p id="p0045" num="0045">If the assist steering torque and the gradient of the assist steering torque are both normal, then the steering wheel torque is superimposed by the assist steering torque received from the DSA module.</p>
<p id="p0046" num="0046">If the assist steering torque is normal, but the gradient of the assist steering torque is abnormal, then the torque to be superimposed currently can be deduced with the above-mentioned gradient calculation method according to the preset gradient<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> value and the latest superimposed torque. For example, if the preset gradient value is k=10Nm/S, the torque superimposed on the steering wheel last time through the ESP module is T<sub>or1</sub> = +0.78Nm; the time difference between the assist steering torques received currently and previously is ΔT=0.2S, and the currently superimposed torque is T<sub>or0</sub>=k* ΔT + T<sub>or1</sub> =10Nm/S*0.2S + (+0.78Nm)=+2.78 Nm.</p>
<p id="p0047" num="0047">If the assist steering torque is abnormal but the gradient of the assist steering torque is either normal or abnormal, then the steering wheel torque is superimposed by the preset torque, and the superposition direction of the preset torque is consistent with that of the assist steering torque received from the DSA module. The preset torque in the embodiment of this invention can be any proper value determined according to the actual requirements, and is optional; the preset torque can be set to the maximum or the minimum value of the preset torque range. For example, if the preset torque range can be set to -3Nm∼+3Nm, wherein the two endpoints -3Nm and +3Nm are included, while the assist steering torque that the EPS module receives from the DSA module is -5Nm, after the EPS module detects that the assist steering torque is abnormal, whatever the gradient of the assist torque is normal or abnormal, the torque of -3Nm can be superimposed on the steering wheel; if the assist steering torque that the EPS module receives from the DSA module is +5Nm, after the EPS module detects that the assist steering torque is abnormal, whatever the gradient of the assist torque is normal or abnormal, the torque of +3Nm can be superimposed on the steering wheel.</p>
<p id="p0048" num="0048">Under the condition that the number of accumulated anomalies is smaller than the predetermined number, the torque can be superimposed on the steering wheel according to the aforementioned strategies through the EPS module, so that the auxiliary adjustment of the steering wheel is more linear and stable.</p>
<p id="p0049" num="0049">Furthermore, under the condition that the number of accumulated anomalies is smaller than the predetermined number, the EPS module can be kept in the active state, or the EPS module can be transferred to the active state from the ready-for-control state. Wherein, if the EPS module is in the ready-for-control state currently and receives the assist steering torque from the DSA module, it is<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> determined that the number of accumulated anomalies is smaller than the predetermined number, and the EPS can be transferred from the ready-for-control state to the active state.</p>
<p id="p0050" num="0050">If it is determined that the current number of accumulated anomalies is equal to the predetermined number after the EPS module receives the assist steering torque from the DSA module, the EPS module may not regulate the steering wheel torque, and the EPS module may be transferred to the permanent failure state from the active state; under such conditions, the EPS module can report errors for the anomaly. The predetermined value in the embodiment of the invention can be set to any proper value according to the actual requirements, and examples are given in the embodiment of the invention by taking the predetermined value as 5.</p>
<p id="p0051" num="0051">Table 1 shows a logic for the ESP module to report errors and anomalies in the embodiment; in the anomaly option of Table 1, the value "1" represents anomaly, and the value "0" represents no anomaly; in the error option, the value "0" represents that the errors are not reported, and the value "1" represents that the errors are reported. Through the logic shown in Table 1, it can indicate the robustness requirement of the DSA module function system. It should be understood that Table 1 is used as an example but not a limitation to this invention, and the table of anomalies can be any table with SN unrestricted.
<tables id="tabl0002" num="0002">
<table frame="all">
<title>Table 1</title>
<tgroup cols="14">
<colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="23mm"/>
<colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="8mm"/>
<colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="8mm"/>
<colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="8mm"/>
<colspec colnum="5" colname="col5" colwidth="8mm"/>
<colspec colnum="6" colname="col6" colwidth="8mm"/>
<colspec colnum="7" colname="col7" colwidth="8mm"/>
<colspec colnum="8" colname="col8" colwidth="8mm"/>
<colspec colnum="9" colname="col9" colwidth="8mm"/>
<colspec colnum="10" colname="col10" colwidth="8mm"/>
<colspec colnum="11" colname="col11" colwidth="8mm"/>
<colspec colnum="12" colname="col12" colwidth="9mm"/>
<colspec colnum="13" colname="col13" colwidth="9mm"/>
<colspec colnum="14" colname="col14" colwidth="9mm"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry valign="top">SN</entry>
<entry valign="top">0</entry>
<entry valign="top">1</entry>
<entry valign="top">2</entry>
<entry valign="top">3</entry>
<entry valign="top">4</entry>
<entry valign="top">5</entry>
<entry valign="top">6</entry>
<entry valign="top">7</entry>
<entry valign="top">8</entry>
<entry valign="top">9</entry>
<entry valign="top">10</entry>
<entry valign="top">11</entry>
<entry valign="top">12</entry></row></thead>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry>Anomaly</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry></row>
<row>
<entry>Account</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>2</entry>
<entry>3</entry>
<entry>2</entry>
<entry>3</entry>
<entry>2</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>2</entry>
<entry>3</entry>
<entry>4</entry>
<entry>5</entry></row>
<row>
<entry>Report Errors</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1</entry></row></tbody></tgroup>
</table>
</tables></p>
<p id="p0052" num="0052">The auxiliary control system for the vehicle, provided by the embodiment of the invention, has the following advantages: (1) based on the function of the arranged DSA module, an interaction framework between the ESP system and the EPS module is proposed for the first time, and the defect that the interaction function of the ESP and EPS systems is not configured on the current automobile market is overcame; (2)<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> the higher performance and safety requirements of customers for the vehicle performance are met, so that the interaction of vehicle control units is more flexible; the DSA module sends commands to the EPS module to assist the driver in operating the vehicle, and the vehicle driving safety and comfort are improved; (2) the anomaly monitoring logical strategy is set for the EPS module, and the strategy makes up the blank of the current torque monitoring logic; the robustness is extremely high and more reliable; (3) the control logic provided by the embodiment of the invention can be applied to more common special working conditions, such as snowy days in Northeast China or rainy environment in South China, in the scenarios of running on packed snow or wet surfaces and dry asphalt roads; after the DSA module is started, the system can assist the driver in operating the vehicle, and the driver can drive the vehicle at will; (4) the control logic provided by the embodiment of the invention embodies vehicle function development rationality and intelligent design level, and the competitiveness of Chinese vehicles against foreign-brand and joint venture-brand vehicles is improved; the performance level and capability of the Chinese vehicles can be fully shown.</p>
<p id="p0053" num="0053"><figref idref="f0002">FIG.3</figref> shows a process diagram of the auxiliary control system for the vehicle according to the embodiment of the invention. As shown in <figref idref="f0002">FIG.3</figref>, the embodiment of the invention further provides an auxiliary control method for vehicles. The method may comprise: the DSA module performs the following steps: S302, detecting whether the vehicle is in a special working condition; S304, calculating the assist steering torque for the current working condition of the vehicle if the vehicle is in a special working condition; S306, generating a torque overlay request comprising the assist steering torque; and S308, sending the torque overlay request to the EPS module; and the EPS module performs S310 (the EPS module regulates the steering wheel torque according to the assist steering torque in the torque overlay request). The steering wheel torque is regulated based on the assist steering torque to assist the driver in operating the vehicle and correcting the dynamic change of the vehicle, so that the vehicle can always be in a stable and controllable state; therefore, the vehicle safety is improved.<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></p>
<p id="p0054" num="0054">The specific working principles and advantages of the auxiliary control method for the vehicle, provided by the embodiment of the invention, are similar to those of the auxiliary control system for the vehicle, provided by the embodiment of the invention, which will not be described in detail here.</p>
<p id="p0055" num="0055">The detailed description of the optional implementation modes of the embodiments of the invention is given in combination with the figures, but the embodiments of the invention is not limited to the specific details of the above implementation modes; in the scope of the technical concept of the embodiments of the invention, the technical scheme of the embodiments of the invention can be varied simply; these simple variations all in the protection scope of the embodiments of the invention.</p>
<p id="p0056" num="0056">Additionally, it should be noted that the specific technical features described in the specific implementation modes can be combined in any proper mode under the condition of no contradiction. In order to avoid unnecessary repetition, the possible combination modes in the embodiments of the invention are not described any more.</p>
<p id="p0057" num="0057">Those skilled in the art can understand that all or a part of the steps in the above embodiments can be completed by instructing related hardware through a program; the program is stored in a storage medium and comprising a plurality of instructions for enabling a single chip microcomputer, a chip or a processor to execute all or a part of the steps of the method stated in the embodiments of the application. The above-mentioned storage medium comprises a USB disk, a mobile hard disk drive, a Read-Only Memory (ROM), a Random Access Memory (RAM), a disk or a compact disc and other various media which can store program codes.</p>
<p id="p0058" num="0058">In addition, various implementation modes of the embodiments of the invention can be further combined randomly, as long as the combination does not violate the concept of the embodiments of the invention, and shall be regarded as the content disclosed by the embodiments of the invention.</p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> -->
<claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>An auxiliary control system for vehicles, <b>characterized in that</b>, the system comprises a Dynamic Stability Assistant (DSA) module and an Electric Power Steering (EPS) module;
<claim-text>the DSA module is configured for performing the following steps: detecting whether the vehicle is in a special working condition; calculating an assist steering torque for a current working condition of the vehicle in the case that the vehicle is in a special working condition; generating a torque overlay request comprising the assist steering torque; and sending the torque overlay request to the EPS module; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the EPS module is configured for regulating the steering wheel torque according to the assist steering torque in the torque overlay request.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>The system according to claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b>,
<claim-text>the DSA module is configured for periodically performing the multiple steps; and/or</claim-text>
<claim-text>the special working conditions comprise one or more of the following items: oversteer, understeer, braking on split-mu surface, accelerating on split-mu surface, cornering with the lateral acceleration which is higher than a predetermined acceleration.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>The system according to claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b>, the EPS module regulates the steering wheel torque according to the assist steering torque and a gradient of the assist steering torque.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>The system, according to claim 3, <b>characterized in that</b> the EPS module is configured for:
<claim-text>in the case that a number of accumulated anomalies of the assist steering torque and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque is smaller than a predetermined number, performing the following steps: superimposing the assist steering torque on the steering wheel torque if the assist steering torque and the gradient are normal; calculating the current torque to be superimposed according to a preset gradient value and a latest superimposed torque if the assist steering torque is normal and the<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> gradient is abnormal; and superimposing a preset torque on the steering wheel torque if the assist steering torque is abnormal but the gradient is normal or abnormal, wherein a superposition direction of the preset torque is the same as that of the assist steering torque; in the case that the assist steering torque is in a preset torque range, determining that the assist steering torque is normal; in the case that the gradient does not exceed the preset gradient value, determining that the gradient is normal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>in the case that the number of accumulated anomalies of the assist steering torque and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque is equal to the predetermined number, not superposing the steering wheel torque.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>The system according to claim 4, <b>characterized in that</b>, the EPS module calculates the number of accumulated anomalies according to the following steps:
<claim-text>if the assist steering torque is abnormal and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque is abnormal, increasing the number of accumulated anomalies by the predetermined value; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>if the assist steering torque and the gradient of the assist steering torque are both abnormal, decreasing the number of accumulated anomalies by the predetermined value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, when the assist steering torque and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque shows abnormality for the first time, starting to count the number of accumulated anomalies.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>The system according to claim 4 or 5, <b>characterized in that</b>, in one or more of the following features:
<claim-text>in the case that the number of accumulated anomalies of the assist steering torque and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque is smaller than the predetermined number, the EPS module is kept in the active state, or the EPS module is transferred to the active state from the ready-for-control state;</claim-text>
<claim-text>in the case that the number of accumulated anomalies of the assist steering torque and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque is equal to the predetermined number, the EPS module is transferred to the permanent failure state from the active state; and<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>the preset toque is a maximum value or a minimum value of the preset torque range.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>The system according to claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b>, the EPS module is further configured for outputting its current state to the DSA module, and the DSA module is configured to send the torque overlay request to the EPS module in the case that the EPS module is in the active state or ready-for-control state.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>An auxiliary control method for vehicles, <b>characterized in that</b>, the method comprises:
<claim-text>performing the following steps by the DSA module: detecting whether the vehicle is in a special working condition; calculating an assist steering torque for a current working condition of the vehicle in the case that the vehicle is in a special working condition; generating a torque overlay request comprising the assist steering torque; sending the torque overlay request to the EPS module; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>regulating, by the EPS module, the torque of the steering wheel according to the assist steering torque in the torque overlay request.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>The method according to claim 8, <b>characterized in that</b>,
<claim-text>the DSA module is configured for periodically performing the multiple steps; and/or</claim-text>
<claim-text>the special working conditions comprise one or more of the following items: oversteer, understeer, braking on split-mu surface, accelerating on split-mu surface. cornering with the lateral acceleration which is higher than a predetermined acceleration.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>The method according to claim 8, <b>characterized in that</b>, the EPS module regulates the steering wheel torque according to the assist steering torque and a gradient of the assist steering torque.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>The method according to claim 8, <b>characterized in that</b>,
<claim-text>in the case that the number of anomalies of the assist steering torque and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque is smaller than a predetermined number, performing the following steps by the EPS module: superposing superimposing the assist steering torque on the steering wheel torque if the assist steering torque and the<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> gradient are normal; calculating the current torque to be superimposed according to a preset gradient value and a latest superimposed torque if the assist steering torque is normal and the gradient is abnormal; and superimposing a preset torque on the steering wheel torque if the assist steering torque is abnormal but the gradient is normal or abnormal, wherein a superposition direction of the preset torque is the same as that of the assist steering torque; in the case that the assist steering torque is in a preset torque range, determining that the assist steering torque is normal; in the case that the gradient does not exceed the preset gradient value, determining that the gradient is normal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>in the case that the number of accumulated anomalies of the assist steering torque and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque is equal to the predetermined number, not superposing the steering wheel torque.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>The method according to claim 11, <b>characterized in that</b>, the EPS module calculates the number of accumulated anomalies according to the following steps:
<claim-text>if the assist steering torque and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque is abnormal, increasing the number of accumulated anomalies by the predetermined value; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>if the assist steering torque and the gradient of the assist steering torque are both abnormal, decreasing the number of accumulated anomalies by the predetermined value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, when the assist steering torque and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque shows abnormality for the first time, starting to count the number of accumulated anomalies.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>The method according to claim 11 or 12, <b>characterized in that</b>, in one or more of the following features:
<claim-text>in the case that the number of accumulated anomalies of the assist steering torque and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque is smaller than the predetermined number, keeping the EPS module in the active state, or switching the EPS module to the active state from the ready-for-control state;<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>in the case that the number of accumulated anomalies of the assist steering torque and/or the gradient of the assist steering torque is equal to the predetermined number, switching the EPS module to the permanent failure state from the active state; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the preset toque is a maximum value or a minimum value of the preset torque range.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>The method according to claim 8, <b>characterized in that</b>, the method further comprises:
<claim-text>outputting, by the EPS module outputs, a current state of the EPS module to the DSA module; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting, by the DSA module, the torque overlay request to the EPS module, in the case that the EPS module is in the active state or ready-for-control state.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1,2"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="109" he="113" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="3"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="163" he="102" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<search-report-data id="srep" lang="en" srep-office="EP" date-produced=""><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="157" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="157" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data>
</ep-patent-document>
