<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP19890724A1" file="EP19890724NWA1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3889165" kind="A1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSKBAHRIS..MTNORSMESMMAKHTNMD..........</B001EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  1100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3889165</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT APPLICATION</B121><B121EP>published in accordance with Art. 153(4) EPC</B121EP></B120><B130>A1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>19890724.8</B210><B220><date>20191128</date></B220><B240><B241><date>20210527</date></B241></B240><B250>ko</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B300><B310>20180150436</B310><B320><date>20181129</date></B320><B330><ctry>KR</ctry></B330></B300><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B430></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>C07K  14/005       20060101AFI20200605BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="2"><text>A23K  20/147       20160101ALI20200605BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="3"><text>A61K  39/205       20060101ALI20200605BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="4"><text>A61K  39/00        20060101ALI20200605BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>IMPFSTOFFZUSAMMENSETZUNG ZUR VORBEUGUNG VON TOLLWUT UND HERSTELLUNGSVERFAHREN DAFÜR</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>VACCINE COMPOSITION FOR PREVENTING RABIES, AND PREPARATION METHOD THEREFOR</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>COMPOSITION DE VACCIN ANTIRABIQUE ET SON PROCÉDÉ DE PRÉPARATION</B542></B540><B590><B598>5</B598></B590></B500><B700><B710><B711><snm>Bioapplications Inc.</snm><iid>101786396</iid><irf>60.129.155232</irf><adr><str>(Jigok-dong, Pohang Technopark) 
394, Jigok-ro 
Nam-gu</str><city>Pohang-si, Gyeongsangbuk-do 37668</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B711><B711><snm>Republic of Korea (Animal and 
Plant Quarantine Agency)</snm><iid>101707651</iid><irf>60.129.155232</irf><adr><str>177 Hyeoksin 8-ro</str><city>Gimcheon-si, Gyeongsangbuk-do 39660</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B711></B710><B720><B721><snm>LEE, Yong Jik</snm><adr><str>1001 Technoville, 394, Jigok-ro, Nam-gu</str><city>Pohang-Si, Gyeongsangbuk-do 37668</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>LEE, Sangmin</snm><adr><str>302-306, 88, Hyoseong-ro, Nam-gu</str><city>Pohang-Si, Gyeongsangbuk-do 37835</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>SONG, Jae-Young</snm><adr><str>206-602, 34, Burim-ro, Dongan-gu</str><city>Anyang-si, Gyeonggi-do 14101</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>OUH, In-Ohk</snm><adr><str>106-1001, 46, Hyeoksin 4-ro</str><city>Gimcheon-si, Gyeongsangbuk-do 39660</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>CHO, Soo Dong</snm><adr><str>502, 31, Anyang-ro 343beon-gil, Manan-gu</str><city>Anyang-si, Gyeonggi-do 14005</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>PARK, Seyeon</snm><adr><str>C-302, 2083-16, Yeongnam-daero</str><city>Gimcheon-si Gyeongsangbuk-do 39646</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>KANG, Beong Sul</snm><adr><str>112-6, Geumsansunhwan-ro, Geumsan-myeon</str><city>Jinju-si, Gyeongsangnam-do 52625</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>YANG, Dong-Kun</snm><adr><str>721-901, 119, Gwangjeong-ro</str><city>Gunpo-si, Gyeonggi-do 15825</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>KIM, Ha-Hyun</snm><adr><str>305-1003, 10, Yongjeon 3-ro</str><city>Gimcheon-si, Gyeongsangbuk-do 39660</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B740><B741><snm>Dehns</snm><iid>101728904</iid><adr><str>St. Bride's House 
10 Salisbury Square</str><city>London EC4Y 8JD</city><ctry>GB</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840><B844EP><B845EP><ctry>BA</ctry></B845EP><B845EP><ctry>ME</ctry></B845EP></B844EP><B848EP><B849EP><ctry>KH</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>MA</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>MD</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>TN</ctry></B849EP></B848EP><B860><B861><dnum><anum>KR2019016569</anum></dnum><date>20191128</date></B861><B862>ko</B862></B860><B870><B871><dnum><pnum>WO2020111814</pnum></dnum><date>20200604</date><bnum>202023</bnum></B871></B870></B800></SDOBI>
<abstract id="abst" lang="en">
<p id="pa01" num="0001">The present invention relates to: a rabies virus glycoprotein comprising an amino acid sequence represented by SEQ ID NO: 2; a recombinant vector for producing the glycoprotein; a transformant comprising the vector; and a vaccine composition comprising the rabies glycoprotein, and the like.<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="71" he="76" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p>
</abstract>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<heading id="h0001">[Technical Field]</heading>
<p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a rabies virus glycoprotein comprising an amino acid sequence represented by SEQ ID NO: 2 and a vaccine composition for preventing rabies, including the glycoprotein as an active ingredient.</p>
<heading id="h0002">[Background Art]</heading>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">As rabies is a disease that occurs when animals carrying the rabies virus bite people, many people are exposed to the rabies virus because not only various animals living in the wild but also pets carry the rabies virus, and 70,000 or more people are reported to die from rabies every year. Recently, the incidence of rabies caused by pets has decreased sharply by regularly vaccinating pets, but forest-type propagation generated by wild animals such as raccoons and badgers is still maintained.</p>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">Meanwhile, vaccines for preventing such rabies are being produced using mainly animal cells without using bacteria due to problems such as protein folding and glycosylation. However, for a vaccine production method using animal cells, the vaccine is not easy to be produced because it costs a lot to expand the equipment for mass production, and in most cases, the vaccine price is high. Further, inactivated rabies virus vaccines prepared using animal cells have disadvantages of not only being difficult to store, but also being highly likely to be contaminated with viruses that can infect animals. However, unlike animal cells, plants are extremely unlikely<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> to be contaminated with viruses that can infect animals, and a vaccine can be mass-produced at any time as long as a cultivation area is secured and can be stored for a long period of time through a plant body, so that it is expected that an inexpensive vaccine can be stably produced (<patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="KR1020130111581"><text>Korean Patent Application Laid-Open No. 10-2013-0111581</text></patcit>).</p>
<heading id="h0003">[Disclosure]</heading>
<heading id="h0004">[Technical Problem]</heading>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">The present invention has been derived in order to solve the problems in the related art as described above, and an object thereof is to provide a recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein that can be efficiently produced using a plant body and shows high immunogenicity and virus neutralizing ability, a vaccine composition including the same, a method for preparing the glycoprotein, and the like.</p>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">However, the technical problems which the present invention intends to solve are not limited to the technical problems which have been mentioned above, and other technical problems which have not been mentioned will be clearly understood by a person with ordinary skill in the art to which the present invention pertains from the following description.</p>
<heading id="h0005">[Technical Solution]</heading>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">The present invention provides a rabies virus glycoprotein comprising an amino acid sequence represented by SEQ ID NO: 2. The rabies virus glycoprotein also includes functional equivalents of the amino acid sequence represented by SEQ ID NO: 2 within the scope of the present invention, the functional equivalent has, as a result of addition, substitution, or deletion of an amino acid, a sequence homology<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> of at least 60% or more, preferably 70% or more, more preferably 80% or more, and most preferably 90% or more with the amino acid sequence, and refers to a polypeptide showing substantially the same activity as that of the amino acid sequence represented by SEQ ID NO: 2, and is not limited thereto as long as the amino acid sequence is an amino acid sequence of a rabies virus glycoprotein which can be stably produced using a plant body.</p>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">In addition, the present invention provides a vaccine composition for preventing rabies and a feed composition for preventing rabies, comprising the rabies virus glycoprotein as an active ingredient.</p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">Furthermore, the present invention provides a method for preventing or treating rabies by administering the rabies virus glycoprotein to an individual.</p>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">Further, the present invention provides a use of the rabies virus glycoprotein for preventing or treating rabies.</p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">In addition, the present invention provides a vector for expressing a rabies virus glycoprotein, comprising a polynucleotide encoding an amino acid sequence represented by SEQ ID NO: 2. The polynucleotide is preferably a polynucleotide sequence represented by SEQ ID NO: 1.</p>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">In an exemplary embodiment of the present invention, the vector may be sequentially linked so as to be operable in a sequence of a promoter gene and a polynucleotide encoding an amino acid sequence represented by SEQ ID NO: 2.</p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">In another exemplary embodiment of the present invention, the promoter is a cauliflower mosaic virus-derived 35S promoter, a cauliflower mosaic virus-derived 19S RNA promoter, an actin protein promoter of a plant, a ubiquitin protein promoter, a cytomegalovirus (CMV) promoter, a simian virus 40 (SV40) promoter, a respiratory syncytial virus (RSV) promoter, an elongation factor-1 alpha (EF-1α)<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> promoter, an pEMU promoter, a Mannopine synthase (MAS) promoter, a histone promoter, a Clp promoter, and the like, but is not limited thereto.</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">In still another exemplary embodiment of the present invention, the recombinant expression vector may further include a polynucleotide encoding a chaperone binding protein (BiP), a gene encoding a His-Asp-Glu-Leu (HDEL) peptide, a gene encoding four or more consecutive histidines, and the like.</p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">Furthermore, the present invention provides a transgenic organism transformed with the vector.</p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">In an exemplary embodiment of the present invention, the transgenic organisms may be microorganisms such as <i>Escherichia coli</i>, <i>Bacillus</i>, <i>Salmonella</i>, and yeast, animal cells including insect cells and human cells, animals such as a mouse, a rat, a dog, a monkey, a pig, a horse, and a cow, <i>Agrobacterium tumefaciens,</i> a plant, and the like, the plant may be food crops including rice, wheat, barley, corn, soybean, potato, wheat, red bean, oats, and sorghum; vegetable crops including thale-cress, Chinese cabbage, white radish, peppers, strawberry, tomatoes, watermelon, cucumber, cabbage, oriental melon, pumpkin, spring onion, onion, and carrot; specialty crops including ginseng, tobacco, cotton, sesame, sugarcane, sugar beet, perilla, peanut, and rapeseed; fruits including apples, pears, jujubes, peaches, grapes, tangerines, persimmons, plums, apricots, and bananas; flowering plants including roses, carnations, chrysanthemums, lilies, and tulips, and the like, but is not limited thereto as long as it may be an organism which may be transformed with the vector of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">Further, the present invention provides a method for producing a rabies virus glycoprotein, the method including: (a) culturing the transgenic organism; and (b) isolating a rabies virus glycoprotein from the transgenic organism or culture solution<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> and purifying the isolated rabies virus glycoprotein. The transgenic organism may be preferably a cell itself, a plant body, or a culture product including the cell, and the culture solution may be preferably a culture solution from which cells are removed after the cells are cultured, but is not limited thereto as long as it includes a recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein of the present invention.</p>
<heading id="h0006">[Advantageous Effect]</heading>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">Since the rabies virus glycoprotein according to the present invention is not only effectively expressed in a plant body, but also has high solubility and thus is easy to isolate and purify, a rabies virus glycoprotein can be mass-produced at low cost, so that it is expected that the rabies virus glycoprotein according to the present invention can be widely used in various fields in which a rabies virus glycoprotein is used. Further, the rabies virus glycoprotein according to the present invention can also be used as a novel rabies vaccine composition because it exhibits remarkable immunogenicity and virus neutralizing ability in the body.</p>
<heading id="h0007">[Description of Drawings]</heading>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li><figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a view illustrating the arrangement of genes for expressing a recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0001">FIG. 2</figref> is a view illustrating the results of confirming the solubility of a recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein according to an embodiment of the present invention by western blotting.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">FIG. 3</figref> is a view illustrating the results confirmed by SDS-PAGE after isolating a recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein according to an exemplary<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> embodiment of the present invention and purifying the isolated recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 4</figref> is a view illustrating the results of confirming whether a recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention is glycosylated.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0004">FIG. 5</figref> is a view illustrating the results of confirming the immunogenicity of a recombinant rabies virus according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</li>
</ul></p>
<heading id="h0008">[Modes of the Invention]</heading>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">In the present invention, it was confirmed that when a rabies virus glycoprotein gene represented by SEQ ID NO: 1 was used, a rabies virus glycoprotein having high immunogenicity and virus neutralizing ability could be efficiently produced and isolated even in a plant body. Therefore, since the rabies virus glycoprotein of the present invention can be stably and efficiently mass-produced, it is expected that an inexpensive and stable rabies vaccine can be provided.</p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">As used herein, the "antigen" generally refers to all materials that cause an immune response in the body, and is preferably a virus, a chemical, a bacterium, pollen, a cancer cell, shrimp, and the like or a partial peptide or protein thereof, but is not limited thereto as long as it is a material that may cause an immune response in the body.</p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">As used herein, "rabies virus" refers to the most well-known pathogen of <i>Rhabdoviridae</i> and belongs to the genus <i>Lyssavirus</i>, the genome of <i>Rhabdoviridae</i><!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> consists of a non-segmented negative single-stranded RNA of about 11 to 15 kb, and five genes are arranged in the order of 3' -N (nucleoprotein)-P (phosphoprotein)-M (matrix protein)-G (glycoprotein)-L (polymerase)- 5'. The rabies virus has a bullet-shaped outer capsid, and the outer capsid portion consists of a bilayer lipid membrane containing a glycoprotein (G) and a matrix protein (M). The glycoprotein is preferably represented by an amino acid sequence represented by SEQ ID NO: 2. Further, the glycoprotein of the present invention includes a variant of SEQ ID NO: 1 within the scope of the present invention. Specifically, the gene may include a base sequence having a sequence homology of 70 % or more, more preferably 80 %, or most preferably 90 % or more with a base sequence of SEQ ID No. 1.</p>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">As used herein, "vaccine" is a biological preparation containing an antigen that causes an immune response in an organism, and refers to an immunogen that induces immunity in an organism by injection or oral administration into a human or animal for prevention of an infectious disease. The animal is a human or non-human animal, and the non-human animal refers to a pig, a cow, a horse, a dog, a goat, sheep, and the like, but is not limited thereto.</p>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">As used herein, the "expression vector" refers to a vector capable of expressing a peptide or protein encoded by a foreign nucleic acid inserted in the vector, preferably a vector prepared so as to express a target antigen to which a porcine Fc fragment is fused. The "vector" refers to any medium for the introduction and/or transfer of a base into a host cell <i>in vitro, ex vivo,</i> or <i>in vivo</i>, and may be a replicon to which another DNA fragment may be bound to bring about the replication of the bound fragment, and the "replicon" refers to any genetic unit (for example, a plasmid, a phage, a cosmid, a chromosome, a virus, and the like) that functions as an autonomous unit of DNA replication <i>in vivo</i>, that is, one which is capable of<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> replication under its own control. The recombinant expression vector of the present invention may include, preferably, a promoter that is a transcription initiation factor to which RNA polymerase binds, any operator sequence for regulating transcription, a sequence encoding a suitable mRNA ribosome binding site, a sequence regulating termination of transcription and translation, a terminator, and the like, more preferably, may further include a 5' UTR site gene of M17 for increasing the synthesis amount of a protein, a BiP gene for transferring a target protein to the endoplasmic reticulum, an HDEL gene for minimizing the degradation of a protein such that the protein may be stably maintained in the endoplasmic reticulum, and the like, and even more preferably, may further include a selection marker gene such as a tag gene for easily isolating a recombinant protein and an antibiotic resistance gene for selecting a transgenic organism, and the like.</p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">The tag gene may include, for example, an Avi tag, a Calmodulin tag, a polyglutamate tag, an E tag, a FLAG tag, a HA tag, a His tag, a Myc tag, an S tag, a SBP tag, an IgG-Fc tag, a CTB tag, a Softag 1 tag, a Softag 3 tag, a Strep tag, a TC tag, a V5 tag, a VSV tag, an Xpress tag, and the like, the selection marker gene may include, for example, herbicide resistance genes such as glyphosate or phosphinothricin, antibiotic resistance genes such as kanamycin, G418, bleomycin, hygromycin, and chloramphenicol, aadA genes, and the like, the promoter may include, for example, an pEMU promoter, a Mannopine synthase (MAS) promoter, a histone promoter, a Clp promoter, a cauliflower-mosaic-virus-derived 35S promoter, a cauliflower-mosaic-virus-derived 19S RNA promoter, an actin protein promoter of a plant, a ubiquitin protein promoter, a cytomegalovirus (CMV) promoter, a simian virus 40 (SV40) promoter, a respiratory syncytial virus (RSV) promoter, an elongation factor-1 alpha (EF-1a) promoter, and the like, representative examples of<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> the terminator include a nopaline synthase (NOS) terminator, a rice amylase A terminator, a phaseolin terminator, a terminator of an octopine gene of <i>Agrobacterium tumefaciens,</i> a rrnB1/B2 terminator of <i>E. coli</i>, and the like, but the examples are only illustrative and are not limited thereto.</p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">As used herein, the "transformation" collectively refers to changes in genetic properties of a living organism by injected DNA, the "transgenic organism" is an organism prepared by injecting an external gene by a molecular genetic method, preferably, an organism transformed by a recombinant expression vector of the present invention, and the organism is not limited as long as it is a living organism such as a microorganism, a eukaryotic cell, an insect, an animal, and a plant, and is preferably <i>Escherichia coli, Salmonella, Bacillus</i>, yeast, an animal cell, a mouse, a rat, a dog, a monkey, a pig, a horse, a cow, <i>Agrobacterium tumefaciens,</i> a plant, and the like, but is not limited thereto. The transgenic organism may be prepared by a method such as transformation, transfection, <i>Agrobacterium</i>-mediated transformation, particle gun bombardment, sonication, electroporation, and polyethylene glycol (PEG)-mediated transformation, but there is no limitation as long as it is a method capable of injecting the vector of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">As used herein, the "solubility" refers to the degree to which a target protein or peptide can be dissolved in a solvent suitable for administration to the human body. Specifically, the solubility may indicate the degree of solute saturation in a given solvent at a specific temperature. The solubility may be measured by determining the saturation concentration of the solute, and for example, an excessive amount of solute is added to a solvent, the resulting mixture is stirred and filtered, and then the concentration may be measured using a UV spectrophotometer, HPLC, or the like, but the method for measuring the solubility is not limited thereto, and high solubility<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> is advantageous in the isolation and purification of a recombinant protein, and has an advantage in that aggregation of the recombinant protein is inhibited, and thus physiological activity or pharmacological activity of the recombinant protein is maintained.</p>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">As used herein, the "prevention" refers to all actions that suppress rabies or delay the onset of rabies by administering the recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">As used herein, the "individual" refers to a subject to which the recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein of the present invention may be administered, and the subject is not limited.</p>
<p id="p0029" num="0029">The "vaccine composition" of the present invention may be used by being formulated in the form of an oral formulation such as powder, granules, a tablet, a capsule, a suspension, an emulsion, a syrup, and an aerosol, and a sterile injection solution, according to a typical method. When the composition is prepared, the composition may be prepared using a commonly used diluent or excipient, such as a filler, an extender, a binder, a wetting agent, a disintegrant, and a surfactant. A solid formulation for oral formulation includes a tablet, a pill, powder, granules, and the like, and the solid formulation may be prepared by mixing at least one excipient, for example, starch, calcium carbonate, sucrose or lactose, gelatin, and the like with a lecithin-like emulsifier. Further, in addition to simple excipients, lubricants such as magnesium stearate and talc may also be used. As a liquid formulation for oral administration, a suspension, a liquid for internal use, an emulsion, a syrup, and the like may be used, and in addition to water and liquid paraffin which are simple commonly used diluents, various excipients, for example, a wetting agent, a sweetener, an aromatic, a preservative, and the like may be included. Examples of a<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> formulation for parenteral administration include an aqueous sterile solution, a non-aqueous solvent, a suspension, an emulsion, and a freeze-dried preparation. As the non-aqueous solvent and the suspension, it is possible to use propylene glycol, polyethylene glycol, a vegetable oil such as olive oil, an injectable ester such as ethyl oleate, and the like. Furthermore, an "immune antigen adjuvant" conventionally known may be further included. The adjuvant may be used without limitation as long as it is known in the art, but for example, immunogenicity may be enhanced by further including Freund's Complete Adjuvant or Incomplete Adjuvant.</p>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">The vaccine composition or pharmaceutical composition of the present invention may be used by being formulated in the form of an oral formulation such as powder, granules, a tablet, a capsule, a suspension, an emulsion, a syrup, and an aerosol, and an external preparation, a suppository, or a sterile injection solution, according to a typical method.</p>
<p id="p0031" num="0031">The route of administration of the vaccine composition according to the present invention includes, but is not limited to, oral, intravenous, intramuscular, intraarterial, intramedullary, intrathecal, intracardiac, transdermal, subcutaneous, intraperitoneal, intranasal, intestinal, topical, sublingual or rectal routes. Oral or parenteral administration is preferred. As used herein, the term "parenteral" includes subcutaneous, intradermal, intravenous, intramuscular, intraarticular, intrasynovial, intrasternal, intrathecal, intralesional and intracranial injection or infusion techniques. The vaccine composition of the present invention may also be administered in the form of a suppository for rectal administration.</p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032">The dose of the vaccine composition or pharmaceutical composition according to the present invention is selected in consideration of the age, body weight, sex, physical condition and the like of an individual. The amount required to<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> induce an immunoprotective response in an individual without particular side effects may vary depending on the recombinant protein used as an immunogen and the presence of a random excipient. In general, each dose contains 0.1 to 1000 µg, preferably 0.1 to 100 µg of a protein per ml of a sterile solution of the recombinant protein of the present invention. In the case of the vaccine composition, an initial dose followed by optionally repeated antigenic stimulation may be performed, if necessary.</p>
<p id="p0033" num="0033">As used herein, the "adjuvant" generally refers to any material that increases the body fluid and/or cell-mediated immune response to an antigen.</p>
<p id="p0034" num="0034">The "feed composition" of the present invention refers to feed including recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein of the present invention, examples of the feed include byproducts such as pork, beef, and chicken, corn, rice, general rice straw, wild grass, grass, silage, hay, mountain wild grass, and the like, but are not limited thereto, and there is no limitation as long as it is used for raising livestock and pet. Examples of a method for adding the recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein of the present invention to feed include a method such as mechanical mixing, adsorption, and occlusion, but are not limited thereto.</p>
<p id="p0035" num="0035">Hereinafter, preferred Examples for helping the understanding of the present invention will be suggested. However, the following Examples are provided for easier understanding of the present invention, and the contents of the present invention are not limited by the following Examples.</p>
<heading id="h0009"><b>[Examples]</b></heading><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> -->
<heading id="h0010"><b><u>Example 1: Preparation of vector for expressing recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein</u></b></heading>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">To prepare an expression vector for expressing a recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein (RVGe) in a plant, as a result of conducting a study to optimize the expression of the protein in the plant body after securing the publically available gene sequences of the rabies virus glycoprotein, a polynucleotide encoding a rabies virus glycoprotein of SEQ ID NO: 1 was obtained. Furthermore, a vector for expressing a recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein was constructed by cloning a polynucleotide (SEQ ID NO: 3) encoding a chaperone binding protein (BiP), a polynucleotide (SEQ ID NO: 1) encoding a rabies virus glycoprotein, a polynucleotide (SEQ ID NO: 4) encoding 6 consecutive histidines, and a polynucleotide (SEQ ID NO: 5) encoding a His-Asp-Glu-Leu (HDEL) peptide in this order between a CaMV 35S promoter gene of a pCAMBIA1300 vector and a NOS terminator.</p>
<heading id="h0011"><b><u>Example 2: Confirmation of expression of recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein</u></b></heading>
<p id="p0037" num="0037">To confirm the expression of a recombinant protein of the vector constructed in the same manner as in Example 1, a transient expression experiment in which transformed <i>Agrobacterium tumefaciens</i> was inoculated into the leaves of <i>Nicotiana benthamiana</i> was performed. More specifically, an <i>Agrobacterium LBA4404</i> was transformed with a vector for expressing a recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein using electroporation. The transformed <i>Agrobacterium</i> was inoculated into 5 ml of a YEP liquid medium (10 g of yeast extract, 10 g of peptone, 5 g of NaCl, 50 mg/l kanamycin, and 25 mg/l rifampicin), and then cultured with shaking under a<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> condition of 28 °C for 16 hours. Then, 1 ml of a culture solution was inoculated into 50 ml of a new YEP medium, the bacteria were again cultured with shaking under a condition of 28°C for 6 hours, and then the supernatant was removed by centrifuging 50 ml of the obtained culture solution at 4 °C and 7,000 rpm for 5 minutes. Next, obtained bacterial cells were suspended in an infiltration buffer (10 mM MES (pH 5.7), 10 mM MgCl<sub>2</sub>, and 200 µM acetosyringone) such that OD<sub>600nm</sub> = 1.0, and <i>Agrobacteria-</i>infiltration was performed by a method of injecting the suspended <i>Agrobacteria</i> into the backside of the leaves of <i>Nicotiana benthamiana</i> using a syringe from which the needle had been removed.</p>
<p id="p0038" num="0038">Then, western blotting was performed by extracting a protein from the leaves of <i>Nicotiana benthamiana</i> expressing the recombinant rabies virus protein and centrifuging the protein to obtain a recombinant protein (S) included in an aqueous solution fraction and a recombinant protein (P) included in a pellet fraction. During the protein extraction, a 20 mM sodium phosphate (pH 7.3) solution supplemented with 0.1 % Triton X-100, 20 mM imidazole (pH 7.5), and 300 mM NaCl was used. For western blotting, after 30 µl of each obtained protein fraction was mixed with an SDS sample buffer, the resulting mixture was heated and electrophoresed on a 10% SDS-PAGE gel to separate proteins by size, and the separated proteins were transferred to a PVDF membrane, then subjected to a blocking step using 5 % skim milk, and bound to an antibody reacting with 6 His, and the recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein was confirmed by treating an ECL solution by a method provided by the manufacturer. The results are illustrated in <figref idref="f0001">FIG 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0039" num="0039">As illustrated in <figref idref="f0001">FIG 2</figref>, most of the expressed recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein was confirmed in the aqueous fraction (S), and only a small amount of recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein was observed in the pellet fraction (P).<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> Through the results, it could be confirmed that a vector for expressing a recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein of the present invention could effectively express a recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein in a plant body, a recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein prepared using the vector has high solubility, and thus is easy to isolate and purify, and the aggregation of the recombinant protein was suppressed, thereby being effective for maintaining the physiological activity or pharmacological activity of the recombinant protein.</p>
<heading id="h0012"><b><u>Example 3: Isolation and purification of recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein</u></b></heading>
<p id="p0040" num="0040">After 200 ml of a protein extraction solution (50 mM sodium phosphate (pH 8.0), 300 mM NaCl, 20 mM imidazole, 0.1% Triton X-100, and a IX protease inhibitor) was added to 40 g of <i>Nicotiana benthamiana</i> obtained in the same manner as in Example 2 and a tissue was crushed by a blender, a protein extract was obtained by centrifugation at 4 °C and 13,000 rpm for 20 minutes. Then, in order to isolate and purify the recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein from the protein extract, affinity chromatography was performed using a column packed with a Ni-NTA agarose resin. More specifically, the column was packed with 5 ml of the resin and then equilibrated using 50 ml of a washing buffer (50 mM sodium phosphate (pH 8.0), 300 mM NaCl, and 20 mM imidazole). A protein extract was injected into the equilibrated column, unbound proteins were removed using 100 ml of the washing buffer, and then the recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein was eluted using an elution buffer (50 mM sodium phosphate (pH 8.0), 300 mM NaCl, and 300 mM imidazole). Then, the eluted solution was replaced with phosphate buffered saline (PBS) using a filter having a size of 30 kD, and a recombinant rabies virus<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> glycoprotein was obtained by concentrating the protein. The obtained protein was confirmed by protein electrophoresis (SDS-PAGE) and Coomassie staining. The results are illustrated in <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0041" num="0041">As illustrated in <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 3</figref>, it was confirmed that the recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein having a size of about 51 Kd was purified.</p>
<heading id="h0013"><b><u>Example 4: Confirmation whether recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein is glycosylated</u></b></heading>
<p id="p0042" num="0042">In order to confirm whether the recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein obtained in the same manner as in Example 3 was glycosylated, an endo H glycosidase N-glycosylation removal analysis was performed. More specifically, after a 10 X denaturation buffer (5 % SDS and 0.4 M DTT) was added to 1 µg of the recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein, the resulting mixture was heated at 100°C, and a sodium citrate buffer (pH 5.5) was added such that the final concentration of the recombinant protein was 50 mM. Then, 50 U of endo H glycosidase was added thereto, and the resulting mixture was allowed to react at 37 °C for 1 hour. An experiment was conducted after adding the same amount of distilled water instead of Endo H glycosidase as a control. After the reaction was completed, a change in molecular weight according to the removal of N-glycosylation of the recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein was confirmed by performing western blotting in the same manner as in Example 2. The results are illustrated in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0043" num="0043">As illustrated in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 4</figref>, it was confirmed that the molecular weight of recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein was reduced by endo H glycosidase, and through this, it could be confirmed that the recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein obtained using the plant body was normally N-glycosylated.<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></p>
<heading id="h0014"><b><u>Example 5. Experiment of confirming immunogenicity of recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein</u></b></heading>
<p id="p0044" num="0044">To confirm whether the recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein obtained in the same manner as in Example 3 had immunogenicity by inducing an antibody <i>in vivo</i> as an antigen, an experiment was performed using 6-week old male C57BL/6J mice. More specifically, 1 µg of the recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein was administered to experimental group mice (6 to 8-week old), and phosphate buffered saline (PBS) was administered to negative control mice. When the recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein was administered, the same amount of Freund's adjuvant was mixed and administered, a complete adjuvant was primarily administered, and an incomplete adjuvant was secondarily administered. Two weeks after the recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein was administered twice, blood was collected and it was confirmed using an ELISA plate coated with the recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein whether a specific antibody against the administered antigen was generated. An experiment was performed using 4 animals of a negative control (CT) and 5 animals of an experimental group (RVGe), and the results are illustrated in <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 5</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0045" num="0045">As illustrated in <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 5</figref>, no reactivity was observed in a serum sample (pre) before administration of the recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein and a serum sample (post) after administration of the phosphate buffered saline to the negative control, but it was confirmed that the serum sample after administration of the recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein showed high reactivity. Through the results, it could be confirmed that the recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein of the present invention acted as an antigen and could effectively generate an antibody.<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></p>
<heading id="h0015"><b><u>Example 6. Experiment of confirming virus neutralizing ability of recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein</u></b></heading>
<p id="p0046" num="0046">Using a serum obtained in the same manner as in Example 5, it was confirmed whether an antibody formed by the administration of the rabies virus glycoprotein of the present invention had a rabies virus neutralizing ability. More specifically, 100 µl of a DMEM medium was aliquoted into 4 wells per sample in a 96-well plate, and then 50 µl of serum to be diluted was added to each of the first wells. Then, a 3-fold serial dilution was performed using the remaining three wells in which the medium was aliquoted. 50 µl each of a standard fixed strain virus (CVS11) diluted to a concentration of 100 tissue culture infectious dose (TCID)<sub>50</sub> /µl was added to the last well in which serum dilution was completed, the resulting mixture was allowed to react at 37 °C for 1 hour, and then 50 µl of BHKT7 cells diluted to a concentration of 4 X 10<sup>5</sup> cells/ml using a DMEM medium supplemented with 10% fetal bovine serum (FBS) was inoculated into each well, cultured at 37 °C for 48 hours, and contaminated with viruses. Then, in order to observe the infected cells under a fluorescence microscope, the culture solution was removed, the cells were fixed using 80 % acetone, and then fluorescent staining was performed using a rabies-specific antibody to which fluorescence was bound. A sample for confirming the neutralizing ability was prepared by using an World Organization for Animal Health(OIE) standard dog serum diluted to a concentration of 0.5 International Units (IU)/ml as a standard positive serum, using a negative control serum as an antibody negative serum, and inactivating other experimental sera. For the antibody titer of each sample, after a fluorescence value of a fluorescence image obtained using a fluorescence microscope using an ImageJ program, the antibody titer of each sample<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> was calculated using the standard positive serum results. The neutralizing antibody titer was determined to be positive when it was 0.5 IU/ml or higher and negative when it was less than 0.5 IU/ml. The results are shown in Table 1.
<tables id="tabl0001" num="0001">
<table frame="all">
<title>[Table 1]</title>
<tgroup cols="3">
<colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="18mm"/>
<colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="33mm"/>
<colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="43mm"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry align="center" valign="middle"><b>Antigen</b></entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle"><b>Individual number</b></entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle"><b>Neutralizing antibody titer</b></entry></row></thead>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry morerows="4" align="center" valign="middle">RVGe</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">1</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">4.56 IU/ml</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">2</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">1.51 IU/ml</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">3</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">13.77 IU/ml</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">4</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">0.87 IU/ml</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">5</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">23.93 IU/ml</entry></row>
<row>
<entry namest="col1" nameend="col2" align="center" valign="middle">Negative</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">&gt; 0.5 IU/ml</entry></row></tbody></tgroup>
</table>
</tables></p>
<p id="p0047" num="0047">As shown in Table 1, it was confirmed that all the individuals in the experimental group to which the recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein of the present invention was administered twice showed a high titer of virus neutralizing antibody.</p>
<p id="p0048" num="0048">Through the results, it could be confirmed that the recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein of the present invention is not only effectively expressed in a plant body, but also has high solubility, and thus is easy to isolate and purify, and the protein activity is also stable. Furthermore, it could be confirmed that the recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein of the present invention shows high immunogenicity and virus neutralizing activity, and thus can be used as a novel rabies vaccine composition.</p>
<p id="p0049" num="0049">Hereinafter, the preparation examples of the pharmaceutical composition and feed composition of the present invention will be described, but the description is not intended to limit the present invention and is merely intended to describe the present invention in detail.<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --></p>
<heading id="h0016"><b><u>Preparation Example 1. Preparation of pharmaceutical composition</u></b></heading>
<heading id="h0017"><b>1.1. Preparation of powder</b></heading>
<p id="p0050" num="0050">
<ul id="ul0002" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>Recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein 20 mg</li>
<li>Lactose 100 mg</li>
<li>Talc 10 mg</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0051" num="0051">A powder is prepared by mixing the ingredients and filling an airtight pack with the ingredients.</p>
<heading id="h0018"><b>1.2. Preparation of tablets</b></heading>
<p id="p0052" num="0052">
<ul id="ul0003" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>Recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein 10 mg</li>
<li>Corn starch 100 mg</li>
<li>Lactose 100 mg</li>
<li>Magnesium stearate 2 mg</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0053" num="0053">After the ingredients are mixed, tablets are prepared by tableting the mixture according to a typical tablet preparation method.</p>
<heading id="h0019"><b>1.3. Preparation of capsules</b></heading>
<p id="p0054" num="0054">
<ul id="ul0004" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>Recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein 10 mg</li>
<li>Crystalline cellulose 3 mg</li>
<li>Lactose 14.8 mg</li>
<li>Magnesium stearate 0.2 mg</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0055" num="0055">Capsules are prepared by mixing the ingredients according to a typical capsule preparation method and filling gelatin capsules with the mixture.</p>
<heading id="h0020"><b>1.4. Preparation of injection</b></heading><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> -->
<p id="p0056" num="0056">
<ul id="ul0005" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>Recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein 10 mg</li>
<li>Mannitol 180 mg</li>
<li>Sterile distilled water for injection 2,974 mg</li>
<li>Na<sub>2</sub>HPO<sub>4</sub>2H<sub>2</sub>O 26 mg</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0057" num="0057">According to the typical method for preparing an injection, an injection is prepared in a content of the ingredients per 1 ampoule (2 ml).</p>
<heading id="h0021"><b>1.5. Preparation of liquid</b></heading>
<p id="p0058" num="0058">
<ul id="ul0006" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>Recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein 20 mg</li>
<li>Isomerized sugar 10 g</li>
<li>Mannitol 5 g</li>
<li>Purified water appropriate amount</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0059" num="0059">According to a typical method for preparing a liquid, each ingredient is added to purified water and dissolved, an appropriate amount of lemon flavor is added, and then the ingredients are mixed, and then purified water is added thereto to adjust the total volume to 100 ml, and then a liquid is prepared by filling a brown bottle with the mixture and sterilizing the brown bottle.</p>
<heading id="h0022"><b><u>Preparation Example 2. Preparation of feed composition</u></b></heading>
<p id="p0060" num="0060">
<ul id="ul0007" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>Recombinant rabies virus glycoprotein 100 mg</li>
<li>Vitamin E 0.7 mg</li>
<li>L-carnitine 0.7 mg</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0061" num="0061">According to a typical method for preparing feed, feed is prepared by mixing the ingredients.<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --></p>
<p id="p0062" num="0062">The above-described description of the present invention is provided for illustrative purposes, and a person skilled in the art to which the present invention pertains will understand that the present invention can be easily modified into other specific forms without changing the technical spirit or essential features of the present invention. Therefore, it should be understood that the above-described embodiments are only illustrative in all aspects and not restrictive.</p>
<heading id="h0023">[Industrial Applicability]</heading>
<p id="p0063" num="0063">The present invention relates to a rabies virus glycoprotein including an amino acid sequence represented by SEQ ID NO: 2, an expression vector for producing the glycoprotein, a transgenic organism transformed with the expression vector, a vaccine composition for preventing rabies, including the glycoprotein as an active ingredient, and the like, and the rabies virus glycoprotein of the present invention is not only effectively expressed in a plant, but also has high solubility, and thus is easy to isolate and purify, thereby being expected to enable the rabies virus glycoprotein to be mass-produced at low cost.<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> -->
<img id="ib0001" file="imgb0001.tif" wi="158" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> -->
<img id="ib0002" file="imgb0002.tif" wi="155" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> -->
<img id="ib0003" file="imgb0003.tif" wi="156" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="26"> -->
<img id="ib0004" file="imgb0004.tif" wi="163" he="82" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> -->
<claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>A rabies virus glycoprotein comprising an amino acid sequence represented by SEQ ID NO: 2.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>A vaccine composition for preventing rabies, comprising a rabies virus glycoprotein comprising an amino acid sequence represented by SEQ ID NO: 2 as an active ingredient.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>A feed composition for preventing rabies, comprising a rabies virus glycoprotein comprising an amino acid sequence represented by SEQ ID NO: 2 as an active ingredient.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>A method for preventing or treating rabies by administering a rabies virus glycoprotein comprising an amino acid sequence represented by SEQ ID NO: 2 to an individual.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>A vector for expressing a rabies virus glycoprotein, comprising a polynucleotide encoding an amino acid sequence represented by SEQ ID NO: 2.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>The vector of claim 5, further comprising a polynucleotide encoding a chaperone binding protein (BiP).<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>The vector of claim 5, further comprising a gene encoding a His-Asp-Glu-Leu (HDEL) peptide.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>A transgenic organism transformed with the vector of any one of claims 5 to 7.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>A method for producing a rabies virus glycoprotein, the method including: (a) culturing the transgenic organism of claim 8; and (b) isolating a rabies virus glycoprotein from the transgenic organism or culture solution and purifying the isolated rabies virus glycoprotein.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>A use of a composition comprising a rabies virus glycoprotein comprising an amino acid sequence represented by SEQ ID NO: 2 as an active ingredient for preventing or treating rabies.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="29"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1,2"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="122" he="201" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="30"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="3"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="76" he="152" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> -->
<figure id="f0003" num="4"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="66" he="202" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> -->
<figure id="f0004" num="5"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="129" he="141" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<search-report-data id="srep" lang="en" srep-office="EP" date-produced=""><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="151" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="151" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data>
<ep-reference-list id="ref-list">
<heading id="ref-h0001"><b>REFERENCES CITED IN THE DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0001" num=""><i>This list of references cited by the applicant is for the reader's convenience only. It does not form part of the European patent document. Even though great care has been taken in compiling the references, errors or omissions cannot be excluded and the EPO disclaims all liability in this regard.</i></p>
<heading id="ref-h0002"><b>Patent documents cited in the description</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0002" num="">
<ul id="ref-ul0001" list-style="bullet">
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0001" dnum="KR1020130111581"><document-id><country>KR</country><doc-number>1020130111581</doc-number></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0001">[0003]</crossref></li>
</ul></p>
</ep-reference-list>
</ep-patent-document>
