<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP13790893B1" file="EP13790893NWB1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="2854309" kind="B1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSK..HRIS..MTNORS..SM..................</B001EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  2100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>2854309</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT SPECIFICATION</B121></B120><B130>B1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>13790893.5</B210><B220><date>20130214</date></B220><B240><B241><date>20141210</date></B241><B242><date>20190104</date></B242></B240><B250>ko</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B300><B310>20120052763</B310><B320><date>20120518</date></B320><B330><ctry>KR</ctry></B330><B310>20130003577</B310><B320><date>20130111</date></B320><B330><ctry>KR</ctry></B330></B300><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20150401</date><bnum>201514</bnum></B430><B450><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B450><B452EP><date>20210506</date></B452EP></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>H04B  10/25        20130101AFI20160316BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="2"><text>H04B  10/40        20130101ALI20160316BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="3"><text>H04J  14/02        20060101ALI20160316BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>G02B   6/4246      20130101 LI20170406BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>H04J  14/02        20130101 LI20150313BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="3"><text>H04B  10/2589      20200501 LI20200501RHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="4"><text>H04B  10/40        20130101 FI20150313BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="5"><text>G02B   6/4263      20130101 LI20170406BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="6"><text>G02B   6/4215      20130101 LI20170406BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="7"><text>H04J  14/0279      20130101 LI20170406BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="8"><text>H04J  14/0265      20130101 LI20170406BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="9"><text>G02B   6/4206      20130101 LI20170406BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="10"><text>G02B   6/4214      20130101 LI20170406BHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>BIDIREKTIONALES OPTISCHES SENDE- UND EMPFANGSMODUL</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>BIDIRECTIONAL OPTICAL TRANSMITTING AND RECEIVING MODULE</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>MODULE D'ÉMISSION ET DE RÉCEPTION OPTIQUE BIDIRECTIONNEL</B542></B540><B560><B561><text>CN-A- 102 279 445</text></B561><B561><text>JP-A- 2006 098 792</text></B561><B561><text>KR-A- 20060 035 448</text></B561><B561><text>KR-A- 20070 034 654</text></B561><B561><text>KR-A- 20070 098 959</text></B561><B561><text>KR-A- 20110 011 123</text></B561><B561><text>KR-A- 20110 021 185</text></B561><B561><text>KR-A- 20110 021 185</text></B561><B561><text>KR-A- 20120 009 785</text></B561><B561><text>KR-B1- 101 040 316</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2002 110 313</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2003 138 204</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2011 044 696</text></B561><B565EP><date>20160322</date></B565EP></B560></B500><B700><B720><B721><snm>KIM, Hongman</snm><adr><str>903-201 Triple City Apt.
Doan 9block
Sangdae-dong
Yuseong-gu</str><city>Daejeon 305-313</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>HWANG, Wolyon</snm><adr><str>209-1105 Expo Apt.
Jeonmin-dong
Yuseong-gu</str><city>Daejeon 305-761</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>HEO, Youngun</snm><adr><str>608-803 Unam Neomia Apt.
Gwanpyeong-dong
Yuseong-gu</str><city>Daejeon 305-746</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>KWON, Yoonkoo</snm><adr><str>505-1102 Gajwamaeul 5-Danji Booyoung Apt.
Yongdam-dong
Sangdang-gu</str><city>Cheongju-si
Chungcheongbuk-do 360-787</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>CHOI, Jinsoo</snm><adr><str>104-402 Hanmaeul Apt.
Songgang-dong
Yuseong-gu</str><city>Daejeon 305-756</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>JUNG, Kangyong</snm><adr><str>108-101 Hanwha Ggumegreen
664 Gwanpyeong-dong
Yuseong-gu</str><city>Daejeon 305-741</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>JIN, Jaehyun</snm><adr><str>126-1002 Hwanggol Jugong Apt.
Yeongtong 1-dong
Yeongtong-gu</str><city>Suwon-si
Gyeonggi-do 443-740</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>YOO, Youngjoon</snm><adr><str>303-307 Moa Miraedo
1216 Jukjeon-dong
Suji-gu</str><city>Yongin-si
Gyeonggi-do 448-160</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>SUNG, Jinsoo</snm><adr><str>921-1503 Pangyowonmaeul Hallimpulever Apt.
Pangyo-dong
Bundang-gu</str><city>Seongnam-si
Gyeonggi-do 463-410</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>LIM, Jongyeong</snm><adr><str>114-2401 Baekma Samsung Apt.
755 Madu 1-dong
Ilsandong-gu</str><city>Goyang-si
Gyeonggi-do 410-708</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>PARK, Sangsu</snm><adr><str>601-1803 Sinyeong Halla Provence Apt.
33 Jukjeon 1-dong
Suji-gu</str><city>Yongin-si
Gyeonggi-do 448-974</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B730><B731><snm>Lightron Fiber-Optic Devices Inc</snm><iid>101381264</iid><irf>NAM002_EP</irf><adr><str>68 Munpyeongdong-ro 
Daedeok-gu</str><city>Daejeon 306-220</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B731></B730><B740><B741><snm>Metroconsult Srl</snm><iid>101811668</iid><adr><str>Via Sestriere, 100</str><city>10060 None (TO)</city><ctry>IT</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840><B860><B861><dnum><anum>KR2013001134</anum></dnum><date>20130214</date></B861><B862>ko</B862></B860><B870><B871><dnum><pnum>WO2013172541</pnum></dnum><date>20131121</date><bnum>201347</bnum></B871></B870></B800></SDOBI>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<heading id="h0001">Technical Field</heading>
<p id="p0001" num="0001">The present disclosure relates to a bi-directional optical transceiver module, and more particularly, to a bidirectional optical transceiver module that performs optical reception/transmission in a CWDM single channel in which the bi-directional optical transceiver module is configured such that the optical transmission/reception is performed in a state where an upstream signal and a downstream signal have different wavelength values in the CWDM single channel.</p>
<heading id="h0002">Background Art</heading>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">In order to meet demand for recently increasing data traffic, capacity expansion of existing optical communication networks is required.</p>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">For this reason, the Wavelength-Division Multiplexing (WDM) has been recognized as the leading alternative among various optical communication system technologies which have been proposed up to now.</p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">The WDM technology is a wavelength division multiplexing method which binds and sends light having different wavelengths through a single strand of optical fiber. The WDM technology provides a point-to-point dedicated channel for each subscriber through the independent allocation of wavelengths, each of which is inherent to one subscriber, and uses an inherent optical wavelength for each subscriber. Thus, the WDM technology is capable of providing a high speed service.</p>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">For example, a WDM-PON (WDM Passive Optical Network) technology has advantages in that since the WDM-PON uses<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> many wavelengths as compared to a TDM (Time-Division Multiplexing) -PON, such as an E-PON (Ethernet-PON) or a G-PON (Gigabit-PON), which is a time division method, a bidirectional symmetric service can be assured and bandwidths can be independently allocated, and since signals with different wavelengths are received only by corresponding subscribers, security is excellent.</p>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">One of the most important requirements in the WDM-PON is that optical terminal devices should be irrelevant to used wavelengths. When this is not satisfied, various kinds of optical terminals corresponding to the number of used optical wavelengths are needed, and this is referred to as an inventory problem. In such a case, considerable difficulties will be caused in manufacturing, management, and installation of optical terminal devices.</p>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">In order to apply bi-directional optical modules in a CWDM method, each of the modules should be applied to transmission and reception using 9 channels should be used among 18 CWDM channels. Consequently, the CWDM method halves optical line use efficiency. Accordingly, technologies that use a single channel in upstream (subscriber → central station) and downstream (central station → subscriber) signal transmissions have been proposed. However, there is a problem in that use of a single channel may cause a link fail between optical communication networks due to reflection and backscattering on an optical line.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">Document <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US2011044696A"><text>US 2011/044696</text></patcit> describes an optical communication module which uses a single optical fiber to enable bidirectional communication or multiplexing communication. The optical communication module includes a platform configured to have a through-hole therein which vertically passes through the platform; an optical receiver configured to be provided on the platform and include a light-receiving element; an optical transmitter configured to be provided on the platform and include a light-emitting element; and an optical filter configured to be provided on one surface of the platform to correspond to the through-hole, transmit light from the light-emitting element to an optical line, and transmit light input through the optical line to the light-receiving element, where one of the light-receiving element and the light-emitting element is provided on one surface of the platform on an opposite side of the optical line with the optical filter interposed therebetween, and the other is provided on the other surface of the platform to correspond to the through-hole. <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="CN102279445"><text>CN102279445</text></patcit> discloses an optical communication module with the features of the preamble of claim 1.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p>
<heading id="h0003">Detailed Description of the Invention</heading>
<heading id="h0004">Technical Problem</heading>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">The present disclosure is to provide a bi-directional optical transceiver module which is configured to prevent a link fail between optical communication networks due to reflection and backscattering on an optical line in a bidirectional optical transceiver module that performs optical transmission/reception in a CWDM single channel.</p>
<heading id="h0005">Technical Solution</heading>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">In order to achieve the objects as described above, a bi-directional optical transceiver module according to an embodiment of the present invention includes the features as claimed in the independent claim.</p>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">The bi-directional optical transceiver module may further include a thermoelectric semiconductor element configured to perform a temperature adjustment of the optical transmission unit in response to an external temperature.</p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">The bi-directional optical transceiver module includes<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> a parallel light lens configured to convert and output the reflected optical signals in a form of<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> parallel light. The reflected light-blocking optical filter unit may pass, as the reception signal, only a signal within a pre-set wavelength range including the wavelength allocated to the reception signal among the optical signals output through the parallel light lens so as to block the external reflected light.</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">Here, the parallel light lens may include an incident surface and a light emission surface opposite to the incident surface. The reflected optical signals may be received by the incident surface and the parallel light is emitted through the light emission surface, and the light emission surface may flat.</p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">In the bi-directional optical transceiver module, the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit may be attached to the light emission surface of the parallel light lens by a transparent UV epoxy. At this time, the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit may be configured in a form coated on the light emission surface of the parallel light lens such that the parallel light lens and the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit may take an integrated form.</p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">According to another embodiment of the present invention, an optical communication system includes the features as claimed in claim 8.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p>
<heading id="h0006">Advantageous Effects</heading>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">Embodiments of the present disclosure may provide an optical communication system in which wavelength separation is performed by applying a temperature adjustment laser technology and a reception end reflection blocking filter is operated according to a separated wavelength value so that the optical communication system may be less affected by reflection and backscattering. In addition, according to an embodiment of the present disclosure, high capacity data is separated into a plurality of wavelengths using a bi-directional high-density optical transceiver and transmitted to a single optical line so that optical line transmission efficiency can be improved as compared to a case where the same wavelength is used in a single channel. As a result, the cost for increasing an optical transmission capacity may be minimized.</p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">In addition, a bi-directional optical transceiver module according to an embodiment of the present disclosure may enhance a condensation degree of a communication channel using parallel light and may be mounted in a miniaturized case required by the SFP or SFP+ standard.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">Further, when an embodiment of the present disclosure is applied, the entire optical network structure may be considerably simplified as compared to applying an ordinary CWDM 2 channel optical transceiver. Thus, it is possible to achieve advantageous effects in terms of cost, installation, maintenance, repairmen, etc.</p>
<heading id="h0007">Brief Description of the Drawings</heading>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li><figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic view illustrating an optical communication using the same wavelength in a Coarse-Wave-Division Multiplexing (CWDM) single channel in upstream and downstream signal transmission and reception.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> is a view illustrating a schematic configuration of a bi-directional optical transceiver module according to a first embodiment not according to the claimed invention.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> is a graph illustrating filter characteristics of a reflected light-blocking optical filter unit designed to receive each of an upstream signal and a downstream signal in a CWDM communication.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0004">FIG. 4</figref> is a view illustrating a form of light incident on the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit from the bi-directional optical transceiver module illustrated in <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0005">FIG. 5</figref> is a graph illustrating filter transmission characteristics of the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit for parallel light and divergent light.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0006">FIG. 6</figref> is a view illustrating a schematic configuration of a bi-directional optical transceiver module according to an embodiment according to the claimed invention.<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></li>
<li><figref idref="f0007">FIG. 7</figref> is a view illustrating a schematic configuration of a bi-directional optical transceiver module according to a second embodiment according to the claimed invention.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0008">FIG. 8</figref> is a schematic view illustrating an optical communication using a bi-directional optical transceiver module according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0009">FIG. 9</figref> is a view illustrating a configuration of an optical communication system according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0010">FIG. 10</figref> is a view illustrating an optical communication system using a bi-directional optical transceiver module, according to another embodiment of the present disclosure.</li>
</ul></p>
<heading id="h0008">Mode for Carrying Out the Invention</heading>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">Hereinafter, embodiments of the present disclosure will be described in more detail. It should be noted that the same components of the drawings are designated by the same reference numeral anywhere. Further, a detailed description of known functions and configurations incorporated herein will be omitted when it may make the subject matter of the present invention rather unclear.</p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021"><figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic view illustrating an optical communication using a same wavelength in a Coarse-Wave-Division Multiplexing (CWDM) single channel in upstream and downstream signal transmission and reception.</p>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">In a CWDM system, 18 channels may be configured at a 20 nm interval from a first channel, of which the central wavelength is 1270 nm, to a last channel, of which the central wavelength is 1610 nm.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></p>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">Here, a protection band of 2.5 nm is allocated at each side of a ± 7.5 nm range. 20 nm allocated in this manner forms one band, and a difference of 5 nm is placed between each two adjacent bands so that channels having a total interval of 20 nm are formed.</p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">As illustrated in <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, a transmission unit TX1 and a reception unit RX1 of a central station side optical transceiver module, and a transmission unit TX2 and a reception unit RX2 of a subscriber side optical transceiver module are configured to perform upstream and downstream signal transmission and reception through any one channel among 18 CWDM channels.</p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">An optical communication using a single wavelength λ1 for upstream and downstream signal transmission and reception has an advantage in that a configuration of a multiplexer/inverse multiplexer is simplified and thus, the entire system configuration costs may be reduced by using one WDM filter per each communication channel. However, there are technical problems to be solved before using such an advantage.</p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">One of the problems to be solved is that reflection components and a backscattering λ'1 by a signal sent from a predetermined direction and a signal sent from an opposite direction cause interference, thereby degrading performance of a system. A representative example of such backscattering is a Rayleigh backscattering. The Rayleigh backscattering refers to an optical signal component which is generated by impurities within an optical fiber when an optical signal passes through the optical fiber, and is returned.</p>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">In addition, the reflection components may be generated by, for example, a defective connection of a<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> passive element or an optical fiber. In a case of bidirectional transmission, the reflection components and backscattering λ'1 cause interference with a signal sent from the opposite direction.</p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">The present disclosure relates to a bi-directional optical transceiver module which is capable of preventing link fail between optical communication networks by the reflection and/or backscattering λ'1 on an optical line.</p>
<p id="p0029" num="0029"><figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> is a view illustrating a schematic configuration of a bi-directional optical transceiver module according to an embodiment not according to the claimed invention.</p>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">As illustrated, the bi-directional optical transceiver module may include an optical transmission unit 110, a splitter 120, an optical reception unit 130, a reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 140, and a Thermo-Electric Cooler (TEC) 150.</p>
<p id="p0031" num="0031">The optical transmission unit 110 is configured to output a transmission signal.</p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032">The optical reception unit 130 is configured to input a reception signal and may include a condensing lens 131 and a light receiving element 133.</p>
<p id="p0033" num="0033">In the present disclosure, the optical transmission unit 110 and the optical reception unit 130 are configured to transmit and receive a transmission signal and a reception signal which have different wavelength values in a single channel.</p>
<p id="p0034" num="0034">The CWDM have 18 channels at a 20 nm interval within a range from 1270 nm to 1610 nm in central wavelength, and a bandwidth for each channel is ± 7.5 nm. Thus, the wavelengths of a transmission signal and a reception signal should be allocated and exist within the ±7.5 nm bandwidth<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> for each channel.</p>
<p id="p0035" num="0035">For example, a channel having a CWDM central wavelength of 1350 nm may be configured such that a transmission signal and a reception signal have wavelengths of 1346 nm and 1352 nm, respectively, which are spaced apart from each other over about 2 nm, and the optical transmission unit 110 and the optical reception unit 130 may be configured to be capable of receiving transmission signals and reception signals having such wavelength values. In other words, the optical transmission unit 110 may be configured to output a transmission signal having the wavelength value of 1346 nm and the optical reception unit 130 may be configured to receive an input of a reception signal having the wavelength value of 1352 nm.</p>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">The splitter 120 is installed to be inclined vertically by a predetermined angle with respect to an incident direction of the transmission signal output from the optical transmission unit 110 and performs functions of causing the transmission signal to pass therethrough to be output to an outside and reflecting an optical signal input from the outside. The inclined angle of the splitter 120 with respect to the incident direction of the transmission signal output from the optical transmission unit 110 may range 30° to 60°. However, the inclined angle is usually determined as 45° in order to ensure good transmission and reception efficiency.</p>
<p id="p0037" num="0037">As described above, the splitter 120 is configured such that the transmission signal and the reception signal respectively have wavelength values within a CWDM single channel may be bi-directionally transmitted and received through a single optical fiber ferrule 160.</p>
<p id="p0038" num="0038">According to the present disclosure,<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> the bi-directional optical transceiver module is provided with a reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 140.</p>
<p id="p0039" num="0039">The reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 140 is configured to pass, as a reception signal, only an optical signal within a pre-set wavelength range allocated to the reception signal among optical signals reflected from the splitter 120 thereby blocking external reflected light.</p>
<p id="p0040" num="0040">Since the transmission signal output from the optical transmission unit 110 has a wavelength value included in the same channel as the reception signal input to the optical reception unit 130, the transmission signal may be reflected to the wavelength bandwidth of the reception signal, thereby affecting a characteristic.</p>
<p id="p0041" num="0041">Accordingly, the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 140 is configured to block all of an internal refection signal input to the optical reception unit 130 and an external reflection (line reflection or Rayleigh backscattering) signal, and to separate the transmission signal existing in the single channel such that only an optical signal corresponding to the reception signal may be incident on the optical reception unit 130.</p>
<p id="p0042" num="0042">The reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 140 has a Band Pass Filter (BPF) characteristic that passes only an optical signal within a pre-set wavelength range including a wavelength value of the reception signal.</p>
<p id="p0043" num="0043">As illustrated in <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>, the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 140 may be provided as a built-in type for the bi-directional optical transceiver module. In addition, the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 140 may be provided as an external-mounting type for the bi-directional optical transceiver module.<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></p>
<p id="p0044" num="0044">The reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 140 may be configured such that the reception signal reflected from the splitter 120 and input to the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 140 can be incident perpendicularly.</p>
<p id="p0045" num="0045">As described above, the bi-directional optical transceiver module is configured such that an upstream signal and a downstream signal have different wavelength values in a single channel and bi-directional optical transmission and reception may be performed. As a result, an advantage of an existing configuration in which an upstream signal and a downstream signal are allocated with the same wavelength value of a single channel can be maintained as it is and a problem of link fail between optical communication networks which is a disadvantage of the existing configuration can be minimized.</p>
<p id="p0046" num="0046">The TEC 150 is configured to perform a temperature adjustment of the optical transmission unit 110 in response to an external temperature. The TEC 150 is a kind of temperature adjustment device which prevents a transmission signal output from the optical transmission unit 110 from being affected by an external temperature change.</p>
<p id="p0047" num="0047">When the optical transmission unit 110 includes a Distributed Feedback-Laser Diode (DFB-LD), the wavelength value of the transmission signal output from the optical transmission unit 110 is changed at a rate of 0.1 nm/°C per unit temperature by the external temperature change.</p>
<p id="p0048" num="0048">The TEC 150 causes the transmission signal output from the optical transmission unit 110 to be fixed to a wavelength value within a specific range even if the<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> external temperature is changed. The range of fluctuation of the wavelength values of the upstream signal and the downstream signal is very small.</p>
<p id="p0049" num="0049">According to the present disclosure, the bi-directional optical transceiver module may enable stable wavelength fixation in consideration of a wavelength change per unit temperature of the DFB-LD (about 0.1 nm/°C) through a temperature adjustment device such as the TEC 150 or a heater.</p>
<p id="p0050" num="0050">When a temperature adjustment device such as the TEC 150 is provided inside the bi-directional optical transceiver module, a control circuit (not illustrated) capable of controlling the temperature adjustment device may be included.</p>
<p id="p0051" num="0051">The TEC 150 allows the transmission signal to satisfy a wavelength range of single channel in an external temperature range of -40 to +85°C.</p>
<p id="p0052" num="0052"><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> is a graph illustrating filter characteristics of a reflected light-blocking optical filter unit designed to receive each of an upstream signal and a downstream signal in a CWDM communication according to the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p0053" num="0053">In the CWDM communication, a downstream signal of a central station side optical transceiver module is input as a reception signal to a subscriber side optical transceiver module, and an upstream signal of the subscriber side optical transceiver module is input as a reception signal to the central station side optical transceiver module. The upstream signal and the downstream signal are allocated with wavelengths such that the upstream signal and the downstream signal have different wavelength values in a CWDM single channel.<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></p>
<p id="p0054" num="0054">As a result, when the central wavelength of the CWDM single channel is 1350 nm, at a room temperature of 25°C, a wavelength value of 1352 nm may be allocated to the upstream signal and a wavelength value of 1346 nm may be allocated to the downstream signal. In addition, when a temperature adjustment device such as the TEC 150 is provided inside each of the central station side and subscriber side optical transceiver modules, it is possible to adjust a desired LD wavelength through the temperature adjustment of the TEC 150. For example, the downstream signal may be allocated with a wavelength value of 1348 nm and the upstream signal may be allocated with a wavelength value of 1355 nm within a single channel.</p>
<p id="p0055" num="0055"><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates filter characteristics of the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 140 which are respectively provided in a subscriber side optical transceiver module that receives a downstream signal and a central station side optical transceiver module which receives an upstream signal in a case where each of the optical transceiver modules is provided with the TEC 150 and a wavelength value of 1348 nm is allocated to the downstream signal and a wavelength value of 1355 nm is allocated to the upstream signal.</p>
<p id="p0056" num="0056">As illustrated in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref>, the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 140 in the subscriber side optical transceiver module that receives the downstream signal may be configured to have a filter blocking characteristic (Isol) of about 19 dB at the wavelength value of 1348 nm of the downstream signal. In addition, the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 140 in the central station side optical transceiver module that receives the upstream signal may be configured to have a<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> filter blocking characteristic (Iso2) of about 22 dB at the wavelength of 1355 nm of the upstream signal.</p>
<p id="p0057" num="0057">Communication quality will vary depending on which level of filter blocking characteristic the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 140 is designed to have. In an embodiment of the present description, the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 140 may be configured to have an isolation characteristic of at least about 9 dB.</p>
<p id="p0058" num="0058">In order to improve the filter blocking characteristic of the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 140, hereinafter, characteristics according to a form of light incident on the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 140 will be discussed.</p>
<p id="p0059" num="0059"><figref idref="f0004">FIG. 4</figref> is a view illustrating a form of light incident on the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit from the bi-directional optical transceiver module illustrated in <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0060" num="0060">The light incident on the splitter 120 through an optical fiber ferrule 160 diverges at 7 to 8 degrees in a half-value angle (in a case of an ordinarily available single mode optical fiber). When light diverging with a half-value angle of 7 to 8 degrees is incident on the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 140 the angle of the incident light is referred to as an "incident angle" which is defined as an inclined angle of the input light with respect to a normal direction.</p>
<p id="p0061" num="0061"><figref idref="f0004">FIG. 4</figref> is a view illustrating a change of light incident angle according to positions deviated from the center of the divergent light when the divergent light incident through the optical fiber ferrule 160 is incident on the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 140 via the splitter 120. As illustrated in <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 4</figref>, when the<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> divergent light is incident on the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 140, the incident angle is increased toward the perimeter.</p>
<p id="p0062" num="0062">As compared to such divergent light, descriptions will be made with reference to <figref idref="f0005">FIG. 5</figref> on an effect on a filter transmission character when a parallel light, of which an incident angle is 0 degree, is incident on the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 140.</p>
<p id="p0063" num="0063"><figref idref="f0005">FIG. 5</figref> is a graph illustrating filter transmission characteristics of the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit for parallel light and divergent light.</p>
<p id="p0064" num="0064">As illustrated, in order for the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 140 to have 30 dB as a light isolation value that represents a light blocking level, the divergent light requires a guard band of at least 14 nm at a reference wavelength of 1355 nm while the parallel light requires only a guard band of 3 nm.</p>
<p id="p0065" num="0065">Here, the guard band means a minimum wavelength interval required for satisfying a light isolation value. The guard band should be narrowed in order to increase an integration degree of an information amount by narrowing a wavelength interval for optical transmission and reception channels in an optical communication network.</p>
<p id="p0066" num="0066">Accordingly, in consideration of the fact that the guard band may be narrowed when parallel light is incident on the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 140 as compared to a case where divergent light is incident, the present disclosure proposes a bi-directional optical transceiver module configured such that the form of incident light incident on the reflected light-blocking optical filter 140 becomes parallel light.</p>
<p id="p0067" num="0067">Hereinafter, descriptions will be made with reference<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> to <figref idref="f0006">FIGs. 6</figref> and <figref idref="f0007">7</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0068" num="0068"><figref idref="f0006">FIG. 6</figref> is a view illustrating a schematic configuration of a bi-directional optical transceiver module according to an embodiment of the present claimed invention .</p>
<p id="p0069" num="0069">The embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 6</figref> includes an optical transmission unit (not illustrated), a splitter 210, and a reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 230, similar to the first embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>, and the functions of respective components are the same. Thus, descriptions for the components will be omitted.</p>
<p id="p0070" num="0070">This embodiment includes a parallel light lens 220. The parallel light lens 220 is configured to convert and output the signal form of an optical signal reflected by the splitter 210 as parallel light.</p>
<p id="p0071" num="0071">Since the light incident on the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 230 through the parallel light lens 220 becomes parallel light, the guard band required for satisfying a preset light isolation value may be considerably narrowed as compared to divergent light as described above. As a result, the condensation degree of communication channels may be greatly improved.</p>
<p id="p0072" num="0072">Meanwhile, when an ordinary parallel light lens is used, a length of a reception end up to the optical reception unit 250 is increased since the parallel light lens is large. In such a case, due to the increased length of the reception end, it is difficult to mount the parallel light lens in an external case having a size designated in SFP (Small Form Pluggable) or SFP+MSA (Multiple Source Agreement) standards.<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --></p>
<p id="p0073" num="0073">Thus, the bi-directional optical transceiver module according to this embodiment is configured to have a reception end length which may be mounted in a case having a miniaturized size requested in the SFP or SFP+ standards while being provided with the parallel lens 220 in a stage in front of the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 230 in order to enhance a condensation degree of optical channels.</p>
<p id="p0074" num="0074">For this purpose, the parallel light lens 220 is characterized in that it does not have a metal lens barrel (unlike a commercially available parallel light lens) and has a short focal distance in a range of 1 mm to 2 mm. In addition, the parallel light lens 220 has an incident surface and a light emission surface opposite to the incident surface and an optical signal is received by the incident surface and output from the light emission surface. Here, the light emission surface is flat.</p>
<p id="p0075" num="0075">In this embodiment, in order to reduce the length of the reception end, the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 230 may be attached to the light emission surface of the parallel light lens 220 having the shape described above via a transparent UV epoxy.</p>
<p id="p0076" num="0076">When the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 230 is directly attached to the light emission surface of the flat parallel light lens 220 via the transparent UV epoxy, the length of the reception end is reduced as compared to a configuration where the parallel light lens 220 and the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 230 are separated from each other.</p>
<p id="p0077" num="0077">In addition, as illustrated in <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 6</figref>, when a<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> condensing lens 251 included in the optical reception unit 250 is mounted on a cap enclosing a light reception lens 253 in an aspheric lens shape rather than in an external-mounting lens shape, the length of the reception end may be reduced.</p>
<p id="p0078" num="0078"><figref idref="f0007">FIG. 7</figref> is a view illustrating a schematic configuration of a bi-directional optical transceiver module according to a second embodiment of the present claimed invention .</p>
<p id="p0079" num="0079">As illustrated in <figref idref="f0007">FIG. 7</figref>, the bi-directional optical transceiver module according to this embodiment is also characterized by including a parallel light lens 220.</p>
<p id="p0080" num="0080">In addition, in the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="f0007">FIG. 7</figref>, in order to reduce the length of the optical reception end, the light emission surface of the parallel light lens 220 is flat and the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 230 is coated on the light emission surface of the parallel light lens 220 such that the parallel light lens 220 and the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 230 are configured in an integrated form.</p>
<p id="p0081" num="0081">The embodiment of coating the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 230 of the light emission surface of the parallel light lens 220 configures the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 230 in a form of thin film and deposits the thin film filter on the light emission surface of the parallel light lens 220.</p>
<p id="p0082" num="0082">In such a case, the length of the optical reception end may be reduced by the thickness of the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit 230, thereby representing a structure which is optimized for miniaturizing the bidirectional<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> optical transceiver module.</p>
<p id="p0083" num="0083">In addition, as described above with reference to <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 6</figref>, the parallel light lens 220 has a focal distance in the range of 1 mm to 2 mm which is shorter than that of an existing parallel light lens.</p>
<p id="p0084" num="0084">The embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="f0007">FIG. 7</figref> has a form which may further miniaturize the bi-directional optical transceiver module as compared to the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 6</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0085" num="0085"><figref idref="f0008">FIG. 8</figref> is a schematic view illustrating an optical communication system using a bi-directional optical transceiver module according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p0086" num="0086">As illustrated, the central station side optical transceiver module and the subscriber side optical transceiver module form a pair, and the bi-directional optical transceiver module of the present disclosure is used. Thus, an upstream signal to the central station side and a downstream signal to the subscriber side will have different wavelength values λ1 and λ2 which have a predetermined difference in interval within a CWDM single channel range.</p>
<p id="p0087" num="0087">In other words, the upstream signal and the downstream signal have different wavelength values λ1 and λ2 unlike the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> in which the upstream signal and the downstream signal have the same wavelength value λ1 of the CWDM single channel. Thus, it is possible to prevent degradation of a communication condition caused due to line reflection or Rayleigh backscattering λ'1. In addition, since the upstream signal and the downstream signal are made to have different<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> wavelength values λ1 and λ2 in the CWDM single channel, transmission efficiency through an optical line may be enhanced and an optical transmission amount may be increased.</p>
<p id="p0088" num="0088"><figref idref="f0009">FIG. 9</figref> is a view illustrating a configuration of an optical communication system according to an embodiment of the present disclosure. <figref idref="f0009">FIG. 9</figref> illustrates an optical communication system which uses a bi-directional optical transceiver module 100 according to an embodiment of the present disclosure configured to perform a communication such that an upstream signal and a downstream signal have different wavelength values λ2n-1 and λ2n (here, n is a natural number which equal to or larger than 1) within a single channel.</p>
<p id="p0089" num="0089">As illustrated, n optical transceiver modules of the central station side and n optical transceiver modules of the subscriber side pair up each other to transmit and receive an upstream signal and a downstream signal, and for the purpose of communication through an optical line, a multiplexer/inverse multiplexer 300-1 and 300-2 are provided to the central station side and the subscriber side, respectively.</p>
<p id="p0090" num="0090"><figref idref="f0010">FIG. 10</figref> is a view illustrating an optical communication system using a bi-directional optical transceiver module, according to another embodiment of the present disclosure. As illustrated, the optical communication system has a configuration in which the central station side and the subscriber side pair up with reference to an optical line. Hereinafter, the optical communication system will be described with reference to the central station side.</p>
<p id="p0091" num="0091">The optical communication system illustrated in <figref idref="f0010">FIG.<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> 10</figref> uses bi-directional optical transceiver module in which an upstream signal and a downstream signal have different wavelength values in a single channel, each two optical transceiver modules provided in the central station side pair up such that two upstream signals and two downstream signals therebetween have different wavelength values λ4n-3, λ4n-2 and λ4n-1, λ4n (here, n is a natural number which is equal to or larger than 1) in a single channel. In other words, the optical communication system illustrated in <figref idref="f0009">FIG. 9</figref> allocates wavelengths to an upstream signal and a downstream signal such that each of the upstream signal and the downstream signal has one wavelength value and the wavelength values of the upstream signal and the downstream signal are different from each other. However, the optical communication system illustrated in <figref idref="f0010">FIG. 10</figref> allocates wavelengths to upstream signals and downstream signals such that each of the upstream signals and the downstream signals has two different wavelength values λ4n-3, A4n-2 and λ4n-1, λ4n.</p>
<p id="p0092" num="0092">The optical communication system of the present disclosure may be configured using bi-directional optical transceiver modules according to an embodiment of the present disclosure such that an optical communication can be performed through a plurality of upstream signals having different wavelength values and a plurality of downstream signals having different wavelength values in which the wavelength values have a predetermined difference in interval in a single channel.</p>
<p id="p0093" num="0093">The multiplexers/inverse multiplexers 400-1a, ..., 400-na may be additionally included separately from the existing multiplexer/inverse multiplexer 300-1. In addition, the multiplexers/inverse multiplexers 400-1a,<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> ..., 400-na connected to a plurality of bi-directional optical transceiver modules so as to perform multiplexing or inverse multiplexing of the upstream signals and the downstream signals thereof.</p>
<p id="p0094" num="0094">Since the configurations of a plurality of bidirectional optical transceiver modules and the multiplexers/inverse multiplexers 400-1b, ..., 400-nb illustrated in the subscriber side in <figref idref="f0010">FIG. 10</figref> correspond to those of the central station side, the descriptions thereof will be omitted.</p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="26"> -->
<claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>A bi-directional optical transceiver module comprising:
<claim-text>an optical transmission unit (110) configured to output a transmission signal, wherein the transmission signal is an upstream signal having a first wavelength value (λ1)</claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical reception unit (130,250) configured to receive an input of a reception signal, wherein the reception signal is a downstream signal having a second wavelength value (λ2) and the first wavelength value (λ1) and the second wavelength value (λ2) are different from each other ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a splitter (120) inclined with respect to an incident direction of the transmission signal output from the optical transmission unit (110) and configured to output said transmission signal to an outside and to reflect optical signals input from the outside, the optical signals comprising said reception signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a reflected light-blocking optical filter unit (140,230) configured to pass, as the reception signal among the optical signals reflected by said splitter (120), an optical signal within a preset wavelength range including the second wavelength value (λ2) so as to block all of an internal reflection signal input to the optical reception unit (130,250) and an external reflection signal, and to separate the first wavelength (λ1) of the transmission signal such that the optical signal corresponding to the reception signal having the second wavelength value (λ2) is incident on the optical reception unit (130,250), wherein the optical signal is converted in a form of parallel light; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a parallel light lens (220) arranged between said splitter (120) and said reflected light-blocking optical filter unit (140,230) and configured to convert and output the reflected optical signals in a form of the parallel light, wherein the parallel light lens (220) includes an incident surface and a light emission surface opposite to the incident surface, the reflected optical signals are received by the incident surface, and the parallel light is emitted through the light emission surface, and the light emission surface is flat</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>characterized in that</b> said first and second wavelength values are allocated within a single Coarse-Wave-Division-Multiplexing, CWDM, channel.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>The bi-directional optical transceiver module of claim 1, wherein the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit (140,230) is directly attached to the light emission surface of the parallel light lens (220), and wherein the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit (140,230) is configured in a form coated on the light emission surface of the parallel light lens (220) such that the parallel light lens and the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit (140,230) take an integrated form.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>The bi-directional optical transceiver module of claim 2, wherein said reflected light-blocking optical filter unit (140,230) is coated on said light emission surface of said parallel light lens (220) under the form of a thin film.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>The bi-directional optical transceiver module of claim 1, further comprising a thermoelectric semiconductor element (150) configured to perform a temperature adjustment of the optical transmission unit in response to an external temperature.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>The bi-directional optical transceiver module of claim 1, wherein the reflected light-blocking optical filter unit (140,230) is attached to the light emission surface of the parallel light lens (220) by a transparent UV epoxy.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>The bi-directional optical transceiver module of claim 1, wherein the parallel light lens (220) does not have a metal lens barrel and has a short focal distance in a range of 1 mm to 2 mm.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>The bi-directional optical transceiver module of claim 1 further comprising a condensing lens (251) included in the optical reception unit (130,250) and mounted on a cap enclosing a light reception lens (253) in an aspheric lens shape.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>An optical communication system comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of bi-directional optical transceiver modules according to one or more of the claims 1 to 7; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a multiplexer/inverse multiplexer connected to the plurality of bidirectional optical transceiver modules to multiplex or inverse-multiplex the<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --> plurality of transmission signals and reception signals having different wavelengths (λ1,λ2).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims02" lang="de"><!-- EPO <DP n="29"> -->
<claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Bidirektionales optisches Transceivermodul, das umfasst:
<claim-text>eine optische Übertragungseinheit (110), die konfiguriert ist, um ein Übertragungssignal auszugeben, wobei das Übertragungssignal ein stromaufwärtiges Signal ist, das einen ersten Wellenlängenwert (λ1) aufweist,</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine optische Empfangseinheit (130, 250), die konfiguriert ist, um eine Eingabe eines Empfangssignals zu empfangen, wobei das Empfangssignal ein stromabwärtiges Signal ist, das einen zweiten Wellenlängenwert (λ2) aufweist, und der erste Wellenlängenwert (λ1) und der zweite Wellenlängenwert (λ2) voneinander unterschiedlich sind;</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Splitter (120), der in Bezug zu einer Einfallsrichtung des Übertragungssignals, das von der optischen Übertragungseinheit (110) ausgegeben wird, geneigt und konfiguriert ist, um das Übertragungssignal nach außen auszugeben und optische Signale, die von außen eingegeben werden, zu reflektieren, wobei die optischen Signale das Empfangssignal umfassen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine reflektiertes Licht blockierende optische Filtereinheit (140, 230), die konfiguriert ist, um als das Empfangssignal unter den optischen Signalen, die von dem Splitter (120) reflektiert werden, ein optisches Signal innerhalb eines voreingestellten Wellenlängenbereichs, der den zweiten Wellenlängenwert (λ2) beinhaltet, durchzulassen, um alle eines internen Reflexionssignals, das zu der optischen Empfangseinheit (130, 250) eingegeben wird, und eines externen Reflexionssignals zu blockieren und die erste Wellenlänge (λ1) des Übertragungssignals derart zu trennen, dass das optische Signal, das dem Empfangssignal entspricht, das den zweiten Wellenlängenwert (λ2) aufweist, auf die optische Empfangseinheit (130, 250) einfällt, wobei das optische Signal in eine Form parallelen Lichts umgewandelt wird; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Linse (220) für paralleles Licht, die zwischen dem Splitter (120) und der reflektierendes Licht blockierenden optischen Filtereinheit (140, 230) eingerichtet und konfiguriert ist, um die reflektierten optischen Signale in eine Form des<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --> parallelen Lichts umzuwandeln und auszugeben, wobei die Linse (220) für paralleles Licht eine Einfallsoberfläche und eine Lichtemissionsoberfläche, die der Einfallsoberfläche entgegengesetzt ist, beinhaltet, wobei die reflektierten optischen Signale von der Einfallsoberfläche empfangen werden, und das parallele Licht durch die Lichtemissionsoberfläche emittiert wird, und die Lichtemissionsoberfläche flach ist, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> der erste und der zweite Wellenlängenwert innerhalb eines einzigen Coarse-Wave-Division-Multiplexing-Kanals, CWDM-Kanals, zugeordnet sind.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Bidirektionales optisches Transceivermodul nach Anspruch 1, wobei die reflektiertes Licht blockierende optische Filtereinheit (140, 230) direkt an der Lichtemissionsoberfläche der Linse (220) für paralleles Licht angebracht ist, und wobei die reflektiertes Licht blockierende optische Filtereinheit (140, 230) in einer Form konfiguriert ist, die auf die Lichtemissionsoberfläche der Linse (220) für paralleles Licht derart aufgebracht ist, dass die Linse für paralleles Licht und die reflektiertes Licht blockierende optische Filtereinheit (140, 230), eine integrierte Form annehmen.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Bidirektionales optisches Transceivermodul nach Anspruch 2, wobei die reflektiertes Licht blockierende optische Filtereinheit (140, 230), auf der Lichtemissionsoberfläche der Linse (220) mit parallelem Licht in der Form einer dünnen Folie aufgebracht ist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Bidirektionales optisches Transceivermodul nach Anspruch 1, das weiter ein thermoelektrisches Halbleiterelement (150) umfasst, das konfiguriert ist, um eine Temperatureinstellung der optischen Übertragungseinheit als Reaktion auf eine externe Temperatur auszuführen.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Bidirektionales optisches Transceivermodul nach Anspruch 1, wobei die reflektiertes Licht blockierende optische Filtereinheit (140, 230), an der<!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --> Lichtemissionsoberfläche der Linse (220) für paralleles Licht durch ein UVtransparentes Epoxidharz angebracht ist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Bidirektionales optisches Transceivermodul nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Linse (220) für paralleles Licht keinen Metallobjektivtubus aufweist und eine kurze Brennweite in einem Bereich von 1 mm bis 2 mm aufweist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Bidirektionales optisches Transceivermodul nach Anspruch 1, das weiter eine Kollektivlinse (251) umfasst, die in der optischen Empfangseinheit (130, 250) beinhaltet und auf einer Kappe montiert ist, die eine Lichtempfangslinse (253) in einer asphärischen Linsenform einschließt.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>Optisches Kommunikationssystem, das umfasst:
<claim-text>eine Vielzahl bidirektionaler optischer Transceivermodule nach einem oder mehreren der Ansprüche 1 bis 7; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Multiplexer/Demultiplexer, der mit der Vielzahl bidirektionaler optischer Transceivermodule verbunden ist, um die Vielzahl von Übertragungssignalen und Empfangssignalen, die unterschiedliche Wellenlängen (λ1, λ2) aufweisen, zu multiplexen oder demultiplexen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims03" lang="fr"><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> -->
<claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Module d'émission et de réception optique bidirectionnel comprenant :
<claim-text>une unité d'émission optique (110) configurée pour délivrer en sortie un signal d'émission, dans lequel le signal d'émission est un signal de liaison montante ayant une première valeur de longueur d'onde (λ1)</claim-text>
<claim-text>une unité de réception optique (130, 250) configurée pour recevoir une entrée d'un signal de réception, dans lequel le signal de réception est un signal de liaison descendante ayant une seconde valeur de longueur d'onde (λ2) et la première valeur de longueur d'onde (λ1) et la seconde valeur de longueur d'onde (λ2) sont différentes l'une de l'autre ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un séparateur (120) incliné par rapport à une direction incidente du signal d'émission délivré en sortie à partir de l'unité d'émission optique (110) et configuré pour délivrer en sortie ledit signal d'émission vers un extérieur et pour réfléchir des signaux optiques appliqués en entrée à partir de l'extérieur, les signaux optiques comprenant ledit signal de réception ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une unité de filtre optique à blocage de lumière réfléchie (140, 230) configurée pour laisser passer, comme le signal de réception parmi les signaux optiques réfléchis par ledit séparateur (120), un signal optique dans une plage de longueur d'onde prédéfinie incluant la seconde valeur de longueur d'onde (λ2) de manière à bloquer la totalité d'un signal de réflexion interne appliqué en entrée à l'unité de réception optique (130, 250) et d'un signal de réflexion externe, et pour séparer la première longueur d'onde (λ1) du signal d'émission de manière que le signal optique correspondant au signal de réception ayant la seconde valeur de longueur d'onde (λ2) soit incident sur l'unité de réception optique (130, 250), dans lequel le signal optique est converti sous une forme de lumière parallèle ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une lentille de lumière parallèle (220) agencée entre ledit séparateur (120) et ladite unité de filtre optique à blocage de lumière réfléchie (140, 230) et configurée pour convertir et délivrer en sortie les signaux optiques réfléchis sous la forme de la lumière parallèle, dans lequel la lentille de lumière parallèle (220) inclut une surface incidente et une surface d'émission de lumière opposée à la surface incidente, les signaux optiques réfléchis sont reçus par la surface incidente et la lumière parallèle<!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --> est émise à travers la surface d'émission de lumière, et la surface d'émission de lumière est plate</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>caractérisé en ce que</b> lesdites première et seconde valeurs de longueur d'onde sont attribuées à l'intérieur d'un canal de multiplexage par répartition en longueur d'onde grossière, CWDM.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Module d'émission et de réception optique bidirectionnel selon la revendication 1, dans lequel l'unité de filtre optique à blocage de lumière réfléchie (140, 230) est fixée directement à la surface d'émission de lumière de la lentille de lumière parallèle (220), et dans lequel l'unité de filtre optique à blocage de lumière réfléchie (140, 230) est configurée sous une forme revêtue sur la surface d'émission de lumière de la lentille de lumière parallèle (220) de manière que la lentille de lumière parallèle et l'unité de filtre optique à blocage de lumière réfléchie (140, 230) prennent une forme intégrée.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Module d'émission et de réception optique bidirectionnel selon la revendication 2, dans lequel ladite unité de filtre optique à blocage de lumière réfléchie (140, 230) est revêtue sur ladite surface d'émission de lumière de ladite lentille de lumière parallèle (220) sous la forme d'un film mince.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Module d'émission et de réception optique bidirectionnel selon la revendication 1, comprenant en outre un élément semi-conducteur thermoélectrique (150) configuré pour réaliser un ajustement de température de l'unité d'émission optique en réponse à une température extérieure.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Module d'émission et de réception optique bidirectionnel selon la revendication 1, dans lequel l'unité de filtre optique à blocage de lumière réfléchie (140, 230) est fixée à la surface d'émission de lumière de la lentille de lumière parallèle (220) par une résine époxy UV transparente.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Module d'émission et de réception optique bidirectionnel selon la revendication 1, dans lequel la lentille de lumière parallèle (220) n'a pas un tube de lentille métallique et a une distance focale courte dans une plage de 1 mm à 2 mm.<!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Module d'émission et de réception optique bidirectionnel selon la revendication 1, comprenant en outre une lentille de condensation (251) incluse dans l'unité de réception optique (130, 250) et montée dans un capuchon enfermant une lentille de réception de lumière (253) dans une forme de lentille asphérique.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>Système de communication optique comprenant :
<claim-text>une pluralité de modules d'émission et de réception optique bidirectionnels selon une ou plusieurs des revendications 1 à 7 ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un multiplexeur/multiplexeur inversé connecté à la pluralité de modules d'émission et de réception optique bidirectionnels pour le multiplexage ou le multiplexage inverse de la pluralité de signaux d'émission et de signaux de réception ayant différentes longueurs d'onde (λ1, λ2).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="35"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="161" he="84" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="36"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="145" he="218" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="37"> -->
<figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="150" he="215" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="38"> -->
<figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="143" he="109" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="39"> -->
<figure id="f0005" num="5"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="151" he="128" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="40"> -->
<figure id="f0006" num="6"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="147" he="167" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="41"> -->
<figure id="f0007" num="7"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="148" he="161" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="42"> -->
<figure id="f0008" num="8"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="161" he="88" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="43"> -->
<figure id="f0009" num="9"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="114" he="207" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="44"> -->
<figure id="f0010" num="10"><img id="if0010" file="imgf0010.tif" wi="108" he="211" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<ep-reference-list id="ref-list">
<heading id="ref-h0001"><b>REFERENCES CITED IN THE DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0001" num=""><i>This list of references cited by the applicant is for the reader's convenience only. It does not form part of the European patent document. Even though great care has been taken in compiling the references, errors or omissions cannot be excluded and the EPO disclaims all liability in this regard.</i></p>
<heading id="ref-h0002"><b>Patent documents cited in the description</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0002" num="">
<ul id="ref-ul0001" list-style="bullet">
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0001" dnum="US2011044696A"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2011044696</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0001">[0008]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0002" dnum="CN102279445"><document-id><country>CN</country><doc-number>102279445</doc-number></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0002">[0008]</crossref></li>
</ul></p>
</ep-reference-list>
</ep-patent-document>
