<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP21150814A1" file="EP21150814NWA1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3890289" kind="A1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSK..HRIS..MTNORS..SM..................</B001EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  1100000/0</B007EP><B053EP>This application was filed on 10.01.2021 as a divisional application to the application mentioned under INID code 62.</B053EP><B053EP>Claims filed after the date of receipt of the divisional application (Rule 68(4) EPC).</B053EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3890289</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT APPLICATION</B121></B120><B130>A1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>21150814.8</B210><B220><date>20140312</date></B220><B250>zh</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B430></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>H04M   1/67        20060101AFI20210826BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="2"><text>H04M   1/72427     20210101ALI20210826BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="3"><text>H04M   1/72448     20210101ALI20210826BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>H04M   1/67        20130101 FI20151029BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>H04M   1/72448     20210101 LI20210101RHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="3"><text>H04M   1/72427     20210101 LI20210101RHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>BILDSCHIRMSPERRVERFAHREN UND MOBILES ENDGERÄT</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>SCREEN LOCKING METHOD AND MOBILE TERMINAL</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>PROCÉDÉ DE VERROUILLAGE D'ÉCRAN ET TERMINAL MOBILE</B542></B540><B590><B598>4</B598></B590></B500><B600><B620><parent><pdoc><dnum><anum>19190672.6</anum><pnum>3629564</pnum></dnum><date>20190808</date></pdoc><pdoc><dnum><anum>14885457.3</anum><pnum>3119064</pnum></dnum><date>20140312</date></pdoc></parent></B620></B600><B700><B710><B711><snm>Huawei Device Co., Ltd.</snm><iid>101787393</iid><irf>84082151EP30</irf><adr><str>B2-5 of Nanfang Factory 
No.2 of Xincheng Road 
Songshan Lake Science and Technology 
Industrial Zone</str><city>Dongguan, Guangdong 523808</city><ctry>CN</ctry></adr></B711></B710><B720><B721><snm>FANG, Chao</snm><adr><str>Huawei Device Co.,Ltd., Intellectual Property
Department
c/o Huawei Administration Building, Bantian
Longgang District</str><city>Shenzhen, Guangdong</city><ctry>CN</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>GAO, Zhang</snm><adr><str>Huawei Device Co.,Ltd., Intellectual Property
Department
c/o Huawei Administration Building, Bantian
Longgang District</str><city>Shenzhen, Guangdong</city><ctry>CN</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>NI, Yuanqiang</snm><adr><str>Huawei Device Co.,Ltd., Intellectual Property
Department
c/o Huawei Administration Building, Bantian
Longgang District</str><city>Shenzhen, Guangdong</city><ctry>CN</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B740><B741><snm>Kreuz, Georg Maria</snm><iid>101362137</iid><adr><str>Huawei Technologies Duesseldorf GmbH 
Riesstraße 25</str><city>80992 München</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840></B800></SDOBI>
<abstract id="abst" lang="en">
<p id="pa01" num="0001">An embodiment of the present invention discloses a screen locking method, including: receiving an instruction, of a user, for lighting up a screen of a mobile terminal, and lighting up the screen of the mobile terminal; and in a lock screen state, invoking a first picture from local pictures stored in the mobile terminal to replace a preset lock screen background, where the first picture is obtained by a user by means of downloading and photographing, or pushed by a server to the mobile terminal according to a preference of a user. An embodiment of the present invention further discloses a mobile terminal. In the present invention, automatic switching of a lock screen background in a lock screen state can be implemented, and a user can see a new lock screen background provided that a screen is lit up, thereby increasing variability of a lock screen background, improving switching efficiency, and enhancing a feeling of freshness of a user on a lock screen.
<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="68" he="117" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p>
</abstract>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<heading id="h0001"><b>TECHNICAL FIELD</b></heading>
<p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to the field of communications technologies, and in particular, to a screen locking method and a mobile terminal.</p>
<heading id="h0002"><b>BACKGROUND</b></heading>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">With popularity of an intelligent mobile terminal, such as a mobile phone and a tablet, and rapid development of a mobile internet, there are an increasing number of users who use an intelligent mobile terminal. A screen locking function, which is a first impression made by an intelligent mobile terminal on a user, has become one of standard applications of the intelligent mobile terminal. Therefore, the screen locking function belongs to an application extremely frequently used by a user. However, only some static functions can be provided by a screen locking manner in the prior art, for example, a conventional lock and unlock function is used to provide protection against a misoperation and security protection such as a cipher lock; a prompting function for basic information is used to prompt a user with incoming-call information and SMS message information; and an entry to a common setting and a common function is used for a user to rapidly set brightness and a data service switch or quick entry to some applications such as photographing. In general, a screen locking manner in the prior art is static. After a user sets a lock screen background, an unlock manner and an application entry, basically, a lock screen desktop may not change except indicating an SMS message or a call. Particularly, a background of the lock screen desktop is mechanical, lacks freshness, and cannot automatically switch.</p>
<heading id="h0003"><b>SUMMARY</b></heading>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">Embodiments of the present invention provide a screen locking method and a mobile terminal, to resolve a problem that a background of a lock screen desktop is mechanical, lacks freshness, and cannot automatically switch.</p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">A first aspect of the embodiments of the present invention provides a screen locking method, including:
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>receiving an instruction, of a user, for lighting up a screen of a mobile terminal, and lighting up the screen of the mobile terminal; and</li>
<li>in a lock screen state, invoking a first picture from local pictures stored in the mobile terminal to replace a preset lock screen background, where the first picture is obtained by a user by means of downloading or photographing, or pushed by a server to the mobile terminal according to a preference of a user.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">In a first possible implementation manner of the first aspect, the method further includes:<br/>
receiving an acquiring instruction generated when the user executes a preset gesture operation, acquiring content introduction information of the first picture, and displaying the content introduction information on a lock screen configuration interface.</p>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">With reference to the first possible implementation manner of the first aspect, in a second possible<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> implementation manner, the method further includes:<br/>
receiving comment information that is of the first picture and is input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and uploading the comment information to the server, so that the server learns the preference of the user and pushes a picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal.</p>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">With reference to the first aspect or the first possible implementation manner of the first aspect, in a third possible implementation manner, the method further includes:
<ul id="ul0002" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>analyzing, by the mobile terminal, the preference of the user according to a search record and a browsing record that are of the user and in a mobile browser, and uploading an analysis result to the server, so that the server pushes a picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal; or</li>
<li>uploading, by the mobile terminal, a search record and a browsing record that are of the user and in a mobile browser to the server, so that the server analyzes the preference of the user and pushes a picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">With reference to the first aspect or with reference to the first, the second, or the third possible implementation manner of the first aspect, in a fourth possible implementation manner, the method further includes:
<ul id="ul0003" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>receiving a picture switching mode configuration instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and enabling or disabling switching of a lock screen background; and</li>
<li>receiving a picture type setting instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, so that when the screen is lit up next time and switching of the lock screen background is enabled, a picture that meets a picture type set by the user is invoked as the lock screen background.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">With reference to the first aspect or with reference to the first, the second, the third, or the fourth possible implementation manner of the first aspect, in a fifth possible implementation manner, the method further includes:
<ul id="ul0004" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>when the mobile terminal receives again, after the screen is turned off, the instruction, of the user, for lighting up the screen of the mobile terminal, lighting up the screen of the mobile terminal; and</li>
<li>in the lock screen state, invoking a second picture from the local pictures stored in the mobile terminal to replace the first picture as the lock screen background.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">With reference to the fourth or the fifth possible implementation manner of the first aspect, in a sixth possible implementation manner, the method further includes:
<ul id="ul0005" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>when there is no picture that meets a preset picture type in the local pictures, randomly invoking a picture of another type in the local pictures to replace the preset lock screen background, or informing the user that there is no eligible picture; and</li>
<li>after all pictures that meet the preset picture type in the local pictures are switched, randomly invoking a picture of another type in the local pictures to replace the preset lock screen background, or informing the user that there is no new picture and pausing switching of the lock screen background until the user updates the local pictures.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">With reference to the first, the second, or the fourth possible implementation manner of the first aspect, in a seventh possible implementation manner, the method further includes:
<ul id="ul0006" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>receiving an instruction, input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, for displaying a next picture, acquiring a second picture and content introduction information of the second picture, replacing the first picture with the second picture as the lock screen background, and displaying the content introduction information of the second picture on the lock screen configuration interface; and/or</li>
<li>receiving a picture sharing instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface,<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> acquiring a to-be-shared picture, and sharing the to-be-shared picture on another mobile terminal or a social network; and/or</li>
<li>receiving a local-picture update setting instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and specifying a network communication mode used when the mobile terminal receives the picture pushed by the server.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">A second aspect of the embodiments of the present invention provides a mobile terminal, including:
<ul id="ul0007" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>a lighting-up unit, configured to: receive an instruction, of a user, for lighting up a screen of a mobile terminal, and light up the screen of the mobile terminal; and</li>
<li>an invoking unit, configured to: in a lock screen state, invoke a first picture from local pictures stored in the mobile terminal to replace a preset lock screen background, where the first picture is obtained by a user by means of downloading or photographing, or pushed by a server to the mobile terminal according to a preference of a user.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">In a first possible implementation manner of the second aspect, the mobile terminal further includes:<br/>
an acquiring unit, configured to: receive an acquiring instruction generated when the user executes a preset gesture operation, acquire content introduction information of the first picture, and display the content introduction information on a lock screen configuration interface.</p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">With reference to the first possible implementation manner of the second aspect, in a second possible implementation manner, the mobile terminal further includes:<br/>
a configuring unit, configured to: receive comment information that is of the first picture and is input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and upload the comment information to the server, so that the server learns the preference of the user and pushes a picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal.</p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">With reference to the second aspect or the first possible implementation manner of the second aspect, in a third possible implementation manner, the mobile terminal further includes:
<ul id="ul0008" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>an uploading unit, configured to: analyze the preference of the user according to a search record and a browsing record that are of the user and in a mobile browser, and upload an analysis result to the server, so that the server pushes a picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal; or</li>
<li>configured to upload a search record and a browsing record that are of the user and in a mobile browser to the server, so that the server analyzes the preference of the user and pushes a picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">With reference to the second aspect or with reference to the first, the second, or the third possible implementation manner of the second aspect, in a fourth possible implementation manner, the configuring unit is further configured to:
<ul id="ul0009" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>receive a picture switching mode configuration instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and enable or disable switching of a lock screen background; and</li>
<li>receive a picture type setting instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, so that when the screen is lit up next time and switching of the lock screen background is enabled, a picture that meets a picture type set by the user is invoked as the lock screen background.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">With reference to the second aspect or with reference to the first, the second, the third, or the fourth possible implementation manner of the second aspect, in a fifth possible implementation manner,<br/>
the lighting-up unit is further configured to: when the mobile terminal receives again, after the screen is turned off, the instruction, of the user, for lighting up the screen of the mobile terminal, light up the screen of the<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> mobile terminal; and<br/>
the invoking unit is further configured to: in the lock screen state, invoke a second picture from the local pictures stored in the mobile terminal to replace the first picture as the lock screen background.</p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">With reference to the fourth or the fifth possible implementation manner of the second aspect, in a sixth possible implementation manner, the invoking unit is further configured to:
<ul id="ul0010" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>when there is no picture that meets a picture type preset by the user in the local pictures, randomly invoke a picture of another type in the local pictures to replace the preset lock screen background, or inform the user that there is no eligible picture; and</li>
<li>after all pictures that meet the picture type preset by the user in the local pictures are switched, randomly invoke a picture of another type in the local pictures to replace the preset lock screen background, or inform the user that there is no new picture and pause switching of the lock screen background until the user updates the local pictures.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">With reference to the first, the second, or the fourth possible implementation manner of the second aspect, in a seventh possible implementation manner, the configuring unit is further configured to:
<ul id="ul0011" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>receive an instruction, input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, for displaying a next picture, acquire a second picture and content introduction information of the second picture, replace the first picture with the second picture as the lock screen background, and display the content introduction information of the second picture on the lock screen configuration interface; and/or</li>
<li>receive a picture sharing instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, acquire a to-be-shared picture, and share the to-be-shared picture on another mobile terminal or a social network; and/or</li>
<li>receive a local-picture update setting instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and specify a network communication mode used when the mobile terminal receives the picture pushed by the server.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">A third aspect of the embodiments of the present invention provides a mobile terminal, including:<br/>
an input device, an output device, a memory, and a processor, where the input device, the output device, the memory, and the processor are connected to a bus, the memory stores a set of program code, and the processor is configured to invoke the program code stored in the memory and execute the following operations:
<ul id="ul0012" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>receiving an instruction, of a user, for lighting up a screen of the mobile terminal, and lighting up the screen of the mobile terminal; and</li>
<li>in a lock screen state, invoking a first picture from local pictures stored in the mobile terminal to replace a preset lock screen background, where the first picture is obtained by a user by means of downloading or photographing, or pushed by a server to the mobile terminal according to a preference of a user.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">In a first possible implementation manner of the third aspect, the processor is further configured to execute the following operations:<br/>
receiving an acquiring instruction generated when the user executes a preset gesture operation, acquiring content introduction information of the first picture, and displaying the content introduction information on a lock screen configuration interface.</p>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">With reference to the first possible implementation manner of the third aspect, in a second possible implementation manner, the mobile terminal further includes a transmitter; the processor is further configured to execute the following operations:<br/>
receiving comment information that is of the first picture and is input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and uploading the comment information to the server by using the transmitter, so that the<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> server learns the preference of the user and pushes a picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal.</p>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">With reference to the third aspect or the first possible implementation manner of the third aspect, in a third possible implementation manner, the mobile terminal further includes a transmitter; the processor is further configured to execute the following operations:
<ul id="ul0013" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>analyzing the preference of the user according to a search record and a browsing record that are of the user and in a mobile browser, and uploading an analysis result to the server by using the transmitter, so that the server pushes a picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal; or</li>
<li>uploading a search record and a browsing record that are of the user and in a mobile browser to the server by using the transmitter, so that the server analyzes the preference of the user and pushes a picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">With reference to the third aspect or with reference to the first, the second, or the third possible implementation manner of the third aspect, in a fourth possible implementation manner, the processor is further configured to execute the following operations:
<ul id="ul0014" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>receiving a picture switching mode configuration instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and enabling or disabling switching of a lock screen background; and</li>
<li>receiving a picture type setting instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, so that when the screen is lit up next time and switching of the lock screen background is enabled, a picture that meets a picture type set by the user is invoked as the lock screen background.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">With reference to the third aspect or with reference to the first, the second, the third, or the fourth possible implementation manner of the third aspect, in a fifth possible implementation manner, the processor is further configured to execute the following operations:
<ul id="ul0015" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>when the mobile terminal receives again, after the screen is turned off, the instruction, of the user, for lighting up the screen of the mobile terminal, lighting up the screen of the mobile terminal; and</li>
<li>in the lock screen state, invoking a second picture from the local pictures stored in the mobile terminal to replace the first picture as the lock screen background.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">With reference to the fourth or the fifth possible implementation manner of the third aspect, in a sixth possible implementation manner, the processor is further configured to execute the following operations:
<ul id="ul0016" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>when there is no picture that meets a picture type preset by the user in the local pictures, randomly invoking a picture of another type in the local pictures to replace the preset lock screen background, or informing the user that there is no eligible picture; and</li>
<li>after all pictures that meet the picture type preset by the user in the local pictures are switched, randomly invoking a picture of another type in the local pictures to replace the preset lock screen background, or informing the user that there is no new picture and pausing switching of the lock screen background until the user updates the local pictures.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">With reference to the first, the second, or the fourth possible implementation manner of the third aspect, in a seventh possible implementation manner, the processor is further configured to execute the following operations:
<ul id="ul0017" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>receiving an instruction, input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, for displaying a next picture, acquiring a second picture and content introduction information about the second picture, replacing the first picture with the second picture as the lock screen background, and displaying the content introduction information of the second picture on the lock screen configuration interface; and/or<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></li>
<li>receiving a picture sharing instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, acquiring a to-be-shared picture, and sharing the to-be-shared picture on another mobile terminal or a social network; and/or</li>
<li>receiving a local-picture update setting instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and specifying a network communication mode used when the mobile terminal receives the picture pushed by the server.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">Implementation of the embodiments of the present invention has the following beneficial effects:<br/>
a screen of a mobile terminal is lit up, and a local picture is invoked to replace a preset lock screen background when the mobile terminal is in a lock screen state, so that a lock screen background automatically switches in the lock screen state, and a user can see a new lock screen background provided that the screen is lit up, thereby increasing variability of a lock screen background, improving switching efficiency, and enhancing a feeling of freshness of a user on a lock screen.</p>
<heading id="h0004"><b>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF DRAWINGS</b></heading>
<p id="p0029" num="0029">To describe the technical solutions in the embodiments of the present invention or in the prior art more clearly, the following briefly introduces the accompanying drawings required for describing the embodiments. Apparently, the accompanying drawings in the following description show merely some embodiments of the present invention, and a person of ordinary skill in the art may still derive other drawings from these accompanying drawings without creative efforts.
<ul id="ul0018" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li><figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic flowchart of a first embodiment of a screen locking method according to the present invention;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0001">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic flowchart of a second embodiment of a screen locking method according to the present invention;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic flowchart of a third embodiment of a screen locking method according to the present invention;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 4</figref> is a schematic flowchart of a fourth embodiment of a screen locking method according to the present invention;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0004">FIG. 5</figref> is a schematic diagram of a lock screen interface when a screen locking method according to the present invention is used;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0005">FIG. 6</figref> is a schematic diagram of a lock screen configuration interface corresponding to the lock screen interface in <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 5</figref>;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0005">FIG. 7</figref> is a schematic structural diagram of a first embodiment of a mobile terminal according to the present invention;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0006">FIG. 8</figref> is a schematic structural diagram of a second embodiment of a mobile terminal according to the present invention;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0006">FIG. 9</figref> is a schematic structural diagram of a third embodiment of a mobile terminal according to the present invention; and</li>
<li><figref idref="f0006">FIG. 10</figref> is a schematic structural diagram of a fourth embodiment of a mobile terminal according to the present invention.</li>
</ul><!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p>
<heading id="h0005"><b>DESCRIPTION OF EMBODIMENTS</b></heading>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">The following clearly and completely describes the technical solutions in the embodiments of the present invention with reference to the accompanying drawings in the embodiments of the present invention. Apparently, the described embodiments are merely a part rather than all of the embodiments of the present invention. All other embodiments obtained by a person of ordinary skill in the art based on the embodiments of the present invention without creative efforts shall fall within the protection scope of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p0031" num="0031">Referring to <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1, FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic flowchart of a first embodiment of a screen locking method according to the present invention. In this embodiment, the method includes the following steps:</p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032">S101: Receive an instruction, of a user, for lighting up a screen of a mobile terminal, and light up the screen of the mobile terminal.</p>
<p id="p0033" num="0033">S102: In a lock screen state, invoke a first picture from local pictures stored in the mobile terminal to replace a preset lock screen background.</p>
<p id="p0034" num="0034">The first picture may be obtained by the user by means of active downloading or photographing, or may be pushed by a server to the mobile terminal according to a preference of the user.</p>
<p id="p0035" num="0035">For example, if the user likes traveling, the user may actively download some scenery photos of a tourist attraction or save a photo photographed during traveling on the mobile terminal, to be used as a candidate picture of a lock screen background. The user may also comment on an existing lock screen background, so that the server learns the preference of the user, and the server pushes a scenery-type picture.</p>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">Optionally, in an implementation manner of this embodiment of the present invention, the first picture may be an electronic magazine in a form of picture. The mobile terminal may invoke a locally stored electronic magazine to replace the preset lock screen background, where the electronic magazine is presented in a form of picture. The electronic magazine may be downloaded by the user, may be made by the user by using local software of the mobile terminal, or may be pushed by the server, for example, an application store regularly pushes an electronic magazine to a terminal, so as to recommend and introduce related information of the application store or a vendor of the terminal. The electronic magazine has both a feature of a plane and a feature of the Internet, and can embrace mutual dynamic combination of a picture, a text, a sound, a video, a game, and the like. After the user lights up the screen, in the lock screen state, the mobile terminal invokes a lock screen magazine to replace the preset lock screen background, which may specifically be the following one or several cases: presenting a cover picture or a content picture of the electronic magazine; playing background music of the electronic magazine; playing a preset video of the electronic magazine; presenting a game interface entry in the electronic magazine; and so on. Further, the electronic magazine may further include a network element such as a hyperlink and a instant interaction, which ensures that a user can participate in an interaction in addition to learning content of the magazine, thereby improving user experience. In this embodiment of the present invention, a format of the electronic magazine is not limited, and may be an ie format, an im format, an flv format, and the like. A travel topic is still used as an example. If a currently stored electronic magazine is a travel-type electronic magazine whose format is the flv format, when the user lights up the mobile terminal, the user generally presses a power button of the mobile terminal. In this case, the mobile terminal receives the instruction, of the user, for lighting up the screen; therefore, in the lock screen state, a scenery picture is invoked from a travel-type electronic magazine stored in the mobile terminal to replace the preset lock screen background. When the picture is invoked from the travel-type electronic magazine, invoking may be performed<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> according to pages of the electronic magazine in order or in reverse order, or invoking may be performed randomly, which is not limited herein. Certainly, content introduction information such as text content, video content, or music content related to the scenery picture may also be shown on a lock screen interface. Certainly, an additional display interface may also be configured to display the content. For example, on the lock screen interface, the user may flick upward to trigger the mobile terminal to switch to another display interface to show the text content, video content, or music content. Therefore, when the user uses the electronic magazine as a lock screen background, in a case in which no misoperation is caused, the user may acquire information from the lock screen interface in a multi-dimensional manner (including an image, a text, a sound, a video, and an interaction), thereby improving user experience.</p>
<p id="p0037" num="0037">In this embodiment, a format of a picture that is invoked for replacing the preset background is not limited, and a jpg format, a bmp format, a png format, a gif format, and the like may all be invoked. A picture in the gif format may be directly invoked as a dynamic lock screen background, or after a picture in the gif format is invoked, a frame of image of the invoked picture may be captured as a static lock screen background, which is not limited in the present invention either.</p>
<p id="p0038" num="0038">It should be noted that, in the foregoing, a scenery-type picture is used as an example for description, but a type of the picture may include but is not limited to a scenery-type picture, a person-type picture, an animal-type picture, an automobile-type picture, a science/technology-type picture, a sports-type picture, and a military-type picture. Specifically, pictures may be stored in different folders, and each type of picture may further be classified into some subtypes, for example, a sports type may be classified into a basketball subtype, a football subtype, and the like.</p>
<p id="p0039" num="0039">A screen of a mobile terminal is lit up, and a local picture is invoked to replace a preset lock screen background when the mobile terminal is in a lock screen state, so that automatic switching of a lock screen background in the lock screen state is implemented, and a user can see a new lock screen background provided that the screen is lit up, thereby increasing variability of a lock screen background, improving switching efficiency, and enhancing a feeling of freshness of a user on a lock screen.</p>
<p id="p0040" num="0040">After the screen of the mobile terminal is turned off, the user needs to light up the screen of the mobile terminal again. Referring to <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 2, FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic flowchart of a second embodiment of a screen locking method according to the present invention. In this embodiment, steps S201 to S202 are the same as steps S 101 to S 102 in the first embodiment of a screen locking method according to the present invention, which are not described herein again.</p>
<p id="p0041" num="0041">S203: When the mobile terminal receives again, after the screen is turned off, the instruction, of the user, for lighting up the screen of the mobile terminal, light up the screen of the mobile terminal.</p>
<p id="p0042" num="0042">S204: In the lock screen state, invoke a second picture from the local pictures stored in the mobile terminal to replace the first picture as a lock screen background.</p>
<p id="p0043" num="0043">In this way, each time when the user lights up the screen, the mobile terminal automatically switches the lock screen background once, so that the lock screen background becomes diversified, thereby improving user experience.</p>
<p id="p0044" num="0044">Optionally, a picture on the mobile terminal may be downloaded by the user, or may be pushed by the server. When the server pushes a picture, to reduce storage pressure of the mobile terminal, a picture liked by the user needs to be pushed according to a preference of the user. Therefore, the server has to learn the preference of the user. A manner for acquiring the preference of the user may be as follows: first configuring a lock screen configuration interface for the mobile terminal, where the lock screen configuration interface is used to configure various functions<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> of a lock screen, for example, the functions may include but are not limited to enabling and disabling of the lock screen, commenting on a current lock screen background, and the like. To enable the user to learn a picture better, content introduction information of the picture may further be displayed on the lock screen configuration interface. Specifically, referring to <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 3, FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic flowchart of a third embodiment of a screen locking method according to the present invention. In this embodiment, steps S301 to S302 are the same as steps S 101 to S102, which are not described herein again.</p>
<p id="p0045" num="0045">S303: Receive an acquiring instruction generated when the user executes a preset gesture operation, acquire content introduction information of the first picture, and display the content introduction information on a lock screen configuration interface.</p>
<p id="p0046" num="0046">Optionally, the preset gesture operation may be an upward flick and a downward flick on the screen of the mobile terminal, touching and holding a screen, or double-tapping a screen, provided that the preset gesture operation does not conflict with a gesture operation of another function. In this embodiment, a gesture operation of an upward flick is used as an example for description.</p>
<p id="p0047" num="0047">The content introduction information of the first picture may be an explanation or a description of picture content. For example, for a scenery-type picture, a site in which scenery is located and a scenery feature may be described; for a picture of a sports star in a sports-type picture, brilliant achievements of the sports star may be introduced and described; and so on. Even a network connection address may further be attached to the content introduction information, so that a user who is interested in the content introduction information taps the address to learn more details.</p>
<p id="p0048" num="0048">S304: Receive comment information that is of the first picture and is input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and upload the comment information to a server, so that the server learns a preference of the user and pushes a picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal.</p>
<p id="p0049" num="0049">On the lock screen configuration interface, a "favorite" option may be set. The user only needs to tap the option to comment on a current lock screen background. The comment information is uploaded to the server, and the server may learn the preference of the user, so that a picture liked by the user is pushed as the lock screen background when a photo is pushed.</p>
<p id="p0050" num="0050">Certainly, when learning the preference of the user, the mobile terminal may further analyze the preference of the user according to a search record and a browsing record that are of the user and in a mobile browser, and upload an analysis result to the server, so that the server pushes the picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal; or<br/>
the mobile terminal uploads a search record and a browsing record that are of the user and in a mobile browser to the server, so that the server analyzes the preference of the user and pushes the picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal.</p>
<p id="p0051" num="0051">The user may only stay on the lock screen interface and not necessarily switch to the lock screen configuration interface to comment on the current lock screen background, and therefore, the mobile terminal may further analyze the preference of the user according to the search record and the browsing record that are of the user and in the mobile browser. If the user often searches for or browses a website about an automobile, an automobile-type picture may be pushed to the user; and when the user often searches for or browses a website about a mobile phone or a computer, a science/technology-type picture may be pushed to the user.</p>
<p id="p0052" num="0052">It should be noted that, when the two manners for learning the preference of the user are performed at<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> the same time, the server may give priority to comment information of the user; certainly, the server may also give priority to an analysis result obtained according to a search record and a browsing record; or the server may further allocate different weights to results that are obtained in the two manners, and acquire a most accurate preference of the user by means of weighted calculation.</p>
<p id="p0053" num="0053">Specifically, when the server pushes a picture, the picture may be pushed in a form of theme or electronic magazine, where the theme may include a lock screen background and display icons of various functions, and the electronic magazine may include a picture, music, a video, and even a hyperlink, and the like. Certainly, the server may also push a picture only in a form of picture, and only a picture used as the lock screen background is included.</p>
<p id="p0054" num="0054">In this embodiment, a screen of a mobile terminal is lit up, and a picture is invoked to replace a preset lock screen background, thereby increasing variability of a lock screen background, and enhancing a feeling of freshness of a user on a lock screen; a picture content introduction after a lock screen background is switched may be viewed by means of a preset gesture operation, thereby enriching content of the lock screen; and an entry to picture commenting is provided, which helps a server learn a preference of the user, so that a picture that meets the preference of the user is pushed to the user as a lock screen background, thereby improving user experience.</p>
<p id="p0055" num="0055">Optionally, another function option may also be configured on the lock screen configuration interface, so that the user performs further configuration for the lock screen, such as an on and off option for switching a lock screen, an option for setting a picture switching type, an option for viewing a next picture, and an option for sharing a current lock screen background. Referring to <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 4, FIG. 4</figref> is a schematic flowchart of a fourth embodiment of a lock screen method according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p0056" num="0056">When these function options exist, the method includes the following steps:
<ul id="ul0019" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>S401: Receive a picture switching mode configuration instruction input by a user on the lock screen configuration interface, and enable or disable switching of a lock screen background. If the user chooses to disable switching of the lock screen background, the lock screen background keeps unchanged each time a screen is lit up.</li>
<li>S402: Receive a picture type setting instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and when the screen is lit up next time, invoke a picture that meets a picture type set by the user. If the user currently selects a scenery-type picture, but the Olympic Games have been held recently and the user expects to acquire more information related to sports, the user may choose to set a picture type as a sports-type picture.</li>
<li>S403: Receive an instruction, input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, for displaying a next picture, acquire a second picture and content introduction information of the second picture, replace a first picture with the second picture as the lock screen background, and display the content introduction information of the second picture on the lock screen configuration interface. When the user likes the sports-type picture but is not interested in sports content displayed in the first picture, the user may actively perform switching. When the lock screen background is switched to a last picture, switching may be stopped or continuing switching to the first picture.</li>
<li>S404: Receive a picture sharing instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, acquire a to-be-shared picture, and share the to-be-shared picture on another mobile terminal or a social network. When the user feels that the current lock screen background may also be liked by another friend, the user may tap a share option, so that the another friend acquires a picture corresponding to the lock screen background.</li>
<li>S405: Receive a local-picture update setting instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and specify a network communication mode used when the mobile terminal receives a picture pushed by the server. For example, the user may choose to perform local-picture updating in a network communication mode of<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> 2G, 3G, or Wireless Fidelity (Wireless Fidelity, Wi-Fi for short), or may choose to perform local-picture updating only in a network communication mode of Wi-Fi to reduce a traffic tariff.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0057" num="0057">Because storage space of the mobile terminal is limited, space used to store local pictures is also limited. When there is no picture that meets a picture type preset by the user in the local pictures, a picture of another type may be randomly invoked from the local pictures to replace a preset lock screen background, or the user is informed that there is no eligible picture.</p>
<p id="p0058" num="0058">After all pictures that meet the picture type preset by the user in the local pictures are switched, a picture of another type in the local pictures may be randomly invoked to replace the preset lock screen background, or the user is informed that there is no new picture and switching of the lock screen background is paused until the user updates the local pictures.</p>
<p id="p0059" num="0059">Certainly, if the user does not set a picture type, the mobile terminal may select a picture pushed by the server according to a preference of the user, to perform switching; and after all pictures are switched, the user may be informed that there is no new picture and switching of the lock screen background is paused until the user updates the local pictures.</p>
<p id="p0060" num="0060">It should be noted that, in this embodiment, some functions of the lock screen configuration interface are described, and the mobile terminal may separately receive different instructions input by the user, so as to perform different processing to implement various functions. Therefore, for steps S401 to S405, there are no strict logical relationships or time sequences. For example, the user may choose to disable switching of a lock screen, but may still set a picture type, so that a picture of the type set by the user is invoked when switching of the lock screen is enabled next time.</p>
<p id="p0061" num="0061">For detailed introductions to a lock screen interface and a lock screen configuration interface, reference may be made to <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 5</figref> and <figref idref="f0005">FIG. 6</figref>. <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 5</figref> is a schematic diagram of a lock screen interface when a lock screen method according to the present invention is used, and <figref idref="f0005">FIG. 6</figref> is a schematic diagram of a lock screen configuration interface corresponding to the lock screen interface in <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 5</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0062" num="0062">In <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 5</figref>, the lock screen interface includes conventional items such as a date, time, signal strength, a battery level, an SMS message, call information, and a quick entry to a photographing application, and a lock screen background and a name of the lock screen background. A picture used as the lock screen background may come from an electronic magazine, and the name of the lock screen background may further be displayed on the lock screen interface. When a user likes the lock screen background and tries to acquire content introduction information of the picture of the lock screen background, the user may flick upward on the lock screen interface, so that a mobile terminal may invoke, from the electronic magazine, the content introduction information of the picture that is used as the lock screen background, and enter the lock screen configuration interface shown in <figref idref="f0005">FIG. 6</figref>. On the lock screen configuration interface, content introduction information of a picture and various function options may be included, for example, Pause(pause), Next (next), Favorite (favorite), Share (share), Setting (setting), and More (more). The "Pause" option may be used to set enabling and disabling of switching of the lock screen background, the "Next" option may be used to view a next picture, the "Favorite" option may be used to comment on a current lock screen background, the "Share" option may be used to share a current lock screen background on another mobile terminal or a social network, the "Setting" option may be used to set a picture type for switching, restriction on a network communication mode used when local pictures are updated, and so on, and the "More" option may be reserved to add a new function option subsequently.<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></p>
<p id="p0063" num="0063">Referring to <figref idref="f0005">FIG. 7, FIG. 7</figref> is a schematic structural diagram of a first embodiment of a mobile terminal according to the present invention. In this embodiment, the mobile terminal includes:
<ul id="ul0020" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>a lighting-up unit 100, configured to receive an instruction, of a user, for lighting up a screen of the mobile terminal, and light up the screen of the mobile terminal; and</li>
<li>an invoking unit 200, configured to: in a lock screen state, invoke a first picture from local pictures stored in the mobile terminal to replace a preset lock screen background, where the first picture is obtained by a user by means of downloading or photographing, or pushed by a server to the mobile terminal according to a preference of a user.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0064" num="0064">Referring to <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 8</figref>, in a second embodiment of the mobile terminal according to the present invention, the mobile terminal may further include:
<ul id="ul0021" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>an acquiring unit 300, configured to: receive an acquiring instruction generated when the user executes a preset gesture operation, acquire content introduction information of the first picture, and display the content introduction information on a lock screen configuration interface; and</li>
<li>a configuring unit 400, configured to: receive comment information that is of the first picture and is input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and upload the comment information to the server, so that the server learns the preference of the user and pushes a picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0065" num="0065">Picture type may include but is not limited to a scenery-type picture, a person-type picture, an animal-type picture, an automobile-type picture, a science/technology-type picture, a sports-type picture, and a military-type picture.</p>
<p id="p0066" num="0066">Optionally, referring to <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 9</figref>, in the second embodiment of the mobile terminal according to the present invention, the mobile terminal may further include an uploading unit 500, configured to: analyze the preference of the user according to a search record and a browsing record that are of the user and in a mobile browser, and upload an analysis result to the server, so that the server pushes the picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal; or<br/>
configured to upload a search record and a browsing record that are of the user and in a mobile browser to the server, so that the server analyzes the preference of the user and pushes the picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal.</p>
<p id="p0067" num="0067">Optionally, the configuring unit 400 is further configured to:
<ul id="ul0022" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>receive a picture switching mode configuration instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and enable or disable switching of a lock screen background; and</li>
<li>receive a picture type setting instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and when the screen is lit up next time, invoke a picture that meets a picture type set by the user.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0068" num="0068">The configuring unit 400 is further configured to:
<ul id="ul0023" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>receive an instruction, input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, for displaying a next picture, acquire a second picture and content introduction information of the second picture, replace the first picture with the second picture as the lock screen background, and display the content introduction information of the second picture on the lock screen configuration interface; and/or</li>
<li>receive a picture sharing instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, acquire a to-be-shared picture, and share the to-be-shared picture on another mobile terminal or a social network; and/or</li>
<li>receive a local-picture update setting instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface,<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> and restrict a network communication mode used when the mobile terminal receives the picture pushed by the server.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0069" num="0069">The lighting-up unit 100 is further configured to: when the mobile terminal receives again, after the screen is turned off, the instruction, of the user, for lighting up the screen of the mobile terminal, light up the screen of the mobile terminal; and<br/>
the invoking unit 200 is further configured to: in the lock screen state, invoke a second picture from the local pictures stored in the mobile terminal to replace the first picture as the lock screen background.</p>
<p id="p0070" num="0070">The invoking unit 200 is further configured to:
<ul id="ul0024" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>when there is no picture that meets a picture type preset by the user in the local pictures, randomly invoke a picture of another type in the local pictures to replace the preset lock screen background, or inform the user that there is no eligible picture; and</li>
<li>after all pictures that meet the picture type preset by the user in the local pictures are switched, randomly invoke a picture of another type in the local pictures to replace the preset lock screen background, or inform the user that there is no new picture and pause switching of the lock screen background until the user updates the local pictures.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0071" num="0071">It should be noted that, the lighting-up unit 100, the invoking unit 200, the acquiring unit 300, the configuring unit 400, and the uploading unit 500 may exist independently, or may be disposed integrally. The lighting-up unit 100, the invoking unit 200, the acquiring unit 300, the configuring unit 400, or the uploading unit 500 in the foregoing mobile terminal embodiments may be independent of a processor of the mobile terminal and be disposed alone in a form of hardware, and a disposing form may be a form of microprocessor; or the foregoing units may be embedded in a processor of the mobile terminal in a form of hardware, or may further be stored in a memory of the mobile terminal in a form of software, so that the processor of the mobile terminal invokes the lighting-up unit 100, the invoking unit 200, the acquiring unit 300, the configuring unit, or the uploading unit 500 to execute corresponding operations.</p>
<p id="p0072" num="0072">For example, in the second embodiment (the embodiment shown in <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 8</figref>) of the mobile terminal according to the present invention, the invoking unit 200 may be a processor of the mobile terminal, and functions of the lighting-up unit 100, the acquiring unit 300, and the configuring unit 400 may be embedded in the processor, may be independent of the processor and be disposed alone, or may be stored in a memory in a form of software. The processor invokes and implements the functions of the foregoing units. Certainly, the lighting-up unit 100, the invoking unit 200, the acquiring unit 300, and the configuring unit 400 may be disposed integrally, may also be set independently, or may further be used as an interface circuit of the mobile terminal and disposed independently or integrally. This embodiment of the present invention imposes no limitation thereto. The processor may be a central processing unit (CPU), a microprocessor, a single-chip microcomputer, or the like.</p>
<p id="p0073" num="0073">Referring to <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 10, FIG. 10</figref> is a schematic structural diagram of a fourth embodiment of a mobile terminal according to the present invention. In this embodiment, the mobile terminal includes:
<ul id="ul0025" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>an input device 600, an output device 700, a memory 800, and a processor 900, where the input device 600, the output device 700, the memory 800, and the processor 900 are connected to a bus, the memory 800 is configured to store a set of program code, and the processor 900 is configured to invoke the program code stored in the memory 800 and execute the following operations:</li>
<li>receiving an instruction, of a user, for lighting up a screen of the mobile terminal, and lighting up the screen of the mobile terminal; and</li>
<li>in a lock screen state, invoking a first picture from local pictures stored in the mobile terminal to replace a<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> preset lock screen background, where the first picture is obtained by a user by means of downloading or photographing, or pushed by a server to the mobile terminal according to a preference of a user.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0074" num="0074">Picture type includes a scenery-type picture, a person-type picture, an animal-type picture, an automobile-type picture, a science/technology-type picture, a sports-type picture, and a military-type picture.</p>
<p id="p0075" num="0075">The processor 900 is further configured to execute the following operations:<br/>
receiving an acquiring instruction generated when the user executes a preset gesture operation, acquiring content introduction information of the first picture, and displaying the content introduction information on a lock screen configuration interface.</p>
<p id="p0076" num="0076">The mobile terminal further includes a transmitter, and the processor 900 is further configured to execute the following operations:<br/>
receiving comment information that is of the first picture and is input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and uploading the comment information to the server by using the transmitter, so that the server learns the preference of the user and pushes a picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal.</p>
<p id="p0077" num="0077">The mobile terminal further includes a transmitter, and the processor 900 is further configured to execute the following operations:
<ul id="ul0026" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>analyzing the preference of the user according to a search record and a browsing record that are of the user and in a mobile browser, and uploading an analysis result to the server by using the transmitter, so that the server pushes a picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal; or</li>
<li>uploading a search record and a browsing record that are of the user and in a mobile browser to the server by using the transmitter, so that the server analyzes the preference of the user and pushes a picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0078" num="0078">The processor 900 is further configured to execute the following operations:
<ul id="ul0027" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>receiving a picture switching mode configuration instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and enabling or disabling switching of a lock screen background; and</li>
<li>receiving a picture type setting instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and when the screen is lit up next time, invoking a picture that meets a picture type set by the user.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0079" num="0079">The processor 900 is further configured to execute the following operations:
<ul id="ul0028" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>when the mobile terminal receives again, after the screen is turned off, the instruction, of the user, for lighting up the screen of the mobile terminal, lighting up the screen of the mobile terminal; and</li>
<li>in the lock screen state, invoking a second picture from the local pictures stored in the mobile terminal to replace the first picture as the lock screen background.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0080" num="0080">The processor 900 is further configured to execute the following operations:
<ul id="ul0029" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>when there is no picture that meets a picture type preset by the user in the local pictures, randomly invoking a picture of another type in the local pictures to replace the preset lock screen background, or informing the user that there is no eligible picture; and</li>
<li>after all pictures that meet the picture type preset by the user in the local pictures are switched, randomly invoking a picture of another type in the local pictures to replace the preset lock screen background, or informing the user that there is no new picture and pausing switching of the lock screen background until the user updates the local pictures.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0081" num="0081">The processor 900 is further configured to execute the following operations:<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> -->
<ul id="ul0030" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>receiving an instruction, input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, for displaying a next picture, acquiring a second picture and content introduction information of the second picture, replacing the first picture with the second picture as the lock screen background, and displaying the content introduction information of the second picture on the lock screen configuration interface; and/or</li>
<li>receiving a picture sharing instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, acquiring a to-be-shared picture, and sharing the to-be-shared picture on another mobile terminal or a social network; and/or</li>
<li>receiving a local-picture update setting instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and restricting a network communication mode used when the mobile terminal receives the picture pushed by the server.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0082" num="0082">It should be noted that, the embodiments in this specification are described in a progressive manner, with each embodiment emphasizing differences between the embodiment and other embodiments, and for same or similar parts, reference may be made among the embodiments. The apparatus embodiments are basically the same as the method embodiments, and are therefore described relatively briefly. For related parts, reference may be made to the part of description in the method embodiments.</p>
<p id="p0083" num="0083">As described in the foregoing embodiments, the present invention has the following advantages: a screen of a mobile terminal is lit up, and a local picture is invoked to replace a preset lock screen background when the mobile terminal is in a lock screen state, so that automatic switching of a lock screen background in the lock screen state is implemented, and a user can see a new lock screen background provided that the screen is lit up, thereby increasing variability of a lock screen background, improving switching efficiency, and enhancing a feeling of freshness of a user on a lock screen.</p>
<p id="p0084" num="0084">Further embodiments of the present invention are provided in the following. It should be noted that the numbering used in the following section does not necessarily need to comply with the numbering used in the previous sections.</p>
<p id="p0085" num="0085">Embodiment 1. A screen locking method, comprising:
<ul id="ul0031" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>receiving an instruction, of a user, for lighting up a screen of a mobile terminal, and lighting up the screen of the mobile terminal; and</li>
<li>in a lock screen state, invoking a first picture from local pictures stored in the mobile terminal to replace a preset lock screen background, wherein the first picture is obtained by a user by means of downloading or photographing, or pushed by a server to the mobile terminal according to a preference of a user.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0086" num="0086">Embodiment 2. The method according to embodiment 1, further comprising:<br/>
receiving an acquiring instruction generated when the user executes a preset gesture operation, acquiring content introduction information of the first picture, and displaying the content introduction information on a lock screen configuration interface.</p>
<p id="p0087" num="0087">Embodiment 3. The method according to embodiment 2, further comprising:<br/>
receiving comment information that is of the first picture and is input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and uploading the comment information to the server, so that the server learns the preference of the user and pushes a picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal.<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></p>
<p id="p0088" num="0088">Embodiment 4. The method according to embodiment 1 or 2, further comprising:
<ul id="ul0032" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>analyzing, by the mobile terminal, the preference of the user according to a search record and a browsing record that are of the user and in a mobile browser, and uploading an analysis result to the server, so that the server pushes a picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal; or</li>
<li>uploading, by the mobile terminal, a search record and a browsing record that are of the user and in a mobile browser to the server, so that the server analyzes the preference of the user and pushes a picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0089" num="0089">Embodiment 5. The method according to any one of embodiment s 1 to 4, further comprising:
<ul id="ul0033" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>receiving a picture switching mode configuration instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and enabling or disabling switching of a lock screen background; and</li>
<li>receiving a picture type setting instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, so that when the screen is lit up next time and switching of the lock screen background is enabled, a picture that meets a picture type set by the user is invoked as the lock screen background.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0090" num="0090">Embodiment 6. The method according to any one of embodiment s 1 to 5, further comprising:
<ul id="ul0034" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>when the mobile terminal receives again, after the screen is turned off, the instruction, of the user, for lighting up the screen of the mobile terminal, lighting up the screen of the mobile terminal; and</li>
<li>in the lock screen state, invoking a second picture from the local pictures stored in the mobile terminal to replace the first picture as the lock screen background.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0091" num="0091">Embodiment 7. The method according to embodiment 5 or 6, further comprising:
<ul id="ul0035" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>when there is no picture that meets a preset picture type in the local pictures, randomly invoking a picture of another type in the local pictures to replace the preset lock screen background, or informing the user that there is no eligible picture; and</li>
<li>after all pictures that meet the preset picture type in the local pictures are switched, randomly invoking a picture of another type in the local pictures to replace the preset lock screen background, or informing the user that there is no new picture and pausing switching of the lock screen background until the user updates the local pictures.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0092" num="0092">Embodiment 8. The method according to embodiment 2, 3, or 5, further comprising:
<ul id="ul0036" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>receiving an instruction, input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, for displaying a next picture, acquiring a second picture and content introduction information of the second picture, replacing the first picture with the second picture as the lock screen background, and displaying the content introduction information of the second picture on the lock screen configuration interface; and/or</li>
<li>receiving a picture sharing instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, acquiring a to-be-shared picture, and sharing the to-be-shared picture on another mobile terminal or a social network; and/or</li>
<li>receiving a local-picture update setting instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and specifying a network communication mode used when the mobile terminal receives the picture pushed by the server.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0093" num="0093">Embodiment 9. A mobile terminal, comprising:
<ul id="ul0037" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>a lighting-up unit, configured to: receive an instruction, of a user, for lighting up a screen of a mobile terminal, and light up the screen of the mobile terminal; and<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></li>
<li>an invoking unit, configured to: in a lock screen state, invoke a first picture from local pictures stored in the mobile terminal to replace a preset lock screen background, wherein the first picture is obtained by a user by means of downloading or photographing, or pushed by a server to the mobile terminal according to a preference of a user.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0094" num="0094">Embodiment 10. The mobile terminal according to embodiment 9, further comprising:<br/>
an acquiring unit, configured to: receive an acquiring instruction generated when the user executes a preset gesture operation, acquire content introduction information of the first picture, and display the content introduction information on a lock screen configuration interface.</p>
<p id="p0095" num="0095">Embodiment 11. The mobile terminal according to embodiment 10, further comprising:<br/>
a configuring unit, configured to: receive comment information that is of the first picture and is input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and upload the comment information to the server, so that the server learns the preference of the user and pushes a picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal.</p>
<p id="p0096" num="0096">Embodiment 12. The mobile terminal according to embodiment 9 or 10, further comprising:
<ul id="ul0038" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>an uploading unit, configured to: analyze the preference of the user according to a search record and a browsing record that are of the user and in a mobile browser, and upload an analysis result to the server, so that the server pushes a picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal; or</li>
<li>an uploading unit, configured to upload a search record and a browsing record that are of the user and in a mobile browser to the server, so that the server analyzes the preference of the user and pushes a picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0097" num="0097">Embodiment 13. The mobile terminal according to any one of embodiments 9 to 12, wherein the configuring unit is further configured to:
<ul id="ul0039" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>receive a picture switching mode configuration instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and enable or disable switching of a lock screen background; and</li>
<li>receive a picture type setting instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, so that when the screen is lit up next time and switching of the lock screen background is enabled, a picture that meets a picture type set by the user is invoked as the lock screen background.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0098" num="0098">Embodiment 14. The mobile terminal according to any one of embodiments 9 to 13, wherein the lighting-up unit is further configured to: when the mobile terminal receives again, after the screen is turned off, the instruction, of the user, for lighting up the screen of the mobile terminal, light up the screen of the mobile terminal; and<br/>
the invoking unit is further configured to: in the lock screen state, invoke a second picture from the local pictures stored in the mobile terminal to replace the first picture as the lock screen background.</p>
<p id="p0099" num="0099">Embodiment 15. The mobile terminal according to embodiment 13 or 14, wherein the invoking unit is further configured to:
<ul id="ul0040" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>when there is no picture that meets a picture type preset by the user in the local pictures, randomly invoke a picture of another type in the local pictures to replace the preset lock screen background, or inform the user that there is no eligible picture; and</li>
<li>after all pictures that meet the picture type preset by the user in the local pictures are switched, randomly invoke a picture of another type in the local pictures to replace the preset lock screen background, or inform the user that<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> there is no new picture and pause switching of the lock screen background until the user updates the local pictures.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0100" num="0100">Embodiment 16. The mobile terminal according to embodiment 10, 11, or 13, wherein the configuring unit is further configured to:
<ul id="ul0041" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>receive an instruction, input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, for displaying a next picture, acquire a second picture and content introduction information of the second picture, replace the first picture with the second picture as the lock screen background, and display the content introduction information of the second picture on the lock screen configuration interface; and/or</li>
<li>receive a picture sharing instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, acquire a to-be-shared picture, and share the to-be-shared picture on another mobile terminal or a social network; and/or</li>
<li>receive a local-picture update setting instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and specify a network communication mode used when the mobile terminal receives the picture pushed by the server.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0101" num="0101">Embodiment 17. A mobile terminal, comprising an input device, an output device, a memory, and a processor, wherein the input device, the output device, the memory, and the processor are connected to a bus, the memory stores a set of program code, and the processor is configured to invoke the program code stored in the memory and execute the following operations:
<ul id="ul0042" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>receiving an instruction, of a user, for lighting up a screen of the mobile terminal, and lighting up the screen of the mobile terminal; and</li>
<li>in a lock screen state, invoking a first picture from local pictures stored in the mobile terminal to replace a preset lock screen background, wherein the first picture is obtained by a user by means of downloading or photographing, or pushed by a server to the mobile terminal according to a preference of a user.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0102" num="0102">Embodiment 18. The mobile terminal according to embodiment 17, wherein the processor is further configured to execute the following operations:<br/>
receiving an acquiring instruction generated when the user executes a preset gesture operation, acquiring content introduction information of the first picture, and displaying the content introduction information on a lock screen configuration interface.</p>
<p id="p0103" num="0103">Embodiment 19. The mobile terminal according to embodiment 18, wherein the mobile terminal further comprises a transmitter; the processor is further configured to execute the following operations:<br/>
receiving comment information that is of the first picture and is input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and uploading the comment information to the server by using the transmitter, so that the server learns the preference of the user and pushes a picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal.</p>
<p id="p0104" num="0104">Embodiment 20. The mobile terminal according to embodiment 17 or 18, wherein the mobile terminal further comprises a transmitter; the processor is further configured to execute the following operations:
<ul id="ul0043" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>analyzing the preference of the user according to a search record and a browsing record that are of the user and in a mobile browser, and uploading an analysis result to the server by using the transmitter, so that the server pushes a picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal; or</li>
<li>uploading a search record and a browsing record that are of the user and in a mobile browser to the server by<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> using the transmitter, so that the server analyzes the preference of the user and pushes a picture that meets the preference of the user to the mobile terminal.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0105" num="0105">Embodiment 21. The mobile terminal according to any one of embodiments 17 to 20, wherein the processor is further configured to execute the following operations:
<ul id="ul0044" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>receiving a picture switching mode configuration instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and enabling or disabling switching of a lock screen background; and</li>
<li>receiving a picture type setting instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, so that when the screen is lit up next time and switching of the lock screen background is enabled, a picture that meets a picture type set by the user is invoked as the lock screen background.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0106" num="0106">Embodiment 22. The mobile terminal according to any one of embodiments 17 to 21, wherein the processor is further configured to execute the following operations:
<ul id="ul0045" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>when the mobile terminal receives again, after the screen is turned off, the instruction, of the user, for lighting up the screen of the mobile terminal, lighting up the screen of the mobile terminal; and</li>
<li>in the lock screen state, invoking a second picture from the local pictures stored in the mobile terminal to replace the first picture as the lock screen background.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0107" num="0107">Embodiment 23. The mobile terminal according to embodiment 21 or 22, wherein the processor is further configured to execute the following operations:
<ul id="ul0046" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>when there is no picture that meets a picture type preset by the user in the local pictures, randomly invoking a picture of another type in the local pictures to replace the preset lock screen background, or informing the user that there is no eligible picture; and</li>
<li>after all pictures that meet the picture type preset by the user in the local pictures are switched, randomly invoking a picture of another type in the local pictures to replace the preset lock screen background, or informing the user that there is no new picture and pausing switching of the lock screen background until the user updates the local pictures.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0108" num="0108">Embodiment 24. The mobile terminal according to embodiment 18, 19, or 21, wherein the processor is further configured to execute the following operations:
<ul id="ul0047" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>receiving an instruction, input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, for displaying a next picture, acquiring a second picture and content introduction information of the second picture, replacing the first picture with the second picture as the lock screen background, and displaying the content introduction information of the second picture on the lock screen configuration interface; and/or</li>
<li>receiving a picture sharing instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, acquiring a to-be-shared picture, and sharing the to-be-shared picture on another mobile terminal or a social network; and/or</li>
<li>receiving a local-picture update setting instruction input by the user on the lock screen configuration interface, and specifying a network communication mode used when the mobile terminal receives the picture pushed by the server.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0109" num="0109">A person of ordinary skill in the art may understand that all or a part of the steps of the method embodiments may be implemented by a program instructing relevant hardware. The program may be stored in a computer readable storage medium. When the program runs, the steps of the method embodiments are performed. The foregoing storage medium includes: any medium that can store program code, such as a ROM, a RAM, a magnetic<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> disk, or an optical disc.</p>
<p id="p0110" num="0110">The foregoing describes in detail a lock screen method and a mobile terminal that are provided in the embodiments of the present invention. Specific examples are used in this specification to describe the principles and implementation manners of the present invention, and the description of the foregoing embodiments is merely used to help the understanding of the methods and core ideas of the present invention; in addition, a person of ordinary skill in the art can make modifications and variations to the specific implementation manners and application scopes according to the ideas of the present invention. In summary, the content of the specification shall not be construed as limitations on the present invention.</p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> -->
<claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>A screen locking method carried out in a mobile terminal, comprising:
<claim-text>in response to a first input, displaying a first interface in a lock screen state, wherein the first interface comprises a first picture, a name of the first picture and a lock screen configuration interface, the first interface uses the first picture as a lock screen background, the lock screen configuration interface is provided with a first function option for sharing a current lock screen background on another mobile terminal or a social network, the lock screen configuration interface is provided with a second function option for setting a picture type;</claim-text>
<claim-text>in response to a second input, sharing the first picture on another mobile terminal or the social network; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>in response to a third input, invoking a picture that meets the picture type as the lock screen background when a screen of the mobile terminal is lit up next time.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>The method according to claim 1, further comprising: the lock screen configuration interface is provided with a third function option for setting a network communication mode when local pictures are updated,<br/>
in response to receiving a fourth input, local-picture updating is performed only in a network communication mode of Wi-Fi.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>The method according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the lock screen configuration interface overlays on the first picture.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>The method according to claim 3, wherein the portion of the first picture which is overlaid by the lock screen configuration is fuzzy.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>The method according to claim 2, further comprising:<br/>
in response to receiving a fifth input for displaying a next picture, changing the lock screen background from the first picture to a second picture, wherein the second picture is new.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>The method according to claim 2, further comprising: in response to a sixth input, disabling switching of a lock screen background; and after the switching of the lock screen background is disabled, the lock screen background of the mobile terminal remains unchanged.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>The method according to claim 2, wherein the first interface comprises content introduction information of the first picture, and the content introduction information is an explanation or a description of picture content.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>The method according to claim 2, wherein local pictures are belonged to different picture types, and are stored in different folders based on the picture types.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>A mobile terminal, comprising a memory, and a processor, wherein the memory stores a set<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> of program code, and the processor is configured to invoke the program code stored in the memory and execute the following operations:
<claim-text>in response to a first input, display a first interface in a lock screen state, wherein the first interface comprises a first picture, a name of the first picture and a lock screen configuration interface, the first interface uses the first picture as a lock screen background, the lock screen configuration interface is provided with a first function option for sharing a current lock screen background on another mobile terminal or a social network, the lock screen configuration interface is provided with a second function option for setting a picture type;</claim-text>
<claim-text>in response to a second input, share the first picture on another mobile terminal or the social network; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>in response to a third input, invoke a picture that meets the picture type as the lock screen background.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>The mobile terminal according to claim 9, wherein the lock screen configuration interface is provided with a third function option for setting a network communication mode when local pictures are updated, the processor is further configured to execute the following operation:<br/>
in response to receiving a fourth input, local-picture updating is performed only in a network communication mode of Wi-Fi.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>The mobile terminal according to claim 9 or 10, wherein the lock screen configuration interface overlays on the first picture.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>The mobile terminal according to claim 11, wherein the portion of the first picture which is overlaid by the lock screen configuration is fuzzy.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>The mobile terminal according to claim 10, the processor is further configured to execute the following operation: in response to receiving a fifth input for displaying a next picture, change the lock screen background from the first picture to a second picture, wherein the second picture is new.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>The mobile terminal according to claim 10, the processor is further configured to execute the following operation: in response to a sixth input, disable switching of a lock screen background; and after the switching of the lock screen background is disabled, the lock screen background of the mobile terminal remains unchanged.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0015" num="0015">
<claim-text>The mobile terminal according to claim 10, wherein the first interface comprises content introduction information of the first picture, and the content introduction information is an explanation or a description of picture content.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0016" num="0016">
<claim-text>The mobile terminal according to claim 10, wherein local pictures are belonged to different picture types, and are stored in different folders based on the picture types.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1,2"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="111" he="178" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="3"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="110" he="135" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> -->
<figure id="f0003" num="4"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="111" he="193" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="26"> -->
<figure id="f0004" num="5"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="74" he="128" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> -->
<figure id="f0005" num="6,7"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="77" he="216" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="28"> -->
<figure id="f0006" num="8,9,10"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="151" he="210" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<search-report-data id="srep" lang="en" srep-office="EP" date-produced=""><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="157" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="155" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data><search-report-data date-produced="20210826" id="srepxml" lang="en" srep-office="EP" srep-type="ep-sr" status="n"><!--
 The search report data in XML is provided for the users' convenience only. It might differ from the search report of the PDF document, which contains the officially published data. The EPO disclaims any liability for incorrect or incomplete data in the XML for search reports.
 -->

<srep-info><file-reference-id>84082151EP30</file-reference-id><application-reference><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>21150814.8</doc-number></document-id></application-reference><applicant-name><name>Huawei Device Co., Ltd.</name></applicant-name><srep-established srep-established="yes"/><srep-invention-title title-approval="yes"/><srep-abstract abs-approval="yes"/><srep-figure-to-publish figinfo="by-examiner"><figure-to-publish><fig-number>4</fig-number></figure-to-publish></srep-figure-to-publish><srep-info-admin><srep-office><addressbook><text>MN</text></addressbook></srep-office><date-search-report-mailed><date>20210901</date></date-search-report-mailed></srep-info-admin></srep-info><srep-for-pub><srep-fields-searched><minimum-documentation><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr><text>H04M</text></classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr></minimum-documentation></srep-fields-searched><srep-citations><citation id="sr-cit0001"><patcit dnum="US2013069962A1" id="sr-pcit0001" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=US2013069962&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2013069962</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>NEALER BRYAN WELBOURNE [US] ET AL</name><date>20130321</date></document-id></patcit><category>A</category><rel-claims>1-16</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* abstract *</passage><passage>* paragraph [0001] - paragraph [0002] *</passage><passage>* paragraph [0005] *</passage><passage>* paragraph [0033] - paragraph [0036] *</passage><passage>* paragraph [0039] *</passage><passage>* paragraph [0042] *</passage><passage>* paragraph [0045] *</passage><passage>* paragraph [0049] - paragraph [0053] *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0002"><patcit dnum="US2009259968A1" id="sr-pcit0002" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=US2009259968&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2009259968</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>HSIEH CHIN-YING [TW] ET AL</name><date>20091015</date></document-id></patcit><category>A</category><rel-claims>1-16</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* paragraph [0008] - paragraph [0012] *</passage><passage>* paragraph [0017] - paragraph [0018] *</passage><passage>* paragraph [0037] - paragraph [0042] *</passage><passage>* figure 2 *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0003"><patcit dnum="US2010075649A1" id="sr-pcit0003" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=US2010075649&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2010075649</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>TENG STEPHANIE E [US]</name><date>20100325</date></document-id></patcit><category>A</category><rel-claims>1-16</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* paragraph [0005] *</passage><passage>* paragraph [0012] *</passage></rel-passage></citation></srep-citations><srep-admin><examiners><primary-examiner><name>Bianchi, Damiano</name></primary-examiner></examiners><srep-office><addressbook><text>Munich</text></addressbook></srep-office><date-search-completed><date>20210826</date></date-search-completed></srep-admin><!--							The annex lists the patent family members relating to the patent documents cited in the above mentioned European search report.							The members are as contained in the European Patent Office EDP file on							The European Patent Office is in no way liable for these particulars which are merely given for the purpose of information.							For more details about this annex : see Official Journal of the European Patent Office, No 12/82						--><srep-patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2013069962</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20130321</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>AU</country><doc-number>2012308685</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140327</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>BR</country><doc-number>112014005977</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20170404</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>CA</country><doc-number>2847565</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20130321</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>CN</country><doc-number>102999262</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20130327</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2756381</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20140723</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2014528213</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20141023</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>KR</country><doc-number>20140075730</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20140619</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>RU</country><doc-number>2014110039</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20150920</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>TW</country><doc-number>201312449</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20130316</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2013069962</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20130321</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2013040048</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20130321</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2009259968</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20091015</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>TW</country><doc-number>200943164</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20091016</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2009259968</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20091015</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2010075649</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20100325</date></document-id></priority-application><text>NONE</text></patent-family></srep-patent-family></srep-for-pub></search-report-data>
</ep-patent-document>
