<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP18188988B1" file="EP18188988NWB1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3473814" kind="B1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSK..HRIS..MTNORS..SM..................</B001EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  2100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3473814</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT SPECIFICATION</B121></B120><B130>B1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>18188988.2</B210><B220><date>20180814</date></B220><B240><B241><date>20191024</date></B241><B242><date>20200406</date></B242></B240><B250>en</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B300><B310>201715786367</B310><B320><date>20171017</date></B320><B330><ctry>US</ctry></B330></B300><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20190424</date><bnum>201917</bnum></B430><B450><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B450><B452EP><date>20210310</date></B452EP></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>F01D  17/16        20060101AFI20190205BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="2"><text>F02C   9/20        20060101ALI20190205BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>F05D2230/60        20130101 LA20190204BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>F02C   9/20        20130101 LI20190204BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="3"><text>F01D  17/165       20130101 LI20190419BHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>SCHAUFELHEBEL MIT KREISTASCHE MIT DREI KEILEN</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>VANE ARM WITH TRI-WEDGE CIRCULAR POCKET</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>BRAS D'AUBE À POCHE CIRCULAIRE AVEC TROIS CALES</B542></B540><B560><B561><text>FR-A1- 2 877 059</text></B561><B561><text>FR-A1- 2 897 120</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2017 081 975</text></B561></B560></B500><B700><B720><B721><snm>PRATT, William S.</snm><adr><str>63 Ardmore Road</str><city>West Hartford, CT Connecticut 06119</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>NAGARAJ, Anand</snm><adr><str>967 Phelps Road</str><city>Teaneck, NJ New Jersey 07666</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>KJELBY, Diane C.</snm><adr><str>79 Robin Court</str><city>Middletown, CT Connecticut 06457</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B730><B731><snm>Raytheon Technologies Corporation</snm><iid>101856195</iid><irf>444.138611</irf><adr><str>10 Farm Springs Road</str><city>Farmington, CT 06032</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B731></B730><B740><B741><snm>Dehns</snm><iid>101728904</iid><adr><str>St. Bride's House 
10 Salisbury Square</str><city>London EC4Y 8JD</city><ctry>GB</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840></B800></SDOBI>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<heading id="h0001"><b>FIELD</b></heading>
<p id="p0001" num="0001">The present disclosure relates to vane structures within gas turbine engines and more specifically, to a vane arm having a tri-wedge circular pocket.</p>
<heading id="h0002"><b>BACKGROUND</b></heading>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">A gas turbine engine implements rotors and stators at various positions throughout the engine. The stators may include variable vane systems in which an angle of attack of the vane airfoils relative to airflow may be changed. Current vane arm geometries (e.g., vane arms comprising a claw feature) tend to have difficulty meeting the stress requirements associated with increased vane stem torque associated with increased engine temperatures and pressures.</p>
<p id="p0003" num="0003"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US2017081975A"><text>US 2017/081975</text></patcit> discloses a vane lever comprising an opening, the opening having a portion of its inner surface comprising a non-cylindrical, multi-lobed shape.</p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004"><patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="FR2897120"><text>FR 2897120</text></patcit> discloses a compressor blade pivot designed to receive an angle adjustment lever that has its other end connected to a control ring.</p>
<p id="p0005" num="0005"><patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="FR2877059"><text>FR 2877059</text></patcit> discloses a drill centering a rod relative to a pivot of a variable pitch vane.</p>
<heading id="h0003"><b>SUMMARY</b></heading>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">According to a first aspect of the present invention, a vane arm as claimed in claim 1 is provided herein.</p>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">In various embodiments, a first groove may be formed in the first vertical surface. A second groove may be formed in the second vertical surface. The first vertical surface, the first groove, the second vertical surface, the second groove, the third vertical surface, and the fourth vertical surface may define the first perimeter of the vane stem aperture. A<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> diameter of the first perimeter may be greater than a diameter of the second perimeter as measured between the first groove and the second groove. In various embodiments, the vane arm may comprise titanium or a titanium alloy.</p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">According to a second aspect of the present invention, a variable vane assembly of a gas turbine engine as claimed in claim 6 is also provided herein.</p>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">In various embodiments, a gap may be located between the third wedge face and the vane stem.</p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">In various embodiments, a distance between the first vertical surface may limit a rotation of the vane arm relative to the vane stem to 1° or less.</p>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">In various embodiments, a first groove may be formed in the first vertical surface. A second groove may be formed in the second vertical surface. The first vertical surface, the first groove, the second vertical surface, the second groove, the third vertical surface, and the fourth vertical surface may define the first perimeter of the vane stem aperture.</p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">According to a third aspect of the present invention, a variable vane assembly as claimed in claim 10 is also provided herein.</p>
<heading id="h0004"><b>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</b></heading>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">The subject matter of the present disclosure is particularly pointed out and distinctly claimed in the concluding portion of the specification. A more complete understanding of the present disclosure, however, is best obtained by referring to the detailed description and claims when considered in connection with the drawing figures, wherein like numerals denote like elements.
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li><figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a cross-sectional view of an exemplary gas turbine engine, according to various embodiments;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates an exemplary variable vane assembly, in accordance with various embodiments;<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">FIGs. 3A, 3B, and 3C</figref> illustrate a vane arm comprising a tri-wedge circular pocket, in accordance with various embodiments;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0004">FIGs. 4A and 4B</figref> illustrate cross-section views of a vane arm tri-wedge circular pocket, in accordance with various embodiments; and</li>
<li><figref idref="f0005">FIGs. 5A and 5B</figref> illustrate cross-sectional view of a vane stems secured to a vane arm comprising a tri-wedge circular pocket, in accordance with various embodiments.</li>
</ul></p>
<heading id="h0005"><b>DETAILED DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">The detailed description of examples and embodiments herein makes reference to the accompanying drawings, which show examples and embodiments of the present invention by way of illustration. While these examples and embodiments are described in sufficient detail to enable those skilled in the art to practice the disclosure, it should be understood that other embodiments may be realized and that logical changes and adaptations in design and construction may be made in accordance with this disclosure and the teachings herein without departing from the scope of the disclosure. Thus, the detailed description herein is presented for purposes of illustration only and not of limitation.</p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">Cross hatching lines may be used throughout the figures to denote different parts but not necessarily to denote the same or different materials. Throughout the present disclosure, like reference numbers denote like elements. Accordingly, elements with like element numbering may be shown in the figures, but may not necessarily be repeated herein for the sake of clarity.</p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">As used herein, "aft" refers to the direction associated with the exhaust (e.g., the back end) of a gas turbine engine. As used herein, "forward" refers to the direction associated with the intake (e.g., the front end) of a gas turbine engine.</p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">A first component that is "radially outward" of a second component means that the first component is positioned at a greater distance away from the engine central<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> longitudinal axis than the second component. A first component that is "radially inward" of a second component means that the first component is positioned closer to the engine central longitudinal axis than the second component. In the case of components that rotate circumferentially about the engine central longitudinal axis, a first component that is radially inward of a second component rotates through a circumferentially shorter path than the second component. The terminology "radially outward" and "radially inward" may also be used relative to references other than the engine central longitudinal axis. The term "axial," as used herein, refers to a direction along or parallel to the engine central longitudinal axis.</p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">In various examples and with reference to <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, a gas turbine engine 20 is provided. Gas turbine engine 20 may be a two-spool turbofan that generally incorporates a fan section 22, a compressor section 24, a combustor section 26 and a turbine section 28. In various configurations, engines may include, for example, an augmentor section among other systems or features. In operation, fan section 22 can drive fluid (e.g., air) along a bypass flow-path B while compressor section 24 can drive fluid along a core flow-path C for compression and communication into combustor section 26 then expansion through turbine section 28. Although depicted as a turbofan gas turbine engine 20 herein, it should be understood that the concepts described herein are not limited to use with turbofans as the teachings may be applied to other types of turbine engines including three-spool architectures.</p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">Gas turbine engine 20 may generally comprise a low speed spool 30 and a high speed spool 32 mounted for rotation about an engine central longitudinal axis A-A' relative to an engine static structure 36 or engine case via several bearing systems 38, 38-1, and 38-2. Engine central longitudinal axis A-A' is oriented in the z direction on the provided xyz axis. It should be understood that various bearing systems 38 at various<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> locations may alternatively or additionally be provided, including for example, bearing system 38, bearing system 38-1, and bearing system 38-2.</p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">Low speed spool 30 may generally comprise an inner shaft 40 that interconnects a fan 42, a low pressure compressor 44 and a low pressure turbine 46. Inner shaft 40 may be connected to fan 42 through a geared architecture 48 that can drive fan 42 at a lower speed than low speed spool 30. Geared architecture 48 may comprise a gear assembly 60 enclosed within a gear housing 62. Gear assembly 60 couples inner shaft 40 to a rotating fan structure. High speed spool 32 may comprise an outer shaft 50 that interconnects a high pressure compressor 52 and high pressure turbine 54.</p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">A combustor 56 may be located between high pressure compressor 52 and high pressure turbine 54. The combustor section 26 may have an annular wall assembly having inner and outer shells that support respective inner and outer heat shielding liners. The heat shield liners may include a plurality of combustor panels that collectively define the annular combustion chamber of the combustor 56. An annular cooling cavity is defined between the respective shells and combustor panels for supplying cooling air. Impingement holes are located in the shell to supply the cooling air from an outer air plenum and into the annular cooling cavity.</p>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">A mid-turbine frame 57 of engine static structure 36 may be located generally between high pressure turbine 54 and low pressure turbine 46. Mid-turbine frame 57 may support one or more bearing systems 38 in turbine section 28. Inner shaft 40 and outer shaft 50 may be concentric and rotate via bearing systems 38 about the engine central longitudinal axis A-A', which is collinear with their longitudinal axes. As used herein, a "high pressure" compressor or turbine experiences a higher pressure than a corresponding "low pressure" compressor or turbine.</p>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">The core airflow C may be compressed by low pressure compressor 44 then high<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> pressure compressor 52, mixed and burned with fuel in combustor 56, then expanded over high pressure turbine 54 and low pressure turbine 46. Turbines 46, 54 rotationally drive the respective low speed spool 30 and high speed spool 32 in response to the expansion.</p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">In various examples, geared architecture 48 may be an epicyclic gear train, such as a star gear system (sun gear in meshing engagement with a plurality of star gears supported by a carrier and in meshing engagement with a ring gear) or other gear system. Geared architecture 48 may have a gear reduction ratio of greater than about 2.3 and low pressure turbine 46 may have a pressure ratio that is greater than about five (5). In various examples, the bypass ratio of gas turbine engine 20 is greater than about ten (10:1). In various examples, the diameter of fan 42 may be significantly larger than that of the low pressure compressor 44, and the low pressure turbine 46 may have a pressure ratio that is greater than about five (5:1). Low pressure turbine 46 pressure ratio may be measured prior to inlet of low pressure turbine 46 as related to the pressure at the outlet of low pressure turbine 46 prior to an exhaust nozzle. It should be understood, however, that the above parameters are exemplary of a suitable geared architecture engine and that the present disclosure contemplates other gas turbine engines including direct drive turbofans. A gas turbine engine may comprise an industrial gas turbine (IGT) or a geared aircraft engine, such as a geared turbofan, or non-geared aircraft engine, such as a turbofan, or may comprise any gas turbine engine as desired.</p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">In various examples, the low pressure compressor 44, the high pressure compressor 52, the low pressure turbine 46, and the high pressure turbine 54 may comprise one or more stages or sets of rotating blades and one or more stages or sets of vanes axially interspersed with the associated blade stages but non-rotating about engine central longitudinal axis A-A'. The vanes may be variable, meaning the angle of attack of the airfoil of the vane may be variable relative to the airflow. The angle of attack of the<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> vanes may be variable during operation, or may be fixable for operation, for instance, being variable during maintenance or construction and fixable for operation.</p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">With reference to <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>, a variable vane assembly 100 having a synchronization ring 120 is illustrated. Synchronization ring 120 includes a first ring portion 121 and a second ring portion 122 that are detachably coupled together to jointly define a plurality of cylindrical bores 125 of the synchronization ring 120. Said differently, first ring portion 121 may be a forward ring portion and the second ring portion 122 may be an aft ring portion (e.g., two separable axial halves that jointly form the synchronization ring 120). Synchronization ring 120 may link a plurality of vanes to an actuator. Thus, one or more actuators may be mechanically coupled to synchronization ring 120, which is mechanically coupled to vane stems 134 of a plurality of vanes (with momentary reference to <figref idref="f0005">FIGs. 5A and 5B</figref>) via a corresponding plurality of vane arms 140. Therefore, in response to actuating the actuator(s), the synchronization ring 120 rotates around and relative to a case 110 (e.g., a compressor case or a turbine case), thereby causing the attack angle of the vanes, which are located radially inward of the compressor case 110, to be simultaneously adjusted.</p>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">The case 110, around which the synchronization ring 120 is situated, defines a plurality of vane stem slots 112 that are circumferentially distributed around the case 110 and that extend radially through the case 110. Vanes of gas turbine engine 20 (<figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>) may located radially inward of case 110. The vanes located inward of case 110 may include a vane body and a vane stem 134 (<figref idref="f0005">FIG. 5A</figref>), according to various embodiments. The vane body may disposed on a radially inward side of the case 110 and the vane stem 134 may extend radially outward through one of the plurality of vane stem slots 112.</p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">With combined reference to <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> and <figref idref="f0005">FIG. 5A</figref>, a radially outward end of the vane stem 134 may protrude from the vane stem slots 112 defined in the case 110, and<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> this radially outward end of the vane stem 134 is coupled to a vane arm 140, according to various embodiments. In various embodiments, a fastener 210 couples vane arm to vane stem 134. Fastener 210 may comprise a nut, bolt, clip, or other suitable attachment component. The vane arm 140 may include a first end 141 and a second end 142. The radially outward end of the vane stem 134 may be coupled to the first end 141, and a radially extending pin 150 (<figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>) may be coupled to the second end 142. In various embodiments, the vane arm 140 extends substantially perpendicular to the vane stem 134 (e.g., perpendicular to the radial direction). As used herein, "substantially perpendicular" means within five degrees of perpendicular. In various embodiments, the pin 150 extends radially through one of the plurality of cylindrical bores 125 that is jointly formed by the first and second ring portions 121, 122.</p>
<p id="p0029" num="0029">In various embodiments, the pin 150 is at least one of rotatably coupled to the second end 142 of the vane arm 140 or rotatable within the one of the plurality of cylindrical bores 125. Said differently, the pin 150 may be coupled in rotatable engagement with the second end 142 of the vane arm 140 and/or the pin 150 may extend through a cylindrical bore 125 jointly formed by the first and second ring portions 121, 122.</p>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">In various embodiments, and with reference to <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref>, the first end 141 of the vane arm 140 comprises opposing surfaces 148 and 151. Surface 148 may be a radially outward surface, oriented generally away from the vane and case 110, with momentary reference to <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>. Surface 151 may be a radially inward surface, oriented generally toward from the vane and case 110, with momentary reference to <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>. First end 141 may define a vane stem aperture 146. Vane stem aperture 146 may extend completely through first end 141 (i.e., from surface 148 to surface 151). A connection portion 144 of vane arm 140 extends between first end 141 and second end 142. Connection portion 144<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> includes opposing surfaces 156 and 158. A radial thickness T1 of connection portion may be less than a radial thickness T2 of first end 141. In various embodiments, the portion of surface 156 proximate to first end 141 may slope, or curve radially outward, to meet first surface 148. The portion of surface 158 proximate to first end 141 may slope, or curve radially inward, to meet surface 151. Second end 142 of vane arm 140 may define a pin aperture 152. Pin aperture 152 may extend completely through second end 142 (i.e., from surface 156 to surface 158).</p>
<p id="p0031" num="0031">Vane arm 140 may comprise a metal or metal allow. For example, vane arm 140 may comprise titanium, nickel, copper, silver, steel, and/or alloys thereof. In various embodiments, vane arm 140 is comprised of titanium. Vane arm 140 may be formed by electrical discharge machining (EDM), casting, punching, laser drilling, or other suitable manufacturing process.</p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032">With reference to <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3B</figref> a radially inward looking view of vane arm 140 is illustrated, in accordance with various embodiments. Surface 148 may define a radially outward perimeter 160 of vane stem aperture 146. In various embodiments, radially outward perimeter 160 comprises a generally rectangular shape with two semi-circular stud clearances 164a and 164b formed in opposing sides of radially outward perimeter 160. In various embodiments, radially outward perimeter 160 includes four flat, or planar, anti-rotation surfaces 166a, 166b, 166c, and 166d. Radially outward perimeter 160 may be configured to complement a shape or geometry of vane stem 134, with momentary reference to <figref idref="f0005">FIG. 5A</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0033" num="0033">With reference to <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3C</figref> a radially outward looking view of vane arm 140 is illustrated, in accordance with various embodiments. Surface 151 may define a radially inward perimeter 162 of vane stem aperture 146. The geometry of radially inward perimeter 162 may be different from the geometry of radially inward perimeter 160. In<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> various embodiments, radially inward perimeter 162 comprises a generally circular or annular shape. A diameter or width D1 of radially inward perimeter 162 may be greater than a diameter or width D2 of radially outward perimeter 160 as measured at stud clearances 164a and 164b.</p>
<p id="p0034" num="0034">With combined reference to <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3C</figref>, <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 4A, and FIG. 4B</figref>, a radially inward portion 170 of vane stem aperture 146 may comprise a generally frustoconical shape and is defined, at least partially, by sloped or angled surfaces 174, 176, and 192 (also referred to herein as wedge faces) and vertical surfaces 178, 180, 190a, and 196. Wedge faces 174, 176, and 192 may extend from vertical surfaces 178, 180, and 196 respectively, toward an axis R-R' extending radially through a central point of vane stem aperture 146. Axis R-R' may be substantially perpendicular to engine central longitudinal axis A-A'. As used herein, "substantially perpendicular" means within five degrees of perpendicular. Vertical surfaces 178, 180, and 196 may extend, respectively, from wedge faces 174, 176, and 192 to surface 151. Vertical surfaces 178, 180, 190a, and 196 may be substantially parallel to axis R-R'. As used herein, "substantially parallel" means within five degrees of parallel.</p>
<p id="p0035" num="0035">A radially outward portion 172 of vane stem aperture 146 is defined, at least partially, by vertical surface 182, 184, 190b, and 194. Vertical surfaces 182, 184, 190b, and 194 are substantially parallel to axis R-R'. As used herein, "substantially parallel" means within five degrees of parallel. Vertical surfaces 182, 184, and 194 may extend, respectively, between wedge faces 174, 176, and 192 and first surface 148. Wedge face 192 and vertical surfaces 194 and 196 may be located at an aft end of vane stem aperture 146. Vertical surfaces 190a and 190b may be located at a forward end of vane stem aperture 146.</p>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">A groove 198 may be formed in vertical surface 182. Groove 198 may<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> define/coincide with stud clearance 164a. A portion 182a of vertical surface 182 may be located between groove 198 and forward vertical surface 190b. Portion 182a may define/coincide with anti-rotation surface 166a. A portion 182b of vertical surface 182 may be located between groove 198 and forward vertical wall 190b. Portion 182b may define/coincide with anti-rotation surface 166b. While <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 4A</figref> illustrates vertical surface 182 and groove 198, it should be understood that vertical surface 184, with momentary reference to <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 4B</figref>, may include the elements and functionalities as described herein with respect to surface 182. Stated differently, a groove similar to groove 198 may be formed in vertical surface 184 and may define/coincide with stud clearance 164b, and a first portion of vertical surface 184 proximate vertical surface 194 may define/coincide with anti-rotation surface 166d, and a second portion of vertical surface 184 between vertical surface 190b and the groove may define/coincide with anti-rotation surface 166c.</p>
<p id="p0037" num="0037">With reference to <figref idref="f0005">FIG. 5B</figref>, wedge faces 174 and 176 may be configured to complement and contact angled walls 202 and 204, respectively, of vane stem 134. For example, fastener 210 may engage vane stem 134 and travel toward vane arm 140. Securing fastener 210 to vane stem 134 may cause vane arm 140 to move radially inward toward case 110 (with momentary referent to <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>). Fastener 210 may apply a pressure to vane arm 140 in the direction of arrow 212. The pressure applied by fastener 210 may cause wedge faces 174 and 176 to contact and press against walls 202 and 204 of vane stem 134. Fastener 210 and walls 202 and 204 may force wedge faces 174 and 176 in to a compressed, or "preloaded" state. In various embodiments, wedge faces 174 and 176 being compressed may cause the shape of radially inward perimeter 162 to transform from a generally circular shape to a generally oval or elliptical shape.</p>
<p id="p0038" num="0038">With combined reference to <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3C</figref> and <figref idref="f0005">FIGs. 5A and 5B</figref>, radially inward perimeter 162 may be configured such that a gap or space G1 exists between vane stem<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> 134 and surface 151. Stated differently, vertical surfaces 178, 180, 190a, and 196 may be configured such that vane stem 134 does not contact vertical surfaces 178, 180, 190a, and 196. In various embodiments, radially outward portion 172 of vane stem apertures is configured such that vane stem 134 does not contact vertical surfaces 182, 184, wedge face 192 and vertical surfaces 190a, 190b, 194, and 196 are configured such that under normal operating conditions, vane stem 134 does not contact wedge face 192 or vertical surfaces 190a, 190b, 194, and 196. Stated differently, during normal operating conditions, only wedge faces 174 and 176 will contact vane stem 134. In this regard, torque is transferred between vane stem 134 and vane arm 140 through wedge faces 174 and 176. The generally circular or elliptical shape of radially inward perimeter 162 and generally frustoconical shape of radially inward portion 170 tends to distribute hoop stress more evenly throughout the first end 141, and tends to avoid areas of increased stress concentration.</p>
<p id="p0039" num="0039">The features of vane arm 140 may allow control of vane arm 140 to be retained should fastener 210 be lost due to, for example, an engine surge or other catastrophic event. For example, if fastener 210 is not present, anti-rotation surfaces 166a, 166b, 166c, and 166d tend to prevent vane arm 140 from rotating about vane stem 134. For example, anti-rotation surfaces 166a, 166b, 166c, and 166d may be configured to allow vane arm 140 to rotate 1° or less before contacting vane stem 134. In various embodiments, anti-rotation surfaces 166a, 166b, 166c, and 166d may be configured to allow vane arm 140 to rotate 0.5° or less before anti-rotation surfaces 166a, 166b, 166c, and 166d contact vane stem 134. Stated differently, a distance D1 between vane stem 134 and vertical surfaces 182 and 184 and may be selected to restrict rotation of vane arm 140 to 1° or less, or 0.5° or less. Preventing vane arm 140 from rotating tends to reduce a likelihood that vane arm will disengage from vane stem 134.<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></p>
<p id="p0040" num="0040">Benefits and other advantages have been described herein with regard to specific embodiments. Furthermore, the connecting lines shown in the various figures contained herein are intended to represent exemplary functional relationships and/or physical couplings between the various elements. It should be noted that many alternative or additional functional relationships or physical connections may be present in a practical system. However, the benefits, advantages, and any elements that may cause any benefit or advantage to occur or become more pronounced are not to be construed as critical, required, or essential features or elements of the disclosure. The scope of the invention is accordingly to be limited by nothing other than the appended claims, in which reference to an element in the singular is not intended to mean "one and only one" unless explicitly so stated, but rather "one or more." Moreover, where a phrase similar to "at least one of A, B, or C" is used in the claims, it is intended that the phrase be interpreted to mean that A alone may be present in an embodiment, B alone may be present in an embodiment, C alone may be present in an embodiment, or that any combination of the elements A, B and C may be present in a single embodiment; for example, A and B, A and C, B and C, or A and B and C.</p>
<p id="p0041" num="0041">Systems, methods and apparatus are provided herein. In the detailed description herein, references to "various embodiments", "one embodiment", "an embodiment", etc., indicate that the embodiment described may include a particular feature, structure, or characteristic, but every embodiment may not necessarily include the particular feature, structure, or characteristic. Moreover, such phrases are not necessarily referring to the same embodiment. Further, when a particular feature, structure, or characteristic is described in connection with an embodiment, it is submitted that it is within the knowledge of one skilled in the art to affect such feature, structure, or characteristic in connection with other embodiments whether or not explicitly described.<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> After reading the description, it will be apparent to one skilled in the relevant art(s) how to implement the disclosure in alternative embodiments.</p>
<p id="p0042" num="0042">As used herein, the terms "comprises", "comprising", or any other variation thereof, are intended to cover a non-exclusive inclusion, such that a process, method, article, or apparatus that comprises a list of elements does not include only those elements but may include other elements not expressly listed or inherent to such process, method, article, or apparatus.</p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> -->
<claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>A vane arm (140) comprising:
<claim-text>a first end (141) having a first surface (148) and a second surface (151) opposite the first surface (148); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a vane stem aperture (146) formed through the first end (141) of the vane arm (140), wherein the first surface (148) of the first end (141) of the vane arm (140) defines a first perimeter (160) of the vane stem aperture (146), and wherein the second surface (151) of the first end (141) of the vane arm (140) defines a second perimeter (162) of the vane stem aperture (146), wherein the second perimeter (162) comprises a first shape that is at least one of circular or elliptical, and wherein the first perimeter (160) comprises a second shape different from the first shape;</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>characterised in that</b> a radially inward portion (170) of the vane stem aperture (146) is defined, at least partially, by:
<claim-text>a first wedge face (174), a second wedge face (176), and a third wedge face (192), wherein the first wedge face (174), the second wedge face (176), and the third wedge face (192) each extends in a radially outward direction toward an axis (R-R') extending radially through a central point of the vane stem aperture (146); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a radially outward portion (172) of the vane stem aperture (146) is defined, at least partially, by:
<claim-text>a first vertical surface (182) extending between the first wedge face (174) and the first surface (148) of the first end (141) of the vane arm (140);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second vertical surface (184) extending between the second wedge face (176) and the first surface (148) of the first end (141) of the vane arm (140);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third vertical surface (194) extending between the third wedge face (192) and the first surface (148) of the first end (141) of the vane arm (140); and<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth vertical surface (190b) located opposite the third vertical surface (194), wherein the first vertical surface (182), the second vertical surface (184), the third vertical surface (194), and the fourth vertical surface (190b) are each generally parallel to the axis (R-R') extending radially through the central point of the vane stem aperture (146); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the radially inward portion (170) of the vane stem aperture (146) is further defined, at least partially, by:
<claim-text>a further first vertical surface (178) extending between the first wedge face (174) and the second surface (151) of the first end (141) of the vane arm (140);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a further second vertical surface (180) extending between the second wedge face (176) and the second surface (151) of the first end (141) of the vane arm (140);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a further third vertical surface (196) extending between the third wedge face (192) and the second surface (151) of the first end (141) of the vane arm (140); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a further fourth vertical surface (190a) located opposite the further third vertical surface (196), wherein the further first vertical surface (178), the further second vertical surface (180), the further third vertical surface (196), and the further fourth vertical surface (190a) are each generally parallel to the axis (R-R') extending radially through the central point of the vane stem aperture (146).</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>The vane arm (140) of claim 1, further comprising:
<claim-text>a first groove (198, 164a) formed in the first vertical surface (182); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second groove (164b) formed in the second vertical surface (184).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>The vane arm (140) of claim 2, wherein the first vertical surface (182), the first groove (198, 164a), the second vertical surface (184), the second groove (164b), the third<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> vertical surface (194), and the fourth vertical surface (190b) define the first perimeter (160) of the vane stem aperture (146).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>The vane arm (140) of claim 3, wherein a diameter (D1) of the second perimeter (162) is greater than a diameter (D1) of the first perimeter (160) as measured between the first groove (164a) and the second groove (164b).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>The vane arm (140) of any preceding claim, wherein the vane arm (140) comprises titanium or a titanium alloy.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>A variable vane assembly (100) of a gas turbine engine (20), comprising:
<claim-text>a synchronization ring (120);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a vane stem (134) coupled to the synchronization ring (120); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a vane arm (140) as claimed in any preceding claim, the vane arm (140) coupling the vane stem (134) to the synchronization ring (120).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>The variable vane assembly (100) of claim 6, wherein the first wedge face (174) and the second wedge face (176) contact the vane stem (134).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>The variable vane assembly (100) of claim 7, wherein a gap (G1) is located between the third wedge face (192) and the vane stem (134).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>The variable vane assembly (100) of any of claims 6 to 8 when dependent on any of claims 1 to 5, wherein a distance between the first vertical surface (148) and the vane stem (134) limits a rotation of the vane arm (140) relative to the vane stem (134) to 1° or less.<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>A variable vane assembly (100), comprising:
<claim-text>a vane stem (134); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the vane arm (140) of any of claims 1 to 5 coupled to the vane stem (134).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims02" lang="de"><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> -->
<claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Schaufelhebel (140), umfassend:
<claim-text>ein erstes Ende (141) mit einer ersten Oberfläche (148) und einer zweiten Oberfläche (151) gegenüber der ersten Oberfläche (148); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Schaufelschaftöffnung (146), die durch das erste Ende (141) des Schaufelhebels (140) hindurch ausgebildet ist, wobei die erste Oberfläche (148) des ersten Endes (141) des Schaufelhebels (140) einen ersten Umfang (160) der Schaufelschaftöffnung (146) definiert und wobei die zweite Oberfläche (151) des ersten Endes (141) des Schaufelhebels (140) einen zweiten Umfang (162) der Schaufelschaftöffnung (146) definiert, wobei der zweite Umfang (162) eine erste Form umfasst, die mindestens eines von kreisförmig oder elliptisch ist, und wobei der erste Umfang (160) eine zweite Form umfasst,</claim-text>
<claim-text>die sich von der ersten Form unterscheidet;</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> ein radial einwärtiger Abschnitt (170) der Schaufelschaftöffnung (146) mindestens teilweise durch Folgendes definiert ist:
<claim-text>eine erste Keilfläche (174), eine zweite Keilfläche (176) und eine dritte Keilfläche (192), wobei sich die erste Keilfläche (174), die zweite Keilfläche (176) und die dritte Keilfläche (192) jeweils in einer radial auswärtigen Richtung zu einer Achse (R-R'), die sich radial durch einen Mittelpunkt der Schaufelschaftöffnung (146) hindurch erstreckt, erstrecken; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei ein radial auswärtiger Abschnitt (172) der Schaufelschaftöffnung (146) mindestens teilweise durch Folgendes definiert ist:
<claim-text>eine erste vertikale Oberfläche (182), die sich zwischen der ersten Keilfläche (174) und der ersten Oberfläche (148) des ersten Endes (141) des Schaufelhebels (140) erstreckt;<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>eine zweite vertikale Oberfläche (184), die sich zwischen der zweiten Keilfläche (176) und der ersten Oberfläche (148) des ersten Endes (141) des Schaufelhebels (140) erstreckt;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine dritte vertikale Oberfläche (194), die sich zwischen der dritten Keilfläche (192) und der ersten Oberfläche (148) des ersten Endes (141) des Schaufelhebels (140) erstreckt; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine vierte vertikale Oberfläche (190b), die sich gegenüber der dritten vertikalen Oberfläche (194) befindet, wobei die erste vertikale Oberfläche (182), die zweite vertikale Oberfläche (184), die dritte vertikale Oberfläche (194) und die vierte vertikale Oberfläche (190b) jeweils im Allgemeinen parallel zu der Achse (R-R'), die sich radial durch den Mittelpunkt der Schaufelschaftöffnung (146) hindurch erstreckt, liegen; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei der radial einwärtige Abschnitt (170) der Schaufelschaftöffnung (146) ferner mindestens teilweise durch Folgendes definiert ist:
<claim-text>eine weitere erste vertikale Oberfläche (178), die sich zwischen der ersten Keilfläche (174) und der zweiten Oberfläche (151) des ersten Endes (141) des Schaufelhebels (140) erstreckt;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine weitere zweite vertikale Oberfläche (180), die sich zwischen der zweiten Keilfläche (176) und der zweiten Oberfläche (151) des ersten Endes (141) des Schaufelhebels (140) erstreckt;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine weitere dritte vertikale Oberfläche (196), die sich zwischen der dritten Keilfläche (192) und der zweiten Oberfläche (151) des ersten Endes (141) des Schaufelhebels (140) erstreckt; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine weitere vierte vertikale Oberfläche (190a), die sich gegenüber der weiteren dritten vertikalen Oberfläche (196) befindet, wobei die weitere erste vertikale Oberfläche (178),</claim-text>
<claim-text>die weitere zweite vertikale Oberfläche (180), die weitere dritte vertikale Oberfläche (196) und die weitere vierte vertikale Oberfläche (190a) jeweils im Allgemeinen parallel zu der Achse (R-R'), die sich radial durch den Mittelpunkt der Schaufelschaftöffnung (146) hindurch erstreckt, liegen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Schaufelhebel (140) nach Anspruch 1, ferner umfassend:
<claim-text>eine erste Nut (198, 164a), die in der ersten vertikalen Oberfläche (182) ausgebildet ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine zweite Nut (164b), die in der zweiten vertikalen Oberfläche (184) ausgebildet ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Schaufelhebel (140) nach Anspruch 2, wobei die erste vertikale Oberfläche (182), die erste Nut (198, 164a), die zweite vertikale Oberfläche (184), die zweite Nut (164b), die dritte vertikale Oberfläche (194) und die vierte vertikale Oberfläche (190b) den ersten Umfang (160) der Schaufelschaftöffnung (146) definieren.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Schaufelhebel (140) nach Anspruch 3, wobei ein Durchmesser (D1) des zweiten Umfangs (162) größer als ein Durchmesser (D1) des ersten Umfangs (160) ist, wie er zwischen der ersten Nut (164a) und der zweiten Nut (164b) gemessen wird.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Schaufelhebel (140) nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei der Schaufelhebel (140) Titan oder eine Titanlegierung umfasst.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Verstellbare Schaufelanordnung (100) eines Gasturbinentriebwerks (20), umfassend:
<claim-text>einen Synchronisationsring (120);</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Schaufelschaft (134), der an den Synchronisationsring (120) gekoppelt ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Schaufelhebel (140) nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei der Schaufelhebel (140) den Schaufelschaft (134) an den Synchronisationsring (120) koppelt.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Verstellbare Schaufelanordnung (100) nach Anspruch 6, wobei die erste Keilfläche (174) und die zweite Keilfläche (176) den Schaufelschaft (134) kontaktieren.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>Verstellbare Schaufelanordnung (100) nach Anspruch 7, wobei sich ein Spalt (G1) zwischen der dritten Keilfläche (192) und dem Schaufelschaft (134) befindet.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>Verstellbare Schaufelanordnung (100) nach einem der Ansprüche 6 bis 8 in Abhängigkeit von einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 5, wobei ein Abstand zwischen der ersten vertikalen Oberfläche (148) und dem Schaufelschaft (134) eine Drehung des Schaufelhebels (140) in Bezug zu dem Schaufelschaft (134) um 1° oder weniger begrenzt.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>Verstellbare Schaufelanordnung (100), umfassend:
<claim-text>einen Schaufelschaft (134); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>den Schaufelhebel (140) nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 5, der an den Schaufelschaft (134) gekoppelt ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims03" lang="fr"><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> -->
<claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Bras d'aube (140) comprenant :
<claim-text>une première extrémité (141) ayant une première surface (148) et une seconde surface (151) opposée à la première surface (148) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une ouverture de tige d'aube (146) formée à travers la première extrémité (141) du bras d'aube (140), dans lequel la première surface (148) de la première extrémité (141) du bras d'aube (140) définit un premier périmètre (160) de l'ouverture de tige d'aube (146), et dans lequel la seconde surface (151) de la première extrémité (141) du bras d'aube (140) définit un second périmètre (162) de l'ouverture de tige d'aube (146), dans lequel le second périmètre (162) comprend une première forme qui est au moins l'une parmi circulaire ou elliptique, et dans lequel le premier périmètre (160) comprend une seconde forme différente de la première forme ;</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>caractérisé en ce que</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>une partie radialement vers l'intérieur (170) de l'ouverture de tige d'aube (146) est définie, au moins partiellement, par :
<claim-text>une première face de coin (174), une deuxième face de coin (176) et une troisième face de coin (192), dans lequel la première face de coin (174), la deuxième face de coin (176) et la troisième face de coin (192) s'étendent chacune dans une direction radialement vers l'extérieur vers un axe (R-R') s'étendant radialement à travers un point central de l'ouverture de tige d'aube (146) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel une partie radialement vers l'extérieur (172) de l'ouverture de tige d'aube (146) est définie, au moins partiellement, par :
<claim-text>une première surface verticale (182) s'étendant entre la première face de coin (174) et la première surface (148) de la première extrémité (141) du bras d'aube (140) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une deuxième surface verticale (184) s'étendant entre la<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> deuxième face de coin (176) et la première surface (148) de la première extrémité (141) du bras d'aube (140) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une troisième surface verticale (194) s'étendant entre la troisième face de coin (192) et la première surface (148) de la première extrémité (141) du bras d'aube (140) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une quatrième surface verticale (190b) située à l'opposé de la troisième surface verticale (194), dans lequel la première surface verticale (182), la deuxième surface verticale (184),</claim-text>
<claim-text>la troisième surface verticale (194) et la quatrième surface verticale (190b) sont chacune généralement parallèles à l'axe (R-R') s'étendant radialement à travers le point central de l'ouverture de tige d'aube (146) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel la partie radialement vers l'intérieur (170) de l'ouverture de tige d'aube (146) est en outre définie, au moins partiellement, par :
<claim-text>une première surface verticale supplémentaire (178) s'étendant entre la première face de coin (174) et la seconde surface (151) de la première extrémité (141) du bras d'aube (140) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une deuxième surface verticale supplémentaire (180) s'étendant entre la deuxième face de coin (176) et la seconde surface (151) de la première extrémité (141) du bras d'aube (140) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une troisième surface verticale supplémentaire (196) s'étendant entre la troisième face de coin (192) et la seconde surface (151) de la première extrémité (141) du bras d'aube (140) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une quatrième surface verticale supplémentaire (190a) située à l'opposé de la troisième surface verticale supplémentaire (196), dans lequel la première surface verticale supplémentaire (178), la deuxième surface verticale supplémentaire (180), la troisième surface verticale supplémentaire (196) et la quatrième surface verticale supplémentaire (190a) sont chacune généralement parallèles à l'axe (R-R') s'étendant radialement à travers le point central de l'ouverture de tige d'aube (146).</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Bras d'aube (140) selon la revendication 1, comprenant en<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> outre :
<claim-text>une première rainure (198, 164a) formée dans la première surface verticale (182) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une seconde rainure (164b) formée dans la deuxième surface verticale (184).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Bras d'aube (140) selon la revendication 2, dans lequel la première surface verticale (182), la première rainure (198, 164a), la deuxième surface verticale (184), la seconde rainure (164b), la troisième surface verticale (194) et la quatrième surface verticale (190b) définissent le premier périmètre (160) de l'ouverture de tige d'aube (146).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Bras d'aube (140) selon la revendication 3, dans lequel un diamètre (D1) du second périmètre (162) est supérieur à un diamètre (D1) du premier périmètre (160) tel que mesuré entre la première rainure (164a) et la seconde rainure (164b).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Bras d'aube (140) selon une quelconque revendication précédente, dans lequel le bras d'aube (140) comprend du titane ou un alliage de titane.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Ensemble d'aubes variables (100) d'un moteur à turbine à gaz (20), comprenant :
<claim-text>une bague de synchronisation (120) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une tige d'aube (134) couplée à la bague de synchronisation (120) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un bras d'aube (140) selon une quelconque revendication précédente, le bras d'aube (140) couplant la tige d'aube (134) à la bague de synchronisation (120).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Ensemble d'aubes variables (100) selon la revendication 6, dans lequel la première face de coin (174) et la deuxième face de coin (176) sont en contact avec la tige d'aube (134).<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>Ensemble d'aubes variables (100) selon la revendication 7, dans lequel un espace (G1) est situé entre la troisième face de coin (192) et la tige d'aube (134).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>Ensemble d'aubes variables (100) selon l'une quelconque des revendications 6 à 8 lorsqu'elles dépendent de l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 5, dans lequel une distance entre la première surface verticale (148) et la tige d'aube (134) limite une rotation du bras d'aube (140) par rapport à la tige d'aube (134) à 1° ou moins.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>Ensemble d'aubes variables (100), comprenant :
<claim-text>une tige d'aube (134) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>le bras d'aube (140) selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 5 couplé à la tige d'aube (134).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="138" he="191" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="28"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="141" he="166" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="29"> -->
<figure id="f0003" num="3A,3B,3C"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="131" he="207" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="30"> -->
<figure id="f0004" num="4A,4B"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="125" he="196" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> -->
<figure id="f0005" num="5A,5B"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="144" he="179" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<ep-reference-list id="ref-list">
<heading id="ref-h0001"><b>REFERENCES CITED IN THE DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0001" num=""><i>This list of references cited by the applicant is for the reader's convenience only. It does not form part of the European patent document. Even though great care has been taken in compiling the references, errors or omissions cannot be excluded and the EPO disclaims all liability in this regard.</i></p>
<heading id="ref-h0002"><b>Patent documents cited in the description</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0002" num="">
<ul id="ref-ul0001" list-style="bullet">
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0001" dnum="US2017081975A"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2017081975</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0001">[0003]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0002" dnum="FR2897120"><document-id><country>FR</country><doc-number>2897120</doc-number></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0002">[0004]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0003" dnum="FR2877059"><document-id><country>FR</country><doc-number>2877059</doc-number></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0003">[0005]</crossref></li>
</ul></p>
</ep-reference-list>
</ep-patent-document>
