<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP15810764B1" file="EP15810764NWB1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3337630" kind="B1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSK..HRIS..MTNORS..SM..................</B001EP><B003EP>*</B003EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  2100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3337630</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT SPECIFICATION</B121></B120><B130>B1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>15810764.9</B210><B220><date>20150819</date></B220><B240><B241><date>20170731</date></B241><B242><date>20190205</date></B242></B240><B250>en</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20180627</date><bnum>201826</bnum></B430><B450><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B450><B452EP><date>20210707</date></B452EP></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>B21D  51/26        20060101AFI20170309BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>B21D  51/26        20130101 LI20170307BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>B21D  51/2638      20130101 LI20170307BHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>AEROSOLBEHÄLTER AUS METALL UND VERFAHREN ZUR HERSTELLUNG</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>METAL AEROSOL CONTAINER AND METHOD OF MANUFACTURE</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>RÉCIPIENT D'AÉROSOL MÉTALLIQUE ET PROCÉDÉ DE FABRICATION</B542></B540><B560><B561><text>US-A- 4 173 883</text></B561><B561><text>US-A- 4 753 364</text></B561><B561><text>US-A- 4 854 149</text></B561><B562><text>None</text></B562></B560></B500><B700><B720><B721><snm>ZAPATA MORAN, Isaias</snm><adr><str>Calzada De Guadalupe 504
Col. Centro Cuatitlan</str><city>Cuatitlan
Edo. De Mexico CP 54800</city><ctry>MX</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>ZAPATA MORAN, Marco</snm><adr><str>Calzada De Guadalupe 504
Col. Centro Cuattlan</str><city>Cuatitlan
Edo. De Mexico CP 54800</city><ctry>MX</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>ALVAREZ ZAVALA, Alberto</snm><adr><str>Calzada De Guadalupe 504
Col. Centro Cuatitlan</str><city>Cuatitlan
Edo. De Mexico CP 54800</city><ctry>MX</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B730><B731><snm>Envases Universales De Mexico SAPI De CV</snm><iid>101653373</iid><irf>408379EP/PDJ</irf><adr><str>Calzada De Guadalupe 504 
Col. Centro Cuattlan</str><city>Cuatitlan, Edo. De Mexico CP 54800</city><ctry>MX</ctry></adr></B731></B730><B740><B741><snm>Jenkins, Peter David</snm><iid>100026614</iid><adr><str>Page White &amp; Farrer 
Bedford House 
John Street</str><city>London WC1N 2BF</city><ctry>GB</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840><B860><B861><dnum><anum>IB2015001905</anum></dnum><date>20150819</date></B861><B862>en</B862></B860><B870><B871><dnum><pnum>WO2017029535</pnum></dnum><date>20170223</date><bnum>201708</bnum></B871></B870></B800></SDOBI>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<heading id="h0001">BACKGROUND</heading>
<heading id="h0002">1. Technical Field</heading>
<p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention is in the field of metal container manufacturing, and more specifically in the field of metal containers adapted to dispense a pressurized or aerosol product.</p>
<heading id="h0003">2. Introduction</heading>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">Metal cans and containers have long been used to hold and dispense a wide variety of goods and materials, in solid, liquid, or gaseous forms. When used to hold an aerosol product, the metal containers are designed to withstand pressure fluctuations caused by external factors such as temperature variations. Such containers may also be subjected to large mechanical stresses and pressure spikes caused by drops and other sudden impacts, providing a further design consideration. Depending on the intended application of the metal container, a combination of qualities is required. Such qualities might include cost, durability, strength, and manufacturing speed.</p>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">The most common type of metal container is formed from a flat metal disc, usually aluminum, which is stretched into a cup-like shape through an inelastic process known as drawing and ironing. A pre-formed metal top is then attached to complete the container. For use in low-pressure applications, drawn metal containers are desirable because of their low cost and high speed of manufacture. Drawn metal containers are most commonly used to hold carbonated beverages. However, these drawn containers have thin walls that are subject to variance in thickness and are more prone to burst and fail at higher pressures or when subjected to impacts or drops.</p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">Rolled metal containers are also available, wherein a flat piece of sheet metal, usually steel, is formed into a cylinder, and base and top components are each attached via crimped seams to the cylindrical sidewall to complete the container. These containers have a more consistent wall thickness than drawn containers, and because they are less likely to suffer burst failures at high pressures, are most commonly used in higher-pressure (e.g. aerosol) applications. However, the top and bottom crimped<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> seams make the container heavy and cause a greater probability of failure from impacts or drops when compared to a drawn container.</p>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">Thus there is an ongoing need for a metal container, particularly in aerosol applications, that can be manufactured to withstand high pressure and failure from impacts and drops, while minimizing the number of crimped seams required.</p>
<p id="p0006" num="0006"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US4753364A"><text>US-A-4753364</text></patcit> discloses making a necked container wherein a sheet material is formed into a generally cylindrical tubular member and the adjacent longitudinally extending edges of the sheet are butt welded. The welded tubular member is progressively necked-in over a dome-shaped surface of a single mandrel provided within the welded tubular member. The free end of the necked end portion of the tubular member is trimmed and curled to form a necked container body.</p>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">From <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="US4753364A"><text>US-A-4 753 364</text></patcit> there is known a method for manufacturing a metal container adapted to receive a dispensing valve assembly for dispensing a pressurized or aerosol product from the container, wherein said container is formed from two pieces of metal, including the steps of: providing a metal body component and a metal base component; rolling the metal body component into a generally tubular shape having two longitudinal proximate free edges and open top and bottom-ends; welding the longitudinal proximate free edges of the tubular shape to form a longitudinal weld seam, thereby forming a welded cylindrical body of a first diameter with open top and bottom ends; and forming the container; forming and sealing the metal base component to the open bottom-end of the welded cylindrical body to form a closed container bottom; forming a curl at the open top-end of the neck portion, the curl being configured to receive a dispensing valve assembly for dispensing a pressurized or aerosol product from the container; wherein the weld seam extends continuously throughout the shoulder portion, neck portion, and curl.</p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">From <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="US4753364A"><text>US-A-4 753 364</text></patcit> there is also known a two-piece metal container comprising:a cylindrical body component made from a single continuous piece of sheet metal rolled into a tubular form and welded to form a continuous weld seam in a direction parallel to a longitudinal axis of the container, the welded cylindrical body component being of a first diameter having open top and bottom ends;a metal base component formed and sealed to close the open bottom end of the welded cylindrical body component to form a closed container bottom; the cylindrical body component having a top portion necked in wherein the neck portion has a reduced second diameter relative to the first diameter of the welded cylindrical body and the open top-end of the neck portion having a curled lip configured to receive a dispensing valve assembly for dispensing a pressurized or aerosol product from the container.</p>
<p id="p0009" num="0009"><patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="US4854149A"><text>US-A-4854149</text></patcit> discloses reducing the cross-section of a terminal portion of a tubular body using an external die which defines a convergent work surface therein of like shape to the exterior of the reduced cross-section to be produced and a plug having a work surface thereon of like shape to the interior of the reduced cross-section to be produced.</p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010"><patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="US4173883A"><text>US-A-4173883</text></patcit> discloses forming integral domed can bodies for aerosol cans using an inside tool and an outside tool so related as progressively to reduce the<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> diameter of an end portion of the tubular body and in doing so gradually increasing the axial extent of an intermediate frustoconical portion.</p>
<heading id="h0004">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">The present invention provides a method of manufacturing a metal container according to claim 1.</p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">In one embodiment, the container when sealed with a dispensing valve assembly and pressurized to 256 psi (1765 kPa) withstands deformation at 100 °F (37.7 °C) for at least 10 minutes.</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">In one embodiment, the container when sealed with a dispensing valve assembly and pressurized to 311 psi (2150 kPa) withstands explosive failure at 100°F (37.7 °C) for at least 5 minutes.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">In one embodiment, the metal body component has a height in a range of 6.4 cm to 24.1 cm (2.5 inches to 9.5 inches) and a first diameter in a range of 4.3 cm to 8.26 cm (1.7 to 3.25 inches).</p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">In one embodiment, the metal body component and the metal base component are each pre-cut from steel sheet.</p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">In one embodiment, the second diameter is at most 50% of the first diameter.</p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">In one embodiment, the second diameter is in a range of 40% to 50% of the first diameter.</p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">In one embodiment, the second diameter is in a range of 20% to 40% of the first diameter.</p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">In one embodiment, the welding step comprises applying welding spots at spaced positions along one or more of the free edges to form the weld seam.</p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">In one embodiment, the necking dies produce a shoulder having an inwardly concave, outwardly concave or flat sloped shape.</p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">In one embodiment, the series of necking dies stretch the top portion of the welded cylindrical body to form the shoulder and neck portions where the reduced second diameter of the neck portion is no greater than 50% of the first diameter without causing fracture or failure of the weld seam.</p>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">In one embodiment, the method further comprises trimming excess material from the neck portion prior to forming the curl.</p>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">In one embodiment, the steps of manufacture are performed sequentially.</p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">The present invention further provides a two-piece metal container according to claim 11.</p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">In one embodiment, the container when sealed with a dispensing valve assembly and pressurized at 256 psi (1765 kPa) withstands deformation at 100 °F (37.7 °C) for at least 10 minutes.</p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">In one embodiment, the container when sealed with a dispensing valve assembly and pressurized to 311 psi (2150 kPa) withstands explosive failure at 100°F (37.7 °C) for at least 5 minutes.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">In one embodiment, the welded container body component has a height in a range of 6.4 cm to 24.1 cm (2.5 inches to 9.5 inches) and a first diameter in a range of 4.3 cm to 8.26 cm (1.7 to 3.25 inches).</p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">In one embodiment, the shoulder portion is of an inwardly concave, outwardly concave or flat sloped.</p>
<p id="p0029" num="0029">In one embodiment, the second diameter is in a range of 40% to 50% of the first diameter.</p>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">In one embodiment, the second diameter is in a range of 20% to 40% of the first diameter.</p>
<p id="p0031" num="0031">Accordingly, a two-piece metal aerosol container and method of manufacture are provided in accordance with the present invention. A rolled and longitudinally welded cylindrical tube forms the container body, including a cylindrical sidewall, and reduced diameter shoulder and neck portions (formed by a sequential necking process), while a separate metal base component is attached via a crimped seam. The open-top end of the container neck portion is curled to receive a manually actuatable dispensing valve assembly. The container of the preferred embodiments of the present invention is resistant to internal pressures in excess of 311 psi (2150 kPa) and offers increased strength and pressure resistance (compared to a three-piece rolled metal aerosol container), while being easy to manufacture and low in cost.</p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032">Additional aspects and/or advantages of the invention will be set forth in the description which follows.</p>
<heading id="h0005">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p0033" num="0033">These and/or other aspects and advantages of the invention will be apparent from the following description of various embodiments, taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings of which:
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li><figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is a perspective view of a final assembly of a two-piece metal aerosol container manufactured according to one embodiment of the present invention;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">Fig. 2A</figref> is a top plan view of a beginning sheet metal form;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">Fig. 2B</figref> is a perspective view of a generally tubular body form;<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> is a front view of the partially formed container, after a concave metal base has been attached but prior to the necking process at the open top-end;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0004">Fig. 4</figref> is a front view of the final result of the sequential necking process, as applied to the container of <figref idref="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0005">Fig. 5A</figref> is a front view of the result of a single necking operation, which causes a first reduction in diameter of the top portion;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0005">Fig. 5B</figref> is a front view of the result of three sequential necking operations, which cause a second and third reduction in diameter of the top portion, subsequent to the first reduction in diameter of <figref idref="f0005">Fig 5A</figref>;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0005 f0006">Fig. 5</figref> is a perspective view of two sequential necking dies;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0007">Fig. 6</figref> is a front view of the completed two-piece aerosol container of <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, with a curled lip formed on the upper edge of the cylindrical neck portion;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0008">Fig. 6A</figref> is an exploded cross sectional view of a curl formed at the open top end of the container;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0009">Fig. 7</figref> is a perspective view of one embodiment of the metal aerosol container with a dispensing valve assembly securely fastened to the open top end of the container;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0010">Fig. 8A</figref> is a front view of a two-piece aerosol container of <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, wherein the bottom of the container has deformed outwardly during testing (under very high internal pressure) into a generally asymmetrical convex position;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0010">Fig. 8B</figref> is a front view of the two-piece aerosol container of <figref idref="f0010">Fig. 8A</figref>, wherein the bottom of the container has burst adjacent the crimped seam;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0011">Fig. 9</figref> is a flowchart depicting a method of manufacture of one embodiment of the present invention, for forming a two-piece aerosol container;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0012">Fig. 10</figref> is a cutaway view of one embodiment of a double seam crimp for attaching the base component to the body component;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0013">Fig. 11</figref> is a front cutaway view of one embodiment of an aerosol dispensing valve assembly to be secured to the open top end of the container.</li>
</ul><!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p>
<heading id="h0006">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p0034" num="0034"><figref idref="f0001">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a perspective view of a final assembly of a two-piece metal aerosol container <b>20</b> manufactured according to one embodiment of the present invention. For purposes of clarity, <figref idref="f0001">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> depicts the container without an attached aerosol valve and closure assembly. When referring to dimensions or directions, unless stated otherwise, all descriptions assume that the container is disposed in a vertically upright manner, wherein the longitudinal axis <b>50</b> runs from the base of the container to the top of the cylindrical container body, and the radial axis <b>51</b> is transverse to the longitudinal axis.</p>
<p id="p0035" num="0035">The two-piece metal aerosol container <b>20</b> includes a container body <b>26</b> and a container base <b>104,</b> the body <b>26</b> including top and bottom portions <b>22, 24</b> respectively, with an open bottom end of the bottom portion <b>24</b> being sealed by the base <b>104.</b> In a feature of this invention, a weld seam <b>102</b> traverses the entire longitudinal length of the container body <b>26,</b> beginning at the bottom end <b>120</b> of the bottom portion <b>24</b> and continuing uninterrupted upwardly through the top portion <b>22.</b> The top portion <b>22</b> includes, in serial order from bottom to top, a tapered shoulder portion <b>109,</b> a cylindrical neck portion <b>110,</b> and a curled lip <b>114</b> formed on an upper edge of the cylindrical neck portion, creating an open top-end <b>115.</b> Bottom portion <b>24</b> and top portion <b>22</b> are fabricated from a single, continuous, first piece of sheet metal, preferably steel, and collectively form a one-piece welded cylindrical container body <b>26</b> of the two-piece aerosol container <b>20.</b> A second piece, a metal base <b>104,</b> is formed from a single, continuous second piece of sheet metal, preferably steel. The metal base <b>104</b> is attached to the open bottom end of the cylindrical body via a crimped seam <b>106</b> (e.g. a double seam), which is airtight and pressure-resistant (e.g. up to at least 256 psi (1765 kPa) for applications such as an aerosol paint container). This crimped seam <b>106</b> is the only additional seam required anywhere on container <b>20.</b> Generally, it is the strength of this crimped seam <b>106,</b> rather than the welded seam <b>102,</b> that tends to be the limiting factor in the container's strength against deformation due to internal pressurization and/or the forces applied on drop impact.</p>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">In the disclosed embodiment, the top portion <b>22</b> includes a tapered shoulder portion <b>109</b> extending from an upper edge <b>107</b> of the cylindrical sidewall <b>100</b>, and<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> shaped concave outwardly, although one skilled in the art would appreciate that other taper geometries are possible to construct, e.g. concave inwardly or linear (flat sloped shape). The tapered portion and/or the sidewall and neck portions may also include additional features such as ribs or grooves. The internal diameter of the tapered shoulder portion <b>109</b> continually decreases, going from edge <b>107</b> (where it adjoins the cylindrical sidewall <b>100)</b> to an upper edge <b>108</b> where it adjoins the cylindrical neck portion <b>110,</b> which is of constant diameter. A curled lip <b>114</b> is formed from an upper edge portion of the cylindrical neck portion, the lip being configured to receive an aerosol valve and closure assembly that is typically attached to the container by crimping (and typically performed by a third party aerosol bottler). The transitions between cylindrical sidewall portion <b>100</b>, tapered shoulder portion <b>109</b>, cylindrical neck <b>110</b> and lip <b>114</b> are all seamless as all portions are formed from a single sheet of metal as described further below.</p>
<p id="p0037" num="0037"><figref idref="f0002 f0003 f0004 f0005 f0006 f0007 f0008 f0009">FIGs. <b>2-7</b></figref> illustrate one embodiment of making the aerosol container of <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>. <figref idref="f0002">FIG. <b>2</b></figref><i>A</i> is a diagrammatic view of a beginning sheet metal form 10. In this embodiment, a flat planar metal body component (form) <b>10</b> is cut or stamped from a sheet of steel with a thickness between .0065 inches and .0094 inches, with pre-determined dimensions of 8.142 inches x 7.038 inches, which are suitable to produce an aerosol container with a body diameter (body portion <b>24</b> in <figref idref="f0001">FIG. <b>1</b></figref><b>)</b> of 2-11/16 inches. In alternate embodiments, the dimensions of the metal body component may vary to allow the metal body component to have a height in a range of 6.4 to 24.1 cm (2.5 to 9.5 inches), and a diameter in a range of 4.3 to 8.26 cm (1.7 to 3.25 inches). The open top-end <b>115</b> of container body <b>26</b> will eventually have a diameter less than 50% (and as low as 30%) of that of the bottom portion <b>24</b>. However, prior to a sequential necking process, the top portion of metal form <b>10</b>, including a shoulder forming portion <b>109</b><i>a</i>, neck forming portion <b>110</b><i>a</i>, and lip forming portion <b>114</b><i>a</i> all begin with the same horizontal width as a body forming portion <b>100</b><i>a</i> from which the cylindrical sidewall is formed. In the process of sequential necking to form the reduced diameter container top portion <b>22</b> (which occurs after forming the longitudinal weld seam 102), material is not removed except (as needed) to deburr or otherwise provide minor smoothing for a finished edge trim. The material of forming portions <b>109</b><i>a</i>/<b>110</b><i>a</i>/<b>114</b><i>a</i> is redistributed to<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> form the tapered shoulder portion <b>109,</b> neck portion <b>110,</b> and curl portion <b>114</b> respectively, during the sequential necking process. This redistribution leads to a variable thickness in the wall of the container body <b>26.</b> In various embodiments, certain areas of the three aforementioned components <b>109/110/114</b> are increased in thickness by up to 50%, and typically in the range of 30%-45%, all as compared to the cylindrical container sidewall portion <b>100</b> (which remains of same constant thickness as the form <b>10</b>). The variable thickness in the top portion has the advantage of providing greater strength and reinforcement where needed, namely in the shoulder 109, neck 110, and lip 114 portions, reducing overall container weight and cost as compared to the alternative of forming the entire aerosol container out of sheet metal with a thickness equal to the thickness found in the cylindrical sidewall (bottom portion) <b>24</b> of the body component <b>26.</b></p>
<p id="p0038" num="0038">The metal body component (form) <b>10</b> may be stacked with other identical body components, and loaded into a tube-making machine, which pulls a single body component between a pair of heavy rollers, thereby rolling the body component into a generally tubular body <b>15,</b> as seen in <figref idref="f0002">FIG. <b>2</b></figref><i>B</i>. A pair of longitudinal free edges, <b>101</b> and <b>103</b> of tubular body <b>15,</b> now proximately located, form an elongated longitudinal opening or slit <b>116,</b> extending longitudinally between the open top and bottom ends of the tubular body, and wherein the slit vertically traverses the entire longitudinal length of the tubular body <b>15.</b> Until the slit <b>116</b> is sealed, the tubular body alone has little in the way of rigidity or structural integrity. It is the application of the weld seam <b>102</b> between the two free edges <b>101</b> and <b>103</b> that create a rigid container body that is able to resist and contain typical aerosol pressure forces.</p>
<p id="p0039" num="0039">In this embodiment, rolled tubular body <b>15</b> is immediately transferred to a welding stage, preferably located within the same tube-making machine. The welding stage pulls together free edges <b>101</b> and <b>103,</b> such that they are touching or overlapping. Using high-speed electro-welding, a current (e.g. 3290 Amperes) is supplied to the welding element, which applies a series of welding spots along the overlapping junction of the two free edges. The centers of adjacent welding spots are separated, in this example, by .02 inches (.5 mm) and each spot is applied with at least 90 pounds of force. Upon being applied, each weld spot expands to overlap its<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> immediately adjacent neighbor, forming a continuous, air-tight, and pressure resistant weld seam <b>102.</b> In one embodiment, the welding head remains stationary and the tubular body <b>15</b> is moved relative to the welding head in order to create the length of the weld seam <b>102,</b> although the opposite arrangement is also possible, wherein the welding head moves relative to the stationary tubular body. By the completion of the welding process, a welded cylindrical container body <b>26</b> has been formed, with a constant diameter and open top and bottom ends. The welding process is designed to ensure that the aerosol container body <b>26</b> can withstand considerable stresses beyond typical aerosol pressurization, such stresses including drops and longitudinal or radial compression. Additionally, weld seam <b>102</b> must withstand the deformation and associated stresses of the sequential necking process.</p>
<p id="p0040" num="0040">After welding, a metal base <b>104</b> is attached (by crimping) to close and seal the open bottom end of the welded cylindrical container body <b>26,</b> forming a container bottom. Here the metal base is shaped concave inwardly to withstand higher pressures. This metal base is generally thicker than the container sidewall <b>24;</b> here the base is made out of a steel sheet .013 inches thick, and may be pre-formed concurrently with the container body form, or may be pre-formed separately. Preferably, after a flat circular form of the base is stamped from the steel sheet, a shaping apparatus, such as a hydraulic press or punch, is used to create a concavity in the middle portion of the base, leaving an outer ring of flat material around the interior concavity. This flat ring forms both the standing ring (for resting vertically upright on another surface) and the crimped lip of the base (for attachment to the sidewall) in the assembled container.</p>
<p id="p0041" num="0041"><figref idref="f0012">FIG. <b>10</b></figref> depicts a detail view of one embodiment of double seaming, for attaching the base <b>104</b> to the body sidewall <b>24.</b> Double seaming is a standard practice used in can manufacturing to attach two components (most typically a container body and a base or top) through crimping, with or without the use of a supplementary adhesive <b>155.</b> On the bottom end of bottom portion <b>24,</b> the bottom edge is rolled such that an upturned lip <b>150</b> is formed, with the lip forming a J-shaped hook. The inwardly concave base <b>104</b> is inset slightly inside of the container body at bottom portion <b>24,</b> with the metal material of the base being bent 180-degrees to travel up and over J-shaped lip <b>150</b> at the folded section <b>160,</b> and subsequently being bent another 180-degrees at<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> <b>170</b> to fit a folded section inside the upturned, J-shaped lip <b>150.</b> With the metal layers thus positioned, they are crimped radially together, firmly securing the layers against loosening, and thereby forming the double seam.</p>
<p id="p0042" num="0042">Returning to <figref idref="f0003">FIG. <b>3</b></figref>, there is shown the assembled container body and base, after the concave metal base <b>104</b> has been attached but prior to the necking process at open top-end <b>115</b>. The crimped seam <b>106</b> is clearly visible, and, while of a slightly larger diameter, is negligibly different from the diameter of the welded cylindrical container body <b>24.</b> At an intersection point <b>120,</b> the weld seam <b>102</b> becomes physically integrated with the crimped seam <b>106.</b> Recalling the requirement of placing an upturned lip on the lower edge of the container body during the seaming process, it is important that the weld seam <b>102</b> be able to withstand the deformation and stress inherent in this 180-degree bend. It is likewise important that the weld seam be as flat as possible, so as to lay flush in the crimped seam.</p>
<p id="p0043" num="0043">After the concave metal base <b>104</b> has been attached via the crimped seam <b>106</b> to the welded container body <b>26,</b> the assembly moves on to the necking stage of the process. The sequential necking process is carried out by a series of necking dies (e.g., as shown in <figref idref="f0006">Fig. 5C</figref>); typically several dozen intermediate reduction (necking) steps (dies) are required to produce the reduced diameter shoulder and neck portions, as depicted in <figref idref="f0004">FIG. <b>4</b></figref><b>.</b> Through the use of a series of necking dies, top portion <b>22</b><i>b</i> is deformed and reshaped to the final dimensions of the shoulder <b>109</b> and neck <b>110</b> of the aerosol container. At this point in the process, the cylindrical neck simply terminates in an open top-end; curl <b>114</b> has yet to be formed on the cylindrical neck. The height and placement of top portion <b>22</b> may be varied, but in the preferred embodiment, the top portion <b>22</b> (shoulder, neck and lip) has a height of 1.3 inches, measured from the upper edge <b>107</b> of the cylindrical sidewall portion <b>100</b> to the uppermost surface of the curled lip.</p>
<p id="p0044" num="0044">The sequential necking process shapes the top portion <b>22</b><i>b</i> of the welded container body <b>26</b> through a series of deformation forces uniformly applied about the entire circumference of the container. These forces are applied in a number of sequential steps, with each individual step only producing a small component of the overall deformation that is required. For example, if the goal is to taper a 2-inch<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> container sidewall down to 1-inch neck, a single necking step might only cause a reduction in diameter of 1/8 inch. <figref idref="f0005 f0006">FIG. <b>5</b></figref><i>A</i> depicts this process, showing a front view of the result of a single necking operation, which causes a first reduction in diameter <b>200</b> of the top portion <b>22</b><i>b</i>.</p>
<p id="p0045" num="0045">To apply the necking force, a series of appropriately sized dies are required, with examples of such dies depicted in <figref idref="f0005 f0006">FIG. <b>5</b></figref><i>C</i>. The opening diameter <b>171</b> of one necking die <b>170</b> is sized such that it is equal to or slightly larger than the starting diameter of the welded container body <b>26,</b> such that the die may slip over the welded container body (along length <b>173</b> of the same opening diameter <b>171</b>) without initially causing any deformation. Deformation does not occur until the welded container body makes contact with reduced diameter necking portion <b>172</b> of the die <b>170,</b> wherein necking portion <b>172</b> is of a smaller diameter than either die opening <b>171</b> or container body <b>26.</b> The diameter of necking portion <b>172</b> is responsible for the first reduction in diameter <b>200.</b> The top portion <b>22</b><i>b</i> of the container is inserted in the first die <b>170</b> and mechanically pushed through the die along its entire length, with the resulting form again illustrated by <figref idref="f0005 f0006">FIG. <b>5</b></figref><i>A</i>. This pushing process reshapes top portion <b>22</b><i>b</i> to have an outer diameter equal to the inner diameter of the die at necking portion <b>172.</b> In an alternate embodiment, the die may move relative to a fixed container, rather than the scenario described above in which the container moves relative to a fixed die.</p>
<p id="p0046" num="0046">Subsequent necking operations follow the same procedure, although the diameter of the die continues to decrease in increments as needed, and additionally, the starting position of the die also varies. In tapered shapes, the greatest diameter is at the base of the top portion <b>22,</b> and the container diameter will then decrease with height, moving towards open top-end <b>115.</b> Consequently, each step begins at a higher initial longitudinal positioning than the step immediately prior, and the top portion <b>22</b><i>b</i> is pushed through a shorter distance. For example, in <figref idref="f0005 f0006">FIG. <b>5</b></figref><i>A</i>, the first necking die operation <b>200</b> is applied over a distance equal to the entire height of the top portion <b>22.</b> The second necking operation <b>202</b> is applied at a location above the first necking operation, and consequently over a shorter distance. The same is true of necking operation <b>204,</b> which is applied over the shortest distance of any of the depicted necking operations. Necking die <b>180</b> of <figref idref="f0005 f0006">FIG. <b>5</b></figref><i>C</i> demonstrates the reduction in diameter<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> of necking portion <b>182</b> and the reduction in necking distance <b>183,</b> as compared to the diameter of necking portion <b>172</b> and necking distance <b>173</b> respectively. The final result of three necking steps is shown in <figref idref="f0005 f0006">Fig. <b>5</b></figref><b><i>B</i></b> as a series of three steps: 29a, 29b, and 29c; additional necking steps will occur (each starting above the last step) to complete the shoulder formation leaving a cylindrical neck portion of a constant second diameter, (substantially less than the starting first diameter of sidewall portion <b>24).</b></p>
<p id="p0047" num="0047">By deforming top portion <b>22</b><i>b</i> over dozens of such necking operations, the mechanical stresses in the metal are reduced in magnitude and therefore severity, and the weld seam <b>102</b> is prevented from wrinkling. If the top portion were to be bent (reduced) in a single necking operation, it would almost certainly fracture or otherwise deform in an undesirable or unexpected manner, beginning at weld seam <b>102.</b> One skilled in the art will appreciate that a dome or tapered top portion formed in this step-wise (sequential) manner will not be perfectly smooth - the transition from one necking diameter to the next leaves a curve or corner, as seen in <figref idref="f0005 f0006">FIG. <b>5</b></figref><i>B</i>. It is therefore advantageous to have a large number of distinct sequential necking steps in order to achieve the desired smoothness of tapered shoulder portion <b>109,</b> as a larger number of steps more closely approximate the appearance of a smooth edge. In this embodiment, 42 distinct necking operations are performed to create the top portion <b>22</b> on the aerosol container.</p>
<p id="p0048" num="0048">In <figref idref="f0005 f0006">FIG. <b>5</b></figref><i>B</i>, each necking operation is represented as having caused the same amount of horizontal diameter reduction, although it is possible to adjust the diameter reduction as needed. For example, in one embodiment of the present invention, the shoulder portion <b>109</b> may be created as a domed (outwardly concave) shape. Starting from the top of the cylindrical sidewall portion <b>100</b>, the diameter of the dome constantly decreases with height, in a non-linear manner. Consequently, different magnitudes of diameter reduction are needed for the distinct steps, and are preferably achieved through the application of a pre-determined number and order of varied necking dies. These adjustments to the necking dies have the additional consequence of changing the thickness of the container walls on the tapered shoulder portion <b>109</b> - in one embodiment, the tapered shoulder portion wall is over 50% thicker at its upper end,<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> than at its lower end, where the lower end is the same wall thickness as the cylindrical sidewall <b>100</b> of bottom portion <b>24.</b></p>
<p id="p0049" num="0049"><figref idref="f0007">FIG. <b>6</b></figref> depicts a completed two-piece aerosol container <b>20,</b> with a curled lip <b>114</b> formed at the top end of the cylindrical neck portion <b>110.</b> As mentioned previously, the neck portion <b>110</b> is created in the last steps of the necking process, through the application of a final necking die to create a constant diameter cylindrical neck portion at the upper end of the tapered shoulder portion <b>109.</b> In one embodiment, the curling operation, to form curled lip <b>114</b> at the top end of the neck, takes place in the same machine as the necking operation, in a back-to-back fashion, and requires 18 steps.</p>
<p id="p0050" num="0050">The steps in the curling operation are similar to those of necking, in that small deformation forces are applied to the metal to cumulatively form a curl of the desired shape or form. However, while the necking forces that form the shoulder and neck are directed radially inwardly and axially upwardly, the curling operation directs the forces in a different manner to form curl <b>114</b> (as shown in cross section in <figref idref="f0007">Fig. <b>6</b></figref><b><i>A</i>),</b> first radially outwardly to create an elongated lip, axially downwardly to begin the curling process, and finally radially inwardly to complete curl <b>114.</b> As a downward turning lip, curl <b>114</b> presents a smooth and radially reinforced lip, on the open end of the container. The smoothly curved and radially thickened nature of one embodiment of a curled lip is depicted in <figref idref="f0007">FIG. <b>6</b></figref><b><i>A</i>.</b> In combination with the previously mentioned increase of wall thickness of the top portion <b>22,</b> the double-walled curled lip advantageously provides increased strength against deformation, which allows a manually actuatable aerosol valve and closure assembly <b>117</b> to be more securely fastened to the two-piece aerosol container <b>20.</b></p>
<p id="p0051" num="0051"><figref idref="f0009">FIG. <b>7</b></figref> shows one embodiment of a valve assembly <b>117</b> secured to the curled lip <b>114</b> to seal the open top end of the container <b>20.</b> An alternate embodiment of a manually actuatable aerosol valve assembly <b>117<i>A</i></b> is depicted in <figref idref="f0013">FIG. <b>11</b></figref> having a complimentary shaped cap portion to be crimped and/or otherwise secured by adhesive over the curl. Both valve assemblies are centrally disposed about the central longitudinal axis <b>50</b> of the aerosol container <b>20,</b> although the two assemblies are of different widths and are disposed at different heights relative to the curled lip <b>114.</b> One skilled in the art will appreciate that the design of aerosol valve closures suitable to be<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> fastened to curled lip <b>114</b> of the present aerosol container <b>20</b> are not limited to those depicted, and that curled lip <b>114</b> may be configured to receive a wide range of closure assemblies.</p>
<p id="p0052" num="0052">Compared to the prior art three-piece welded steel aerosol container, the present two-piece container <b>20</b> offers improved strength and reduced weight. The strength of such a pressurized container is measured in its ability to resist deformation, and then if the pressure continues to increase, to resist burst. Using a hydraulic pressurization device, aerosol containers are tested to determine their deformation and burst points. Such a device seals and holds the aerosol container by the cylindrical neck portion <b>110,</b> where the aerosol valve and closure assembly would otherwise be mounted. An airtight seal between the pressurization device and the container is established, and the container is suspended in mid-air, free of any surface contact points that could counter the pressure forces.</p>
<p id="p0053" num="0053">The two-piece aerosol container <b>20,</b> starting at ambient pressure, is then slowly internally pressurized. It may be pressurized in steps, with pauses between successive increases, to simulate changes in climate or atmosphere it may undergo during normal use, or it may be continually pressurized. A deformation is considered to be any irreversible change in container geometry, such as a visible dent, that still maintains the pressurization level. The crimped seam <b>106</b> and the concave metal base <b>104</b> comprise the weakest parts of the aerosol container <b>20,</b> and are therefore the failure locations. As depicted in <figref idref="f0010">FIG. <b>8</b></figref><i>A</i>, after reaching a certain level of internal pressurization, the bottom of the aerosol container deforms outwardly, inverting from a symmetrical concave position <b>130</b> to a generally asymmetrical convex position 132. It is the metal base <b>104</b> that deforms - not the crimped seam <b>106</b> itself, although this seam certainly experiences stresses beyond a normally expected amount. In the present embodiment, the two-piece aerosol container <b>20</b> was found to deform at 256 psi (1765 kPa), a 36% improvement over the 188 psi (1300 kPa) deformation point of a three-piece construction of similar dimensions and materials tested on the same apparatus.</p>
<p id="p0054" num="0054">If pressure continues to build after deformation occurs, the two-piece aerosol container <b>20</b> will eventually burst (explode), as depicted in <figref idref="f0010">FIG. <b>8</b></figref><i>B</i>, wherein a burst is considered to be any breach of the aerosol container walls that cause a loss of<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> pressurization. Prior to deformation, the concave inward shape of metal base <b>104</b> was the portion of the metal container weakest against internal pressurization forces. However, with the metal base <b>104</b> now deformed into a concave outward shape <b>130,</b> double seam <b>106</b> is now the weakest spot on the aerosol container <b>20.</b> Consequently, the explosive failure will likely occur somewhere along this seam <b>106,</b> illustratively depicted here as a failure point <b>134,</b> although one skilled in the art will appreciate that such a failure point could be located anywhere along the circumference of crimped seam <b>106.</b> In the present embodiment, the two-piece aerosol container <b>20</b> was found to explode at 311 psi (2150 kPa), a 30% improvement over the 239 psi (1650 kPa) explosion point of the three-piece construction.</p>
<p id="p0055" num="0055"><figref idref="f0011">FIG. <b>9</b></figref> is a flowchart depicting one embodiment of a method of manufacture of the present invention, wherein the two-piece aerosol container <b>20</b> is formed in a series of steps <b>200-206</b> that follow in a sequential manner, starting with step <b>200,</b> which provides the pre-formed metal body component <b>10.</b> While step <b>208</b> is placed side-by-side with step <b>200</b> in the vertical hierarchy of the flowchart, it is not a requirement that these two steps be performed simultaneously - step <b>208</b> only must take place before step <b>206,</b> which requires as input the pre-formed metal base component <b>104</b> of step <b>208.</b></p>
<p id="p0056" num="0056">These and other embodiments of the invention will be apparent to the skilled person and the invention is not limited to the foregoing examples.</p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> -->
<claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>A method for manufacturing a metal container (20) adapted to receive a dispensing valve assembly (117) for dispensing a pressurized or aerosol product from the container, wherein said container is formed from two pieces of metal, including the steps of:
<claim-text>providing a metal body component (10) and a metal base component (104);</claim-text>
<claim-text>rolling the metal body component into a generally tubular shape having two longitudinal proximate free edges (101, 103), and open top and bottom-ends;</claim-text>
<claim-text>welding the longitudinal proximate free edges of the tubular shape to form a longitudinal weld seam (102), thereby forming a welded cylindrical body (26) of a first diameter with open top and bottom ends; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming the container by:
<claim-text>forming and sealing the metal base component to the open bottom-end of the welded cylindrical body to form a closed container bottom;</claim-text>
<claim-text>after forming the closed container bottom, sequentially applying a series of reducing diameter necking dies about an outer circumference of a top portion (22) of the welded cylindrical body such that:
<claim-text>the application of each necking die causes a diameter reduction such that an inwardly tapering shoulder portion (109) having step-wise corner transitions between each diameter reduction is formed; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the application of a final necking die creates a constant diameter ending in a neck portion (110) extending from the inwardly tapering shoulder portion, where the neck portion has a reduced second diameter relative to the first diameter of the welded cylindrical body;</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a curl (114) at the open top-end (115) of the neck portion, the curl being configured to receive a dispensing valve assembly (117) for dispensing a pressurized or aerosol product from the container;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the weld seam extends continuously throughout the shoulder portion, neck portion, and curl.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>The method of claim 1 wherein the container when sealed with a dispensing valve assembly and pressurized to 256 psi (1765 kPa) withstands deformation at 100 °F<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> (37.7 °C) for at least 10 minutes, or wherein the container when sealed with a dispensing valve assembly and pressurized to 311 psi (2150 kPa) withstands explosive failure at 100 °F (37.7 °C) for at least 5 minutes.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>The method of claim 1 wherein the metal body component has a height in a range of 6.4 cm to 24.1 cm (2.5 inches to 9.5 inches) and a first diameter in a range of 4.3 to 8.26 cm (1.7 to 3.25 inches).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>The method of claim 1 wherein the metal body component and the metal base component are each pre-cut from steel sheet.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>The method of claim 1 wherein the second diameter is at most 50% of the first diameter, optionally wherein the second diameter is in a range of 40% to 50% of the first diameter, or wherein the second diameter is in a range of 20% to 40% of the first diameter.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>The method of claim 1 wherein the welding step comprises applying welding spots at spaced positions along one or more of the free edges to form the weld seam.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>The method of claim 1 wherein the necking dies produce a shoulder having an inwardly concave, outwardly concave, or a flat sloped shape.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>The method of claim 1 wherein the series of necking dies stretch the top portion of the welded cylindrical body to form the shoulder and neck portions where the reduced second diameter of the neck portion is no greater than 50% of the first diameter without causing fracture or failure of the weld seam.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>The method of claim 1 additionally comprising trimming excess material from the neck portion prior to forming the curl.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>The method of claim 1, wherein the steps of manufacture are performed sequentially.<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>A two-piece metal container (20) comprising:
<claim-text>a cylindrical body component (10) made from a single continuous piece of sheet metal rolled into a tubular form and welded to form a continuous weld seam (102) in a direction parallel to a longitudinal axis of the container, the welded cylindrical body component (26) being of a first diameter having open top and bottom ends;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a metal base component (104) formed and sealed to close the open bottom end of the welded cylindrical body component to form a closed container bottom;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the cylindrical body component having a top portion (22) necked in by sequentially applying a series of reducing diameter necking dies about an outer circumference along the longitudinal length of the top portion of the welded cylindrical body, such that:
<claim-text>the application of each necking die causes a diameter reduction to form an inwardly tapering shoulder portion (109) having step-wise corner transitions between each diameter reduction; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the application of a final necking die creates a constant diameter ending in a neck portion (110) extending from the inwardly tapering shoulder portion, where the neck portion has a reduced second diameter relative to the first diameter of the welded cylindrical body, wherein the second diameter is at most 50% of the first diameter;</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>the open top-end (115) of the neck portion having a curled lip (114) configured to receive a dispensing valve assembly (117) for dispensing a pressurized or aerosol product from the container.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>The container of claim 11 wherein the container when sealed with a dispensing valve assembly and pressurized at 256 psi (1765 kPa) withstands deformation at 100 °F (37.7 °C) for at least 10 minutes, or wherein the container when sealed with a dispensing valve assembly and pressurized to 311 psi (2150 kPa) withstands explosive failure at 100 °F (37.7 °C) for at least 5 minutes.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>The container of claim 11 wherein the welded container body component has a height in a range of 6.4 cm to 24.1 cm (2.5 inches to 9.5 inches) and a first diameter in a range of 4.3 to 8.26 cm (1.7 to 3.25 inches).<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>The container of claim 12 wherein the shoulder portion is of an inwardly concave, outwardly concave or flat sloped shape.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0015" num="0015">
<claim-text>The container of claim 11 wherein the second diameter is in a range of 40% to 50% of the first diameter, or wherein the second diameter is in a range of 20% to 40% of the first diameter.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims02" lang="de"><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> -->
<claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Verfahren zum Herstellen eines Metallbehälters (20), der angepasst ist, um eine Abgabeventilanordnung (117) zum Abgeben eines unter Druck stehenden oder Aerosol-Produkts aus dem Behälter aufzunehmen, wobei der Behälter aus zwei Metallstücken gebildet ist, aufweisend die Schritte:
<claim-text>Bereitstellen einer Metallkörperkomponente (10) und einer Metallbasiskomponente (104);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Walzen der Metallkörperkomponente in eine hauptsächlich röhrenförmige Form mit zwei benachbarten freien Längskanten (101, 103) und offenen oberen und unteren Enden;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Verschweißen der benachbarten freien Längskanten der röhrenförmigen Form, um eine Längsschweißnaht (102) zu bilden, wodurch ein geschweißter zylindrischer Körper (27) eines ersten Durchmessers mit offenen oberen und unteren Enden gebildet wird; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Bilden des Behälters durch:
<claim-text>Bilden und Abdichten der Metallbasiskomponente an das offene untere Ende des geschweißten zylindrischen Körpers, um einen geschlossenen Behälterboden zu bilden;</claim-text>
<claim-text>nach dem Bilden des geschlossenen Behälterbodens sequenzielles Anlegen einer Reihe von durchmesserreduzierenden Einschnürwerkzeugen um einen Außenumfang eines oberen Abschnitts (22) des geschweißten zylindrischen Körpers derart, dass:
<claim-text>die Anlegung jedes Einschnürwerkzeugs eine Durchmesserreduktion bewirkt, sodass ein sich nach innen verjüngender Schulterabschnitt (109) mit stufenweisen Eckübergängen zwischen jeder Durchmesserreduktion gebildet wird; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>die Anlegung eines letzten Einschnürwerkzeugs ein Ende konstanten Durchmessers in einem Halsabschnitt (110) erzeugt, der sich von dem sich nach innen verjüngenden Schulterabschnitt aus erstreckt, wobei der Halsabschnitt einen verringerten zweiten Durchmesser relativ zum ersten Durchmesser des geschweißten zylindrischen Körpers hat;</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>Bilden eines Kringels (114) am offenen oberen Ende (115) des Halsabschnitts,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei der Kringel ausgestaltet ist, um eine Abgabeventilanordnung (117) zum<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> Abgeben eines unter Druck stehenden oder Aerosol-Produkts aus dem Behälter aufzunehmen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei sich die Schweißnaht fortlaufend über den Schulterabschnitt, den Halsabschnitt und den Kringel erstreckt.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, bei welchem der Behälter, wenn er mit einer Abgabeventilanordnung abgedichtet und auf 256 psi (1765 kPa) unter Druck gesetzt ist, bei 100°F (37,7°C) für mindestens 10 Minuten einer Verformung widersteht, oder bei welchem der Behälter, wenn er mit einer Abgabeventilanordnung abgedichtet und auf 311 psi (2150 kPa) unter Druck gesetzt ist, bei 100°F (37,7°C) für mindestens 5 Minuten einem explosiven Defekt widersteht.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, bei welchem die Metallkörperkomponente eine Höhe in einem Bereich von 6,4 cm bis 24,1 cm (2,5 Zoll bis 9,5 Zoll) und einen ersten Durchmesser in einem Bereich von 4,3 bis 8,26 cm (1,7 bis 3,25 Zoll) hat.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, bei welchem die Metallkörperkomponente und die Metallbasiskomponente jeweils aus Stahlblech vorgestanzt sind.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, bei welchem der zweite Durchmesser höchstens 50% des ersten Durchmessers beträgt, wobei optional der zweite Durchmesser in einem Bereich von 40% bis 50% des ersten Durchmessers liegt oder der zweite Durchmesser in einem Bereich von 20% bis 40% des ersten Durchmessers liegt.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, bei welchem der Schweißschritt ein Aufbringen von Schweißpunkten an beabstandeten Positionen entlang einer oder mehrerer der freien Kanten aufweist, um die Schweißnaht zu bilden.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, bei welchem die Einschnürwerkzeuge eine Schulter mit einer nach innen konkaven, einer nach außen konkaven oder einer flach geneigten Form erzeugen.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, bei welchem die Reihe von Einschnürwerkzeugen den oberen Abschnitt des geschweißten zylindrischen Körpers strecken, um die Schulter- und Halsabschnitte zu bilden, wobei der verringerte zweite Durchmesser<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> des Halsabschnitts nicht größer als 50% des ersten Durchmessers ist, ohne einen Bruch oder Defekt der Schweißnaht zu verursachen.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, welches zusätzlich ein Schneiden von überschüssigem Material vom Halsabschnitt vor dem Bilden des Kringels aufweist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, bei welchem die Herstellungsschritte sequenziell durchgeführt werden.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>Zweiteiliger Metallbehälter (20), aufweisend:
<claim-text>eine zylindrische Körperkomponente (20), die aus einem einzigen durchgehenden Stück Blech gemacht ist, das in eine röhrenförmige Form gewalzt ist und geschweißt ist, um eine durchgehende Schweißnaht (102) in einer Richtung parallel zu einer Längsachse des Behälters zu bilden, wobei die geschweißte zylindrische Körperkomponente (26) eines ersten Durchmessers offene obere und untere Enden hat;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Metallbasiskomponente (104), die gebildet und abgedichtet ist, um das offene untere Ende der geschweißten zylindrischen Körperkomponente zu schließen, um einen geschlossenen Behälterboden zu bilden;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei die zylindrische Körperkomponente einen oberen Abschnitt (22) hat, der durch sequenzielles Anlegen einer Reihe von durchmesserreduzierenden Einschnürwerkzeugen um einen Außenumfang entlang der Längslänge des oberen Abschnitts des geschweißten zylindrischen Körpers derart eingeschnürt ist, dass:
<claim-text>die Anlegung jedes Einschnürwerkzeugs eine Durchmesserreduktion bewirkt, um einen sich nach innen verjüngenden Schulterabschnitt (109) mit stufenweisen Eckübergängen zwischen jeder Durchmesserreduktion zu bilden; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>die Anlegung eines letzten Einschnürwerkzeugs ein Ende konstanten Durchmessers in einem Halsabschnitt (110) erzeugt, der sich von dem sich nach innen verjüngenden Schulterabschnitt aus erstreckt, wobei der Halsabschnitt einen verringerten zweiten Durchmesser relativ zum ersten Durchmesser des geschweißten zylindrischen Körpers hat, wobei der zweite Durchmesser höchstens 50% des ersten Durchmessers beträgt;</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei das offene obere Ende (115) des Halsabschnitts einen gekringelten Rand (114) hat, der ausgestaltet ist, um eine Abgabeventilanordnung (117) zum Abgeben eines unter Druck stehenden oder Aerosol-Produkts aus dem Behälter aufzunehmen.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>Behälter nach Anspruch 11, wobei der Behälter, wenn er mit einer Abgabeventilanordnung abgedichtet und auf 256 psi (1765 kPa) unter Druck gesetzt ist, bei 100°F (37,7°C) für mindestens 10 Minuten einer Verformung widersteht, oder der Behälter, wenn er mit einer Abgabeventilanordnung abgedichtet und auf 311 psi (2150 kPa) unter Druck gesetzt ist, bei 100°F (37,7°C) für mindestens 5 Minuten einem explosiven Defekt widersteht.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>Behälter nach Anspruch 11, bei welchem die geschweißte Behälterkörperkomponente eine Höhe in einem Bereich von 6,4 cm bis 24,1 cm (2,5 Zoll bis 9,5 Zoll) und einen ersten Durchmesser in einem Bereich von 4,3 bis 8,26 cm (1,7 bis 3,25 Zoll) hat.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>Behälter nach Anspruch 12, bei welchem der Schulterabschnitt einer nach innen konkave, nach außen konkave oder flach geneigte Form hat.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0015" num="0015">
<claim-text>Behälter nach Anspruch 11, bei welchem der zweite Durchmesser in einem Bereich von 40% bis 50% des ersten Durchmessers liegt oder bei welchem der zweite Durchmesser in einem Bereich von 20% bis 40% des ersten Durchmessers liegt.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims03" lang="fr"><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> -->
<claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Un procédé permettant de fabriquer un récipient métallique (20) adapté pour recevoir un ensemble soupape de distribution (117) afin de distribuer un produit sous pression ou en aérosol depuis le récipient, dans lequel ledit récipient est formé à partir de deux parties de métal, incluant les étapes consistant à :
<claim-text>fournir un composant de corps métallique (10) et un composant de base métallique (104) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>laminer le composant de corps métallique en une forme généralement tubulaire ayant deux bords libres proximaux longitudinaux (101, 103) et des extrémités inférieure et supérieure ouvertes ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>souder les bords libres proximaux longitudinaux de la forme tubulaire pour former un cordon de soudure longitudinal (102), ce qui forme ainsi un corps cylindrique soudé (26) d'un premier diamètre ayant des extrémités inférieure et supérieure ouvertes ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>former le récipient ce qui consiste à :
<claim-text>former et sceller le composant de base métallique à l'extrémité inférieure ouverte du corps cylindrique soudé pour former une partie inférieure de récipient fermée ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>après la formation de la partie inférieure de récipient fermée, appliquer séquentiellement une série de matrices de striction réduisant le diamètre autour d'une circonférence extérieure d'une partie supérieure (22) du corps cylindrique soudé de telle sorte que :
<claim-text>l'application de chaque matrice de striction provoque une réduction de diamètre de telle sorte qu'une partie épaulement se rétrécissant vers l'intérieur (109) ayant des transitions d'angle par étapes entre chaque réduction de diamètre est formée ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'application d'une matrice de striction finale crée un diamètre constant se terminant dans une partie col (110) s'étendant de la partie épaulement se rétrécissant vers l'intérieur, où la partie col a un deuxième diamètre réduit par rapport au premier diamètre du corps cylindrique soudé ;</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>former un enroulement (114) à l'extrémité supérieure ouverte (115) de la partie col, l'enroulement étant configuré pour recevoir un ensemble soupape de distribution (117) afin de distribuer un produit sous pression ou en aérosol depuis le récipient ;<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel le cordon de soudure s'étend en continu sur toute la partie épaulement, la partie col et l'enroulement.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Le procédé selon la revendication 1, dans lequel le récipient, quand il est scellé par un ensemble soupape de distribution et pressurisé à 256 psi (1765 kPa), résiste à la déformation à 100°F (37,7°C) pendant au moins 10 minutes ou dans lequel le récipient, quand il est scellé par un ensemble soupape de distribution et pressurisé à 311 psi (2150 kPa), résiste à une explosion catastrophique à 100°F (37,7°C) pendant au moins 5 minutes.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Le procédé selon la revendication 1, dans lequel le composant de corps métallique a une hauteur dans une plage de 6,4 cm à 24,1 cm (2,5 pouces à 9,5 pouces) et un premier diamètre dans une plage de 4,3 cm à 8,26 cm (1,7 pouce à 3,25 pouces).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Le procédé selon la revendication 1, dans lequel le composant de corps métallique et le composant de base métallique sont chacun prédécoupés dans une tôle d'acier.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Le procédé selon la revendication 1, dans lequel le deuxième diamètre fait au plus 50 % du premier diamètre, en option dans lequel le deuxième diamètre est dans une plage de 40 % à 50 % du premier diamètre ou dans lequel le deuxième diamètre est dans une plage de 20 % à 40 % du premier diamètre.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Le procédé selon la revendication 1, dans lequel l'étape de soudage consiste à appliquer des points de soudure à des positions espacées le long d'un ou plusieurs des bords libres pour former le cordon de soudure.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Le procédé selon la revendication 1, dans lequel les matrices de striction produisent un épaulement ayant une forme concave vers l'intérieur, concave vers l'extérieur ou plate inclinée.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>Le procédé selon la revendication 1, dans lequel la série de matrices de striction étirent la partie supérieure du corps cylindrique soudé pour former les parties épaulement et col où le deuxième diamètre réduit de la partie col n'est pas supérieur à 50 % du premier diamètre sans provoquer la fracture ou la défaillance<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --> du cordon de soudure.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>Le procédé selon la revendication 1 consistant en outre à rogner le matériau excédentaire de la partie col avant de former l'enroulement.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>Le procédé selon la revendication 1, dans lequel les étapes de fabrication sont effectuées séquentiellement.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>Un récipient métallique en deux parties (20) comprenant :
<claim-text>un composant de corps cylindrique (10) fabriqué à partir d'une seule tôle continue laminée en une forme tubulaire et soudée pour former un cordon de soudure continu (102) dans une direction parallèle à un axe longitudinal du récipient, le composant de corps cylindrique soudé (26) étant d'un premier diamètre qui a des extrémités inférieure et supérieure ouvertes ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un composant de base métallique (104) formé et scellé pour fermer l'extrémité inférieure ouverte du composant de corps cylindrique soudé pour former une partie supérieure de récipient fermée ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>le composant de corps cylindrique ayant une partie supérieure (22) rétrécie en appliquant séquentiellement une série de matrices de striction réduisant le diamètre autour d'une circonférence extérieure le long de la longueur longitudinale de la partie supérieure du corps cylindrique soudé, de telle sorte que :
<claim-text>l'application de chaque matrice de striction provoque une réduction de diamètre pour former une partie épaulement se rétrécissant vers l'intérieur (109) ayant des transitions d'angle par étapes entre chaque réduction de diamètre ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'application d'une matrice de striction finale crée un diamètre constant se terminant dans une partie col (110) s'étendant de la partie épaulement se rétrécissant vers l'intérieur, où la partie col a un deuxième diamètre réduit par rapport au premier diamètre du corps cylindrique soudé, dans lequel le deuxième diamètre fait au plus 50 % du premier diamètre ;</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>l'extrémité supérieure ouverte (115) de la partie col ayant une lèvre enroulée (114) configurée pour recevoir un ensemble soupape de distribution (117) afin de distribuer un produit sous pression ou en aérosol depuis le récipient.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>Le récipient selon la revendication 11, dans lequel le récipient, quand il est<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --> scellé par un ensemble soupape de distribution et pressurisé à 256 psi (1765 kPa), résiste à la déformation à 100°F (37,7°C) pendant au moins 10 minutes ou dans lequel le récipient, quand il est scellé par un ensemble soupape de distribution et pressurisé à 311 psi (2150 kPa), résiste à une explosion catastrophique à 100°F (37,7°C) pendant au moins 5 minutes.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>Le récipient selon la revendication 11, dans lequel le composant de corps de récipient soudé a une hauteur dans une plage de 6,4 cm à 24,1 cm (2,5 pouces à 9,5 pouces) et un premier diamètre dans une plage de 4,3 cm à 8,26 cm (1,7 pouce à 3,25 pouces).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>Le récipient selon la revendication 12, dans lequel la partie épaulement est d'une forme concave vers l'intérieur, concave vers l'extérieur ou plate inclinée.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0015" num="0015">
<claim-text>Le récipient selon la revendication 11, dans lequel le deuxième diamètre est dans une plage de 40 % à 50 % du premier diamètre ou dans lequel le deuxième diamètre est dans une plage de 20 % à 40 % du premier diamètre.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="29"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="123" he="209" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="30"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="2A,2B"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="137" he="224" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> -->
<figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="115" he="196" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> -->
<figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="114" he="210" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="33"> -->
<figure id="f0005" num="5A,5B"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="148" he="202" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="34"> -->
<figure id="f0006" num="5C"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="165" he="158" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="35"> -->
<figure id="f0007" num="6"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="111" he="204" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="36"> -->
<figure id="f0008" num="6A"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="146" he="155" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="37"> -->
<figure id="f0009" num="7"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="111" he="187" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="38"> -->
<figure id="f0010" num="8A,8B"><img id="if0010" file="imgf0010.tif" wi="133" he="203" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="39"> -->
<figure id="f0011" num="9"><img id="if0011" file="imgf0011.tif" wi="129" he="208" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="40"> -->
<figure id="f0012" num="10"><img id="if0012" file="imgf0012.tif" wi="119" he="181" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="41"> -->
<figure id="f0013" num="11"><img id="if0013" file="imgf0013.tif" wi="96" he="155" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<ep-reference-list id="ref-list">
<heading id="ref-h0001"><b>REFERENCES CITED IN THE DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0001" num=""><i>This list of references cited by the applicant is for the reader's convenience only. It does not form part of the European patent document. Even though great care has been taken in compiling the references, errors or omissions cannot be excluded and the EPO disclaims all liability in this regard.</i></p>
<heading id="ref-h0002"><b>Patent documents cited in the description</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0002" num="">
<ul id="ref-ul0001" list-style="bullet">
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0001" dnum="US4753364A"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>4753364</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0001">[0006]</crossref><crossref idref="pcit0002">[0007]</crossref><crossref idref="pcit0003">[0008]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0002" dnum="US4854149A"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>4854149</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0004">[0009]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0003" dnum="US4173883A"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>4173883</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0005">[0010]</crossref></li>
</ul></p>
</ep-reference-list>
</ep-patent-document>
