<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP21161473A1" file="EP21161473NWA1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3889408" kind="A1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSKBAHRIS..MTNORSMESMMAKHTNMD..........</B001EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  1100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3889408</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT APPLICATION</B121></B120><B130>A1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>21161473.0</B210><B220><date>20210309</date></B220><B250>en</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B300><B310>202063002070 P</B310><B320><date>20200330</date></B320><B330><ctry>US</ctry></B330></B300><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B430></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>F02C   7/228       20060101AFI20210802BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="2"><text>F02C   9/34        20060101ALI20210802BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>F02C   9/34        20130101 LI20210714BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>F02C   7/228       20130101 FI20210713BHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>GEREGELTE STRÖMUNGSTEILERVENTILE MIT SEKUNDÄREN AUSGLEICHSVENTILEN</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>REGULATED FLOW DIVIDER VALVES WITH SECONDARY EQUALIZATION VALVES</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>SOUPAPES DISTRIBUTRICES RÉGULÉES AVEC SOUPAPES D'ÉGALISATION SECONDAIRES</B542></B540><B590><B598>1</B598></B590></B500><B700><B710><B711><snm>Hamilton Sundstrand Corporation</snm><iid>101526361</iid><irf>75.153978</irf><adr><str>Four Coliseum Centre 
2730 West Tyvola Road</str><city>Charlotte, NC 28217-4578</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B711></B710><B720><B721><snm>RUTAR, Matej</snm><adr><str>95 Briarwood Drive</str><city>Manchester, CT Connecticut 06050</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>MAROCCHINI, Francis P.</snm><adr><str>104 Pond Circle</str><city>Somers, CT Connecticut 06071</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B740><B741><snm>Dehns</snm><iid>101728904</iid><adr><str>St. Bride's House 
10 Salisbury Square</str><city>London EC4Y 8JD</city><ctry>GB</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840><B844EP><B845EP><ctry>BA</ctry></B845EP><B845EP><ctry>ME</ctry></B845EP></B844EP><B848EP><B849EP><ctry>KH</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>MA</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>MD</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>TN</ctry></B849EP></B848EP></B800></SDOBI>
<abstract id="abst" lang="en">
<p id="pa01" num="0001">A system (100) includes a flow inlet conduit (102). A primary conduit (104) branches from the flow inlet conduit (102) for delivering flow to a set of primary nozzles. An equalization bypass valve (EBV) (106) connects between the flow inlet conduit (102) and a secondary conduit (!08) for delivering flow to a set of secondary nozzles. The EBV (106) is connected to be controlled to apportion flow from the flow inlet conduit (102) to the secondary conduit (108). A secondary equalization valve (SEV) (114) connects between the flow inlet conduit (102) and the secondary conduit (108). The SEV (114) is connected to be controlled by drain pressure (PD) to apportion flow from the flow inlet conduit (102) to the secondary conduit (108).
<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="155" he="95" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p>
</abstract>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<heading id="h0001"><b><u>BACKGROUND</u></b></heading>
<heading id="h0002"><b>1. <u>Field</u></b></heading>
<p id="p0001" num="0001">The present disclosure relates to flow regulating systems, and more particularly to flow divider valves such as for use in aerospace fuel systems.</p>
<heading id="h0003"><b>2. <u>Description of Related Art</u></b></heading>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">Gas turbine burners can have at least two sets of fuel injection nozzles, e.g., primary nozzles and secondary nozzles. Valves are used to control the flow split between the primary and secondary nozzles. There are transitions from one flow split to another that need to be rate controlled to prevent disturbances, especially at low flow conditions. The better the time response when switching from one flow split to another without disturbances, the better the system can perform.</p>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">The conventional techniques have been considered satisfactory for their intended purpose. However, there is an ever present need for improved systems and methods for regulated flow divider valves. This disclosure provides a solution for this need.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p>
<heading id="h0004"><b><u>SUMMARY</u></b></heading>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">A system includes a flow inlet conduit. A primary conduit branches from the flow inlet conduit for delivering flow to a set of primary nozzles. An equalization bypass valve (EBV) connects between the flow inlet conduit and a secondary conduit for delivering flow to a set of secondary nozzles. The EBV is connected to be controlled to apportion flow from the flow inlet conduit to the secondary conduit. A secondary equalization valve (SEV) connects between the flow inlet conduit and the secondary conduit. The SEV is connected to be controlled by drain pressure (PD) to apportion flow from the flow inlet conduit to the secondary conduit.</p>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">The SEV can include a piston that divides between inlet pressure from fuel flow meter (PFDV) and PD to apportion flow from the flow inlet conduit to the secondary conduit based on pressure differential between PFDV and PD. The EBV can include a piston that divides between an equalization conduit and the flow inlet conduit to apportion flow from the flow inlet conduit to the secondary conduit based on pressure in the equalization conduit. The equalization conduit can be connected to a pressure equalization solenoid (PES) configured to equalize pressure between PFA and PD.</p>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">An un-equalized enrichment valve (UEV) can connect between the flow inlet conduit and the secondary conduit. The UEV can be configured to pressurize the primary conduit higher than the secondary conduit in the un-equalized mode. The SEV can be configured to passively open as pressure rises in the equalized or unequalized mode.</p>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">A method includes opening an alternate flow path to a flow path through the EBV in a system as described above, wherein the alternate flow path passes through the SEV. Opening the alternate flow path can include providing an equalization back up in case of failure of a pressure<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> equalization solenoid (PES) configured to equalize pressure between PFA and PD, and/or providing an equalization back-up in case of failure of the EBV.</p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">At a low acceleration pressure rise in the flow inlet conduit, the alternate flow path need not open. At a high acceleration pressure rise (wherein high acceleration is relative to the low acceleration pressure rise), the alternate flow path can open. The method can include preventing system over pressurization during the high-pressure acceleration pressure rise when the EBV is too slow. The SEV can open after the system switches from an un-equalized mode to an equalized mode, wherein in the equalized mode the primary and secondary conduits are at equal pressure, and in the un-equalized mode the primary and secondary conduits are at unequal pressure.</p>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">These and other features of the systems and methods of the subject disclosure will become more readily apparent to those skilled in the art from the following detailed description of the preferred embodiments taken in conjunction with the drawings.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p>
<heading id="h0005"><b><u>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</u></b></heading>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">So that those skilled in the art to which the subject disclosure appertains will readily understand how to make and use the devices and methods of the subject disclosure without undue experimentation, preferred embodiments thereof will be described in detail herein below with reference to the figure, wherein:<br/>
<figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is a schematic view of an embodiment of a system constructed in accordance with the present disclosure, showing the inlet flow conduit, primary conduit, secondary conduit, and the valves.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p>
<heading id="h0006"><b><u>DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</u></b></heading>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">Reference will now be made to the drawings wherein like reference numerals identify similar structural features or aspects of the subject disclosure. For purposes of explanation and illustration, and not limitation, a partial view of an embodiment of a system in accordance with the disclosure is shown in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> and is designated generally by reference character 100. The systems and methods described herein can be used to provide an alternate path for equalization between primary and secondary conduits, e.g. supplying fuel respectively to primary and secondary nozzles in an aerospace combustion system. This can provide back up in case of failure of the switching solenoid or the main equalization valve. Total pressure drop at equalization can be reduced due to the additional valve relative to traditional systems. During fast accelerations in flow, the secondary equalization valve (SEV) opens to prevent system over pressurization, as the main equalization valve may be rate limited to be too slow to handle the fast acceleration without disturbances e.g. at downstream nozzles, especially at low flow conditions.</p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">The system 100 includes a flow inlet conduit 102. A primary conduit 104 branches from the flow inlet conduit 102 for delivering flow to a set of primary nozzles. An equalization bypass valve (EBV) 106 connects between the flow inlet conduit 102 and a secondary conduit 108 for delivering flow to a set of secondary nozzles. The EBV 106 is connected to be controlled by IFPC servo pump supply pressure fine filtered (PFA) pressure (indicated at inlet 110 from integrated fuel pump controls (IFPC) in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>) to apportion flow from the flow inlet conduit 102 to the secondary conduit 108. A secondary equalization valve (SEV) 114 connects between the flow inlet conduit 102 and the secondary conduit 108. The SEV is connected to be controlled by drain pressure (PD, indicated at inlet 112 from IFPC in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, also referred to as<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> IFPC gear pump inlet pressure) to apportion flow from the flow inlet conduit 102 to the secondary conduit 108.</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">The SEV 114 includes a piston 116 that divides between inlet pressure from fuel flow meter (PFDV) in the flow inlet conduit 102 and PD from inlet 112 to apportion flow from the flow inlet conduit 102 to the secondary conduit 108 based on pressure differential between PFDV and PD. As the difference between PFDV and PD increases, the piston 116 moves more to the right oriented in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, to reduce the occlusion of the SEV outlet 118 by the piston 116.</p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">The EBV 106 is a two position valve. When closed (with the EBV piston 120 on the left as oriented in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>), all PFDV flow from the inlet conduit 102 to secondary conduit 108 (at secondary pressure Psec) has to flow through the unequalized enrichment valve (UEV) 134, which regulates PFDV to a higher pressure then Psec (e.g., a 100 psid difference). When EBV 106 is open (with the piston 120 of the EBV 120 on the right as oriented in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>), the EBV 106 opens a large flow path between PFDV of the inlet conduit 102 and Psec of the secondary conduit 108. The pressure difference from Psec to PFDV is reduced (equalized) to 0 psid, or nearly 0 psid. The UEV 134 ends up closing when the EBV 106 is open because UEV 134 cannot set its regulation pressure because the flow area through the EBV 106 is big enough.</p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">In positioning the EBV 106, PFA and PFDV pressure always act to open the valve (push the piston 120 to the right as oriented in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> to unocclude the outlet 124 of the EBV 106). Then the pressure on the backside of the EBV 106 (the pressure in the equalization conduit 122) is switched between PFA and PD based on the positioning of the Pressure Equalization Solenoid (PES) 126. When the pressure in the conduit 122 is at PFA, the piston 120 of the EBV 106 moves to the left as oriented in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> (to the closed position). When the pressure in the conduit<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> 122 is at PD, the piston 120 of the EBV 106 moves to the right as oriented in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> (to the open position). This valve actuation is a result of the inequality: PFA &gt; PFDV &gt; PD.</p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">The UEV 134 can connect between the flow inlet conduit 102 and the secondary conduit 108. The UEV 134 can be configured to pressurize the primary conduit 104 higher than the secondary conduit 108 in the un-equalized mode, e.g. for starting and burner tonal control. The SEV 114 is configured to passively open as pressure rises in the flow inlet conduit 102 in the equalized mode. The SEV 114 can also open unequalized, but its opening is triggered between PFDV and PD, with PD pressure staying relatively low.</p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">A method includes opening an alternate flow path to a flow path through the EBV 106 in a system 100 as described above, wherein the alternate flow path passes through the SEV 114. Opening the alternate flow path can include providing an equalization back up in case of failure of a PES 126 configured to switch pressure on the right side (as oriented in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>) of the piston 120 the EBV 122 between PFA and PD, which causes the EBV to open or close. It is also contemplated that this can provide an equalization back up in case of failure of the EBV 106.</p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">At a low acceleration pressure rise in the flow inlet conduit 102, the alternate flow path need not open. At a high acceleration pressure rise (wherein high acceleration is relative to the low acceleration pressure rise), the alternate flow path can open. The method can include preventing system over pressurization during the high-pressure acceleration pressure rise when the EBV 106 is too slow. The SEV 114 can open after the system switches from the un-equalized mode to the equalized mode.</p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">The methods and systems of the present disclosure, as described above and shown in the drawings, can provide an alternate path for equalization between primary and secondary conduits, e.g. supplying fuel respectively to primary and secondary nozzles in an aerospace combustion<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> system. This can provide back up in case of failure of the switching solenoid or the main equalization valve. Total pressure drop at equalization can be reduced due to the additional valve relative to traditional systems. During fast accelerations in flow, the secondary equalization valve (SEV) opens to prevent system over pressurization, as the main equalization valve may be rate limited to be too slow. While the apparatus and methods of the subject disclosure have been shown and described with reference to preferred embodiments, those skilled in the art will readily appreciate that changes and/or modifications may be made thereto without departing from the scope of the subject disclosure.</p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="9"> -->
<claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>A system (100) comprising:
<claim-text>a flow inlet conduit (102);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a primary conduit (104) branching from the flow inlet conduit for delivering flow to a set of primary nozzles;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an equalization bypass valve (106), EBV, that connects between the flow inlet conduit and a secondary conduit (108) for delivering flow to a set of secondary nozzles, wherein the EBV is connected to be controlled to apportion flow from the flow inlet conduit (102) to the secondary conduit (108); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a secondary equalization valve (114), SEV. that connects between the flow inlet conduit (102) and the secondary conduit (108), wherein the SEV is connected to be controlled by drain pressure, PD, to apportion flow from the flow inlet conduit to the secondary conduit.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>The system as recited in claim 1, wherein the SEV includes a piston (116) that divides the SEV between inlet pressure from fuel flow meter, PFDV, and PD to apportion flow from the flow inlet conduit to the secondary conduit based on a pressure differential between PFDV and PD.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>The system as recited in claim 2, wherein the EBV includes a piston (120) that divides between an equalization conduit (122) and the flow inlet conduit to apportion flow from the flow inlet conduit to the secondary conduit based on a pressure in the equalization conduit.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>The system as recited in claim 3, wherein the equalization conduit (122) is connected to a pressure equalization solenoid (126), PES, configured to equalize pressure between the PFA and the PD.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>The system as recited in claim 4, further comprising an un-equalized enrichment valve (134), UEV, that connects between the flow inlet conduit and the secondary conduit.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>The system as recited in claim 5, wherein the UEV (134) is configured to pressurize the primary conduit higher than the secondary conduit in the un-equalized mode.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>The system as recited in claim 5, wherein the SEV (114) is configured to passively open as pressure rises in the equalized or unequalized mode.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>A method comprising:<br/>
in a system as recited in claim 1, opening an alternate flow path to a flow path through the EBV, wherein the alternate flow path passes through the SEV.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>The method as recited in claim 8, wherein opening the alternate flow path includes providing an equalization back up in case of failure of a pressure equalization solenoid, PES, configured to equalize pressure between integrated fuel pump controls, IFPC, servo pump supply pressure fine filtered, PFA, and drain pressure, PD.<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>The method as recited in claim 8, wherein opening the alternate flow path includes providing an equalization back up in case of failure of the EBV.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>The method as recited in claim 8, wherein at a low acceleration pressure rise in the flow inlet conduit, the alternate flow path does not open.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>The method as recited in claim 11, wherein at a high acceleration pressure rise, wherein high acceleration is relative to the low acceleration pressure rise, the alternate flow path does open.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>The method as recited in claim 11, further comprising preventing system over pressurization during the high-pressure acceleration pressure rise when the EBV is too slow.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>The method as recited in claim 8, wherein the SEV opens after the system switches from an un-equalized mode to an equalized mode, wherein in the equalized mode the primary and secondary conduits are at equal pressure, and in the un-equalized mode the primary and secondary conduits are at unequal pressure.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="12"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="143" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<search-report-data id="srep" lang="en" srep-office="EP" date-produced=""><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="157" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="155" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data><search-report-data date-produced="20210723" id="srepxml" lang="en" srep-office="EP" srep-type="ep-sr" status="n"><!--
 The search report data in XML is provided for the users' convenience only. It might differ from the search report of the PDF document, which contains the officially published data. The EPO disclaims any liability for incorrect or incomplete data in the XML for search reports.
 -->

<srep-info><file-reference-id>75.153978</file-reference-id><application-reference><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>21161473.0</doc-number></document-id></application-reference><applicant-name><name>Hamilton Sundstrand Corporation</name></applicant-name><srep-established srep-established="yes"/><srep-invention-title title-approval="yes"/><srep-abstract abs-approval="yes"/><srep-figure-to-publish figinfo="by-applicant"><figure-to-publish><fig-number>1</fig-number></figure-to-publish></srep-figure-to-publish><srep-info-admin><srep-office><addressbook><text>DH</text></addressbook></srep-office><date-search-report-mailed><date>20210806</date></date-search-report-mailed></srep-info-admin></srep-info><srep-for-pub><srep-fields-searched><minimum-documentation><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr><text>F02C</text></classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr></minimum-documentation></srep-fields-searched><srep-citations><citation id="sr-cit0001"><patcit dnum="US2010050593A1" id="sr-pcit0001" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=US2010050593&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2010050593</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>FUTA PAUL [US] ET AL</name><date>20100304</date></document-id></patcit><category>X</category><rel-claims>1-14</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* paragraphs [0024] - [0034] *</passage><passage>* figures 1-6 *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0002"><patcit dnum="US2007245744A1" id="sr-pcit0002" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=US2007245744&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2007245744</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>DOOLEY KEVIN A [CA]</name><date>20071025</date></document-id></patcit><category>A</category><rel-claims>1-14</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* paragraphs [0020] - [0028] *</passage><passage>* figure 2 *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0003"><patcit dnum="EP2535644A2" id="sr-pcit0003" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=EP2535644&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2535644</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><name>HONEYWELL INT INC [US]</name><date>20121219</date></document-id></patcit><category>A</category><rel-claims>1-14</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* paragraphs [0027] - [0037] *</passage><passage>* figures 2-4 *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0004"><patcit dnum="US5339636A" id="sr-pcit0004" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=US5339636&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>5339636</doc-number><kind>A</kind><name>DONNELLY BRIAN G [US] ET AL</name><date>19940823</date></document-id></patcit><category>A</category><rel-claims>1-14</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* column 4, line 25 - column 5, line 26 *</passage><passage>* figures 1-3 *</passage></rel-passage></citation></srep-citations><srep-admin><examiners><primary-examiner><name>Gebker, Ulrich</name></primary-examiner></examiners><srep-office><addressbook><text>The Hague</text></addressbook></srep-office><date-search-completed><date>20210723</date></date-search-completed></srep-admin><!--							The annex lists the patent family members relating to the patent documents cited in the above mentioned European search report.							The members are as contained in the European Patent Office EDP file on							The European Patent Office is in no way liable for these particulars which are merely given for the purpose of information.							For more details about this annex : see Official Journal of the European Patent Office, No 12/82						--><srep-patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2010050593</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20100304</date></document-id></priority-application><text>NONE</text></patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2007245744</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20071025</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>CA</country><doc-number>2643392</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20071101</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>CA</country><doc-number>2847641</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20071101</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>1849975</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20071031</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2007245744</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20071025</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2010199681</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20100812</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2014245739</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140904</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2014245745</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140904</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2007121553</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20071101</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2535644</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20121219</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>CN</country><doc-number>102829488</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20121219</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2535644</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20121219</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2012312378</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20121213</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>5339636</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>19940823</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>DE</country><doc-number>69302585</doc-number><kind>T2</kind><date>19960912</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>0672220</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>19950920</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>3143924</doc-number><kind>B2</kind><date>20010307</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>H08504247</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>19960507</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>5339636</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>19940823</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>9413945</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>19940623</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family></srep-patent-family></srep-for-pub></search-report-data>
</ep-patent-document>
