<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP18808097B1" file="EP18808097NWB1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3661744" kind="B1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSK..HRIS..MTNORS..SM..................</B001EP><B003EP>*</B003EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  2100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3661744</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT SPECIFICATION</B121></B120><B130>B1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>18808097.2</B210><B220><date>20181120</date></B220><B240><B241><date>20200306</date></B241><B242><date>20200731</date></B242></B240><B250>en</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B300><B310>201719408</B310><B320><date>20171122</date></B320><B330><ctry>GB</ctry></B330></B300><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20200610</date><bnum>202024</bnum></B430><B450><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B450><B452EP><date>20210422</date></B452EP></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>B32B  19/06        20060101AFI20190531BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>B32B  19/06        20130101 FI20190220BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>B32B2260/046       20130101 LA20190220BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="3"><text>B32B   5/26        20130101 LI20190220BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="4"><text>B32B2457/00        20130101 LA20190220BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="5"><text>B32B   5/028       20130101 LI20190220BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="6"><text>B32B2307/7246      20130101 LA20190220BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="7"><text>B32B  29/02        20130101 LI20190220BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="8"><text>B32B2255/26        20130101 LA20190220BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="9"><text>F16L  59/029       20130101 LI20201029BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="10"><text>B32B   5/02        20130101 LI20190220BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="11"><text>Y02E  60/10        20130101 LA20201215BGEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="12"><text>B32B  27/32        20130101 LI20190220BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="13"><text>B32B2262/10        20130101 LA20190220BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="14"><text>B32B2260/021       20130101 LA20190220BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="15"><text>B32B2307/3065      20130101 LA20190220BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="16"><text>B32B2264/104       20130101 LA20190220BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="17"><text>B32B  15/20        20130101 LI20190220BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="18"><text>B32B2262/101       20130101 LA20190220BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="19"><text>B32B   3/04        20130101 LI20190220BHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>BRANDSCHUTZMATERIALIEN</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>MATERIALS FOR FIRE PROTECTION</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>MATÉRIAUX POUR LA PROTECTION CONTRE LES INCENDIES</B542></B540><B560><B561><text>GB-A- 2 234 938</text></B561><B561><text>US-A- 4 505 977</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2012 321 868</text></B561></B560></B500><B700><B720><B721><snm>JEONG, Seob Kyo</snm><adr><str>394 Dunchon-daero
Jungwon-gu</str><city>Seongnam-si
Gyeonggi-do</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>SHIN, Jeong Mo</snm><adr><str>27 46gil
Nongongjungan Road
Nongong-eup</str><city>Dalsseong-gun
Daegu</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>LEE, Jun Sik</snm><adr><str>27 46gil
Nongongjungan Road
Nongong-eup</str><city>Dalsseong-gun
Daegu</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>MURRAY, Dean</snm><adr><str>c/o Thermal Ceramics UK Limited
Tebay Road
Bromborough</str><city>Wirral
Merseyside CH62 3PH</city><ctry>GB</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B730><B731><snm>Morgan Korea Co., Ltd</snm><iid>101848096</iid><irf>P100673EP</irf><adr><str>27, Nongongjungang-ro 46-gil 
Nongong-eup</str><city>Dalseong-gun, Daegu</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B731></B730><B740><B741><snm>Phillips &amp; Leigh LLP</snm><iid>101168945</iid><adr><str>Temple Chambers 
3-7 Temple Avenue</str><city>London EC4Y 0DA</city><ctry>GB</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840><B860><B861><dnum><anum>GB2018053351</anum></dnum><date>20181120</date></B861><B862>en</B862></B860><B870><B871><dnum><pnum>WO2019102185</pnum></dnum><date>20190531</date><bnum>201922</bnum></B871></B870></B800></SDOBI>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<p id="p0001" num="0001">This invention relates to materials for fire protection. The materials of the present invention are particularly useful for providing passive fire protection to prevent thermal runaway in electrical storage devices, for example in electric vehicle power assemblies, however the present invention is not limited to use in such assemblies.</p>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">Electrical storage devices may, for example, comprise a plurality of cells or batteries (e.g. lithium ion cells). Lithium ion cells may fail in operation, and this can result in an uncontrolled release of stored energy from a failing cell that can create localized areas of very high temperatures. For example, various types of cells have been shown to produce temperatures in the region of 600-900°C in so-called "thermal runaway" conditions.</p>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">Such high temperatures may ignite adjacent combustibles, thereby creating a fire hazard. Elevated temperature may also cause some materials to begin to decompose and generate gas. Gases generated during such events can be toxic and/or flammable, further increasing the hazards associated with thermal runaway events.</p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">Lithium ion cells may use organic electrolytes that have high volatility and flammability. Such electrolytes tend to start breaking down at temperatures starting in the region 150°C to 200°C and in any event have a significant vapour pressure even before break down starts. Once breakdown commences the gas mixtures produced (typically a mixture of CO<sub>2</sub>, CH<sub>4</sub>, C<sub>2</sub>H<sub>4</sub>, C<sub>2</sub>H<sub>5</sub>F and others) can ignite. The generation of such gases on breakdown of the electrolyte leads to an increase in pressure and the gases are generally vented to atmosphere; however this venting process is hazardous as the dilution of the gases with air can lead to formation of an explosive fuel-air mixture that if ignited can flame back into the cell in question igniting the whole arrangement.</p>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">The issue of thermal runaway becomes compounded in devices comprising a plurality of cells, since cells adjacent to a failing cell may absorb enough energy from the failing cell to rise above their designed operating temperatures, and so be triggered to enter into thermal runaway. This can result in a chain reaction in which cells enter into a cascading series of thermal runaways, as one cell ignites adjacent cells.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">Insulation materials comprising ceramic fibre papers laminated between mica paper sheets are known.<br/>
<patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US2012321868A1"><text>US2012/321868 A1</text></patcit> discloses thermal and acoustic insulation comprising a core of fibrous material encapsulated by two composites each comprising a thermoplastic film layer, an inorganic platelet layer, and a moisture barrier exterior to the inorganic platelet layers. The thermoplastic layers are laminated together at their edges to encapsulate the core of fibrous material.<br/>
<patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="GB2234938A"><text>GB2234938</text></patcit> discloses an intumescent fire barrier which comprises a layer of wire mesh sandwiched between sheets of ceramic fibre material each coated on at least one face with vermiculite, one or both sides of each sheet being coated with an intumescent paint, the assembly of the wire mesh and coated fibre sheets being enveloped in one or more sheets of material having an external metallic foil surface.<br/>
<patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="US4505977A"><text>US4505977</text></patcit> discloses thermal insulation comprising a double-walled housing with an evacuated space between the two housing walls in which at least one mica paper layer is arranged perpendicularly to the temperature gradient between the two housing walls.</p>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">However specific requirements for providing fire protection for electric vehicle power assemblies may include one or more of the following:-
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="bullet" compact="compact">
<li>a low electrical conductivity to prevent shorting (e.g. preferably less than 1.0 × 10<sup>-13</sup> S/cm and more preferably less than 1.0 × 10<sup>-14</sup> S/cm).</li>
<li>resistance to humidity</li>
<li>appropriate compression characteristics to meet the specific design of electric vehicle power assembly</li>
<li>freedom from silicones to permit end of life recycling.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">In a first aspect of the present invention, an electrical storage device is provided comprising a plurality of cells or batteries of which at least some are separated by a composite material comprising:-
<ol id="ol0001" ol-style="">
<li>a) an inorganic fibre core comprising inorganic fibres interlocked or entangled to form a coherent body resistant against separation laminated between<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></li>
<li>b) at least two layers of phyllosilicate insulation characterised in that the material further comprises</li>
<li>c) a barrier integral to the material to hinder ingress of humidity to, and sealing edges of, the inorganic fibre core.</li>
</ol></p>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">In a second aspect, the present invention provides the use for providing passive fire protection to prevent thermal runaway in electrical storage devices of a composite material comprising:-
<ol id="ol0002" compact="compact" ol-style="">
<li>a) an inorganic fibre core comprising inorganic fibres interlocked or entangled to form a coherent body resistant against separation laminated between</li>
<li>b) at least two layers of phyllosilicate insulation characterised in that the material further comprises</li>
<li>c) a barrier integral to the material to hinder ingress of humidity to, and sealing edges of, the inorganic fibre core.</li>
</ol></p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">The moisture uptake (when the sample is exposed to an environment of 40°C, 95% relative humidity for 23 hours) of the sealed inorganic fibre core layer is preferably less than 5 wt%, more preferably less than 4wt%, even more preferably less than 3 wt% and most preferably less than 2.5 wt%.</p>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">In addition to the sealed edges of the inorganic fibre core layer preventing moisture ingress, the sealed edges also prevent dust formation within the inorganic core layer from being expelled into the environment.</p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">The present invention provides a use of a composite material and electrical storage devices as set out in the appended claims. In the claims, the term "phyllosilicate insulation" means a material or materials comprising one or more phyllosilicate minerals in an amount greater than 5% by weight of the material (and optionally &gt;10%, &gt;20%, &gt;30%, &gt;40%, &gt;50%, &gt;60%, &gt;70%, or &gt;80% by weight of the insulation material). The phyllosilicate insulation may comprise other components, including, as non-limitative examples, fillers and/or binders and/or fibres.</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">The invention is illustrated but not limited by the following description with reference to the drawings in which:-<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> -->
<ul id="ul0002" list-style="none">
<li><figref idref="f0001">Fig.1</figref> shows schematically a paper/mica sheet as is conventionally known.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0001">Fig.2</figref> shows schematically a paper/mica sheet as in a first embodiment of the present invention.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">Fig.3</figref> shows schematically a paper/mica sheet as in a second embodiment of the present invention.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">Fig.4</figref> shows schematically a paper/mica sheet as in a third embodiment of the present invention.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">Fig. 5</figref> shows the results of a test on heat resistance of a material usable in the first, second and third embodiments.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0004">Fig. 6</figref> shows the results of a test on heat resistance of a material usable in the first, second and third embodiments.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">The conventional mica sheet of <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is a laminate comprising a inorganic fibre core 1 sandwiched between mica paper sheets 2,2' which optionally include scrim layers 3,3' providing mechanical integrity to the mica paper sheets. The layers of the laminate are secured adhesively. Such a laminate provides free edges 4 of the inorganic fibre core that may act as a path for humidity or liquids to enter the laminate. Humidity and liquids can result in damage to the paper, and to reducing the electrical resistivity of the paper. The thickness of the mica paper sheets is preferably at least 0.06 mm with a minimum areal density of 100 g/m<sup>2</sup> to enable the sheet to provide a sufficient barrier to prevent moisture ingress enabling the sealant to be localised to the free edges 4. This provides the advantage of reducing the extent of sealant required, thereby reducing weight and size of the composite material.</p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">In a first embodiment shown in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 2</figref>, and using the same references for like integers as <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, a sealant 5 is impregnated into the edges of the inorganic fibre core 1 reducing or eliminating ingress of humidity or liquid.</p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">In a second embodiment shown in <figref idref="f0002">Fig. 3</figref>, and using the same references for like integers as <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, a protective coat 6 adheres to the face of the laminate and surrounds at least the edges 7 of the laminate of inorganic fibre core 1 and mica paper sheets 2,2'. The protective coat 6 may optionally be omitted from regions 8 of the face of the laminate.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">In a third embodiment shown in <figref idref="f0002">Fig. 4</figref>, and using the same references for like integers as <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, a sealant 5 is impregnated into the edges of the inorganic fibre core 1 reducing or eliminating ingress of humidity or liquid; and a protective coat 6 surrounds the laminate of inorganic fibre core 1 and mica paper sheets 2,2'.</p>
<heading id="h0001">In more (but not limiting) detail:-</heading>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">The inorganic fibre core 1 comprises inorganic fibres interlocked or entangled to form a coherent body resistant against separation, but having sufficient spaces between the fibres to provide a thermal insulation effect, and a degree of compressibility. The inorganic fibres may be interlocked or entangled by any known means, for example by deposition as non-woven material, or by needling or otherwise entangling fibres from a fleece to form a blanket. However a particularly useful form is as a paper, formed from the inorganic fibres by paper making techniques.</p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">The inorganic fibres may be of any type sufficient to provide the insulative and fire-resistant properties required, and typically will be of a fibre having a melting point above 1000°C. suitable fibres include (without limitation), aluminosilicate fibres, alkaline earth silicate fibres, alkali metal aluminosilicate fibres.</p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">The inorganic fibre core 1 has a ceramic has a thickness greater than 0.5mm to provide some scope for compressibility and resilience to deformation. This assists both in the assembly of products using the composite, and in providing a degree of cushioning for products protected by the composite. The maximum thickness of the inorganic fibre core 1 depends upon application and maintaining integrity of the composite, but is typically less than 10cm, less than 5cm, or less than 1cm. Preferably, the density of the core is in the range of 200 to 280 kg/m<sup>3</sup> and more preferably 220 to 250 kg/m<sup>3</sup>.</p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">An example material that can be used is SUPERWOOL<sup>®</sup> PLUS alkaline earth silicate paper which is available in thicknesses including 2mm, 3mm and 6mm. This material has a loss in ignition of about 8% by weight, and the present invention contemplates inorganic fibre cores in which the inorganic fibres comprise as little as 50% by weight of the inorganic fibre cores, but preferably the amount of inorganic fibre is &gt; 60%, &gt;70%, &gt;80%, &gt;90% or even &gt;95% of the<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> inorganic fibre core. In addition to fibres, the inorganic fibre cores may comprise other materials as fillers, binders, or otherwise.</p>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">The mica paper sheets 2,2' and optional scrim layers 3,3' may be of any material appropriate to the functions of providing a fire barrier and mechanical integrity. A suitable material is a 0.1mm thick mica paper with a glass cloth backing. Such paper/scrim materials typically have a resin binder present. The resin binder may be ready cured (in which case adhesive securing of the paper/scrim material to the inorganic fibre core 1 is required) or the paper/scrim material may be an uncured prepreg (for curing of the resin during direct lamination of the with the inorganic fibre core 1).</p>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">Preferably the areal density of the mica paper is in the range of 100 to 150 g/m<sup>2</sup>. Suitable materials are supplied by SWECO Inc. [http://www.swecomica.net/eng/]. Mica paper sheets typically have a density of up to around 1300kg.m<sup>-3</sup> but the density varies with the relative proportions of paper and backing. The invention is not limited to any particular density.</p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">It is preferable for some applications that that the mica paper sheets 2,2' and optional scrim layers 3,3' have a low silicone (i.e. preferably less than 5 wt%, more preferably less than 1 wt% and most preferably substantially free of silicone) content and epoxy binders can be used in this application, but any suitable binder system is contemplated.</p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">Where the mica paper sheets 2,2' and optional scrim layers 3,3' are adhesively bonded to the inorganic fibre core 1, any suitable adhesive may be used. Good results have been obtained with a binder comprising acrylic ester copolymer, salified alkyl ether sulfosuccinate and polyoxyethylene alkyl ether.</p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">The sealant 5 may be of any material capable of performing the function of sealing the edges of the inorganic fibre core 1. Typical materials include polymeric materials, but also include inorganic materials (for example colloidal inorganic materials, including (for example) silica sols, alumina sols).</p>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">The protective coat 6 surrounds at least the edges of the laminate of inorganic fibre core 1 and mica paper sheets 2,2' and may (as shown) cover the entirety of the laminate. Suitable materials include polymeric coatings applied and cured in place (e.g. synthetic rubbers) or may comprise<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> polymeric sheets heat laminated to the laminate of inorganic fibre core 1 and mica paper sheets 2,2'. Vacuum encapsulation (for example with high density polyethylene [HDPE]) is a convenient method.</p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">The materials of the invention may be used as they are, or in combination with materials such as metals to provide a heat spreading effect to limit "hot spots". Heat conductive layers (such as metal foils or meshes) may be provided as part of the composite for the same purpose.</p>
<p id="p0029" num="0029">Typical requirements for suitability for use as insulation against thermal runaway in lithium ion battery assemblies include the ability to withstand 600°C for 10 minutes; and on exposure to 600°C on one side, having a temperature of no more than 120°C on the reverse side after 10 minutes and preferably after 20 minutes.</p>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">This was tested by subjecting one side of a number of samples to 600°C using a heat gun, and measuring temperature with a thermocouple disposed on the hot side, and with two spaced thermocouples on the cold side, one being adjacent the sample, and the other spaced 30mm from the sample.</p>
<heading id="h0002"><u>Examples</u></heading>
<p id="p0031" num="0031"><b><i>Example 1</i></b> comprised an inorganic fibre core of 6mm thick SUPERWOOL<sup>®</sup> PLUS alkaline earth silicate paper, adhesively laminated between sheets of 0.1mm thick mica/glass cloth paper from SWECO Inc. <figref idref="f0003">Fig 5</figref>, shows a temperature time plot with the solid line indicating the hot face temperature and the other lines indicating the temperature adjacent Δ and spaced from □ the sample. As can be seen this material meets the requirement of the temperature on the cold face not reaching 120°C after 10 minutes exposure. Appropriate impregnation of the edges, and/or coating the inorganic fibre core provides a barrier integral to the material to hinder ingress of humidity to edges of the inorganic fibre core and will result in a material that not only meets the thermal requirement but also guards against attack by humidity.</p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032">The moisture uptake of the sealed inorganic core was tested by first subjecting the sample to a salt spray conditions in accordance with ASTM B117 (Standard Practice for Operating Salt Spray (Fog) Apparatus); salt solution: 5 wt% NaCl; Temperature 35°C; 1 hour duration using Temperature and Humidity Chamber (JEIO TECH co./TH-ME-065). The samples were then<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> dried for 24 hours at room temperature before putting the sample in the Temperature and Humidity Chamber at 40°C, 95% relative humidity for 23 hours. After drying at room temperature of 24 hours, the moisture uptake of the sample was calculated 2.23wt% (average of three samples).</p>
<p id="p0033" num="0033"><i><b>Example 2</b></i> comprised a 3mm thick SUPERWOOL<sup>®</sup> PLUS alkaline earth silicate paper adhesively laminated between sheets of 0.1mm thick mica/glass cloth paper from SWECO Inc. The laminate of alkaline earth silicate paper and mica/glass cloth paper was secured to a 3mm thick aluminium plate. <figref idref="f0004">Fig 6</figref>. shows a temperature time plot with the solid line indicating the hot face temperature and the other lines indicating the temperature adjacent Δ and spaced from □ the sample. As can be seen this material meets the requirement of the temperature on the cold face not reaching 120°C after 10 minutes exposure and indeed shows temperatures below those of Example 1. However the compressibility of this material is less than that of Example 1; and inclusion of metal adds a conductive layer, and so is not necessarily preferred. However the provision of an aluminium plate provides greater rigidity and heat spreading that may be useful in some applications.</p>
<heading id="h0003"><u>Uses</u></heading>
<p id="p0034" num="0034">The present invention provides a range of composite materials that may be either compressible and resilient, or relatively rigid, and that having low through-material electrical conductivity, that are resistant to humidity; and that optionally have a low silicone content.</p>
<p id="p0035" num="0035">The composite materials may be used in electric power assemblies to protect cells against thermal runaway, or in other applications where fire protection is required.</p>
<heading id="h0004"><u>Variants</u></heading>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">The above examples use mica paper. The mica group of minerals are sheet silicates (phyllosilicates) comprising a number of minerals (e.g. Biotite, Muscovite, Phlogopite, Lepidolite, Margarite, Glauconite). Other sheet silicates show similar insulative effects (e.g. vermiculite). The present invention is not limited to mica insulation but extends also to insulation comprising other sheet silicates.<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></p>
<p id="p0037" num="0037">In addition, the above examples use phyllosilicate insulation in paper form, but the insulation need not be in the form of paper and may comprise a coating resulting from painting, spraying, or otherwise applying a suspension comprising (optionally with other ingredients) one or more phyllosilicate minerals to the surface of the inorganic fibre core. Such a coating may further constitute the, or part of the, barrier hindering ingress of humidity to edges of the inorganic fibre core.</p>
<p id="p0038" num="0038">The above examples use an inorganic fibre core in the form of a paper of alkaline earth silicate fibres. The inorganic fibre core need not comprise such fibres and any suitable fibre may be used.</p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="10"> -->
<claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>An electrical storage device comprising a plurality of cells or batteries of which at least some are separated by a composite material comprising:-
<claim-text>a) an inorganic fibre core (1) comprising inorganic fibres interlocked or entangled to form a coherent body resistant against separation laminated between</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) at least two layers (2,2') of phyllosilicate insulation <b>characterised in that</b> the material further comprises</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) a barrier (5,6) integral to the material to hinder ingress of humidity to, and sealing edges of, the inorganic fibre core.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>An electrical storage device, as claimed in Claim 1, in which the barrier comprises a sealant (5) impregnated into edges of the inorganic fibre core.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>An electrical storage device, as claimed in Claim 1 or Claim 2, in which the barrier comprises a protective coat (6) adhering to at least the edges of the laminate of inorganic fibre core (1) and phyllosilicate insulation (2,2').</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>An electrical storage device, as claimed in Claim 3, in which the protective coat (6) surrounds and encapsulates the entirety of the laminate of inorganic fibre core (1) and phyllosilicate insulation (2,2').</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>An electrical storage device, as claimed in any of Claims 1 to 4, in which the inorganic fibre core (1) comprises a paper comprising at least 90% by weight inorganic fibres.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>An electrical storage device, as claimed in any of Claims 1 to 5, in which the inorganic fibre core (1) comprises a paper formed from alkaline earth silicate fibres.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>An electrical storage device, as claimed in any of Claims 1 to 6, in which the inorganic fibre core (1) has a thickness greater than 0.5mm.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>An electrical storage device, as claimed in any of Claims 1 to 7, in which the inorganic fibre core (1) has a thickness less than 10cm, less than 5cm, or less than 1cm.<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>An electrical storage device, as claimed in any of Claims 1 to 8, in which the phyllosilicate insulation (2,2') comprises a mica paper secured to a backing (3,3'), optionally in which the backing is a scrim or a glass cloth.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>An electrical storage device, as claimed in any of Claims 1 to 9, in which the phyllosilicate insulation (2,2') has a thickness between 0.06mm and 0.25mm, optionally in the range 0.08mm to 0.15mm.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>An electrical storage device, as claimed in Claim 2, or any of Claims 3 to 10 as dependent on Claim 2, in which the sealant comprises a material selected from the group polymeric materials, inorganic materials, and mixtures thereof, optionally in which the inorganic materials comprise colloidal inorganic materials.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>An electrical storage device, as claimed in Claim 3, or any of Claims 4 to 10 as dependent on Claim 3, in which the protective coating (6) comprises a polymeric coating.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>An electrical storage device, as claimed in Claim 12, in which the polymeric coating comprises (6) polymeric sheets heat laminated to the laminate of inorganic fibre core and phyllosilicate insulation.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>Use for providing passive fire protection to prevent thermal runaway in electrical storage devices of a composite material comprising:-
<claim-text>a) an inorganic fibre core (1) comprising inorganic fibres interlocked or entangled to form a coherent body resistant against separation laminated between</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) at least two layers (2,2') of phyllosilicate insulation <b>characterised in that</b> the material further comprises</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) a barrier (5,6) integral to the material to hinder ingress of humidity to, and sealing edges of, the inorganic fibre core.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims02" lang="de"><!-- EPO <DP n="12"> -->
<claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Elektrische Speichervorrichtung, die eine Vielzahl von Zellen oder Batterien umfasst, von denen mindestens einige durch ein Verbundmaterial getrennt sind, umfassend:
<claim-text>a) einen anorganischen Faserkern (1), der anorganische Fasern umfasst, die miteinander verflochten oder verschlungen sind, um einen zusammenhängenden Körper zu bilden, der gegen Entmischung beständig ist laminiert zwischen</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) mindestens zwei Lagen (2,2') Schichtsilikat-Dämmung</claim-text>
<b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> das Material ferner umfasst:<br/>
c) eine Sperre (5,6), die in das Material integriert ist, um das Eindringen von Feuchtigkeit in den anorganischen Faserkern zu verhindern und die Kanten des anorganischen Faserkerns abzudichten.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Elektrische Speichervorrichtung nach Anspruch 1, bei der die Sperre ein Dichtmittel (5) umfasst, das in die Kanten des anorganischen Faserkerns imprägniert ist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Elektrische Speichervorrichtung nach Anspruch 1 oder Anspruch 2, bei der die Sperre eine Schutzschicht (6) umfasst, die zumindest an den Kanten des Laminats aus anorganischem Faserkern (1) und Schichtsilikatisolierung (2, 2 .) haftet').</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Elektrische Speichervorrichtung nach Anspruch 3, bei der die Schutzschicht (6) das gesamte Laminat aus anorganischem Faserkern (1) und Schichtsilikatisolierung (2, 2') umgibt und einkapselt.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Elektrische Speichervorrichtung nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 4, bei der der anorganische Faserkern (1) ein Papier umfasst, das mindestens 90 Gew.-% anorganische Fasern umfasst.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Elektrische Speichervorrichtung nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 5, bei der der anorganische Faserkern (1) ein aus Erdalkalisilikatfasern gebildetes Papier umfasst.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Elektrische Speichervorrichtung nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 6, bei der der anorganische Faserkern (1) eine Dicke von mehr als 0,5 mm hat.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>Elektrische Speichervorrichtung nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 7, bei der der anorganische Faserkern (1) eine Dicke von weniger als 10 cm, weniger als 5 cm, oder weniger als 1 cm hat.<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>Elektrische Speichervorrichtung nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 8, bei der die SchichtsilikatIsolierung (2, 2') ein Glimmerpapier umfasst, das an einer Unterlage (3,3') befestigt ist, wobei die Unterlage wahlweise a . ist Gitter oder ein Glastuch.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>Elektrische Speichervorrichtung nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 9, bei der die Schichtsilikatisolierung (2, 2') eine Dicke zwischen 0,06 mm und 0,25 mm, wahlweise im Bereich von 0,08 mm bis 0,15 mm, aufweist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>Elektrische Speichervorrichtung nach Anspruch 2 oder einem der Ansprüche 3 bis 10 in Abhängigkeit von Anspruch 2, wobei das Dichtmittel ein Material umfasst, ausgewählt aus der Gruppe Polymermaterialien, anorganische Materialien und Mischungen davon, wahlweise worin die anorganischen Materialien umfassen kolloidale anorganische Materialien.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>Elektrische Speichervorrichtung nach Anspruch 3 oder einem der Ansprüche 4 bis 10 in Abhängigkeit von Anspruch 3, wobei die Schutzbeschichtung (6) eine Polymerbeschichtung umfasst.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>Elektrische Speichervorrichtung nach Anspruch 12, bei der die Polymerbeschichtung (6) Polymerfolien umfasst, die auf das Laminat aus einem anorganischen Faserkern und einer Schichtsilikatisolierung wärmelaminiert sind.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>Verwendung zur Bereitstellung eines passiven Brandschutzes zur Verhinderung von thermischem Durchgehen in elektrischen Speichervorrichtungen aus einem Verbundmaterial, umfassend:
<claim-text>a) einen anorganischen Faserkern (1), der anorganische Fasern umfasst, die miteinander verflochten oder verschlungen sind, um einen zusammenhängenden Körper zu bilden, der gegen Entmischung beständig ist laminiert zwischen</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) mindestens zwei Lagen (2,2') Schichtsilikat-Dämmung</claim-text>
<b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> das Material ferner umfasst:<br/>
c) eine Sperre (5,6), die in das Material integriert ist, um das Eindringen von Feuchtigkeit in den anorganischen Faserkern zu verhindern und die Kanten des anorganischen Faserkerns abzudichten.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims03" lang="fr"><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> -->
<claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Dispositif de stockage électrique comprenant une pluralité d'éléments ou de batteries dont au moins certains sont séparés par un matériau composite comprenant :-
<claim-text>a) une âme de fibre inorganique (1) comprenant des fibres inorganiques entrelacées ou enchevêtrées pour former un corps cohérent résistant à la séparation laminé entre</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) au moins deux couches (2,2') d'isolant en phyllosilicate<br/>
<b>caractérisé en ce que</b> le matériau comprend en outre</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) une barrière (5, 6) intégrée au matériau pour empêcher l'entrée d'humidité dans, et les bords de scellement de, l'âme en fibre inorganique.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Dispositif de stockage électrique selon la revendication 1, dans lequel la barrière comprend un scellant (5) imprégné dans les bords de l'âme en fibre inorganique.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Un dispositif de stockage électrique, tel que revendiqué dans la revendication 1 ou la revendication 2, dans lequel la barrière comprend un revêtement protecteur (6) adhérant au moins aux bords du stratifié d'une âme en fibres inorganiques (1) et d'une isolation en phyllosilicate (2,2 ').</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Dispositif de stockage électrique selon la revendication 3, dans lequel le revêtement protecteur (6) entoure et encapsule la totalité du stratifié d'une âme en fibre inorganique (1) et d'une isolation en phyllosilicate (2,2').</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Dispositif de stockage électrique selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 4, dans lequel l'âme en fibres inorganiques (1) comprend un papier comprenant au moins 90 % en poids de fibres inorganiques.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Dispositif de stockage électrique selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 5, dans lequel l'âme en fibres inorganiques (1) comprend un papier formé de fibres de silicate alcalino-terreux.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Dispositif de stockage électrique selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 6, dans lequel l'âme en fibre inorganique (1) a une épaisseur supérieure à 0,5 mm.<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>Dispositif de stockage électrique selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 7, dans lequel le noyau de fibre inorganique (1) a une épaisseur inférieure à 10 cm, inférieure à 5 cm ou inférieure à 1 cm.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>Dispositif de stockage électrique selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 8, dans lequel l'isolant en phyllosilicate (2,2') comprend un papier mica fixé à un support (3,3'), éventuellement dans lequel le support est un canevas ou un chiffon de verre.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>Dispositif de stockage électrique selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 9, dans lequel l'isolant en phyllosilicate (2,2') a une épaisseur comprise entre 0,06 mm et 0,25 mm, éventuellement comprise entre 0,08 mm et 0,15 mm.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>Dispositif de stockage électrique selon la revendication 2, ou l'une quelconque des revendications 3 à 10 dépendantes de la revendication 2, dans lequel le matériau d'étanchéité comprend un matériau choisi dans le groupe des matériaux polymères, des matériaux inorganiques et des mélanges de ceux-ci, éventuellement dans lesquels les matériaux inorganiques comprennent des matériaux inorganiques colloïdaux.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>Dispositif de stockage électrique selon la revendication 3, ou l'une quelconque des revendications 4 à 10 dépendantes de la revendication 3, dans lequel le revêtement protecteur (6) comprend un revêtement polymère.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>Dispositif de stockage électrique selon la revendication 12, dans lequel le revêtement polymère comprend (6) des feuilles polymères laminées à chaud sur le stratifié d'une âme en fibres inorganiques et d'un isolant en phyllosilicate.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>Utilisation pour fournir une protection passive contre l'incendie pour empêcher l'emballement thermique dans les dispositifs de stockage électrique d'un matériau composite comprenant : -
<claim-text>a) une âme de fibre inorganique (1) comprenant des fibres inorganiques entrelacées ou enchevêtrées pour former un corps cohérent résistant à la séparation laminé entre</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) au moins deux couches (2,2') d'isolant en phyllosilicate <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> le matériau comprend en outre</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) une barrière (5, 6) intégrée au matériau pour empêcher l'entrée d'humidité dans, et les bords de scellement de, l'âme en fibre inorganique.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1,2"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="153" he="180" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="3,4"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="153" he="195" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> -->
<figure id="f0003" num="5"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="123" he="194" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> -->
<figure id="f0004" num="6"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="130" he="178" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<ep-reference-list id="ref-list">
<heading id="ref-h0001"><b>REFERENCES CITED IN THE DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0001" num=""><i>This list of references cited by the applicant is for the reader's convenience only. It does not form part of the European patent document. Even though great care has been taken in compiling the references, errors or omissions cannot be excluded and the EPO disclaims all liability in this regard.</i></p>
<heading id="ref-h0002"><b>Patent documents cited in the description</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0002" num="">
<ul id="ref-ul0001" list-style="bullet">
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0001" dnum="US2012321868A1"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2012321868</doc-number><kind>A1</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0001">[0006]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0002" dnum="GB2234938A"><document-id><country>GB</country><doc-number>2234938</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0002">[0006]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0003" dnum="US4505977A"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>4505977</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0003">[0006]</crossref></li>
</ul></p>
</ep-reference-list>
</ep-patent-document>
