<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP21156104A1" file="EP21156104NWA1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3889139" kind="A1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSK..HRIS..MTNORS..SM..................</B001EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  1100000/0</B007EP><B053EP>This application was filed on 09-02-2021 as a divisional application to the application mentioned under INID code 62.</B053EP><B053EP>Claims filed after the date of filing of the application / after the date of receipt of the divisional application (Rule 68(4) EPC).</B053EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3889139</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT APPLICATION</B121></B120><B130>A1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>21156104.8</B210><B220><date>20161130</date></B220><B250>en</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B300><B310>201562261240 P</B310><B320><date>20151130</date></B320><B330><ctry>US</ctry></B330></B300><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B430></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>C07D 235/32        20060101AFI20210614BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="2"><text>C07D 405/12        20060101ALI20210614BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="3"><text>A61P  35/00        20060101ALI20210614BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="4"><text>A61K  31/4184      20060101ALI20210614BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>A61P  35/00        20180101 LI20190411BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>C07D 235/32        20130101 LI20170629BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="3"><text>C07D 405/12        20130101 LI20170629BHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>VERBINDUNGEN ZUR BEHANDLUNG VON PROLIFERATIVEN ERKRANKUNGEN</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>COMPOUNDS FOR TREATING PROLIFERATIVE DISEASES</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>COMPOSÉS DE TRAITEMENT DE MALADIES PROLIFÉRANTES</B542></B540><B590><B598>1</B598></B590></B500><B600><B620><parent><pdoc><dnum><anum>16871440.0</anum><pnum>3383852</pnum></dnum><date>20161130</date></pdoc></parent></B620></B600><B700><B710><B711><snm>The Children's Medical Center Corporation</snm><iid>101835379</iid><irf>P256883EPD1</irf><adr><str>55 Shattuck Street</str><city>Boston, MA 02115</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B711><B711><snm>Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center, Inc.</snm><iid>101757799</iid><irf>P256883EPD1</irf><adr><str>Technology Ventures Office 
330 Brookline Avenue 
BR-244</str><city>Boston, MA 02215</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B711></B710><B720><B721><snm>ZETTER, Bruce, R.</snm><adr><str>41 Grove Street</str><city>Wayland, Massachusetts 01778</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>SUN, Lijun</snm><adr><str>148 Depot Road</str><city>Harvard, Massachusetts 01451</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B740><B741><snm>HGF</snm><iid>101702048</iid><adr><str>1 City Walk</str><city>Leeds West Yorkshire LS11 9DX</city><ctry>GB</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840></B800></SDOBI>
<abstract id="abst" lang="en">
<p id="pa01" num="0001">The present disclosure provides compounds of Formula (I). The compounds described herein may be useful in treating and/or preventing proliferative diseases (e.g., cancer). Also provided in the present disclosure are pharmaceutical compositions, kits, methods, and uses including or using a compound described herein.
<chemistry id="chema01" num="0001"><img id="ia01" file="imga0001.tif" wi="42" he="30" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="102" he="75" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p>
</abstract>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<heading id="h0001"><b>RELATED APPLICATIONS</b></heading>
<p id="p0001" num="0001">This application claims priority under 35 U.S.C. § 119(e) to U.S. Provisional Application, U.S.S.N. <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US62261240B"><text>62/261,240, filed November 30, 2015</text></patcit>, which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<heading id="h0002"><b>BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</b></heading>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">The spread of cancer cells from a primary tumor site to distant organs is known as metastasis. The progression of human cancer to metastatic disease is the major contributing factor to its lethality. Metastasis has been considered one of the most intriguing aspects of the pathogenesis of cancer, where cancer is a type of proliferative disease. Cancer tumor metastasis, or otherwise known as metastatic disease, is responsible for most therapeutic failures in treating the disease, as patients succumb to the multiple tumor growth, accounting for more than 90% of human cancer-related deaths. <i>See,</i> for example, <nplcit id="ncit0001" npl-type="b"><text>Cancer, A Comprehensive Treatise, F. F. Becker (Editor), Volume 4, Chapter 3, Plenum Press, New York, 1975</text></nplcit>.</p>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">Thus, there is a need for novel therapies to inhibit growth and increase the death of metastatic tumor cells.</p>
<heading id="h0003"><b>SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</b></heading>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">The present disclosure provides compounds, such as compounds of Formula (<b>I</b>). The compounds described herein may be useful in treating and/or preventing proliferative diseases <i>(e.g.,</i> cancer <i>(e.g.,</i> lung cancer, breast cancer, leukemia, lymphoma, melanoma, multiple myeloma, Ewing's sarcoma, osteosarcoma, brain cancer, neuroblastoma), benign neoplasms, angiogenesis, inflammatory diseases, autoinflammatory diseases, and autoimmune diseases). Also provided are pharmaceutical compositions, kits, methods, and uses of a compound described herein.</p>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">In one aspect, the present disclosure provides compounds of Formula (<b>I</b>):
<chemistry id="chem0001" num="0001"><img id="ib0001" file="imgb0001.tif" wi="50" he="24" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry><!-- EPO <DP n="2"> -->
and pharmaceutically acceptable salts, solvates, hydrates, polymorphs, co-crystals, tautomers, stereoisomers, isotopically labeled derivatives, and prodrugs thereof, wherein R<sup>1</sup>, R<sup>2</sup>, R<sup>3</sup>, and R<sup>4</sup> are described herein.</p>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">Exemplary compounds of Formula (<b>I</b>) include, but are not limited to:
<chemistry id="chem0002" num="0002"><img id="ib0002" file="imgb0002.tif" wi="151" he="35" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
<chemistry id="chem0003" num="0003"><img id="ib0003" file="imgb0003.tif" wi="134" he="40" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
<chemistry id="chem0004" num="0004"><img id="ib0004" file="imgb0004.tif" wi="150" he="36" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
<chemistry id="chem0005" num="0005"><img id="ib0005" file="imgb0005.tif" wi="128" he="35" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
<chemistry id="chem0006" num="0006"><img id="ib0006" file="imgb0006.tif" wi="146" he="35" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
and pharmaceutically acceptable salts, solvates, hydrates, polymorphs, co-crystals, tautomers, stereoisomers, isotopically labeled derivatives, and prodrugs thereof.</p>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">The compound may be as described in the following numbered paragraphs:<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">In another aspect, the present disclosure provides pharmaceutical compositions including a compound described herein, and optionally a pharmaceutically acceptable excipient. In certain embodiments, the pharmaceutical compositions described herein include an effective amount of a compound described herein. An effective amount described herein may be a therapeutically effective amount or prophylactically effective amount. The pharmaceutical composition may be useful for treating a proliferative disease in a subject in need thereof and/or preventing a proliferative disease in a subject in need thereof.</p>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">In certain embodiments, a proliferative disease being treated and/or prevented is cancer. In certain embodiments, the cancer is metastatic cancer.</p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">In certain embodiments, the subject being treated is a mammal (<i>e.g</i>., human or non-human mammal).</p>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">Another aspect of the present disclosure relates to methods of treating and/or preventing a proliferative disease in a subject.</p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">In certain embodiments, the method described herein includes administering to the subject an effective amount of a compound, or pharmaceutical composition thereof, described herein.</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">Another aspect of the present disclosure relates to a method of contacting a cell with an effective amount of a compound, or pharmaceutical composition thereof, as described herein. In certain embodiments, a cell contacted with an effective amount of a compound or pharmaceutical composition described herein is <i>in vitro</i> or <i>in vivo.</i> In certain embodiments, the method further includes administering to the subject an additional pharmaceutical agent.</p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">Another aspect of the present disclosure relates to a method of contacting the cell with an additional pharmaceutical agent. In certain embodiments, the method further includes performing radiotherapy, immunotherapy, and/or transplantation on the subject.</p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">Another aspect of the present disclosure relates to kits comprising a container with a compound, or pharmaceutical composition thereof, as described herein. The kits described herein may include a single dose or multiple doses of the compound or pharmaceutical composition. The kits may be useful in a method of the disclosure. In certain embodiments, the kit further includes instructions for using the compound or pharmaceutical composition.</p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">In yet another aspect, the present disclosure provides compounds and pharmaceutical compositions described herein for use in a method of the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">The details of one or more embodiments of the disclosure are set forth herein. Other features, objects, and advantages of the disclosure will be apparent from the Detailed Description, the Examples, and the Claims.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p>
<heading id="h0004"><b>DEFINITIONS</b></heading>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">Definitions of specific functional groups and chemical terms are described in more detail below. The chemical elements are identified in accordance with the Periodic Table of the Elements, CAS version, <nplcit id="ncit0002" npl-type="b"><text>Handbook of Chemistry and Physics, 75th Ed</text></nplcit>., inside cover, and specific functional groups are generally defined as described therein. Additionally, general principles of organic chemistry, as well as specific functional moieties and reactivity, are described in <nplcit id="ncit0003" npl-type="b"><text>Thomas Sorrell, Organic Chemistry, University Science Books, Sausalito, 1999</text></nplcit>; <nplcit id="ncit0004" npl-type="b"><text>Smith and March, March's Advanced Organic Chemistry, 5th Edition, John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc., New York, 2001</text></nplcit>; <nplcit id="ncit0005" npl-type="b"><text>Larock, Comprehensive Organic Transformations, VCH Publishers, Inc., New York, 1989</text></nplcit>; and <nplcit id="ncit0006" npl-type="b"><text>Carruthers, Some Modern Methods of Organic Synthesis, 3rd Edition, Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, 1987</text></nplcit>. The disclosure is not intended to be limited in any manner by the exemplary listing of substituents described herein.</p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">Compounds described herein can comprise one or more asymmetric centers, and thus can exist in various isomeric forms, <i>e.g</i>., enantiomers and/or diastereomers. For example, the compounds described herein can be in the form of an individual enantiomer, diastereomer or geometric isomer, or can be in the form of a mixture of stereoisomers, including racemic mixtures and mixtures enriched in one or more stereoisomer. Isomers can be isolated from mixtures by methods known to those skilled in the art, including chiral high pressure liquid chromatography (HPLC) and the formation and crystallization of chiral salts; or preferred isomers can be prepared by asymmetric syntheses. See, for example, <nplcit id="ncit0007" npl-type="b"><text>Jacques et al., Enantiomers, Racemates and Resolutions (Wiley Interscience, New York, 1981</text></nplcit>); <nplcit id="ncit0008" npl-type="s"><text>Wilen et al., Tetrahedron 33:2725 (1977</text></nplcit>); <nplcit id="ncit0009" npl-type="b"><text>Eliel, Stereochemistry of Carbon Compounds (McGraw-Hill, NY, 1962</text></nplcit>); and <nplcit id="ncit0010" npl-type="b"><text>Wilen, Tables ofResolving Agents and Optical Resolutions p. 268 (E.L. Eliel, Ed., Univ. of Notre Dame Press, Notre Dame, IN 1972</text></nplcit>). The disclosure additionally encompasses compounds described herein as individual isomers substantially free of other isomers, and alternatively, as mixtures of various isomers.</p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">When a range of values is listed, it is intended to encompass each value and sub-range within the range. For example "C<sub>1-6</sub>" is intended to encompass, C<sub>1</sub>, C<sub>2</sub>, C<sub>3</sub>, C<sub>4</sub>, C<sub>5</sub>, C<sub>6</sub>, C<sub>1-6</sub>, C<sub>1-5</sub>, C<sub>1-4</sub>, C<sub>1-3</sub>, C<sub>1-2</sub>, C<sub>2-6</sub>, C<sub>2-5</sub>, C<sub>2-4</sub>, C<sub>2-3</sub>, C<sub>3-6</sub>, C<sub>3-5</sub>, C<sub>3-4</sub>, C<sub>4-6</sub>, C<sub>4-5</sub>, and C<sub>5-6</sub>.</p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">The term "aliphatic" includes both saturated and unsaturated, straight chain (<i>i.e.,</i> unbranched), branched, acyclic, cyclic, or polycyclic aliphatic hydrocarbons, which are optionally substituted with one or more functional groups. As will be appreciated by one of ordinary skill in the art, "aliphatic" is intended herein to include, but is not limited to, alkyl, alkenyl, alkynyl, cycloalkyl, cycloalkenyl, and cycloalkynyl moieties. Thus, the term "alkyl"<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> includes straight, branched and cyclic alkyl groups. An analogous convention applies to other generic terms such as "alkenyl", "alkynyl", and the like. Furthermore, the terms "alkyl", "alkenyl", "alkynyl", and the like encompass both substituted and unsubstituted groups. In certain embodiments, "lower alkyl" is used to indicate those alkyl groups (cyclic, acyclic, substituted, unsubstituted, branched or unbranched) having 1-6 carbon atoms.</p>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">In certain embodiments, the alkyl, alkenyl, and alkynyl groups employed in the disclosure contain 1-20 aliphatic carbon atoms. In certain other embodiments, the alkyl, alkenyl, and alkynyl groups employed in the disclosure contain 1-10 aliphatic carbon atoms. In yet other embodiments, the alkyl, alkenyl, and alkynyl groups employed in the disclosure contain 1-8 aliphatic carbon atoms. In still other embodiments, the alkyl, alkenyl, and alkynyl groups employed in the disclosure contain 1-6 aliphatic carbon atoms. In yet other embodiments, the alkyl, alkenyl, and alkynyl groups employed in the disclosure contain 1-4 carbon atoms. Illustrative aliphatic groups thus include, but are not limited to, for example, methyl, ethyl, n-propyl, isopropyl, cyclopropyl, -CH<sub>2</sub>-cyclopropyl, vinyl, allyl, n-butyl, sec-butyl, isobutyl, tert-butyl, cyclobutyl, -CH<sub>2</sub>-cyclobutyl, n-pentyl, sec-pentyl, isopentyl, tert-pentyl, cyclopentyl, -CH<sub>2</sub>-cyclopentyl, n-hexyl, sec-hexyl, cyclohexyl, -CH<sub>2</sub>-cyclohexyl moieties and the like, which again, may bear one or more substituents. Alkenyl groups include, but are not limited to, for example, ethenyl, propenyl, butenyl, 1-methyl-2-buten-1-yl, and the like. Representative alkynyl groups include, but are not limited to, ethynyl, 2-propynyl (propargyl), 1-propynyl, and the like.</p>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">The term "alkyl" refers to a radical of a straight-chain or branched saturated hydrocarbon group having from 1 to 10 carbon atoms ("C<sub>1-10</sub> alkyl"). In some embodiments, an alkyl group has 1 to 9 carbon atoms ("C<sub>1-9</sub> alkyl"). In some embodiments, an alkyl group has 1 to 8 carbon atoms ("C<sub>1-8</sub> alkyl"). In some embodiments, an alkyl group has 1 to 7 carbon atoms ("C<sub>1-7</sub> alkyl"). In some embodiments, an alkyl group has 1 to 6 carbon atoms ("C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl"). In some embodiments, an alkyl group has 1 to 5 carbon atoms ("C<sub>1-5</sub> alkyl"). In some embodiments, an alkyl group has 1 to 4 carbon atoms ("C<sub>1-4</sub> alkyl"). In some embodiments, an alkyl group has 1 to 3 carbon atoms ("C<sub>1-3</sub> alkyl"). In some embodiments, an alkyl group has 1 to 2 carbon atoms ("C<sub>1-2</sub> alkyl"). In some embodiments, an alkyl group has 1 carbon atom ("C<sub>1</sub> alkyl"). In some embodiments, an alkyl group has 2 to 6 carbon atoms ("C<sub>2-6</sub> alkyl"). Examples of C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl groups include methyl (C<sub>1</sub>), ethyl (C<sub>2</sub>), propyl (C<sub>3</sub>) <i>(e.g.,</i> n-propyl, isopropyl), butyl (C<sub>4</sub>) (<i>e.g.,</i> n-butyl, tert-butyl, sec-butyl, iso-butyl), pentyl (C<sub>5</sub>) <i>(e.g.,</i> n-pentyl, 3-pentanyl, amyl, neopentyl, 3-methyl-2-butanyl, tertiary amyl), and hexyl (C<sub>6</sub>) <i>(e.g.,</i> n-hexyl). Additional examples of alkyl groups include n-heptyl (C<sub>7</sub>), n-octyl<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> (C<sub>8</sub>), and the like. Unless otherwise specified, each instance of an alkyl group is independently unsubstituted (an "unsubstituted alkyl") or substituted (a "substituted alkyl") with one or more substituents (<i>e.g</i>., halogen, such as F). In certain embodiments, the alkyl group is an unsubstituted C<sub>1-10</sub> alkyl (such as unsubstituted C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl, <i>e.g.,</i> -CH<sub>3</sub>). In certain embodiments, the alkyl group is a substituted C<sub>1-10</sub> alkyl (such as substituted C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl, <i>e.g.,</i> -CF<sub>3</sub>).</p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">"Alkenyl" refers to a radical of a straight-chain or branched hydrocarbon group having from 2 to 20 carbon atoms, one or more carbon-carbon double bonds, and no triple bonds ("C<sub>2-20</sub> alkenyl"). In some embodiments, an alkenyl group has 2 to 10 carbon atoms ("C<sub>2-10</sub> alkenyl"). In some embodiments, an alkenyl group has 2 to 9 carbon atoms ("C<sub>2-9</sub> alkenyl"). In some embodiments, an alkenyl group has 2 to 8 carbon atoms ("C<sub>2-8</sub> alkenyl"). In some embodiments, an alkenyl group has 2 to 7 carbon atoms ("C<sub>2-7</sub> alkenyl"). In some embodiments, an alkenyl group has 2 to 6 carbon atoms ("C<sub>2-6</sub> alkenyl"). In some embodiments, an alkenyl group has 2 to 5 carbon atoms ("C<sub>2-5</sub> alkenyl"). In some embodiments, an alkenyl group has 2 to 4 carbon atoms ("C<sub>2-4</sub> alkenyl"). In some embodiments, an alkenyl group has 2 to 3 carbon atoms ("C<sub>2-3</sub> alkenyl"). In some embodiments, an alkenyl group has 2 carbon atoms ("C<sub>2</sub> alkenyl"). The one or more carbon-carbon double bonds can be internal (such as in 2-butenyl) or terminal (such as in 1-butenyl). Examples of C<sub>2-4</sub> alkenyl groups include ethenyl (C<sub>2</sub>), 1-propenyl (C<sub>3</sub>), 2-propenyl (C<sub>3</sub>), 1-butenyl (C<sub>4</sub>), 2-butenyl (C<sub>4</sub>), butadienyl (C<sub>4</sub>), and the like. Examples of C<sub>2-6</sub> alkenyl groups include the aforementioned C<sub>2-4</sub> alkenyl groups as well as pentenyl (C<sub>5</sub>), pentadienyl (C<sub>5</sub>), hexenyl (C<sub>6</sub>), and the like. Additional examples of alkenyl include heptenyl (C<sub>7</sub>), octenyl (C<sub>8</sub>), octatrienyl (C<sub>8</sub>), and the like. Unless otherwise specified, each instance of an alkenyl group is independently optionally substituted, <i>i.e.,</i> unsubstituted (an "unsubstituted alkenyl") or substituted (a "substituted alkenyl") with one or more substituents. In certain embodiments, the alkenyl group is unsubstituted C<sub>2-10</sub> alkenyl. In certain embodiments, the alkenyl group is substituted C<sub>2-10</sub> alkenyl. In an alkenyl group, a C=C double bond for which the stereochemistry is not specified (<i>e.g</i>., -CH=CHCH<sub>3</sub> or
<chemistry id="chem0007" num="0007"><img id="ib0007" file="imgb0007.tif" wi="16" he="8" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
) may be an (<i>E</i>)- or (Z)-double bond.</p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">"Alkynyl" refers to a radical of a straight-chain or branched hydrocarbon group having from 2 to 20 carbon atoms, one or more carbon-carbon triple bonds, and optionally one or more double bonds ("C<sub>2-20</sub> alkynyl"). In some embodiments, an alkynyl group has 2 to 10 carbon atoms ("C<sub>2-10</sub> alkynyl"). In some embodiments, an alkynyl group has 2 to 9 carbon<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> atoms ("C<sub>2-9</sub> alkynyl"). In some embodiments, an alkynyl group has 2 to 8 carbon atoms ("C<sub>2-8</sub> alkynyl"). In some embodiments, an alkynyl group has 2 to 7 carbon atoms ("C<sub>2-7</sub> alkynyl"). In some embodiments, an alkynyl group has 2 to 6 carbon atoms ("C<sub>2-6</sub> alkynyl"). In some embodiments, an alkynyl group has 2 to 5 carbon atoms ("C<sub>2-5</sub> alkynyl"). In some embodiments, an alkynyl group has 2 to 4 carbon atoms ("C<sub>2-4</sub> alkynyl"). In some embodiments, an alkynyl group has 2 to 3 carbon atoms ("C<sub>2-3</sub> alkynyl"). In some embodiments, an alkynyl group has 2 carbon atoms ("C<sub>2</sub> alkynyl"). The one or more carbon-carbon triple bonds can be internal (such as in 2-butynyl) or terminal (such as in 1-butynyl). Examples of C<sub>2-4</sub> alkynyl groups include, without limitation, ethynyl (C<sub>2</sub>), 1-propynyl (C<sub>3</sub>), 2-propynyl (C<sub>3</sub>), 1-butynyl (C<sub>4</sub>), 2-butynyl (C<sub>4</sub>), and the like. Examples of C<sub>2-6</sub> alkenyl groups include the aforementioned C<sub>2-4</sub> alkynyl groups as well as pentynyl (C<sub>5</sub>), hexynyl (C<sub>6</sub>), and the like. Additional examples of alkynyl include heptynyl (C<sub>7</sub>), octynyl (C<sub>8</sub>), and the like. Unless otherwise specified, each instance of an alkynyl group is independently optionally substituted, <i>i.e.,</i> unsubstituted (an "unsubstituted alkynyl") or substituted (a "substituted alkynyl") with one or more substituents. In certain embodiments, the alkynyl group is unsubstituted C<sub>2-10</sub> alkynyl. In certain embodiments, the alkynyl group is substituted C<sub>2-10</sub> alkynyl.</p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">"Carbocyclyl" or "carbocyclic" refers to a radical of a non-aromatic cyclic hydrocarbon group having from 3 to 10 ring carbon atoms ("C<sub>3-10</sub> carbocyclyl") and zero heteroatoms in the non-aromatic ring system. In some embodiments, a carbocyclyl group has 3 to 8 ring carbon atoms ("C<sub>3-8</sub> carbocyclyl"). In some embodiments, a carbocyclyl group has 3 to 6 ring carbon atoms ("C<sub>3-6</sub> carbocyclyl"). In some embodiments, a carbocyclyl group has 3 to 6 ring carbon atoms ("C<sub>3-6</sub> carbocyclyl"). In some embodiments, a carbocyclyl group has 5 to 10 ring carbon atoms ("C<sub>5-10</sub> carbocyclyl"). Exemplary C<sub>3-6</sub> carbocyclyl groups include, without limitation, cyclopropyl (C<sub>3</sub>), cyclopropenyl (C<sub>3</sub>), cyclobutyl (C<sub>4</sub>), cyclobutenyl (C<sub>4</sub>), cyclopentyl (C<sub>5</sub>), cyclopentenyl (C<sub>5</sub>), cyclohexyl (C<sub>6</sub>), cyclohexenyl (C<sub>6</sub>), cyclohexadienyl (C<sub>6</sub>), and the like. Exemplary C<sub>3-8</sub> carbocyclyl groups include, without limitation, the aforementioned C<sub>3-6</sub> carbocyclyl groups as well as cycloheptyl (C<sub>7</sub>), cycloheptenyl (C<sub>7</sub>), cycloheptadienyl (C<sub>7</sub>), cycloheptatrienyl (C<sub>7</sub>), cyclooctyl (C<sub>8</sub>), cyclooctenyl (C<sub>8</sub>), bicyclo[2.2.1]heptanyl (C<sub>7</sub>), bicyclo[2.2.2]octanyl (C<sub>8</sub>), and the like. Exemplary C<sub>3-10</sub> carbocyclyl groups include, without limitation, the aforementioned C<sub>3-8</sub> carbocyclyl groups as well as cyclononyl (C<sub>9</sub>), cyclononenyl (C<sub>9</sub>), cyclodecyl (C<sub>10</sub>), cyclodecenyl (C<sub>10</sub>), octahydro-1<i>H</i>-indenyl (C<sub>9</sub>), decahydronaphthalenyl (C<sub>10</sub>), spiro[4.5]decanyl (C<sub>10</sub>), and the like. As the foregoing examples illustrate, in certain embodiments, the carbocyclyl group is<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> either monocyclic ("monocyclic carbocyclyl") or contain a fused, bridged or spiro ring system such as a bicyclic system ("bicyclic carbocyclyl") and can be saturated or can be partially unsaturated. "Carbocyclyl" also includes ring systems wherein the carbocyclic ring, as defined above, is fused with one or more aryl or heteroaryl groups wherein the point of attachment is on the carbocyclic ring, and in such instances, the number of carbons continue to designate the number of carbons in the carbocyclic ring system. Unless otherwise specified, each instance of a carbocyclyl group is independently optionally substituted, <i>i.e.,</i> unsubstituted (an "unsubstituted carbocyclyl") or substituted (a "substituted carbocyclyl") with one or more substituents. In certain embodiments, the carbocyclyl group is unsubstituted C<sub>3-10</sub> carbocyclyl. In certain embodiments, the carbocyclyl group is substituted C<sub>3-10</sub> carbocyclyl.</p>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">In some embodiments, "carbocyclyl" is a monocyclic, saturated carbocyclyl group having from 3 to 10 ring carbon atoms ("C<sub>3-10</sub> cycloalkyl"). In some embodiments, a cycloalkyl group has 3 to 8 ring carbon atoms ("C<sub>3-8</sub> cycloalkyl"). In some embodiments, a cycloalkyl group has 3 to 6 ring carbon atoms ("C<sub>3-6</sub> cycloalkyl"). In some embodiments, a cycloalkyl group has 5 to 6 ring carbon atoms ("C<sub>5-6</sub> cycloalkyl"). In some embodiments, a cycloalkyl group has 5 to 10 ring carbon atoms ("C<sub>5-10</sub> cycloalkyl"). Examples of C<sub>5-6</sub> cycloalkyl groups include cyclopentyl (C<sub>5</sub>) and cyclohexyl (C<sub>5</sub>). Examples of C<sub>3-6</sub> cycloalkyl groups include the aforementioned C<sub>5-6</sub> cycloalkyl groups as well as cyclopropyl (C<sub>3</sub>) and cyclobutyl (C<sub>4</sub>). Examples of C<sub>3-8</sub> cycloalkyl groups include the aforementioned C<sub>3-6</sub> cycloalkyl groups as well as cycloheptyl (C<sub>7</sub>) and cyclooctyl (C<sub>8</sub>). Unless otherwise specified, each instance of a cycloalkyl group is independently unsubstituted (an "unsubstituted cycloalkyl") or substituted (a "substituted cycloalkyl") with one or more substituents. In certain embodiments, the cycloalkyl group is unsubstituted C<sub>3-10</sub> cycloalkyl. In certain embodiments, the cycloalkyl group is substituted C<sub>3-10</sub> cycloalkyl.</p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">"Heterocyclyl" or "heterocyclic" refers to a radical of a 3- to 10-membered non-aromatic ring system having ring carbon atoms and 1 to 4 ring heteroatoms, wherein each heteroatom is independently selected from nitrogen, oxygen, sulfur, boron, phosphorus, and silicon ("3-10 membered heterocyclyl"). In heterocyclyl groups that contain one or more nitrogen atoms, the point of attachment can be a carbon or nitrogen atom, as valency permits. A heterocyclyl group can either be monocyclic ("monocyclic heterocyclyl") or a fused, bridged, or spiro ring system, such as a bicyclic system ("bicyclic heterocyclyl"), and can be saturated or can be partially unsaturated. Heterocyclyl bicyclic ring systems can include one or more heteroatoms in one or both rings. "Heterocyclyl" also includes ring systems wherein<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> the heterocyclic ring, as defined above, is fused with one or more carbocyclyl groups wherein the point of attachment is either on the carbocyclyl or heterocyclic ring, or ring systems wherein the heterocyclic ring, as defined above, is fused with one or more aryl or heteroaryl groups, wherein the point of attachment is on the heterocyclic ring, and in such instances, the number of ring members continue to designate the number of ring members in the heterocyclic ring system. Unless otherwise specified, each instance of heterocyclyl is independently optionally substituted, <i>i.e.,</i> unsubstituted (an "unsubstituted heterocyclyl") or substituted (a "substituted heterocyclyl") with one or more substituents. In certain embodiments, the heterocyclyl group is unsubstituted 3-10 membered heterocyclyl. In certain embodiments, the heterocyclyl group is substituted 3-10 membered heterocyclyl.</p>
<p id="p0029" num="0029">In some embodiments, a heterocyclyl group is a 5-10 membered non-aromatic ring system having ring carbon atoms and 1-4 ring heteroatoms, wherein each heteroatom is independently selected from nitrogen, oxygen, sulfur, boron, phosphorus, and silicon ("5-10 membered heterocyclyl"). In some embodiments, a heterocyclyl group is a 5-8 membered non-aromatic ring system having ring carbon atoms and 1-4 ring heteroatoms, wherein each heteroatom is independently selected from nitrogen, oxygen, and sulfur ("5-8 membered heterocyclyl"). In some embodiments, a heterocyclyl group is a 5-6 membered non-aromatic ring system having ring carbon atoms and 1-4 ring heteroatoms, wherein each heteroatom is independently selected from nitrogen, oxygen, and sulfur ("5-6 membered heterocyclyl"). In some embodiments, the 5-6 membered heterocyclyl has 1-3 ring heteroatoms selected from nitrogen, oxygen, and sulfur. In some embodiments, the 5-6 membered heterocyclyl has 1-2 ring heteroatoms selected from nitrogen, oxygen, and sulfur. In some embodiments, the 5-6 membered heterocyclyl has one ring heteroatom selected from nitrogen, oxygen, and sulfur.</p>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">Exemplary 3-membered heterocyclyl groups containing one heteroatom include, without limitation, azirdinyl, oxiranyl, thiiranyl. Exemplary 4-membered heterocyclyl groups containing one heteroatom include, without limitation, azetidinyl, oxetanyl and thietanyl. Exemplary 5-membered heterocyclyl groups containing one heteroatom include, without limitation, tetrahydrofuranyl, dihydrofuranyl, tetrahydrothiophenyl, dihydrothiophenyl, pyrrolidinyl, dihydropyrrolyl, and pyrrolyl-2,5-dione. Exemplary 5-membered heterocyclyl groups containing two heteroatoms include, without limitation, dioxolanyl, oxasulfuranyl, disulfuranyl, and oxazolidin-2-one. Exemplary 5-membered heterocyclyl groups containing three heteroatoms include, without limitation, triazolinyl, oxadiazolinyl, and thiadiazolinyl. Exemplary 6-membered heterocyclyl groups containing one heteroatom include, without limitation, piperidinyl, tetrahydropyranyl, dihydropyridinyl, and thianyl. Exemplary 6-membered<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> heterocyclyl groups containing two heteroatoms include, without limitation, piperazinyl, morpholinyl, dithianyl, and dioxanyl. Exemplary 6-membered heterocyclyl groups containing two heteroatoms include, without limitation, triazinanyl. Exemplary 7-membered heterocyclyl groups containing one heteroatom include, without limitation, azepanyl, oxepanyl and thiepanyl. Exemplary 8-membered heterocyclyl groups containing one heteroatom include, without limitation, azocanyl, oxecanyl and thiocanyl. Exemplary 5-membered heterocyclyl groups fused to a C<sub>6</sub> aryl ring (also referred to herein as a 5,6-bicyclic heterocyclic ring) include, without limitation, indolinyl, isoindolinyl, dihydrobenzofuranyl, dihydrobenzothienyl, benzoxazolinonyl, and the like. Exemplary 6-membered heterocyclyl groups fused to an aryl ring (also referred to herein as a 6,6-bicyclic heterocyclic ring) include, without limitation, tetrahydroquinolinyl, tetrahydroisoquinolinyl, and the like.</p>
<p id="p0031" num="0031">"Aryl" refers to a radical of a monocyclic or polycyclic (<i>e.g</i>., bicyclic or tricyclic) 4n+2 aromatic ring system (<i>e.g</i>., having 6, 10, or 14 pi electrons shared in a cyclic array) having 6-14 ring carbon atoms and zero heteroatoms provided in the aromatic ring system ("C<sub>6-14</sub> aryl"). In some embodiments, an aryl group has six ring carbon atoms ("C<sub>6</sub> aryl"; <i>e.g.,</i> phenyl). In some embodiments, an aryl group has ten ring carbon atoms ("C<sub>10</sub> aryl"; <i>e.g.,</i> naphthyl such as 1-naphthyl and 2-naphthyl). In some embodiments, an aryl group has fourteen ring carbon atoms ("C<sub>14</sub> aryl"; <i>e.g</i>., anthracyl). "Aryl" also includes ring systems wherein the aryl ring, as defined above, is fused with one or more carbocyclyl or heterocyclyl groups wherein the radical or point of attachment is on the aryl ring, and in such instances, the number of carbon atoms continue to designate the number of carbon atoms in the aryl ring system. Unless otherwise specified, each instance of an aryl group is independently optionally substituted, <i>i.e.,</i> unsubstituted (an "unsubstituted aryl") or substituted (a "substituted aryl") with one or more substituents. In certain embodiments, the aryl group is unsubstituted C<sub>6-14</sub> aryl. In certain embodiments, the aryl group is substituted C<sub>6-14</sub> aryl.</p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032">"Aralkyl" is a subset of alkyl and aryl and refers to an optionally substituted alkyl group substituted by an optionally substituted aryl group. In certain embodiments, the aralkyl is optionally substituted benzyl. In certain embodiments, the aralkyl is benzyl. In certain embodiments, the aralkyl is optionally substituted phenethyl. In certain embodiments, the aralkyl is phenethyl.</p>
<p id="p0033" num="0033">"Heteroaryl" refers to a radical of a 5-10 membered monocyclic or bicyclic 4n+2 aromatic ring system (<i>e.g</i>., having 6 or 10 pi electrons shared in a cyclic array) having ring carbon atoms and 1-4 ring heteroatoms provided in the aromatic ring system, wherein each heteroatom is independently selected from nitrogen, oxygen and sulfur ("5-10 membered<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> heteroaryl"). In heteroaryl groups that contain one or more nitrogen atoms, the point of attachment can be a carbon or nitrogen atom, as valency permits. Heteroaryl bicyclic ring systems can include one or more heteroatoms in one or both rings. "Heteroaryl" includes ring systems wherein the heteroaryl ring, as defined above, is fused with one or more carbocyclyl or heterocyclyl groups wherein the point of attachment is on the heteroaryl ring, and in such instances, the number of ring members continue to designate the number of ring members in the heteroaryl ring system. "Heteroaryl" also includes ring systems wherein the heteroaryl ring, as defined above, is fused with one or more aryl groups wherein the point of attachment is either on the aryl or heteroaryl ring, and in such instances, the number of ring members designates the number of ring members in the fused (aryl/heteroaryl) ring system. Bicyclic heteroaryl groups wherein one ring does not contain a heteroatom (<i>e.g</i>., indolyl, quinolinyl, carbazolyl, and the like) the point of attachment can be on either ring, <i>i.e.,</i> either the ring bearing a heteroatom <i>(e.g.,</i> 2-indolyl) or the ring that does not contain a heteroatom (<i>e.g.,</i> 5-indolyl).</p>
<p id="p0034" num="0034">In some embodiments, a heteroaryl group is a 5-10 membered aromatic ring system having ring carbon atoms and 1-4 ring heteroatoms provided in the aromatic ring system, wherein each heteroatom is independently selected from nitrogen, oxygen, and sulfur ("5-10 membered heteroaryl"). In some embodiments, a heteroaryl group is a 5-8 membered aromatic ring system having ring carbon atoms and 1-4 ring heteroatoms provided in the aromatic ring system, wherein each heteroatom is independently selected from nitrogen, oxygen, and sulfur ("5-8 membered heteroaryl"). In some embodiments, a heteroaryl group is a 5-6 membered aromatic ring system having ring carbon atoms and 1-4 ring heteroatoms provided in the aromatic ring system, wherein each heteroatom is independently selected from nitrogen, oxygen, and sulfur ("5-6 membered heteroaryl"). In some embodiments, the 5-6 membered heteroaryl has 1-3 ring heteroatoms selected from nitrogen, oxygen, and sulfur. In some embodiments, the 5-6 membered heteroaryl has 1-2 ring heteroatoms selected from nitrogen, oxygen, and sulfur. In some embodiments, the 5-6 membered heteroaryl has 1 ring heteroatom selected from nitrogen, oxygen, and sulfur. Unless otherwise specified, each instance of a heteroaryl group is independently optionally substituted, <i>i.e.,</i> unsubstituted (an "unsubstituted heteroaryl") or substituted (a "substituted heteroaryl") with one or more substituents. In certain embodiments, the heteroaryl group is unsubstituted 5-14 membered heteroaryl. In certain embodiments, the heteroaryl group is substituted 5-14 membered heteroaryl.<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></p>
<p id="p0035" num="0035">Exemplary 5-membered heteroaryl groups containing one heteroatom include, without limitation, pyrrolyl, furanyl, and thiophenyl. Exemplary 5-membered heteroaryl groups containing two heteroatoms include, without limitation, imidazolyl, pyrazolyl, oxazolyl, isoxazolyl, thiazolyl, and isothiazolyl. Exemplary 5-membered heteroaryl groups containing three heteroatoms include, without limitation, triazolyl, oxadiazolyl, and thiadiazolyl. Exemplary 5-membered heteroaryl groups containing four heteroatoms include, without limitation, tetrazolyl. Exemplary 6-membered heteroaryl groups containing one heteroatom include, without limitation, pyridinyl. Exemplary 6-membered heteroaryl groups containing two heteroatoms include, without limitation, pyridazinyl, pyrimidinyl, and pyrazinyl. Exemplary 6-membered heteroaryl groups containing three or four heteroatoms include, without limitation, triazinyl and tetrazinyl, respectively. Exemplary 7-membered heteroaryl groups containing one heteroatom include, without limitation, azepinyl, oxepinyl, and thiepinyl. Exemplary 5,6-bicyclic heteroaryl groups include, without limitation, indolyl, isoindolyl, indazolyl, benzotriazolyl, benzothiophenyl, isobenzothiophenyl, benzofuranyl, benzoisofuranyl, benzimidazolyl, benzoxazolyl, benzisoxazolyl, benzoxadiazolyl, benzthiazolyl, benzisothiazolyl, benzthiadiazolyl, indolizinyl, and purinyl. Exemplary 6,6-bicyclic heteroaryl groups include, without limitation, naphthyridinyl, pteridinyl, quinolinyl, isoquinolinyl, cinnolinyl, quinoxalinyl, phthalazinyl, and quinazolinyl.</p>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">"Heteroaralkyl" is a subset of alkyl and heteroaryl and refers to an optionally substituted alkyl group substituted by an optionally substituted heteroaryl group.</p>
<p id="p0037" num="0037">"Unsaturated" or "partially unsaturated" refers to a group that includes at least one double or triple bond. A "partially unsaturated" ring system is further intended to encompass rings having multiple sites of unsaturation, but is not intended to include aromatic groups <i>(e.g.,</i> aryl or heteroaryl groups). Likewise, "saturated" refers to a group that does not contain a double or triple bond, <i>i.e.,</i> contains all single bonds.</p>
<p id="p0038" num="0038">Alkyl, alkenyl, alkynyl, carbocyclyl, heterocyclyl, aryl, and heteroaryl groups, which are divalent bridging groups, are further referred to using the suffix -ene, <i>e.g.,</i> alkylene, alkenylene, alkynylene, carbocyclylene, heterocyclylene, arylene, and heteroarylene.</p>
<p id="p0039" num="0039">An atom, moiety, or group described herein may be unsubstituted or substituted, as valency permits, unless otherwise provided expressly. The term "optionally substituted" refers to substituted or unsubstituted.</p>
<p id="p0040" num="0040">A group is optionally substituted unless expressly provided otherwise. The term "optionally substituted" refers to being substituted or unsubstituted. In certain embodiments, alkyl, alkenyl, alkynyl, carbocyclyl, heterocyclyl, aryl, and heteroaryl groups are optionally<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> substituted (<i>e.g</i>., "substituted" or "unsubstituted" alkyl, "substituted" or "unsubstituted" alkenyl, "substituted" or "unsubstituted" alkynyl, "substituted" or "unsubstituted" carbocyclyl, "substituted" or "unsubstituted" heterocyclyl, "substituted" or "unsubstituted" aryl or "substituted" or "unsubstituted" heteroaryl group). In general, the term "substituted", whether preceded by the term "optionally" or not, means that at least one hydrogen present on a group <i>(e.g.,</i> a carbon or nitrogen atom) is replaced with a permissible substituent, <i>e.g.,</i> a substituent which upon substitution results in a stable compound, <i>e.g.,</i> a compound which does not spontaneously undergo transformation such as by rearrangement, cyclization, elimination, or other reaction. Unless otherwise indicated, a "substituted" group has a substituent at one or more substitutable positions of the group, and when more than one position in any given structure is substituted, the substituent is either the same or different at each position. The term "substituted" is contemplated to include substitution with all permissible substituents of organic compounds, any of the substituents described herein that results in the formation of a stable compound. The present disclosure contemplates any and all such combinations in order to arrive at a stable compound. For purposes of this disclosure, heteroatoms such as nitrogen may have hydrogen substituents and/or any suitable substituent as described herein which satisfy the valencies of the heteroatoms and results in the formation of a stable moiety. In certain embodiments, the substituent is a carbon atom substituent. In certain embodiments, the substituent is a nitrogen atom substituent. In certain embodiments, the substituent is an oxygen atom substituent. In certain embodiments, the substituent is a sulfur atom substituent.</p>
<p id="p0041" num="0041">Exemplary carbon atom substituents include, but are not limited to, halogen, -CN, - NO<sub>2</sub>, -N<sub>3</sub>, -SO<sub>2</sub>H, -SO<sub>3</sub>H, -OH, -OR<sup>aa</sup>, -ON(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -N(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -N(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>3</sub><sup>+</sup>X<sup>-</sup>, -N(OR<sup>cc</sup>)R<sup>bb</sup>, - SH, -SR<sup>aa</sup>, -SSR<sup>cc</sup>, -C(=O)R<sup>aa</sup>, -CO<sub>2</sub>H, -CHO, -C(OR<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -CO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>aa</sup>, -OC(=O)R<sup>aa</sup>, - OCO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=O)N(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -OC(=O)N(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -NR<sup>bb</sup>C(=O)R<sup>aa</sup>, -NR<sup>bb</sup>CO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>aa</sup>, - NR<sup>bb</sup>C(=O)N(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -C(=NR<sup>bb</sup>)R<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=NR<sup>bb</sup>)OR<sup>aa</sup>, -OC(=NR<sup>bb</sup>)R<sup>aa</sup>, -OC(=NR<sup>bb</sup>)OR<sup>aa</sup>, - C(=NR<sup>bb</sup>)N(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -OC(=NR<sup>bb</sup>)N(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -NR<sup>bb</sup>C(=NR<sup>bb</sup>)N(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -C(=O)NR<sup>bb</sup>SO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>aa</sup>, - NR<sup>bb</sup>SO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>aa</sup>, -SO<sub>2</sub>N(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -SO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>aa</sup>, -SO<sub>2</sub>OR<sup>aa</sup>, -OSO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>aa</sup>, -S(=O)R<sup>aa</sup>, -OS(=O)R<sup>aa</sup>, - Si(R<sup>aa</sup>)<sub>3</sub>, -OSi(R<sup>aa</sup>)<sub>3</sub> -C(=S)N(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -C(=O)SR<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=S)SR<sup>aa</sup>, -SC(=S)SR<sup>aa</sup>, -SC(=O)SR<sup>aa</sup>, -OC(=O)SR<sup>aa</sup>, -SC(=O)OR<sup>aa</sup>, -SC(=O)R<sup>aa</sup>, -P(=O)(R<sup>aa</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -P(=O)(OR<sup>cc</sup>)2, -OP(=O)(R<sup>aa</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, - OP(=O)(OR<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -P(=O)(N(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>)<sub>2</sub>, -OP(=O)(N(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>)<sub>2</sub>, -NR<sup>bb</sup>P(=O)(R<sup>aa</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, - NR<sup>bb</sup>P(=O)(OR<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -NR<sup>bb</sup>P(=O)(N(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>)<sub>2</sub>, -P(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -P(OR<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -P(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>3</sub><sup>+</sup>X<sup>-</sup>, -P(OR<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>3</sub><sup>+</sup>X<sup>-</sup>, -P(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>4</sub>, -P(OR<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>4</sub>, -OP(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -OP(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>3</sub><sup>+</sup>X<sup>-</sup>, -OP(OR<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -OP(OR<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>3</sub><sup>+</sup>X<sup>-</sup>, -OP(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>4</sub>, -OP(OR<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>4</sub>, -B(R<sup>aa</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -B(OR<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -BR<sup>aa</sup>(OR<sup>cc</sup>), C<sub>1-10</sub> alkyl, C<sub>1-10</sub> perhaloalkyl, C<sub>2-10</sub> alkenyl,<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> C<sub>2-10</sub> alkynyl, C<sub>3-10</sub> carbocyclyl, 3-14 membered heterocyclyl, C<sub>6-14</sub> aryl, and 5-14 membered heteroaryl, wherein each alkyl, alkenyl, alkynyl, carbocyclyl, heterocyclyl, aryl, and heteroaryl is independently substituted with 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, or 5 R<sup>dd</sup> groups; wherein X- is a counterion;
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>or two geminal hydrogens on a carbon atom are replaced with the group =O, =S, =NN(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, =NNR<sup>bb</sup>C(=O)R<sup>aa</sup>, =NNR<sup>bb</sup>C(=O)OR<sup>aa</sup>, =NNR<sup>bb</sup>S(=O)<sub>2</sub>R<sup>aa</sup>, =NR<sup>bb</sup>, or =NOR<sup>cc</sup>;</li>
<li>each instance of R<sup>aa</sup> is, independently, selected from C<sub>1-10</sub> alkyl, C<sub>1-10</sub> perhaloalkyl, C<sub>2-10</sub> alkenyl, C<sub>2-10</sub> alkynyl, C<sub>3-10</sub> carbocyclyl, 3-14 membered heterocyclyl, C<sub>6-14</sub> aryl, and 5-14 membered heteroaryl, or two R<sup>aa</sup> groups are joined to form a 3-14 membered heterocyclyl or 5-14 membered heteroaryl ring, wherein each alkyl, alkenyl, alkynyl, carbocyclyl, heterocyclyl, aryl, and heteroaryl is independently substituted with 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, or 5 R<sup>dd</sup> groups;</li>
<li>each instance of R<sup>bb</sup> is, independently, selected from hydrogen, -OH, -OR<sup>aa</sup>, - N(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -CN, -C(=O)R<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=O)N(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -CO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>aa</sup>, -SO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=NR<sup>cc</sup>)OR<sup>aa</sup>, - C(=NR<sup>cc</sup>)N(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -SO<sub>2</sub>N(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -SO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>cc</sup>, -SO<sub>2</sub>OR<sup>cc</sup>, -SOR<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=S)N(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -C(=O)SR<sup>cc</sup>, - C(=S)SR<sup>cc</sup>, -P(=O)(R<sup>aa</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -P(=O)(OR<sup>cc</sup>)2, -P(=O)(N(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>)<sub>2</sub>, C<sub>1-10</sub> alkyl, C<sub>1-10</sub> perhaloalkyl, C<sub>2-10</sub> alkenyl, C<sub>2-10</sub> alkynyl, C<sub>3-10</sub> carbocyclyl, 3-14 membered heterocyclyl, C<sub>6-14</sub> aryl, and 5-14 membered heteroaryl, or two R<sup>bb</sup> groups are joined to form a 3-14 membered heterocyclyl or 5-14 membered heteroaryl ring, wherein each alkyl, alkenyl, alkynyl, carbocyclyl, heterocyclyl, aryl, and heteroaryl is independently substituted with 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, or 5 R<sup>dd</sup> groups; wherein X<sup>-</sup> is a counterion;</li>
<li>each instance of R<sup>cc</sup> is, independently, selected from hydrogen, C<sub>1-10</sub> alkyl, C<sub>1-10</sub> perhaloalkyl, C<sub>2-10</sub> alkenyl, C<sub>2-10</sub> alkynyl, C<sub>3-10</sub> carbocyclyl, 3-14 membered heterocyclyl, C<sub>6-14</sub> aryl, and 5-14 membered heteroaryl, or two R<sup>cc</sup> groups are joined to form a 3-14 membered heterocyclyl or 5-14 membered heteroaryl ring, wherein each alkyl, alkenyl, alkynyl, carbocyclyl, heterocyclyl, aryl, and heteroaryl is independently substituted with 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, or 5 R<sup>dd</sup> groups;</li>
<li>each instance of R<sup>dd</sup> is, independently, selected from halogen, -CN, -NO<sub>2</sub>, -N<sub>3</sub>, - SO<sub>2</sub>H, -SO<sub>3</sub>H, -OH, -OR<sup>ee</sup>, -ON(R<sup>ff</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -N(R<sup>ff</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -N(R<sup>ff</sup>)<sub>3</sub><sup>+</sup>X<sup>-</sup>, -N(OR<sup>ee</sup>)R<sup>ff</sup>, -SH, -SR<sup>ee</sup>, - SSR<sup>ee</sup>, -C(=O)R<sup>ee</sup>, -CO<sub>2</sub>H, -CO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>ee</sup>, -OC(=O)R<sup>ee</sup>, -OCO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>ee</sup>, -C(=O)N(R<sup>ff</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, - OC(=O)N(R<sup>ff</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -NR<sup>ff</sup>C(=O)R<sup>ee</sup>, -NR<sup>ff</sup>CO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>ee</sup>, -NR<sup>ff</sup>C(=O)N(R<sup>ff</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -C(=NR<sup>ff</sup>)OR<sup>ee</sup>, - OC(=NR<sup>ff</sup>)R<sup>ee</sup>, -OC(=NR<sup>ff</sup>)OR<sup>ee</sup>, -C(=NR<sup>ff</sup>)N(R<sup>ff</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -OC(=NR<sup>ff</sup>)N(R<sup>ff</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, - NR<sup>ff</sup>C(=NR<sup>ff</sup>)N(R<sup>ff</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -NR<sup>ff</sup>SO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>ee</sup>, -SO<sub>2</sub>N(R<sup>ff</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -SO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>ee</sup>, -SO<sub>2</sub>OR<sup>ee</sup>, -OSO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>ee</sup>, -S(=O)R<sup>ee</sup>, -Si(R<sup>ee</sup>)<sub>3</sub>, -OSi(R<sup>ee</sup>)<sub>3</sub>, -C(=S)N(R<sup>ff</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -C(=O)SR<sup>ee</sup>, -C(=S)SR<sup>ee</sup>, -SC(=S)SR<sup>ee</sup>, -<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> P(=O)(OR<sup>ee</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -P(=O)(R<sup>ee</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -OP(=O)(R<sup>ee</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -OP(=O)(OR<sup>ee</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl, C<sub>1-6</sub> perhaloalkyl, C<sub>2-6</sub> alkenyl, C<sub>2-6</sub> alkynyl, C<sub>3-10</sub> carbocyclyl, 3-10 membered heterocyclyl, C<sub>6-10</sub> aryl, 5-10 membered heteroaryl, wherein each alkyl, alkenyl, alkynyl, carbocyclyl, heterocyclyl, aryl, and heteroaryl is independently substituted with 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, or 5 R<sup>gg</sup> groups, or two geminal R<sup>dd</sup> substituents can be joined to form =O or =S; wherein X<sup>-</sup> is a counterion;</li>
<li>each instance of R<sup>ee</sup> is, independently, selected from C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl, C<sub>1-6</sub> perhaloalkyl, C<sub>2-6</sub> alkenyl, C<sub>2-6</sub> alkynyl, C<sub>3-10</sub> carbocyclyl, C<sub>6-10</sub> aryl, 3-10 membered heterocyclyl, and 3-10 membered heteroaryl, wherein each alkyl, alkenyl, alkynyl, carbocyclyl, heterocyclyl, aryl, and heteroaryl is independently substituted with 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, or 5 R<sup>gg</sup> groups;</li>
<li>each instance of R<sup>ff</sup> is, independently, selected from hydrogen, C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl, C<sub>1-6</sub> perhaloalkyl, C<sub>2-6</sub> alkenyl, C<sub>2-6</sub> alkynyl, C<sub>3-10</sub> carbocyclyl, 3-10 membered heterocyclyl, C<sub>6-10</sub> aryl and 5-10 membered heteroaryl, or two R<sup>ff</sup> groups are joined to form a 3-14 membered heterocyclyl or 5-14 membered heteroaryl ring, wherein each alkyl, alkenyl, alkynyl, carbocyclyl, heterocyclyl, aryl, and heteroaryl is independently substituted with 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, or 5 R<sup>gg</sup> groups; and</li>
<li>each instance of R<sup>gg</sup> is, independently, halogen, -CN, -NO<sub>2</sub>, -N<sub>3</sub>, -SO<sub>2</sub>H, -SO<sub>3</sub>H, - OH, -OC<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl, -ON(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl)<sub>2</sub>, -N(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl)<sub>2</sub>, -N(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl)<sub>3</sub><sup>+</sup>X<sup>-</sup>, -NH(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl)<sub>2</sub><sup>+</sup>X<sup>-</sup>, -NH<sub>2</sub>(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl) <sup>+</sup>X<sup>-</sup>, -NH<sub>3</sub><sup>+</sup>X<sup>-</sup>, -N(OC<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl)(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl), -N(OH)(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl), -NH(OH), -SH, -SC<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl, -SS(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl), -C(=O)(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl), -CO<sub>2</sub>H, -CO<sub>2</sub>(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl), -OC(=O)(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl), -OCO<sub>2</sub>(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl), -C(=O)NH<sub>2</sub>, -C(=O)N(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl)<sub>2</sub>, - OC(=O)NH(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl), -NHC(=O)(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl), -N(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl)C(=O)(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl), - NHCO<sub>2</sub>(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl), -NHC(=O)N(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl)<sub>2</sub>, -NHC(=O)NH(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl), -NHC(=O)NH<sub>2</sub>, - C(=NH)O(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl),-OC(=NH)(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl), -OC(=NH)OC<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl, -C(=NH)N(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl)<sub>2</sub>, -C(=NH)NH(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl), -C(=NH)NH<sub>2</sub>, -OC(=NH)N(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl)<sub>2</sub>, -OC(NH)NH(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl), -OC(NH)NH<sub>2</sub>, -NHC(NH)N(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl)<sub>2</sub>, -NHC(=NH)NH<sub>2</sub>, -NHSO<sub>2</sub>(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl), - SO<sub>2</sub>N(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl)<sub>2</sub>, -SO<sub>2</sub>NH(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl), -SO<sub>2</sub>NH<sub>2</sub>, -SO<sub>2</sub>C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl, -SO<sub>2</sub>OC<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl, - OSO<sub>2</sub>C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl, -SOC<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl, -Si(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl)<sub>3</sub>, -OSi(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl)<sub>3</sub> -C(=S)N(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl)<sub>2</sub>, C(=S)NH(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl), C(=S)NH<sub>2</sub>, -C(=O)S(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl), -C(=S)SC<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl, -SC(=S)SC<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl, -P(=O)(OC<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl)<sub>2</sub>, -P(=O)(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl)<sub>2</sub>, -OP(=O)(C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl)<sub>2</sub>, -OP(=O)(OC<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl)<sub>2</sub>, C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl, C<sub>1-6</sub> perhaloalkyl, C<sub>2-6</sub> alkenyl, C<sub>2-6</sub> alkynyl, C<sub>3-10</sub> carbocyclyl, C<sub>6-10</sub> aryl, 3-10 membered heterocyclyl, 5-10 membered heteroaryl; or two geminal R<sup>gg</sup> substituents can be joined to form =O or =S; wherein X<sup>-</sup> is a counterion.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0042" num="0042">In certain embodiments, exemplary carbon atom substituents include, but are not limited to, halogen, -OH, -CO<sub>2</sub>H, -CHO, -CO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=O)N(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -ON(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, acyl, C<sub>1-10</sub><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> alkyl, C<sub>1-10</sub> perhaloalkyl, C<sub>2-10</sub> alkenyl, C<sub>2-10</sub> alkynyl, C<sub>3-10</sub> carbocyclyl, 3-14 membered heterocyclyl, C<sub>6-14</sub> aryl, and 5-14 membered heteroaryl, wherein each alkyl, alkenyl, alkynyl, carbocyclyl, heterocyclyl, aryl, and heteroaryl is independently substituted;<br/>
or two geminal hydrogens on a carbon atom are replaced with the group =O, or =S;<br/>
each instance of R<sup>aa</sup> is, independently, selected from C<sub>1-10</sub> alkyl, C<sub>1-10</sub> perhaloalkyl, C<sub>2-10</sub> alkenyl, C<sub>2-10</sub> alkynyl, C<sub>3-10</sub> carbocyclyl, 3-14 membered heterocyclyl, C<sub>6-14</sub> aryl, and 5-14 membered heteroaryl, or two R<sup>aa</sup> groups are joined to form a 3-14 membered heterocyclyl or 5-14 membered heteroaryl ring, wherein each alkyl, alkenyl, alkynyl, carbocyclyl, heterocyclyl, aryl, and heteroaryl is independently substituted; and<br/>
each instance of R<sup>bb</sup> is, independently selected from hydrogen, -OH, C<sub>1-10</sub> alkyl, C<sub>1-10</sub> perhaloalkyl, C<sub>2-10</sub> alkenyl, C<sub>2-10</sub> alkynyl, C<sub>3-10</sub> carbocyclyl, 3-14 membered heterocyclyl, C<sub>6-14</sub> aryl, and 5-14 membered heteroaryl, or two R<sup>bb</sup> groups are joined to form a 3-14 membered heterocyclyl or 5-14 membered heteroaryl ring, wherein each alkyl, alkenyl, alkynyl, carbocyclyl, heterocyclyl, aryl, and heteroaryl is independently substituted.</p>
<p id="p0043" num="0043">A "counterion" or "anionic counterion" is a negatively charged group associated with a cationic quaternary amino group in order to maintain electronic neutrality. An anionic counterion may be monovalent (i.e., including one formal negative charge). An anionic counterion may also be multivalent (i.e., including more than one formal negative charge), such as divalent or trivalent. Exemplary counterions include halide ions (<i>e.g.,</i> F<sup>-</sup>, Cl<sup>-</sup>, Br<sup>-</sup>, I<sup>-</sup>), NO<sub>3</sub><sup>-</sup>, ClO<sub>4</sub><sup>-</sup>, OH<sup>-</sup>, H<sub>2</sub>PO<sub>4</sub><sup>-</sup>, HCO<sub>3</sub><sup>-</sup>, HSO<sub>4</sub><sup>-</sup>, sulfonate ions (e.g., methansulfonate, trifluoromethanesulfonate, <i>p</i>-toluenesulfonate, benzenesulfonate, 10-camphor sulfonate, naphthalene-2-sulfonate, naphthalene-1-sulfonic acid-5-sulfonate, ethan-1-sulfonic acid-2-sulfonate, and the like), carboxylate ions (<i>e.g</i>., acetate, propanoate, benzoate, glycerate, lactate, tartrate, glycolate, gluconate, and the like), BF<sub>4</sub><sup>-</sup>, PF<sub>4</sub><sup>-</sup>, PF<sub>6</sub><sup>-</sup>, AsF<sub>6</sub><sup>-</sup>, SbF<sub>6</sub><sup>-</sup>, B[3,5-(CF<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub>C<sub>6</sub>H<sub>3</sub>]<sub>4</sub>]<sup>-</sup>, B(C<sub>6</sub>F<sub>5</sub>)<sub>4</sub><sup>-</sup>, BPh<sub>4</sub><sup>-</sup>, Al(OC(CF<sub>3</sub>)<sub>3</sub>)<sub>4</sub><sup>-</sup>, and carborane anions (<i>e.g.</i>, CB<sub>11</sub>H<sub>12</sub><sup>-</sup> or (HCB<sub>11</sub>Me<sub>5</sub>Br<sub>6</sub>)<sup>-</sup>). Exemplary counterions which may be multivalent include CO<sub>3</sub><sup>2-</sup>, HPO<sub>4</sub><sup>2-</sup>, PO<sub>4</sub><sup>3-</sup>, B<sub>4</sub>O<sub>7</sub><sup>2-</sup>, SO<sub>4</sub><sup>2-</sup>, S<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub><sup>2-</sup>, carboxylate anions (<i>e.g</i>., tartrate, citrate, fumarate, maleate, malate, malonate, gluconate, succinate, glutarate, adipate, pimelate, suberate, azelate, sebacate, salicylate, phthalates, aspartate, glutamate, and the like), and carboranes.</p>
<p id="p0044" num="0044">"Halo" or "halogen" refers to fluorine (fluoro, -F), chlorine (chloro, -Cl), bromine (bromo, -Br), or iodine (iodo, -I).</p>
<p id="p0045" num="0045">"Acyl" refers to a moiety selected from the group consisting of -C(=O)R<sup>aa</sup>,-CHO, - CO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=O)N(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -C(=NR<sup>bb</sup>)R<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=NR<sup>bb</sup>)OR<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=NR<sup>bb</sup>)N(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> C(=O)NR<sup>bb</sup>SO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=S)N(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -C(=O)SR<sup>aa</sup>, or -C(=S)SR<sup>aa</sup>, wherein R<sup>aa</sup> and R<sup>bb</sup> are as defined herein.</p>
<p id="p0046" num="0046">Nitrogen atoms can be substituted or unsubstituted as valency permits, and include primary, secondary, tertiary, and quaternary nitrogen atoms. Exemplary nitrogen atom substituents include, but are not limited to, hydrogen, -OH, -OR<sup>aa</sup>, -N(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -CN, - C(=O)R<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=O)N(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -CO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>aa</sup>, -SO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=NR<sup>bb</sup>)R<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=NR<sup>cc</sup>)OR<sup>aa</sup>, - C(=NR<sup>cc</sup>)N(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -SO<sub>2</sub>N(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -SO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>cc</sup>, -SO<sub>2</sub>OR<sup>cc</sup>, -SOR<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=S)N(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -C(=O)SR<sup>cc</sup>, - C(=S)SR<sup>cc</sup>, -P(=O)(OR<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -P(=O)(R<sup>aa</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -P(=O)(N(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>)<sub>2</sub>, C<sub>1-10</sub> alkyl, C<sub>1-10</sub> perhaloalkyl, C<sub>2-10</sub> alkenyl, C<sub>2-10</sub> alkynyl, C<sub>3-10</sub> carbocyclyl, 3-14 membered heterocyclyl, C<sub>6-14</sub> aryl, and 5-14 membered heteroaryl, or two R<sup>cc</sup> groups attached to a nitrogen atom are joined to form a 3-14 membered heterocyclyl or 5-14 membered heteroaryl ring, wherein each alkyl, alkenyl, alkynyl, carbocyclyl, heterocyclyl, aryl, and heteroaryl is independently substituted with 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, or 5 R<sup>dd</sup> groups, and wherein R<sup>aa</sup>, R<sup>bb</sup>, R<sup>cc</sup>, and R<sup>dd</sup> are as defined above.</p>
<p id="p0047" num="0047">In certain embodiments, the substituent present on a nitrogen atom is a nitrogen protecting group (also referred to as an amino protecting group). Nitrogen protecting groups include, but are not limited to, -OH, -OR<sup>aa</sup>, -N(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -C(=O)R<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=O)N(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -CO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>aa</sup>, -SO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=NR<sup>cc</sup>)R<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=NR<sup>cc</sup>)OR<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=NR<sup>cc</sup>)N(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -SO<sub>2</sub>N(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -SO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>cc</sup>, - SO<sub>2</sub>OR<sup>cc</sup>, -SOR<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=S)N(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -C(=O)SR<sup>cc</sup>, -C(=S)SR<sup>cc</sup>, C<sub>1-10</sub> alkyl (<i>e.g</i>., aralkyl, heteroaralkyl), C<sub>2-10</sub> alkenyl, C<sub>2-10</sub> alkynyl, C<sub>3-10</sub> carbocyclyl, 3-14 membered heterocyclyl, C<sub>6-14</sub> aryl, and 5-14 membered heteroaryl groups, wherein each alkyl, alkenyl, alkynyl, carbocyclyl, heterocyclyl, aralkyl, aryl, and heteroaryl is independently substituted with 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, or 5 R<sup>dd</sup> groups, and wherein R<sup>aa</sup>, R<sup>bb</sup>, R<sup>cc</sup> and R<sup>dd</sup> are as defined herein. Nitrogen protecting groups are well known in the art and include those described in detail in <nplcit id="ncit0011" npl-type="b"><text>Protecting Groups in Organic Synthesis, T. W. Greene and P. G. M. Wuts, 3rd edition, John Wiley &amp; Sons, 1999</text></nplcit>, incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p id="p0048" num="0048">For example, nitrogen protecting groups such as amide groups (<i>e.g.,</i> -C(=O)R<sup>aa</sup>) include, but are not limited to, formamide, acetamide, chloroacetamide, trichloroacetamide, trifluoroacetamide, phenylacetamide, 3-phenylpropanamide, picolinamide, 3-pyridylcarboxamide, <i>N</i>-benzoylphenylalanyl derivative, benzamide, <i>p</i>-phenylbenzamide, <i>o-</i>nitophenylacetamide, <i>o</i>-nitrophenoxyacetamide, acetoacetamide, (<i>N'-</i>dithiobenzyloxyacylamino)acetamide, 3-(<i>p</i>-hydroxyphenyl)propanamide, 3-(<i>o-</i>nitrophenyl)propanamide, 2-methyl-2-(<i>o</i>-nitrophenoxy)propanamide, 2-methyl-2-(<i>o-</i>phenylazophenoxy)propanamide, 4-chlorobutanamide, 3-methyl-3-nitrobutanamide, <i>o-</i>nitrocinnamide,<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> <i>N</i>-acetylmethionine derivative, <i>o</i>-nitrobenzamide, and <i>o-</i>(benzoyloxymethyl)benzamide.</p>
<p id="p0049" num="0049">Nitrogen protecting groups such as carbamate groups (<i>e.g.,</i> -C(=O)OR<sup>aa</sup>) include, but are not limited to, methyl carbamate, ethylcarbamate, 9-fluorenylmethyl carbamate (Fmoc), 9-(2-sulfo)fluorenylmethyl carbamate, 9-(2,7-dibromo)fluoroenylmethyl carbamate, 2,7-di<i>t-</i>butyl-[9-(10,10-dioxo-10,10,10,10-tetrahydrothioxanthyl)]methyl carbamate (DBD-Tmoc), 4-methoxyphenacyl carbamate (Phenoc), 2,2,2-trichloroethyl carbamate (Troc), 2-trimethylsilylethyl carbamate (Teoc), 2-phenylethyl carbamate (hZ), 1-(1-adamantyl)-1-methylethyl carbamate (Adpoc), 1,1-dimethyl-2-haloethyl carbamate, 1,1-dimethyl-2,2-dibromoethyl carbamate (DB-<i>t</i>-BOC), 1,1-dimethyl-2,2,2-trichloroethyl carbamate (TCBOC), 1-methyl-1-(4-biphenylyl)ethyl carbamate (Bpoc), 1-(3,5-di-<i>t</i>-butylphenyl)-1-methylethyl carbamate (<i>t-</i>Bumeoc), 2-(2'- and 4'-pyridyl)ethyl carbamate (Pyoc), <i>2-</i>(<i>N,N-</i>dicyclohexylcarboxamido)ethyl carbamate, <i>t</i>-butyl carbamate (BOC or Boc), 1-adamantyl carbamate (Adoc), vinyl carbamate (Voc), allyl carbamate (Alloc), 1-isopropylallyl carbamate (Ipaoc), cinnamyl carbamate (Coc), 4-nitrocinnamyl carbamate (Noc), 8-quinolyl carbamate, <i>N</i>-hydroxypiperidinyl carbamate, alkyldithio carbamate, benzyl carbamate (Cbz), <i>p</i>-methoxybenzyl carbamate (Moz), <i>p</i>-nitobenzyl carbamate, <i>p</i>-bromobenzyl carbamate, <i>p-</i>chlorobenzyl carbamate, 2,4-dichlorobenzyl carbamate, 4-methylsulfinylbenzyl carbamate (Msz), 9-anthrylmethyl carbamate, diphenylmethyl carbamate, 2-methylthioethyl carbamate, 2-methylsulfonylethyl carbamate, 2-(<i>p</i>-toluenesulfonyl)ethyl carbamate, [2-(1,3-dithianyl)]methyl carbamate (Dmoc), 4-methylthiophenyl carbamate (Mtpc), 2,4-dimethylthiophenyl carbamate (Bmpc), 2-phosphonioethyl carbamate (Peoc), 2-triphenylphosphonioisopropyl carbamate (Ppoc), 1,1-dimethyl-2-cyanoethyl carbamate, <i>m-</i>chloro-<i>p</i>-acyloxybenzyl carbamate, <i>p</i>-(dihydroxyboryl)benzyl carbamate, 5-benzisoxazolylmethyl carbamate, 2-(trifluoromethyl)-6-chromonylmethyl carbamate (Tcroc), <i>m</i>-nitrophenyl carbamate, 3,5-dimethoxybenzyl carbamate, <i>o</i>-nitrobenzyl carbamate, 3,4-dimethoxy-6-nitrobenzyl carbamate, phenyl(<i>o</i>-nitrophenyl)methyl carbamate, <i>t</i>-amyl carbamate, <i>S</i>-benzyl thiocarbamate, <i>p-</i>cyanobenzyl carbamate, cyclobutyl carbamate, cyclohexyl carbamate, cyclopentyl carbamate, cyclopropylmethyl carbamate, <i>p-</i>decyloxybenzyl carbamate, 2,2-dimethoxyacylvinyl carbamate, <i>o-(N,N-</i>dimethylcarboxamido)benzyl carbamate, 1,1-dimethyl-3-(<i>N,N</i>-dimethylcarboxamido)propyl carbamate, 1,1-dimethylpropynyl carbamate, di(2-pyridyl)methyl carbamate, 2-furanylmethyl carbamate, 2-iodoethyl carbamate, isoborynl carbamate, isobutyl carbamate,<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> isonicotinyl carbamate, <i>p</i>-(<i>p'</i>-methoxyphenylazo)benzyl carbamate, 1-methylcyclobutyl carbamate, 1-methylcyclohexyl carbamate, 1-methyl-1-cyclopropylmethyl carbamate, 1-methyl-1-(3,5-dimethoxyphenyl)ethyl carbamate, 1-methyl-1-(<i>p</i>-phenylazophenyl)ethyl carbamate, 1-methyl-1-phenylethyl carbamate, 1-methyl-1-(4-pyridyl)ethyl carbamate, phenyl carbamate, <i>p</i>-(phenylazo)benzyl carbamate, 2,4,6-tri-<i>t</i>-butylphenyl carbamate, 4-(trimethylammonium)benzyl carbamate, and 2,4,6-trimethylbenzyl carbamate.</p>
<p id="p0050" num="0050">Nitrogen protecting groups such as sulfonamide groups <i>(e.g.,</i> -S(=O)<sub>2</sub>R<sup>aa</sup>) include, but are not limited to, <i>p</i>-toluenesulfonamide (Ts), benzenesulfonamide, 2,3,6,-trimethyl-4-methoxybenzenesulfonamide (Mtr), 2,4,6-trimethoxybenzenesulfonamide (Mtb), 2,6-dimethyl-4-methoxybenzenesulfonamide (Pme), 2,3,5,6-tetramethyl-4-methoxybenzenesulfonamide (Mte), 4-methoxybenzenesulfonamide (Mbs), 2,4,6-trimethylbenzenesulfonamide (Mts), 2,6-dimethoxy-4-methylbenzenesulfonamide (iMds), 2,2,5,7,8-pentamethylchroman-6-sulfonamide (Pmc), methanesulfonamide (Ms), β-trimethylsilylethanesulfonamide (SES), 9-anthracenesulfonamide, 4-(4',8'-dimethoxynaphthylmethyl)benzenesulfonamide (DNMBS), benzylsulfonamide, trifluoromethylsulfonamide, and phenacylsulfonamide.</p>
<p id="p0051" num="0051">Other nitrogen protecting groups include, but are not limited to, phenothiazinyl-(10)-acyl derivative, <i>N'</i>-<i>p</i>-toluenesulfonylaminoacyl derivative, <i>N'</i>-phenylaminothioacyl derivative, <i>N</i>-benzoylphenylalanyl derivative, <i>N</i>-acetylmethionine derivative, 4,5-diphenyl-3-oxazolin-2-one, <i>N</i>-phthalimide, <i>N</i>-dithiasuccinimide (Dts), <i>N</i>-2,3-diphenylmaleimide, <i>N</i>-2,5-dimethylpyrrole, <i>N</i>-1,1,4,4-tetramethyldisilylazacyclopentane adduct (STABASE), 5-substituted 1,3-dimethyl-1,3,5-triazacyclohexan-2-one, 5-substituted 1,3-dibenzyl-1,3,5-triazacyclohexan-2-one, 1-substituted 3,5-dinitro-4-pyridone, <i>N</i>-methylamine, <i>N-</i>allylamine, <i>N</i>-[2-(trimethylsilyl)ethoxy]methylamine (SEM), <i>N</i>-3-acetoxypropylamine, <i>N-</i>(1-isopropyl-4-nitro-2-oxo-3-pyroolin-3-yl)amine, quaternary ammonium salts, <i>N-</i>benzylamine, <i>N</i>-di(4-methoxyphenyl)methylamine, <i>N</i>-5-dibenzosuberylamine, <i>N-</i>triphenylmethylamine (Tr), <i>N</i>-[(4-methoxyphenyl)diphenylmethyl]amine (MMTr), N-9-phenylfluorenylamine (PhF), <i>N</i>-2,7-dichloro-9-fluorenylmethyleneamine, <i>N-</i>ferrocenylmethylamino (Fcm), <i>N</i>-2-picolylamino <i>N'</i>-oxide, <i>N</i>-1,1-dimethylthiomethyleneamine, <i>N</i>-benzylideneamine, <i>N-p</i>-methoxybenzylideneamine, <i>N-</i>diphenylmethyleneamine, <i>N</i>-[(2-pyridyl)mesityl]methyleneamine, <i>N</i>-(<i>N',N'-</i>dimethylaminomethylene)amine, <i>N,N'</i>-isopropylidenediamine, <i>N-p</i>-nitrobenzylideneamine, <i>N</i>-salicylideneamine, <i>N-</i>5-chlorosalicylideneamine, <i>N</i>-(5-chloro-2-hydroxyphenyl)phenylmethyleneamine,<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> <i>N</i>-cyclohexylideneamine, <i>N</i>-(5,5-dimethyl-3-oxo-1-cyclohexenyl)amine, <i>N</i>-borane derivative, <i>N</i>-diphenylborinic acid derivative, <i>N-</i>[phenyl(pentaacylchromium- or tungsten)acyl]amine, <i>N</i>-copper chelate, <i>N</i>-zinc chelate, <i>N-</i>nitroamine, <i>N</i>-nitrosoamine, amine <i>N</i>-oxide, diphenylphosphinamide (Dpp), dimethylthiophosphinamide (Mpt), diphenylthiophosphinamide (Ppt), dialkyl phosphoramidates, dibenzyl phosphoramidate, diphenyl phosphoramidate, benzenesulfenamide, <i>o</i>-nitrobenzenesulfenamide (Nps), 2,4-dinitrobenzenesulfenamide, pentachlorobenzenesulfenamide, 2-nitro-4-methoxybenzenesulfenamide, triphenylmethylsulfenamide, and 3-nitropyridinesulfenamide (Npys).</p>
<p id="p0052" num="0052">Exemplary oxygen atom substituents include, but are not limited to, -R<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=O)SR<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=O)R<sup>aa</sup>, -CO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=O)N(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -C(=NR<sup>bb</sup>)R<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=NR<sup>bb</sup>)OR<sup>aa</sup>, - C(=NR<sup>bb</sup>)N(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -S(=O)R<sup>aa</sup>, -SO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>aa</sup>, -Si(R<sup>aa</sup>)<sub>3</sub>, -P(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -P(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>3</sub><sup>+</sup>X<sup>-</sup>, -P(OR<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -P(OR<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>3</sub><sup>+</sup>X<sup>-</sup>, -P(=O)(R<sup>aa</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -P(=O)(OR<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, and -P(=O)(N(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>)<sub>2,</sub> wherein X<sup>-</sup>, R<sup>aa</sup>, R<sup>bb</sup>, and R<sup>cc</sup> are as defined herein. In certain embodiments, the oxygen atom substituent present on an oxygen atom is an oxygen protecting group (also referred to as a hydroxyl protecting group). Oxygen protecting groups are well known in the art and include those described in detail in <nplcit id="ncit0012" npl-type="b"><text>Protecting Groups in Organic Synthesis, T. W. Greene and P. G. M. Wuts, 3rd edition, John Wiley &amp; Sons, 1999</text></nplcit>, incorporated herein by reference. Exemplary oxygen protecting groups include, but are not limited to, methyl, <i>t</i>-butyloxycarbonyl (BOC or Boc), methoxylmethyl (MOM), methylthiomethyl (MTM), <i>t</i>-butylthiomethyl, (phenyldimethylsilyl)methoxymethyl (SMOM), benzyloxymethyl (BOM), <i>p-</i>methoxybenzyloxymethyl (PMBM), (4-methoxyphenoxy)methyl (<i>p</i>-AOM), guaiacolmethyl (GUM), <i>t</i>-butoxymethyl, 4-pentenyloxymethyl (POM), siloxymethyl, 2-methoxyethoxymethyl (MEM), 2,2,2-trichloroethoxymethyl, bis(2-chloroethoxy)methyl, 2-(trimethylsilyl)ethoxymethyl (SEMOR), tetrahydropyranyl (THP), 3-bromotetrahydropyranyl, tetrahydrothiopyranyl, 1-methoxycyclohexyl, 4-methoxytetrahydropyranyl (MTHP), 4-methoxytetrahydrothiopyranyl, 4-methoxytetrahydrothiopyranyl S,S-dioxide, 1-[(2-chloro-4-methyl)phenyl]-4-methoxypiperidin-4-yl (CTMP), 1,4-dioxan-2-yl, tetrahydrofuranyl, tetrahydrothiofuranyl, 2,3,3a,4,5,6,7,7a-octahydro-7,8,8-trimethyl-4,7-methanobenzofuran-2-yl, 1-ethoxyethyl, 1-(2-chloroethoxy)ethyl, 1-methyl-1-methoxyethyl, 1-methyl-1-benzyloxyethyl, 1-methyl-1-benzyloxy-2-fluoroethyl, 2,2,2-trichloroethyl, 2-trimethylsilylethyl, 2-(phenylselenyl)ethyl, <i>t</i>-butyl, allyl, <i>p</i>-chlorophenyl, <i>p</i>-methoxyphenyl, 2,4-dinitrophenyl, benzyl (Bn), <i>p</i>-methoxybenzyl, 3,4-dimethoxybenzyl, <i>o</i>-nitrobenzyl, <i>p</i>-nitrobenzyl, <i>p-</i>halobenzyl,<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> 2,6-dichlorobenzyl, <i>p</i>-cyanobenzyl, <i>p</i>-phenylbenzyl, 2-picolyl, 4-picolyl, 3-methyl-2-picolyl <i>N</i>-oxido, diphenylmethyl, <i>p,p'</i>-dinitrobenzhydryl, 5-dibenzosuberyl, triphenylmethyl, α-naphthyldiphenylmethyl, <i>p</i>-methoxyphenyldiphenylmethyl, di(<i>p-</i>methoxyphenyl)phenylmethyl, tri(<i>p</i>-methoxyphenyl)methyl, 4-(4'-bromophenacyloxyphenyl)diphenylmethyl, 4,4',4"-tris(4,5-dichlorophthalimidophenyl)methyl, 4,4',4"-tris(levulinoyloxyphenyl)methyl, 4,4',4"-tris(benzoyloxyphenyl)methyl, 3-(imidazol-1-yl)bis(4',4"-dimethoxyphenyl)methyl, 1,1-bis(4-methoxyphenyl)-1'-pyrenylmethyl, 9-anthryl, 9-(9-phenyl)xanthenyl, 9-(9-phenyl-10-oxo)anthryl, 1,3-benzodisulfuran-2-yl, benzisothiazolyl S,S-dioxido, trimethylsilyl (TMS), triethylsilyl (TES), triisopropylsilyl (TIPS), dimethylisopropylsilyl (IPDMS), diethylisopropylsilyl (DEIPS), dimethylthexylsilyl, <i>t</i>-butyldimethylsilyl (TBDMS), <i>t-</i>butyldiphenylsilyl (TBDPS), tribenzylsilyl, tri-<i>p</i>-xylylsilyl, triphenylsilyl, diphenylmethylsilyl (DPMS), <i>t</i>-butylmethoxyphenylsilyl (TBMPS), formate, benzoylformate, acetate, chloroacetate, dichloroacetate, trichloroacetate, trifluoroacetate, methoxyacetate, triphenylmethoxyacetate, phenoxyacetate, <i>p</i>-chlorophenoxyacetate, 3-phenylpropionate, 4-oxopentanoate (levulinate), 4,4-(ethylenedithio)pentanoate (levulinoyldithioacetal), pivaloate, adamantoate, crotonate, 4-methoxycrotonate, benzoate, <i>p-</i>phenylbenzoate, 2,4,6-trimethylbenzoate (mesitoate), alkyl methyl carbonate, 9-fluorenylmethyl carbonate (Fmoc), alkyl ethyl carbonate, alkyl 2,2,2-trichloroethyl carbonate (Troc), 2-(trimethylsilyl)ethyl carbonate (TMSEC), 2-(phenylsulfonyl) ethyl carbonate (Psec), 2-(triphenylphosphonio) ethyl carbonate (Peoc), alkyl isobutyl carbonate, alkyl vinyl carbonate alkyl allyl carbonate, alkyl <i>p-</i>nitrophenyl carbonate, alkyl benzyl carbonate, alkyl <i>p</i>-methoxybenzyl carbonate, alkyl 3,4-dimethoxybenzyl carbonate, alkyl o-nitrobenzyl carbonate, alkyl <i>p</i>-nitrobenzyl carbonate, alkyl <i>S</i>-benzyl thiocarbonate, 4-ethoxy-1-napththyl carbonate, methyl dithiocarbonate, 2-iodobenzoate, 4-azidobutyrate, 4-nitro-4-methylpentanoate, <i>o</i>-(dibromomethyl)benzoate, 2-formylbenzenesulfonate, 2-(methylthiomethoxy)ethyl, 4-(methylthiomethoxy)butyrate, 2-(methylthiomethoxymethyl)benzoate, 2,6-dichloro-4-methylphenoxyacetate, 2,6-dichloro-4-(1,1,3,3-tetramethylbutyl)phenoxyacetate, 2,4-bis(1,1-dimethylpropyl)phenoxyacetate, chlorodiphenylacetate, isobutyrate, monosuccinoate, (<i>E</i>)-2-methyl-2-butenoate, o-(methoxyacyl)benzoate, α-naphthoate, nitrate, alkyl <i>N,N,N',N'-</i>tetramethylphosphorodiamidate, alkyl <i>N</i>-phenylcarbamate, borate, dimethylphosphinothioyl,<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> alkyl 2,4-dinitrophenylsulfenate, sulfate, methanesulfonate (mesylate), benzylsulfonate, and tosylate (Ts).</p>
<p id="p0053" num="0053">Exemplary sulfur atom substituents include, but are not limited to, -R<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=O)SR<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=O)R<sup>aa</sup>, -CO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=O)N(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -C(=NR<sup>bb</sup>)R<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=NR<sup>bb</sup>)OR<sup>aa</sup>, -C(=NR<sup>bb</sup>)N(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, - S(=O)R<sup>aa</sup>, -SO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>aa</sup>, -Si(R<sup>aa</sup>)<sub>3</sub>, -P(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -P(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>3</sub>, -P(=O)<sub>2</sub>R<sup>aa</sup>, -P(=O)(R<sup>aa</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -P(=O)(OR<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, - P(=O)<sub>2</sub>N(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, and -P(=O)(NR<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, wherein R<sup>aa</sup>, R<sup>bb</sup>, and R<sup>cc</sup> are as defined herein. In certain embodiments, the sulfur atom substituent present on a sulfur atom is a sulfur protecting group (also referred to as a thiol protecting group). Sulfur protecting groups are well known in the art and include those described in detail in <nplcit id="ncit0013" npl-type="b"><text>Protecting Groups in Organic Synthesis, T. W. Greene and P. G. M. Wuts, 3rd edition, John Wiley &amp; Sons, 1999</text></nplcit>, incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p id="p0054" num="0054">A "hydrocarbon chain" refers to a substituted or unsubstituted divalent alkyl, alkenyl, or alkynyl group. A hydrocarbon chain includes (1) one or more chains of carbon atoms immediately between the two radicals of the hydrocarbon chain; (2) optionally one or more hydrogen atoms on the chain(s) of carbon atoms; and (3) optionally one or more substituents ("non-chain substituents," which are not hydrogen) on the chain(s) of carbon atoms. A chain of carbon atoms consists of consecutively connected carbon atoms ("chain atoms" or "carbon units") and does not include hydrogen atoms or heteroatoms. However, a non-chain substituent of a hydrocarbon chain may include any atoms, including hydrogen atoms, carbon atoms, and heteroatoms. For example, hydrocarbon chain -C<sup>A</sup>H(C<sup>B</sup>H<sub>2</sub>C<sup>C</sup>H<sub>3</sub>)- includes one chain atom C<sup>A</sup>, one hydrogen atom on C<sup>A</sup>, and non-chain substituent -(C<sup>B</sup>H<sub>2</sub>C<sup>C</sup>H<sub>3</sub>). The term "C<sub>x</sub> hydrocarbon chain," wherein x is a positive integer, refers to a hydrocarbon chain that includes x number of chain atom(s) between the two radicals of the hydrocarbon chain. If there is more than one possible value of x, the smallest possible value of x is used for the definition of the hydrocarbon chain. For example, -CH(C<sub>2</sub>H<sub>5</sub>)- is a C<sub>1</sub> hydrocarbon chain, and
<chemistry id="chem0008" num="0008"><img id="ib0008" file="imgb0008.tif" wi="24" he="15" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
is a C<sub>3</sub> hydrocarbon chain. When a range of values is used, the meaning of the range is as described herein. For example, a C<sub>3-10</sub> hydrocarbon chain refers to a hydrocarbon chain where the number of chain atoms of the shortest chain of carbon atoms immediately between the two radicals of the hydrocarbon chain is 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, or 10. A hydrocarbon chain may be saturated (e.g., -(CH<sub>2</sub>)<sub>4</sub>-). A hydrocarbon chain may also be unsaturated and include one or more C=C and/or C≡C bonds anywhere in the hydrocarbon chain. For instance, -CH=CH-(CH<sub>2</sub>)<sub>2</sub>-, -CH<sub>2</sub>-C≡C-CH<sub>2</sub>-, and -C≡C-CH=CH- are all<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> examples of a unsubstituted and unsaturated hydrocarbon chain. In certain embodiments, the hydrocarbon chain is unsubstituted (<i>e.g</i>., -C≡C- or -(CH<sub>2</sub>)<sub>4</sub>-). In certain embodiments, the hydrocarbon chain is substituted (<i>e.g</i>., -CH(C<sub>2</sub>H<sub>5</sub>)- and -CF<sub>2</sub>-). Any two substituents on the hydrocarbon chain may be joined to form an optionally substituted carbocyclyl, optionally substituted heterocyclyl, optionally substituted aryl, or optionally substituted heteroaryl ring. For instance,
<chemistry id="chem0009" num="0009"><img id="ib0009" file="imgb0009.tif" wi="124" he="21" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
and
<chemistry id="chem0010" num="0010"><img id="ib0010" file="imgb0010.tif" wi="24" he="15" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
are all examples of a hydrocarbon chain. In contrast, in certain embodiments,
<chemistry id="chem0011" num="0011"><img id="ib0011" file="imgb0011.tif" wi="54" he="22" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
are not within the scope of the hydrocarbon chains described herein. When a chain atom of a C<sub>x</sub> hydrocarbon chain is replaced with a heteroatom, the resulting group is referred to as a C<sub>x</sub> hydrocarbon chain wherein a chain atom is replaced with a heteroatom, as opposed to a C<sub>x-1</sub> hydrocarbon chain. For example,
<chemistry id="chem0012" num="0012"><img id="ib0012" file="imgb0012.tif" wi="24" he="7" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
is a C<sub>3</sub> hydrocarbon chain wherein one chain atom is replaced with an oxygen atom.</p>
<p id="p0055" num="0055">The term "leaving group" is given its ordinary meaning in the art of synthetic organic chemistry and refers to an atom or a group capable of being displaced by a nucleophile. Examples of suitable leaving groups include, but are not limited to, halogen (such as F, Cl, Br, or I (iodine)), alkoxycarbonyloxy, aryloxycarbonyloxy, alkanesulfonyloxy, arenesulfonyloxy, alkyl-carbonyloxy (<i>e.g</i>., acetoxy), arylcarbonyloxy, aryloxy, methoxy, <i>N,O</i>-dimethylhydroxylamino, pixyl, and haloformates. Exemplary leaving groups include, but are not limited to, activated substituted hydroxyl groups (<i>e.g.,</i> -OC(=O)SR<sup>aa</sup>, - OC(=O)R<sup>aa</sup>, -OCO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>aa</sup>, -OC(=O)N(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -OC(=NR<sup>bb</sup>)R<sup>aa</sup>, -OC(=NR<sup>bb</sup>)OR<sup>aa</sup>, - OC(=NR<sup>bb</sup>)N(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -OS(=O)R<sup>aa</sup>, -OSO<sub>2</sub>R<sup>aa</sup>, -OP(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -OP(R<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>3</sub>, -OP(=O)<sub>2</sub>R<sup>aa</sup>, - OP(=O)(R<sup>aa</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -OP(=O)(OR<sup>cc</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, -OP(=O)<sub>2</sub>N(R<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, and -OP(=O)(NR<sup>bb</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, wherein R<sup>aa</sup>, R<sup>bb</sup>, and R<sup>cc</sup> are as defined herein). In some cases, the leaving group is a sulfonic acid ester, such as toluenesulfonate (tosylate, -OTs), methanesulfonate (mesylate, -OMs), p-bromobenzenesulfonyloxy (brosylate, -OBs), -OS(=O)<sub>2</sub>(CF<sub>2</sub>)<sub>3</sub>CF<sub>3</sub> (nonaflate, -ONf), or trifluoromethanesulfonate (triflate, -OTf). In some cases, the leaving group is a brosylate, such as <i>p</i>-bromobenzenesulfonyloxy. In some cases, the leaving group is a nosylate, such as 2-nitrobenzenesulfonyloxy. In some embodiments, the leaving group is a sulfonate-containing<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> group. In some embodiments, the leaving group is a tosylate group. The leaving group may also be a phosphineoxide (<i>e.g</i>., formed during a Mitsunobu reaction) or an internal leaving group such as an epoxide or cyclic sulfate. Other non-limiting examples of leaving groups are water, ammonia, alcohols, ether moieties, thioether moieties, zinc halides, magnesium moieties, diazonium salts, and copper moieties.</p>
<p id="p0056" num="0056">The term "pharmaceutically acceptable salt" refers to those salts which are, within the scope of sound medical judgment, suitable for use in contact with the tissues of humans and lower animals without undue toxicity, irritation, allergic response, and the like, and are commensurate with a reasonable benefit/risk ratio. Pharmaceutically acceptable salts are well known in the art. For example, <nplcit id="ncit0014" npl-type="s"><text>Berge et al., describe pharmaceutically acceptable salts in detail in J. Pharmaceutical Sciences, 1977, 66, 1-19</text></nplcit>, incorporated herein by reference. Pharmaceutically acceptable salts of the compounds described herein include those derived from suitable inorganic and organic acids and bases. Examples of pharmaceutically acceptable, nontoxic acid addition salts are salts of an amino group formed with inorganic acids such as hydrochloric acid, hydrobromic acid, phosphoric acid, sulfuric acid, and perchloric acid or with organic acids such as acetic acid, oxalic acid, maleic acid, tartaric acid, citric acid, succinic acid, or malonic acid or by using other methods known in the art such as ion exchange. Other pharmaceutically acceptable salts include adipate, alginate, ascorbate, aspartate, benzenesulfonate, benzoate, bisulfate, borate, butyrate, camphorate, camphorsulfonate, citrate, cyclopentanepropionate, digluconate, dodecylsulfate, ethanesulfonate, formate, fumarate, glucoheptonate, glycerophosphate, gluconate, hemisulfate, heptanoate, hexanoate, hydroiodide, 2-hydroxy-ethanesulfonate, lactobionate, lactate, laurate, lauryl sulfate, malate, maleate, malonate, methanesulfonate, 2-naphthalenesulfonate, nicotinate, nitrate, oleate, oxalate, palmitate, pamoate, pectinate, persulfate, 3-phenylpropionate, phosphate, picrate, pivalate, propionate, stearate, succinate, sulfate, tartrate, thiocyanate, p-toluenesulfonate, undecanoate, valerate salts, and the like. Salts derived from appropriate bases include alkali metal, alkaline earth metal, ammonium and N<sup>+</sup>(C<sub>1-4</sub> alkyl)<sub>4</sub><sup>-</sup> salts. Representative alkali or alkaline earth metal salts include sodium, lithium, potassium, calcium, magnesium, and the like. Further pharmaceutically acceptable salts include, when appropriate, nontoxic ammonium, quaternary ammonium, and amine cations formed using counterions such as halide, hydroxide, carboxylate, sulfate, phosphate, nitrate, lower alkyl sulfonate, and aryl sulfonate.</p>
<p id="p0057" num="0057">The term "solvate" refers to forms of the compound that are associated with a solvent, usually by a solvolysis reaction. This physical association may include hydrogen bonding.<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> Conventional solvents include water, methanol, ethanol, acetic acid, DMSO, THF, diethyl ether, and the like. The compounds described herein may be prepared, <i>e.g.,</i> in crystalline form, and may be solvated. Suitable solvates include pharmaceutically acceptable solvates and further include both stoichiometric solvates and non-stoichiometric solvates. In certain instances, the solvate will be capable of isolation, for example, when one or more solvent molecules are incorporated in the crystal lattice of a crystalline solid. "Solvate" encompasses both solution-phase and isolatable solvates. Representative solvates include hydrates, ethanolates, and methanolates.</p>
<p id="p0058" num="0058">The term "hydrate" refers to a compound that is associated with water. Typically, the number of the water molecules contained in a hydrate of a compound is in a definite ratio to the number of the compound molecules in the hydrate. Therefore, a hydrate of a compound may be represented, for example, by the general formula R·x H<sub>2</sub>O, wherein R is the compound, and x is a number greater than 0. A given compound may form more than one type of hydrate, including, <i>e.g</i>., monohydrates (x is 1), lower hydrates (x is a number greater than 0 and smaller than 1, <i>e.g</i>., hemihydrates (R·0.5 H<sub>2</sub>O)), and polyhydrates (x is a number greater than 1, <i>e.g</i>., dihydrates (R·2 H<sub>2</sub>O) and hexahydrates (R·6 H<sub>2</sub>O)).</p>
<p id="p0059" num="0059">The term "tautomers" or "tautomeric" refers to two or more interconvertible compounds resulting from at least one formal migration of a hydrogen atom and at least one change in valency <i>(e.g.,</i> a single bond to a double bond, a triple bond to a single bond, or <i>vice versa</i>)<i>.</i> The exact ratio of the tautomers depends on several factors, including temperature, solvent, and pH. Tautomerizations <i>(i.e.,</i> the reaction providing a tautomeric pair) may catalyzed by acid or base. Exemplary tautomerizations include keto-to-enol, amide-to-imide, lactam-to-lactim, enamine-to-imine, and enamine-to-(a different enamine) tautomerizations.</p>
<p id="p0060" num="0060">It is also to be understood that compounds that have the same molecular formula but differ in the nature or sequence of bonding of their atoms or the arrangement of their atoms in space are termed "isomers". Isomers that differ in the arrangement of their atoms in space are termed "stereoisomers".</p>
<p id="p0061" num="0061">Stereoisomers that are not mirror images of one another are termed "diastereomers" and those that are non-superimposable mirror images of each other are termed "enantiomers". When a compound has an asymmetric center, for example, it is bonded to four different groups, a pair of enantiomers is possible. An enantiomer can be characterized by the absolute configuration of its asymmetric center and is described by the R- and S-sequencing rules of Cahn and Prelog, or by the manner in which the molecule rotates the plane of polarized light<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> and designated as dextrorotatory or levorotatory <i>(i.e.,</i> as (+) or (-)-isomers respectively). A chiral compound can exist as either individual enantiomer or as a mixture thereof. A mixture containing equal proportions of the enantiomers is called a "racemic mixture".</p>
<p id="p0062" num="0062">The term "polymorphs" refers to a crystalline form of a compound (or a salt, hydrate, or solvate thereof) in a particular crystal packing arrangement. All polymorphs have the same elemental composition. Different crystalline forms usually have different X-ray diffraction patterns, infrared spectra, melting points, density, hardness, crystal shape, optical and electrical properties, stability, and solubility. Recrystallization solvent, rate of crystallization, storage temperature, and other factors may cause one crystal form to dominate. Various polymorphs of a compound can be prepared by crystallization under different conditions.</p>
<p id="p0063" num="0063">The term "prodrugs" refers to compounds that have cleavable groups and become by solvolysis or under physiological conditions the compounds described herein, which are pharmaceutically active <i>in vivo.</i> Such examples include, but are not limited to, choline ester derivatives and the like, N-alkylmorpholine esters and the like. Other derivatives of the compounds described herein have activity in both their acid and acid derivative forms, but in the acid sensitive form often offer advantages of solubility, tissue compatibility, or delayed release in the mammalian organism (see, <nplcit id="ncit0015" npl-type="b"><text>Bundgard, H., Design of Prodrugs, pp. 7-9, 21-24, Elsevier, Amsterdam 1985</text></nplcit>). Prodrugs include acid derivatives well known to practitioners of the art, such as, for example, esters prepared by reaction of the parent acid with a suitable alcohol, or amides prepared by reaction of the parent acid compound with a substituted or unsubstituted amine, or acid anhydrides, or mixed anhydrides. Simple aliphatic or aromatic esters, amides, and anhydrides derived from acidic groups pendant on the compounds described herein are particular prodrugs. In some cases it is desirable to prepare double ester type prodrugs such as (acyloxy)alkyl esters or ((alkoxycarbonyl)oxy)alkylesters. C<sub>1</sub>-C<sub>8</sub> alkyl, C<sub>2</sub>-C<sub>8</sub> alkenyl, C<sub>2</sub>-C<sub>8</sub> alkynyl, aryl, C<sub>7</sub>-C<sub>12</sub> substituted aryl, and C<sub>7</sub>-C<sub>12</sub> arylalkyl esters of the compounds described herein may be preferred.</p>
<p id="p0064" num="0064">The term "inhibition", "inhibiting", "inhibit," or "inhibitor" refer to the ability of a compound to reduce, slow, halt or prevent activity of a particular biological process (e.g., activity of a bromodomain and/or a bromodomain-containing protein) in a cell relative to vehicle.</p>
<p id="p0065" num="0065">When a compound, pharmaceutical composition, method, use, or kit is referred to as "selectively," "specifically," or "competitively" binding a first protein or a first chromatin, the compound, pharmaceutical composition, method, use, or kit binds the first protein or the first chromatin with a higher binding affinity (<i>e.g</i>., not less than about 2-fold, not less than<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --> about 5-fold, not less than about 10-fold, not less than about 30-fold, not less than about 100-fold, not less than about 1,000-fold, or not less than about 10,000-fold) than binding a second protein or second chromatin that is different from the first protein and the first chromatin. When a compound, pharmaceutical composition, method, use, or kit is referred to as "selectively," "specifically," or "competitively" modulating (<i>e.g.</i>, increasing or inhibiting) the activity of a bromodomain-containing protein, the compound, pharmaceutical composition, method, use, or kit modulates the activity of the bromodomain-containing protein to a greater extent <i>(e.g.,</i> not less than about 2-fold, not less than about 5-fold, not less than about 10-fold, not less than about 30-fold, not less than about 100-fold, not less than about 1,000-fold, or not less than about 10,000-fold) than the activity of at least one protein that is different from the bromodomain-containing protein.</p>
<p id="p0066" num="0066">The term "aberrant activity" refers to activity deviating from normal activity. The term "increased activity" refers to activity higher than normal activity.</p>
<p id="p0067" num="0067">The terms "composition" and "formulation" are used interchangeably.</p>
<p id="p0068" num="0068">A "subject" to which administration is contemplated refers to a human <i>(i.e.,</i> male or female of any age group, <i>e.g.,</i> pediatric subject <i>(e.g.,</i> infant, child, or adolescent) or adult subject (<i>e.g</i>., young adult, middle-aged adult, or senior adult)) or non-human animal. In certain embodiments, the non-human animal is a mammal <i>(e.g.,</i> primate <i>(e.g.,</i> cynomolgus monkey or rhesus monkey), commercially relevant mammal (<i>e.g</i>., cattle, pig, horse, sheep, goat, cat, or dog), or bird (<i>e.g.</i>, commercially relevant bird, such as chicken, duck, goose, or turkey)). In certain embodiments, the non-human animal is a fish, reptile, or amphibian. The non-human animal may be a male or female at any stage of development. The non-human animal may be a transgenic animal or genetically engineered animal. A "patient" refers to a human subject in need of treatment of a disease. The subject may also be a plant. In certain embodiments, the plant is a land plant. In certain embodiments, the plant is a non-vascular land plant. In certain embodiments, the plant is a vascular land plant. In certain embodiments, the plant is a seed plant. In certain embodiments, the plant is a cultivated plant. In certain embodiments, the plant is a dicot. In certain embodiments, the plant is a monocot. In certain embodiments, the plant is a flowering plant. In some embodiments, the plant is a cereal plant, <i>e.g.,</i> maize, corn, wheat, rice, oat, barley, rye, or millet. In some embodiments, the plant is a legume, <i>e.g.,</i> a bean plant, <i>e.g.,</i> soybean plant. In some embodiments, the plant is a tree or shrub.</p>
<p id="p0069" num="0069">The term "biological sample" refers to any sample including tissue samples (such as tissue sections and needle biopsies of a tissue); cell samples (<i>e.g</i>., cytological smears (such as<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --> Pap or blood smears) or samples of cells obtained by microdissection); samples of whole organisms (such as samples of yeasts or bacteria); or cell fractions, fragments or organelles (such as obtained by lysing cells and separating the components thereof by centrifugation or otherwise). Other examples of biological samples include blood, serum, urine, semen, fecal matter, cerebrospinal fluid, interstitial fluid, mucous, tears, sweat, pus, biopsied tissue (<i>e.g.</i>, obtained by a surgical biopsy or needle biopsy), nipple aspirates, milk, vaginal fluid, saliva, swabs (such as buccal swabs), or any material containing biomolecules that is derived from a first biological sample. In certain embodiments, "viability" refers to cell viability.</p>
<p id="p0070" num="0070">The terms "administer," "administering," or "administration" refers to implanting, absorbing, ingesting, injecting, inhaling, or otherwise introducing a compound described herein, or a composition thereof, in or on a subject.</p>
<p id="p0071" num="0071">The terms "treatment," "treat," and "treating" refer to reversing, alleviating, delaying the onset of, or inhibiting the progress of a disease described herein. In some embodiments, treatment may be administered after one or more signs or symptoms of the disease have developed or have been observed. In other embodiments, treatment may be administered in the absence of signs or symptoms of the disease. For example, treatment may be administered to a susceptible subject prior to the onset of symptoms (<i>e.g</i>., in light of a history of symptoms and/or in light of exposure to a pathogen). Treatment may also be continued after symptoms have resolved, for example, to delay or prevent recurrence.</p>
<p id="p0072" num="0072">The terms "condition," "disease," and "disorder" are used interchangeably.</p>
<p id="p0073" num="0073">An "effective amount" of a compound described herein refers to an amount sufficient to elicit the desired biological response, <i>i.e.,</i> treating the condition. As will be appreciated by those of ordinary skill in this art, the effective amount of a compound described herein may vary depending on such factors as the desired biological endpoint, the pharmacokinetics of the compound, the condition being treated, the mode of administration, and the age and health of the subject. In certain embodiments, an effective amount is a therapeutically effective amount. In certain embodiments, an effective amount is a prophylactic treatment. In certain embodiments, an effective amount is the amount of a compound described herein in a single dose. In certain embodiments, an effective amount is the combined amounts of a compound described herein in multiple doses.</p>
<p id="p0074" num="0074">A "therapeutically effective amount" of a compound described herein is an amount sufficient to provide a therapeutic benefit in the treatment of a condition or to delay or minimize one or more symptoms associated with the condition. A therapeutically effective amount of a compound means an amount of therapeutic agent, alone or in combination with<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --> other therapies, which provides a therapeutic benefit in the treatment of the condition. The term "therapeutically effective amount" can encompass an amount that improves overall therapy, reduces or avoids symptoms, signs, or causes of the condition, and/or enhances the therapeutic efficacy of another therapeutic agent.</p>
<p id="p0075" num="0075">A "prophylactically effective amount" of a compound described herein is an amount sufficient to prevent a condition, or one or more symptoms associated with the condition or prevent its recurrence. A prophylactically effective amount of a compound means an amount of a therapeutic agent, alone or in combination with other agents, which provides a prophylactic benefit in the prevention of the condition. The term "prophylactically effective amount" can encompass an amount that improves overall prophylaxis or enhances the prophylactic efficacy of another prophylactic agent.</p>
<p id="p0076" num="0076">A "proliferative disease" refers to a disease that occurs due to abnormal growth or extension by the multiplication of cells (<nplcit id="ncit0016" npl-type="b"><text>Walker, Cambridge Dictionary of Biology; Cambridge University Press: Cambridge, UK, 1990</text></nplcit>). A proliferative disease may be associated with: 1) the pathological proliferation of normally quiescent cells; 2) the pathological migration of cells from their normal location (<i>e.g.,</i> metastasis of neoplastic cells); 3) the pathological expression of proteolytic enzymes such as the matrix metalloproteinases (<i>e.g</i>., collagenases, gelatinases, and elastases); or 4) the pathological angiogenesis as in proliferative retinopathy and tumor metastasis. Exemplary proliferative diseases include cancers <i>(i.e.,</i> "malignant neoplasms"), benign neoplasms, angiogenesis, inflammatory diseases, and autoimmune diseases.</p>
<p id="p0077" num="0077">The term "angiogenesis" refers to the physiological process through which new blood vessels form from pre-existing vessels. Angiogenesis is distinct from vasculogenesis, which is the <i>de novo</i> formation of endothelial cells from mesoderm cell precursors. The first vessels in a developing embryo form through vasculogenesis, after which angiogenesis is responsible for most blood vessel growth during normal or abnormal development. Angiogenesis is a vital process in growth and development, as well as in wound healing and in the formation of granulation tissue. However, angiogenesis is also a fundamental step in the transition of tumors from a benign state to a malignant one, leading to the use of angiogenesis inhibitors in the treatment of cancer. Angiogenesis may be chemically stimulated by angiogenic proteins, such as growth factors <i>(e.g.,</i> VEGF). "Pathological angiogenesis" refers to abnormal <i>(e.g.,</i> excessive or insufficient) angiogenesis that amounts to and/or is associated with a disease.</p>
<p id="p0078" num="0078">The terms "neoplasm" and "tumor" are used herein interchangeably and refer to an abnormal mass of tissue wherein the growth of the mass surpasses and is not coordinated<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --> with the growth of a normal tissue. A neoplasm or tumor may be "benign" or "malignant," depending on the following characteristics: degree of cellular differentiation (including morphology and functionality), rate of growth, local invasion, and metastasis. A "benign neoplasm" is generally well differentiated, has characteristically slower growth than a malignant neoplasm, and remains localized to the site of origin. In addition, a benign neoplasm does not have the capacity to infiltrate, invade, or metastasize to distant sites. Exemplary benign neoplasms include, but are not limited to, lipoma, chondroma, adenomas, acrochordon, senile angiomas, seborrheic keratoses, lentigos, and sebaceous hyperplasias. In some cases, certain "benign" tumors may later give rise to malignant neoplasms, which may result from additional genetic changes in a subpopulation of the tumor's neoplastic cells, and these tumors are referred to as "pre-malignant neoplasms." An exemplary pre-malignant neoplasm is a teratoma. In contrast, a "malignant neoplasm" is generally poorly differentiated (anaplasia) and has characteristically rapid growth accompanied by progressive infiltration, invasion, and destruction of the surrounding tissue. Furthermore, a malignant neoplasm generally has the capacity to metastasize to distant sites. The term "metastasis," "metastatic," or "metastasize" refers to the spread or migration of cancerous cells from a primary or original tumor to another organ or tissue and is typically identifiable by the presence of a "secondary tumor" or "secondary cell mass" of the tissue type of the primary or original tumor and not of that of the organ or tissue in which the secondary (metastatic) tumor is located. For example, a prostate cancer that has migrated to bone is said to be metastasized prostate cancer and includes cancerous prostate cancer cells growing in bone tissue.</p>
<p id="p0079" num="0079">The term "cancer" refers to a class of diseases characterized by the development of abnormal cells that proliferate uncontrollably and have the ability to infiltrate and destroy normal body tissues. See, <i>e.g.,</i> <nplcit id="ncit0017" npl-type="b"><text>Stedman's Medical Dictionary, 25th ed.; Hensyl ed.; Williams &amp; Wilkins: Philadelphia, 1990</text></nplcit>. Exemplary cancers include, but are not limited to, hematological malignancies. Additional exemplary cancers include, but are not limited to, acoustic neuroma; adenocarcinoma; adrenal gland cancer; anal cancer; angiosarcoma (e.g., lymphangiosarcoma, lymphangioendotheliosarcoma, hemangiosarcoma); appendix cancer; benign monoclonal gammopathy; biliary cancer (<i>e.g</i>., cholangiocarcinoma); bladder cancer; breast cancer (<i>e.g.</i>, adenocarcinoma of the breast, papillary carcinoma of the breast, mammary cancer, medullary carcinoma of the breast); brain cancer (<i>e.g.</i>, meningioma, glioblastomas, glioma (<i>e.g</i>., astrocytoma, oligodendroglioma), medulloblastoma); bronchus cancer; carcinoid tumor; cervical cancer (<i>e.g</i>., cervical adenocarcinoma); choriocarcinoma; chordoma; craniopharyngioma; colorectal cancer <i>(e.g.,</i> colon cancer, rectal cancer, colorectal<!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --> adenocarcinoma); connective tissue cancer; epithelial carcinoma; ependymoma; endotheliosarcoma (<i>e.g</i>., Kaposi's sarcoma, multiple idiopathic hemorrhagic sarcoma); endometrial cancer <i>(e.g.,</i> uterine cancer, uterine sarcoma); esophageal cancer <i>(e.g.,</i> adenocarcinoma of the esophagus, Barrett's adenocarcinoma); Ewing's sarcoma; ocular cancer (<i>e.g</i>., intraocular melanoma, retinoblastoma); familiar hypereosinophilia; gall bladder cancer; gastric cancer (<i>e.g</i>., stomach adenocarcinoma); gastrointestinal stromal tumor (GIST); germ cell cancer; head and neck cancer (<i>e.g.,</i> head and neck squamous cell carcinoma, oral cancer <i>(e.g.,</i> oral squamous cell carcinoma), throat cancer <i>(e.g.,</i> laryngeal cancer, pharyngeal cancer, nasopharyngeal cancer, oropharyngeal cancer)); heavy chain disease (<i>e.g</i>., alpha chain disease, gamma chain disease, mu chain disease; hemangioblastoma; hypopharynx cancer; inflammatory myofibroblastic tumors; immunocytic amyloidosis; kidney cancer <i>(e.g.,</i> nephroblastoma <i>a.k.a.</i> Wilms' tumor, renal cell carcinoma); liver cancer <i>(e.g.,</i> hepatocellular cancer (HCC), malignant hepatoma); lung cancer (<i>e.g.</i>, bronchogenic carcinoma, small cell lung cancer (SCLC), non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC), adenocarcinoma of the lung); leiomyosarcoma (LMS); mastocytosis (<i>e.g.,</i> systemic mastocytosis); muscle cancer; myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS); mesothelioma; myeloproliferative disorder (MPD) <i>(e.g.,</i> polycythemia vera (PV), essential thrombocytosis (ET), agnogenic myeloid metaplasia (AMM) <i>a.k.a.</i> myelofibrosis (MF), chronic idiopathic myelofibrosis, chronic myelocytic leukemia (CML), chronic neutrophilic leukemia (CNL), hypereosinophilic syndrome (HES)); neuroblastoma; neurofibroma (<i>e.g.,</i> neurofibromatosis (NF) type 1 or type 2, schwannomatosis); neuroendocrine cancer (<i>e.g.,</i> gastroenteropancreatic neuroendoctrine tumor (GEP-NET), carcinoid tumor); osteosarcoma (<i>e.g.,bone</i> cancer); ovarian cancer <i>(e.g.,</i> cystadenocarcinoma, ovarian embryonal carcinoma, ovarian adenocarcinoma); papillary adenocarcinoma; pancreatic cancer (<i>e.g.,</i> pancreatic andenocarcinoma, intraductal papillary mucinous neoplasm (IPMN), Islet cell tumors); penile cancer (<i>e.g.,</i> Paget's disease of the penis and scrotum); pinealoma; primitive neuroectodermal tumor (PNT); plasma cell neoplasia; paraneoplastic syndromes; intraepithelial neoplasms; prostate cancer (<i>e.g.,</i> prostate adenocarcinoma); rectal cancer; rhabdomyosarcoma; salivary gland cancer; skin cancer <i>(e.g.,</i> squamous cell carcinoma (SCC), keratoacanthoma (KA), melanoma, basal cell carcinoma (BCC)); small bowel cancer <i>(e.g.,</i> appendix cancer); soft tissue sarcoma <i>(e.g.,</i> malignant fibrous histiocytoma (MFH), liposarcoma, malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumor (MPNST), chondrosarcoma, fibrosarcoma, myxosarcoma); sebaceous gland carcinoma; small intestine cancer; sweat gland carcinoma; synovioma; testicular cancer (<i>e.g.,</i> seminoma, testicular embryonal carcinoma); thyroid cancer (<i>e.g.,</i> papillary carcinoma of the thyroid,<!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --> papillary thyroid carcinoma (PTC), medullary thyroid cancer); urethral cancer; vaginal cancer; and vulvar cancer (<i>e.g.,</i> Paget's disease of the vulva).</p>
<p id="p0080" num="0080">The term "hematological malignancy" refers to tumors that affect blood, bone marrow, and/or lymph nodes. Exemplary hematological malignancies include, but are not limited to, leukemia, such as acute lymphocytic leukemia (ALL) <i>(e.g.,</i> B-cell ALL, T-cell ALL), acute myelocytic leukemia (AML) <i>(e.g.,</i> B-cell AML, T-cell AML), chronic myelocytic leukemia (CML) <i>(e.g.,</i> B-cell CML, T-cell CML), and chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL) <i>(e.g.,</i> B-cell CLL, T-cell CLL)); lymphoma, such as Hodgkin lymphoma (HL) <i>(e.g.,</i> B-cell HL, T-cell HL) and non-Hodgkin lymphoma (NHL) (<i>e.g.,</i> B-cell NHL, such as diffuse large cell lymphoma (DLCL) <i>(e.g.,</i> diffuse large B-cell lymphoma (DLBCL, <i>e.g</i>., activated B-cell (ABC) DLBCL (ABC-DLBCL))), follicular lymphoma, chronic lymphocytic leukemia/small lymphocytic lymphoma (CLL/SLL), mantle cell lymphoma (MCL), marginal zone B-cell lymphoma (<i>e.g.,</i> mucosa-associated lymphoid tissue (MALT) lymphoma, nodal marginal zone B-cell lymphoma, splenic marginal zone B-cell lymphoma), primary mediastinal B-cell lymphoma, Burkitt lymphoma, Waldenstrom's macroglobulinemia (WM, lymphoplasmacytic lymphoma), hairy cell leukemia (HCL), immunoblastic large cell lymphoma, precursor B-lymphoblastic lymphoma, central nervous system (CNS) lymphoma (<i>e.g.,</i> primary CNS lymphoma and secondary CNS lymphoma); and T-cell NHL, such as precursor T-lymphoblastic lymphoma/leukemia, peripheral T-cell lymphoma (PTCL) <i>(e.g.,</i> cutaneous T-cell lymphoma (CTCL) <i>(e.g.,</i> mycosis fungoides, Sezary syndrome), angioimmunoblastic T-cell lymphoma, extranodal natural killer T-cell lymphoma, enteropathy type T-cell lymphoma, subcutaneous panniculitis-like T-cell lymphoma, and anaplastic large cell lymphoma); lymphoma of an immune privileged site <i>(e.g.,</i> cerebral lymphoma, ocular lymphoma, lymphoma of the placenta, lymphoma of the fetus, testicular lymphoma); a mixture of one or more leukemia/lymphoma as described above; myelodysplasia; and multiple myeloma (MM).</p>
<p id="p0081" num="0081">The term "inflammatory disease" refers to a disease caused by, resulting from, or resulting in inflammation. The term "inflammatory disease" may also refer to a dysregulated inflammatory reaction that causes an exaggerated response by macrophages, granulocytes, and/or T-lymphocytes leading to abnormal tissue damage and/or cell death. An inflammatory disease can be either an acute or chronic inflammatory condition and can result from infections or non-infectious causes. Inflammatory diseases include, without limitation, atherosclerosis, arteriosclerosis, autoimmune disorders, multiple sclerosis, systemic lupus erythematosus, polymyalgia rheumatica (PMR), gouty arthritis, degenerative arthritis,<!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --> tendonitis, bursitis, psoriasis, cystic fibrosis, arthrosteitis, rheumatoid arthritis, inflammatory arthritis, Sjogren's syndrome, giant cell arteritis, progressive systemic sclerosis (scleroderma), ankylosing spondylitis, polymyositis, dermatomyositis, pemphigus, pemphigoid, diabetes (<i>e.g.,</i> Type I), myasthenia gravis, Hashimoto's thyroiditis, Graves' disease, Goodpasture's disease, mixed connective tissue disease, sclerosing cholangitis, inflammatory bowel disease, Crohn's disease, ulcerative colitis, pernicious anemia, inflammatory dermatoses, usual interstitial pneumonitis (UIP), asbestosis, silicosis, bronchiectasis, berylliosis, talcosis, pneumoconiosis, sarcoidosis, desquamative interstitial pneumonia, lymphoid interstitial pneumonia, giant cell interstitial pneumonia, cellular interstitial pneumonia, extrinsic allergic alveolitis, Wegener's granulomatosis and related forms of angiitis (temporal arteritis and polyarteritis nodosa), inflammatory dermatoses, hepatitis, delayed-type hypersensitivity reactions (<i>e.g.,</i> poison ivy dermatitis), pneumonia, respiratory tract inflammation, Adult Respiratory Distress Syndrome (ARDS), encephalitis, immediate hypersensitivity reactions, asthma, hayfever, allergies, acute anaphylaxis, rheumatic fever, glomerulonephritis, pyelonephritis, cellulitis, cystitis, chronic cholecystitis, ischemia (ischemic injury), reperfusion injury, allograft rejection, host-versus-graft rejection, appendicitis, arteritis, blepharitis, bronchiolitis, bronchitis, cervicitis, cholangitis, chorioamnionitis, conjunctivitis, dacryoadenitis, dermatomyositis, endocarditis, endometritis, enteritis, enterocolitis, epicondylitis, epididymitis, fasciitis, fibrositis, gastritis, gastroenteritis, gingivitis, ileitis, iritis, laryngitis, myelitis, myocarditis, nephritis, omphalitis, oophoritis, orchitis, osteitis, otitis, pancreatitis, parotitis, pericarditis, pharyngitis, pleuritis, phlebitis, pneumonitis, proctitis, prostatitis, rhinitis, salpingitis, sinusitis, stomatitis, synovitis, testitis, tonsillitis, urethritis, urocystitis, uveitis, vaginitis, vasculitis, vulvitis, vulvovaginitis, angitis, chronic bronchitis, osteomyelitis, optic neuritis, temporal arteritis, transverse myelitis, necrotizing fasciitis, and necrotizing enterocolitis. An ocular inflammatory disease includes, but is not limited to, post-surgical inflammation.</p>
<p id="p0082" num="0082">An "autoimmune disease" refers to a disease arising from an inappropriate immune response of the body of a subject against substances and tissues normally present in the body. In other words, the immune system mistakes some part of the body as a pathogen and attacks its own cells. This may be restricted to certain organs <i>(e.g.,</i> in autoimmune thyroiditis) or involve a particular tissue in different places (<i>e.g.,</i> Goodpasture's disease which may affect the basement membrane in both the lung and kidney). The treatment of autoimmune diseases is typically with immunosuppression, <i>e.g</i>., medications which decrease the immune response. Exemplary autoimmune diseases include, but are not limited to, glomerulonephritis,<!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --> Goodpasture's syndrome, necrotizing vasculitis, lymphadenitis, peri-arteritis nodosa, systemic lupus erythematosis, rheumatoid arthritis, psoriatic arthritis, systemic lupus erythematosis, psoriasis, ulcerative colitis, systemic sclerosis, dermatomyositis/polymyositis, anti-phospholipid antibody syndrome, scleroderma, pemphigus vulgaris, ANCA-associated vasculitis (<i>e.g.,</i> Wegener's granulomatosis, microscopic polyangiitis), uveitis, Sjogren's syndrome, Crohn's disease, Reiter's syndrome, ankylosing spondylitis, Lyme disease, Guillain-Barre syndrome, Hashimoto's thyroiditis, and cardiomyopathy.</p>
<heading id="h0005"><b>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</b></heading>
<p id="p0083" num="0083">
<ul id="ul0002" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li><figref idref="f0001"><i>Figure 1</i></figref> shows the results of a BCA assay, and of caspase activity in parental (DU145) and high metastatic (DU145LN4) prostate cancer cells upon treatment of compound OBD9. Cells were seeded in 6-well dishes at 50% confluence. Cells were treated with the compound OBD9 after 24 hours. 48 hours later, cells were lysed with lysis buffer and protein was collected and quantified with the BCA assay (Invitrogen). 20 micrograms of protein were loaded on 10% polyacrylamide gels. The gels were blotted onto nitrocellulose and stained with rabbit antibody to PARP-1 and Caspase-3 (both from Cell Signaling) and then visualized with goat, anti-rabbit HRP-conjugated antibody and HRP conjugated GAPDH. <figref idref="f0001"><i>Figure 1</i></figref> shows that the compound OBD9 induces apoptosis in parental (DU145) and high metastatic (DU145LN4) prostate cancer cells.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002"><i>Figure 2</i></figref> shows a tubulin polymerization assay for selected compound OBD9. Tubulin polymerization was measured using the tubulin polymerization assay kit from Cytoskeleton Inc., which measures tubulin polymerization kinetic via fluorescent enhancement to the incorporation of a fluorescent reporter into microtubules as polymerization takes place. <figref idref="f0002"><i>Figure 2</i></figref> shows that OBD9 disrupts (inhibits) tubulin polymerization.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003 f0004 f0005"><i>Figure 3</i></figref> shows the effects of two OBD compounds (OBD9 and OBD17) on viability of prostate cancer cell lines (DU145, PC3, and PC3MLN4) and on viability of lung cancer lines (A549, H157, and PC9). 5000 cells were seeded in each well of 96 well plates. 24 hours later, the wells were treated with DMSO or the OBD compounds (OBD9 and OBD17) at the respective indicated concentrations (0.013 µM, 0.04 µM, 0.12 µM, 0.37 µM, 1.1 µM, 3.3 µM, or 10 µM). 72 hours after treatment, the cells were analyzed using the MTT cell viability assay (Sigma).</li>
<li><figref idref="f0006"><i>Figure</i> 4</figref> shows imaging of microtubule stability in in PC3M-prostate cancer cells. Cells were seeded on glass coverslips. 24 hours later, cells were treated with compound<!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --> OBD9. After the indicated times (24 hours, 48 hours, and 72 hours), cells were fixed with paraformaldehyde (4% in PBS), permeabilized Triton-X100 (0.02% in Phosphate buffered saline), then stained with mouse antibody to human tubulin (1:200 dilution) and then with 1:400 goat anti-mouse IgG (Invitrogen) and viewed via confocal microscopy at (63X objective). <figref idref="f0006"><i>Figure 4</i></figref> shows that OBD9 interferes with microtubule (tubulin) stability in PC3M-prostate cancer cells.</li>
</ul></p>
<heading id="h0006"><b>DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF CERTAIN EMBODIMENTS OF THE INVENTION</b></heading>
<p id="p0084" num="0084">The present disclosure provides compounds of Formula (<b>I</b>). The compounds described herein are useful in treating and/or preventing proliferative diseases (<i>e.g</i>., cancer). The compounds may act by inhibiting growth of cells (<i>e.g</i>., aggressive cancer cells). Also provided in the present disclosure are pharmaceutical compositions, kits, methods, and uses including a compound described herein.</p>
<heading id="h0007"><i>Compounds</i></heading>
<p id="p0085" num="0085">One aspect of the present disclosure relates to compounds of Formula (<b>I</b>) as described herein. The compounds described herein are compounds that are useful in treating and/or preventing proliferative diseases in a subject. The compounds may also be useful for contacting a biological sample, tissue, or cell with an effective amount of a compound or pharmaceutical composition described herein. In certain embodiments, a compound described herein is a compound of Formula (<b>I</b>), or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt, solvate, hydrate, polymorph, co-crystal, tautomer, stereoisomer, isotopically labeled derivative, or prodrug thereof. In certain embodiments, a compound described herein is a compound of Formula (<b>I</b>), or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof.</p>
<p id="p0086" num="0086">In certain embodiments, a compound described herein is of Formula (<b>I</b>):
<chemistry id="chem0013" num="0013"><img id="ib0013" file="imgb0013.tif" wi="50" he="24" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt, solvate, hydrate, polymorph, co-crystal, tautomer, stereoisomer, isotopically labeled derivative, or prodrug thereof, wherein:
<ul id="ul0003" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>R<sup>1</sup> is independently substituted or unsubstituted alkyl, substituted or unsubstituted carbocyclyl, or substituted or unsubstituted heterocyclyl;<!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --></li>
<li>R<sup>2</sup> is independently substituted or unsubstituted acyl, substituted or unsubstituted alkyl, substituted or unsubstituted heteroalkyl, substituted or unsubstituted heterocyclyl, substituted or unsubstituted aryl, substituted or unsubstituted heteroaryl, -OR<sup>A</sup>, -N(R<sup>B</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, or - SR<sup>a</sup>;</li>
<li>R<sup>A</sup> is substituted or unsubstituted alkyl, substituted or unsubstituted carbocyclyl, substituted or unsubstituted heterocyclyl, substituted or unsubstituted aryl, substituted or unsubstituted heteroaryl or an oxygen protecting group when attached to an oxygen atom or a nitrogen protecting group when attached to a nitrogen atom;</li>
<li>each occurrence of R<sup>B</sup> is independently substituted or unsubstituted alkyl, substituted or unsubstituted carbocyclyl, substituted or unsubstituted heterocyclyl, substituted or unsubstituted aryl, substituted or unsubstituted heteroaryl; or a nitrogen protecting group; or optionally two instances of R<sup>B</sup> are joined to form a substituted or unsubstituted, heterocyclic ring, or substituted or unsubstituted, heteroaryl ring;</li>
<li>R<sup>3</sup> is independently hydrogen, substituted or unsubstituted C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl, or a nitrogen protecting group; and</li>
<li>R<sup>4</sup> is independently hydrogen, substituted or unsubstituted C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl, or a nitrogen protecting group.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0087" num="0087">Formula (<b>I</b>) includes substituent R<sup>1</sup>. In certain embodiments, R<sup>1</sup> is substituted or unsubstituted alkyl (e.g., substituted or unsubstituted C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl). In certain embodiments, R<sup>1</sup> is independently -CH<sub>3</sub>, -CH<sub>2</sub>CH<sub>3</sub>, -CH<sub>2</sub>CH<sub>2</sub>CH<sub>3</sub>, -CH<sub>2</sub>CH<sub>2</sub>CH<sub>2</sub>CH<sub>3</sub>,. In certain embodiments, R<sup>1</sup> is substituted alkyl, <i>e.g.</i>, heterocyclalkyl. In certain embodiments, R<sup>1</sup> is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0014" num="0014"><img id="ib0014" file="imgb0014.tif" wi="23" he="15" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
In certain embodiments, R<sup>1</sup> is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0015" num="0015"><img id="ib0015" file="imgb0015.tif" wi="22" he="12" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
In certain embodiments, R<sup>1</sup> is substituted or unsubstituted carbocyclyl (e.g., substituted or unsubstituted, 3- to 7-membered, monocyclic carbocyclyl comprising zero, one, or two double bonds in the carbocyclic ring system). In certain embodiments, R<sup>1</sup> is substituted or unsubstituted heterocyclyl (e.g., substituted or unsubstituted, 3- to 9-membered, monocyclic heterocyclyl comprising zero, one, or two double bonds in the heterocyclic ring system, wherein one, two, or three atoms in the heterocyclic ring system are independently nitrogen, oxygen, or sulfur). In certain embodiments, R<sup>1</sup> is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0016" num="0016"><img id="ib0016" file="imgb0016.tif" wi="19" he="13" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
In certain<!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --> embodiments, R<sup>1</sup> is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0017" num="0017"><img id="ib0017" file="imgb0017.tif" wi="19" he="15" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
In certain embodiments, R<sup>1</sup> is -(CH<sub>2</sub>)<sub>a</sub>N(R<sup>A1</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, a is 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, or 6, and each occurrence of R<sup>A1</sup> is independently hydrogen, or substituted or unsubstituted C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl (<i>e.g.,</i> R<sup>1</sup> is -(CH<sub>2</sub>)<sub>2</sub>NMe<sub>2</sub>)). In certain embodiments, R<sup>1</sup> is - (CH<sub>2</sub>)<sub>3</sub>NMe<sub>2</sub>). In certain embodiments, R<sup>A1</sup> is independently -CH<sub>2</sub>CH<sub>3</sub>, or -CH<sub>2</sub>CH<sub>2</sub>CH<sub>3</sub>.</p>
<p id="p0088" num="0088">Formula (<b>I</b>) includes substituent R<sup>2</sup>. In certain embodiments, R<sup>2</sup> is substituted or unsubstituted acyl <i>(e.g.,</i> acetyl). In certain embodiments, R<sup>2</sup> is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0018" num="0018"><img id="ib0018" file="imgb0018.tif" wi="32" he="21" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
In certain embodiments, R<sup>A2</sup> is independently hydrogen, halogen <i>(e.g.,</i> F, Cl, Br, or I), or -N(R<sup>C</sup>)<sub>2</sub>. In certain embodiments, R<sup>A2</sup> is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0019" num="0019"><img id="ib0019" file="imgb0019.tif" wi="22" he="18" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
In certain embodiments, R<sup>A2</sup> is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0020" num="0020"><img id="ib0020" file="imgb0020.tif" wi="23" he="20" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
In certain embodiments, R<sup>C</sup> is independently substituted or unsubstituted alkyl, or substituted or unsubstituted heterocyclyl. When Formula (<b>I</b>) includes two or more instances of the substituent R<sup>C</sup>, any two instances of R<sup>C</sup> may be the same or different from each other. In certain embodiments, at least one instance of R<sup>C</sup> is substituted or unsubstituted C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl <i>(e.g.,</i> -Me). In certain embodiments, at least one instance of R<sup>C</sup> is substituted or unsubstituted heterocyclyl (e.g., substituted or unsubstituted, 3- to 9-membered, monocyclic heterocyclyl comprising zero, one, or two double bonds in the heterocyclic ring system, wherein one, two, or three atoms in the heterocyclic ring system are independently nitrogen, oxygen, or sulfur).</p>
<p id="p0089" num="0089">In certain embodiments, R<sup>2</sup> is -OR<sup>A</sup>. In certain embodiments, R<sup>A</sup> is substituted or unsubstituted carbocyclyl (<i>e.g.,</i> substituted or unsubstituted, 3- to 7-membered, monocyclic carbocyclyl comprising zero, one, or two double bonds in the carbocyclic ring system). In certain embodiments, R<sup>A</sup> is substituted or unsubstituted heterocyclyl (<i>e.g.,</i> substituted or unsubstituted, 3- to 9-membered, monocyclic heterocyclyl comprising zero, one, or two double bonds in the heterocyclic ring system, wherein one, two, or three atoms in the heterocyclic ring system are independently nitrogen, oxygen, or sulfur). In certain embodiments, R<sup>A</sup> is a substituted or unsubstituted, aryl ring (<i>e.g</i>., substituted or unsubstituted, 6- to 10-membered aryl). In certain embodiments, R<sup>2</sup> is -OR<sup>A</sup> (<i>e.g</i>. -O(substituted or unsubstituted phenyl) <i>(e.g.,</i> -OPh)).<!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --></p>
<p id="p0090" num="0090">In certain embodiments, R<sup>2</sup> is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0021" num="0021"><img id="ib0021" file="imgb0021.tif" wi="30" he="16" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
wherein R<sup>A3</sup> is -N(R<sup>A4</sup>)<sub>2</sub>. In certain embodiments, R<sup>A4</sup> is independently substituted or unsubstituted alkyl, substituted or unsubstituted carbocyclyl, substituted or unsubstituted heterocyclyl, substituted or unsubstituted aryl, or substituted or unsubstituted heteroaryl. In certain embodiments, R<sup>2</sup> is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0022" num="0022"><img id="ib0022" file="imgb0022.tif" wi="30" he="16" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
wherein R<sup>A3</sup> is -N(R<sup>A4</sup>)<sub>2</sub>. In certain embodiments, two instances of R<sup>A4</sup> are joined to form a substituted or unsubstituted, heterocyclic ring <i>(e.g.,</i> substituted or unsubstituted, 5- to 6- membered, monocyclic heterocyclic ring comprising zero, one, or two double bonds in the heterocyclic ring system, wherein one, two, or three atoms in the heterocyclic ring system are independently nitrogen, oxygen, or sulfur). In certain embodiments, two instances of R<sup>A4</sup> are joined to form a substituted or unsubstituted heteroaryl ring (<i>e.g</i>., substituted or unsubstituted, 5- to 6-membered, monocyclic heteroaryl ring, wherein one, two, three, or four atoms in the heteroaryl ring system are independently nitrogen, oxygen, or sulfur). In certain embodiments, R<sup>A3</sup> is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0023" num="0023"><img id="ib0023" file="imgb0023.tif" wi="29" he="18" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></p>
<p id="p0091" num="0091">In certain embodiments, R<sup>2</sup> is -SR<sup>A</sup>. In certain embodiments, R<sup>A</sup> is substituted or unsubstituted C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl. In certain embodiments, R<sup>A</sup> is substituted or unsubstituted benzyl, or substituted or unsubstituted phenyl.</p>
<p id="p0092" num="0092">Formula (<b>I</b>) includes substituent R<sup>3</sup>. In certain embodiments, R<sup>3</sup> is H. In certain embodiments, R<sup>3</sup> is substituted or unsubstituted alkyl (<i>e.g</i>., substituted or unsubstituted C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl). In certain embodiments, R<sup>3</sup> is a nitrogen protecting group (<i>e.g.</i>, benzyl (Bn), t-butyl carbonate (BOC or Boc), benzyl carbamate (Cbz), 9-fluorenylmethyl carbonate (Fmoc), trifluoroacetyl, triphenylmethyl, acetyl, or p-toluenesulfonamide (Ts)).</p>
<p id="p0093" num="0093">Formula (<b>I</b>) includes substituent R<sup>4</sup>. In certain embodiments, R<sup>4</sup> is H. In certain embodiments, R<sup>4</sup> is substituted or unsubstituted alkyl (<i>e.g</i>., substituted or unsubstituted C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl). In certain embodiments, R<sup>4</sup> is a nitrogen protecting group (<i>e.g</i>., benzyl (Bn), t-butyl carbonate (BOC or Boc), benzyl carbamate (Cbz), 9-fluorenylmethyl carbonate (Fmoc), trifluoroacetyl, triphenylmethyl, acetyl, or p-toluenesulfonamide (Ts)).<!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --></p>
<p id="p0094" num="0094">In certain embodiments, the compound of Formula (<b>I</b>) is of the following formula:
<chemistry id="chem0024" num="0024"><img id="ib0024" file="imgb0024.tif" wi="65" he="24" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof.</p>
<p id="p0095" num="0095">In certain embodiments, the compound of Formula (<b>I</b>) is of one of the following formulae:
<chemistry id="chem0025" num="0025"><img id="ib0025" file="imgb0025.tif" wi="85" he="24" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
<chemistry id="chem0026" num="0026"><img id="ib0026" file="imgb0026.tif" wi="94" he="24" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof.</p>
<p id="p0096" num="0096">In certain embodiments, the compound of Formula (<b>I</b>) is of one of the following formulae:
<chemistry id="chem0027" num="0027"><img id="ib0027" file="imgb0027.tif" wi="151" he="27" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof.</p>
<p id="p0097" num="0097">In certain embodiments, the compound of Formula (<b>I</b>) is of one of the following formulae:
<chemistry id="chem0028" num="0028"><img id="ib0028" file="imgb0028.tif" wi="148" he="32" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry><!-- EPO <DP n="40"> -->
<chemistry id="chem0029" num="0029"><img id="ib0029" file="imgb0029.tif" wi="136" he="33" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof.</p>
<p id="p0098" num="0098">In certain embodiments, the compound of Formula (<b>I</b>) is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0030" num="0030"><img id="ib0030" file="imgb0030.tif" wi="151" he="38" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
<chemistry id="chem0031" num="0031"><img id="ib0031" file="imgb0031.tif" wi="154" he="36" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
<chemistry id="chem0032" num="0032"><img id="ib0032" file="imgb0032.tif" wi="139" he="36" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
<chemistry id="chem0033" num="0033"><img id="ib0033" file="imgb0033.tif" wi="153" he="35" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
<chemistry id="chem0034" num="0034"><img id="ib0034" file="imgb0034.tif" wi="146" he="35" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof.<!-- EPO <DP n="41"> --></p>
<p id="p0099" num="0099">The invention may be as described in the following numbered paragraphs:
<ol id="ol0001" ol-style="">
<li>1. A compound of Formula (<b>I</b>):
<chemistry id="chem0035" num="0035"><img id="ib0035" file="imgb0035.tif" wi="49" he="24" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein:
<ul id="ul0004" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>R<sup>1</sup> is independently substituted or unsubstituted alkyl, substituted or unsubstituted carbocyclyl, or substituted or unsubstituted heterocyclyl;</li>
<li>R<sup>2</sup> is independently substituted or unsubstituted acyl, substituted or unsubstituted alkyl, substituted or unsubstituted heteroalkyl, substituted or unsubstituted heterocyclyl, substituted or unsubstituted aryl, substituted or unsubstituted heteroaryl, -OR<sup>A</sup>, -N(R<sup>B</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, or - SR<sup>A</sup>;</li>
<li>R<sup>A</sup> is substituted or unsubstituted alkyl, substituted or unsubstituted carbocyclyl, substituted or unsubstituted heterocyclyl, substituted or unsubstituted aryl, or substituted or unsubstituted heteroaryl or an oxygen protecting group when attached to an oxygen atom or a nitrogen protecting group when attached to a nitrogen atom;</li>
<li>each occurrence of R<sup>B</sup> is independently substituted or unsubstituted alkyl, substituted or unsubstituted carbocyclyl, substituted or unsubstituted heterocyclyl, substituted or unsubstituted aryl, substituted or unsubstituted heteroaryl; or a nitrogen protecting group; or optionally</li>
<li>two instances of R<sup>B</sup> are joined to form a substituted or unsubstituted, heterocyclic ring, or substituted or unsubstituted, heteroaryl ring;</li>
<li>R<sup>3</sup> is independently hydrogen, substituted or unsubstituted C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl, or a nitrogen protecting group; and</li>
<li>R<sup>4</sup> is independently hydrogen, substituted or unsubstituted C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl, or a nitrogen protecting group.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>2. The compound of paragraph 1, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>1</sup> is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0036" num="0036"><img id="ib0036" file="imgb0036.tif" wi="18" he="12" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry><!-- EPO <DP n="42"> --></li>
<li>3. The compound of paragraph 1, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>1</sup> is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0037" num="0037"><img id="ib0037" file="imgb0037.tif" wi="18" he="15" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></li>
<li>4. The compound of paragraph 1, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>1</sup> is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0038" num="0038"><img id="ib0038" file="imgb0038.tif" wi="24" he="15" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></li>
<li>5. The compound of paragraph 1, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>1</sup> is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0039" num="0039"><img id="ib0039" file="imgb0039.tif" wi="24" he="17" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></li>
<li>6. The compound of paragraph 1, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>1</sup> is substituted or unsubstituted C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl.</li>
<li>7. The compound of paragraph 6, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>1</sup> is substituted C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl.</li>
<li>8. The compound of paragraph 6, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>1</sup> is unsubstituted C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl.</li>
<li>9. The compound of any one of paragraphs 1, 6, or 8, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>1</sup> is methyl.</li>
<li>10. The compound of any one of paragraphs 1, 6, or 8, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>1</sup> is ethyl.</li>
<li>11. The compound of any one of paragraphs 1, 6, or 8, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>1</sup> is propyl.<!-- EPO <DP n="43"> --></li>
<li>12. The compound of any one of paragraphs 1, 6, or 8, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>1</sup> is butyl.</li>
<li>13. The compound of any one of paragraphs 1, 6, or 8, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>1</sup> is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0040" num="0040"><img id="ib0040" file="imgb0040.tif" wi="29" he="10" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
wherein: each instance of R<sup>A1</sup> is independently substituted or unsubstituted C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl; and a is 1, 2, or 3.</li>
<li>14. The compound of paragraph 13, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein at least one instance of R<sup>A1</sup> is methyl.</li>
<li>15. The compound of paragraph 13, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein at least one instance of R<sup>A1</sup> is propyl.</li>
<li>16. The compound of paragraph 13, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein at least one instance of R<sup>A1</sup> is butyl.</li>
<li>17. The compound of any one of paragraphs 1, 6, or 7, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>1</sup> is -CH<sub>2</sub>CH<sub>2</sub>N(CH<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub>.</li>
<li>18. The compound of any one of paragraphs 1, 6, or 7, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>1</sup> is -CH<sub>2</sub>CH<sub>2</sub>CH<sub>2</sub>N(CH<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub>.</li>
<li>19. The compound of any one of paragraphs 1-18, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>2</sup> is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0041" num="0041"><img id="ib0041" file="imgb0041.tif" wi="30" he="23" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
wherein:
<ul id="ul0005" list-style="none">
<li>R<sup>A2</sup> is independently hydrogen, halogen, or -N(R<sup>C</sup>)<sub>2</sub>; and</li>
<li>each instance of R<sup>C</sup> is independently substituted or unsubstituted alkyl, or substituted or unsubstituted heterocyclyl.</li>
</ul><!-- EPO <DP n="44"> --></li>
<li>20. The compound of paragraph 19, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>A2</sup> is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0042" num="0042"><img id="ib0042" file="imgb0042.tif" wi="23" he="17" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></li>
<li>21. The compound of paragraph 19, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>A2</sup> is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0043" num="0043"><img id="ib0043" file="imgb0043.tif" wi="24" he="19" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></li>
<li>22. The compound of paragraph 19, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>A2</sup> is hydrogen.</li>
<li>23. The compound of paragraph 19, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>A2</sup> is halogen.</li>
<li>24. The compound of paragraph 19, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>A2</sup> is fluorine.</li>
<li>25. The compound of any one of paragraphs 1-18, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>2</sup> is -OR<sup>A</sup>, and<br/>
R<sup>A</sup> is substituted or unsubstituted carbocyclyl, substituted or unsubstituted heterocyclyl, substituted or unsubstituted aryl, or substituted or unsubstituted heteroaryl.</li>
<li>26. The compound of paragraph 25, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>2</sup> is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0044" num="0044"><img id="ib0044" file="imgb0044.tif" wi="30" he="15" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
wherein:
<ul id="ul0006" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>R<sup>A3</sup> is -N(R<sup>A4</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, and<!-- EPO <DP n="45"> --></li>
<li>two instances of R<sup>A4</sup> are joined to form a substituted or unsubstituted, heterocyclic ring, or substituted or unsubstituted, heteroaryl ring.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>27. The compound of paragraph 25, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>2</sup> is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0045" num="0045"><img id="ib0045" file="imgb0045.tif" wi="30" he="15" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
wherein:
<ul id="ul0007" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>R<sup>A3</sup> is -N(R<sup>A4</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, and</li>
<li>R<sup>A4</sup> is independently substituted or unsubstituted alkyl, substituted or unsubstituted carbocyclyl, substituted or unsubstituted heterocyclyl, substituted or unsubstituted aryl, or substituted or unsubstituted heteroaryl.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>28. The compound of any one of paragraphs 1 or 25, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>2</sup> is -OR<sup>A</sup>, and<br/>
R<sup>A</sup> is substituted or unsubstituted phenyl.</li>
<li>29. The compound of paragraph 25, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>2</sup> is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0046" num="0046"><img id="ib0046" file="imgb0046.tif" wi="30" he="15" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
wherein:
<ul id="ul0008" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>R<sup>A3</sup> is -N(R<sup>A4</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, and</li>
<li>two instances of R<sup>A4</sup> are joined to form a substituted or unsubstituted, heterocyclic ring, or substituted or unsubstituted, heteroaryl ring.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>30. The compound of paragraph 27 or 29, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>A3</sup> is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0047" num="0047"><img id="ib0047" file="imgb0047.tif" wi="29" he="17" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry><!-- EPO <DP n="46"> --></li>
<li>31. The compound of any one of paragraphs 1-18, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>2</sup> is -SR<sup>A</sup>, wherein R<sup>A</sup> is substituted or unsubstituted C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl, or substituted or unsubstituted phenyl.</li>
<li>32. The compound of paragraph 31, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>2</sup> is -SCH<sub>2</sub>CH<sub>2</sub>CH<sub>3</sub>.</li>
<li>33. The compound of paragraph 31, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>2</sup> is -SPh.</li>
<li>34. The compound of any one of paragraphs 1-33, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>3</sup> is hydrogen.</li>
<li>35. The compound of any one of paragraphs 1-34, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>4</sup> is hydrogen.</li>
<li>36. The compound of any one of paragraphs 1-35, wherein the compound is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0048" num="0048"><img id="ib0048" file="imgb0048.tif" wi="151" he="35" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
<chemistry id="chem0049" num="0049"><img id="ib0049" file="imgb0049.tif" wi="142" he="45" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
<chemistry id="chem0050" num="0050"><img id="ib0050" file="imgb0050.tif" wi="139" he="29" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry><!-- EPO <DP n="47"> -->
<chemistry id="chem0051" num="0051"><img id="ib0051" file="imgb0051.tif" wi="97" he="6" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
<chemistry id="chem0052" num="0052"><img id="ib0052" file="imgb0052.tif" wi="151" he="35" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
<chemistry id="chem0053" num="0053"><img id="ib0053" file="imgb0053.tif" wi="147" he="35" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof.</li>
<li>37. A pharmaceutical composition comprising a compound of any one of paragraphs 1-36, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and optionally a pharmaceutically acceptable excipient.</li>
<li>38. A method of treating a proliferative disease in a subject in need thereof, the method comprising administering to the subject an effective amount of a compound of any one of paragraphs 1-36, a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, or a pharmaceutical composition of paragraph 37.</li>
<li>39. The method of paragraph 38, wherein the proliferative disease is cancer.</li>
<li>40. The method of paragraph 39, wherein the cancer is metastatic cancer.</li>
<li>41. The method of paragraph 39, wherein the cancer is lung cancer.</li>
<li>42. The method of paragraph 39, wherein the cancer is prostate cancer.</li>
<li>43. A kit comprising:
<ul id="ul0009" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>a compound of any one of paragraphs 1-36, a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, or a pharmaceutical composition of paragraph 37; and</li>
<li>instructions for using the compound or pharmaceutical composition.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol><!-- EPO <DP n="48"> --></p>
<heading id="h0008"><i>Pharmaceutical Compositions, Kits, and Administration</i></heading>
<p id="p0100" num="0100">The present disclosure provides pharmaceutical compositions comprising a compound described herein, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and optionally a pharmaceutically acceptable excipient. In certain embodiments, a pharmaceutical composition described herein comprises a compound described herein, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and a pharmaceutically acceptable excipient. The pharmaceutical compositions described herein are useful in treating and/or preventing proliferative diseases <i>(e.g.,</i> cancer (e.g., lung cancer, breast cancer, leukemia, lymphoma, melanoma, multiple myeloma, Ewing's sarcoma, osteosarcoma, brain cancer, neuroblastoma), benign neoplasms, angiogenesis, inflammatory diseases, autoinflammatory diseases, and autoimmune diseases) in a subject, biological sample, tissue, or cell.</p>
<p id="p0101" num="0101">In certain embodiments, a subject being treated herein is an animal. The animal may be of either sex and may be at any stage of development. In certain embodiments, the subject is a human. In certain embodiments, the subject is a non-human animal. In certain embodiments, the subject is a mammal (<i>e.g</i>., non-human mammal). In certain embodiments, the subject is a domesticated animal, such as a dog, cat, cow, pig, horse, sheep, or goat. In certain embodiments, a subject being treated herein is a companion animal such as a dog or cat. In certain embodiments, a subject being treated herein is a livestock animal such as a cow, pig, horse, sheep, or goat. In certain embodiments, a subject being treated herein is a zoo animal. In another embodiment, a subject being treated herein is a research animal such as a rodent (e.g., mouse, rat), dog, pig, or non-human primate. In certain embodiments, the animal is a genetically engineered animal. In certain embodiments, the animal is a transgenic or genetically engineered animal (<i>e.g</i>., transgenic mice and transgenic pigs). In certain embodiments, a subject described herein is a fish or reptile.</p>
<p id="p0102" num="0102">In certain embodiments, the cell contacted with an effective amount of a compound or pharmaceutical composition described herein is <i>in vitro.</i> In certain embodiments, the contacted cell is <i>ex vivo.</i> In certain embodiments, the cell described herein is <i>in vivo.</i> In certain embodiments, the cell described herein is a malignant cell (<i>e.g</i>., malignant blood cell).</p>
<p id="p0103" num="0103">In certain embodiments, the compound described herein is provided in an effective amount in the pharmaceutical composition. In certain embodiments, the effective amount is a therapeutically effective amount (<i>e.g</i>., amount effective for treating a proliferative disease in a subject in need thereof). In certain embodiments, the proliferative disease is cancer. In certain embodiments, the proliferative disease is metastatic cancer. In certain embodiments, the effective amount is a prophylactically effective amount (<i>e.g</i>., amount effective for<!-- EPO <DP n="49"> --> preventing a proliferative disease in a subject in need thereof and/or for keeping a subject in need thereof in remission of a proliferative disease).</p>
<p id="p0104" num="0104">Pharmaceutical compositions described herein can be prepared by any method known in the art of pharmacology. In general, such preparatory methods include bringing the compound described herein (<i>i.e.,</i> the "active ingredient") into association with a carrier or excipient, and/or one or more other accessory ingredients, and then, if necessary and/or desirable, shaping, and/or packaging the product into a desired single- or multi-dose unit.</p>
<p id="p0105" num="0105">Pharmaceutical compositions can be prepared, packaged, and/or sold in bulk, as a single unit dose, and/or as a plurality of single unit doses. A "unit dose" is a discrete amount of the pharmaceutical composition comprising a predetermined amount of the active ingredient. The amount of the active ingredient is generally equal to the dosage of the active ingredient which would be administered to a subject and/or a convenient fraction of such a dosage, such as one-half or one-third of such a dosage.</p>
<p id="p0106" num="0106">Relative amounts of the active ingredient, the pharmaceutically acceptable excipient, and/or any additional ingredients in a pharmaceutical composition described herein will vary, depending upon the identity, size, and/or condition of the subject treated and further depending upon the route by which the composition is to be administered. The composition may comprise between 0.1% and 100% (w/w) active ingredient.</p>
<p id="p0107" num="0107">Pharmaceutically acceptable excipients used in the manufacture of provided pharmaceutical compositions include inert diluents, dispersing and/or granulating agents, surface active agents and/or emulsifiers, disintegrating agents, binding agents, preservatives, buffering agents, lubricating agents, and/or oils. Excipients such as cocoa butter and suppository waxes, coloring agents, coating agents, sweetening, flavoring, and perfuming agents may also be present in the composition.</p>
<p id="p0108" num="0108">Liquid dosage forms for oral and parenteral administration include pharmaceutically acceptable emulsions, microemulsions, solutions, suspensions, syrups and elixirs. In addition to the active ingredients, the liquid dosage forms may comprise inert diluents commonly used in the art such as, for example, water or other solvents, solubilizing agents and emulsifiers such as ethyl alcohol, isopropyl alcohol, ethyl carbonate, ethyl acetate, benzyl alcohol, benzyl benzoate, propylene glycol, 1,3-butylene glycol, dimethylformamide, oils (e.g., cottonseed, groundnut, corn, germ, olive, castor, and sesame oils), glycerol, tetrahydrofurfuryl alcohol, polyethylene glycols and fatty acid esters of sorbitan, and mixtures thereof. Besides inert diluents, the oral compositions can include adjuvants such as wetting agents, emulsifying and suspending agents, sweetening, flavoring, and perfuming agents. In certain embodiments for<!-- EPO <DP n="50"> --> parenteral administration, the conjugates described herein are mixed with solubilizing agents such as Cremophor®, alcohols, oils, modified oils, glycols, polysorbates, cyclodextrins, polymers, and mixtures thereof.</p>
<p id="p0109" num="0109">Injectable preparations, for example, sterile injectable aqueous or oleaginous suspensions can be formulated according to the known art using suitable dispersing or wetting agents and suspending agents. The sterile injectable preparation can be a sterile injectable solution, suspension, or emulsion in a nontoxic parenterally acceptable diluent or solvent, for example, as a solution in 1,3-butanediol. Among the acceptable vehicles and solvents that can be employed are water, Ringer's solution, U.S.P., and isotonic sodium chloride solution. In addition, sterile, fixed oils are conventionally employed as a solvent or suspending medium. For this purpose any bland fixed oil can be employed including synthetic mono- or di-glycerides. In addition, fatty acids such as oleic acid are used in the preparation of injectables.</p>
<p id="p0110" num="0110">The injectable formulations can be sterilized, for example, by filtration through a bacterial-retaining filter, or by incorporating sterilizing agents in the form of sterile solid compositions which can be dissolved or dispersed in sterile water or other sterile injectable medium prior to use.</p>
<p id="p0111" num="0111">In order to prolong the effect of a drug, it is often desirable to slow the absorption of the drug from subcutaneous or intramuscular injection. This can be accomplished by the use of a liquid suspension of crystalline or amorphous material with poor water solubility. The rate of absorption of the drug then depends upon its rate of dissolution, which, in turn, may depend upon crystal size and crystalline form. Alternatively, delayed absorption of a parenterally administered drug form may be accomplished by dissolving or suspending the drug in an oil vehicle.</p>
<p id="p0112" num="0112">Compositions for rectal or vaginal administration are typically suppositories which can be prepared by mixing the conjugates described herein with suitable non-irritating excipients or carriers such as cocoa butter, polyethylene glycol, or a suppository wax which are solid at ambient temperature but liquid at body temperature and therefore melt in the rectum or vaginal cavity and release the active ingredient.</p>
<p id="p0113" num="0113">Solid dosage forms for oral administration include capsules, tablets, pills, powders, and granules. In such solid dosage forms, the active ingredient is mixed with at least one inert, pharmaceutically acceptable excipient or carrier such as sodium citrate or dicalcium phosphate and/or (a) fillers or extenders such as starches, lactose, sucrose, glucose, mannitol, and silicic acid, (b) binders such as, for example, carboxymethylcellulose, alginates, gelatin,<!-- EPO <DP n="51"> --> polyvinylpyrrolidinone, sucrose, and acacia, (c) humectants such as glycerol, (d) disintegrating agents such as agar, calcium carbonate, potato or tapioca starch, alginic acid, certain silicates, and sodium carbonate, (e) solution retarding agents such as paraffin, (f) absorption accelerators such as quaternary ammonium compounds, (g) wetting agents such as, for example, cetyl alcohol and glycerol monostearate, (h) absorbents such as kaolin and bentonite clay, and (i) lubricants such as talc, calcium stearate, magnesium stearate, solid polyethylene glycols, sodium lauryl sulfate, and mixtures thereof. In the case of capsules, tablets, and pills, the dosage form may include a buffering agent.</p>
<p id="p0114" num="0114">Solid compositions of a similar type can be employed as fillers in soft and hard-filled gelatin capsules using such excipients as lactose or milk sugar as well as high molecular weight polyethylene glycols and the like. The solid dosage forms of tablets, dragees, capsules, pills, and granules can be prepared with coatings and shells such as enteric coatings and other coatings well known in the art of pharmacology. They may optionally comprise opacifying agents and can be of a composition that they release the active ingredient(s) only, or preferentially, in a certain part of the intestinal tract, optionally, in a delayed manner. Examples of encapsulating compositions which can be used include polymeric substances and waxes. Solid compositions of a similar type can be employed as fillers in soft and hard-filled gelatin capsules using such excipients as lactose or milk sugar as well as high molecular weight polethylene glycols and the like.</p>
<p id="p0115" num="0115">The active ingredient can be in a micro-encapsulated form with one or more excipients as noted above. The solid dosage forms of tablets, dragees, capsules, pills, and granules can be prepared with coatings and shells such as enteric coatings, release controlling coatings, and other coatings well known in the pharmaceutical formulating art. In such solid dosage forms the active ingredient can be admixed with at least one inert diluent such as sucrose, lactose, or starch. Such dosage forms may comprise, as is normal practice, additional substances other than inert diluents, <i>e</i>.<i>g</i>., tableting lubricants and other tableting aids such a magnesium stearate and microcrystalline cellulose. In the case of capsules, tablets and pills, the dosage forms may comprise buffering agents. They may optionally comprise opacifying agents and can be of a composition that they release the active ingredient(s) only, or preferentially, in a certain part of the intestinal tract, optionally, in a delayed manner. Examples of encapsulating agents which can be used include polymeric substances and waxes.</p>
<p id="p0116" num="0116">Dosage forms for topical and/or transdermal administration of a compound described herein may include ointments, pastes, creams, lotions, gels, powders, solutions, sprays,<!-- EPO <DP n="52"> --> inhalants, and/or patches. Generally, the active ingredient is admixed under sterile conditions with a pharmaceutically acceptable carrier or excipient and/or any needed preservatives and/or buffers as can be required. Additionally, the present disclosure contemplates the use of transdermal patches, which often have the added advantage of providing controlled delivery of an active ingredient to the body. Such dosage forms can be prepared, for example, by dissolving and/or dispensing the active ingredient in the proper medium. Alternatively or additionally, the rate can be controlled by either providing a rate controlling membrane and/or by dispersing the active ingredient in a polymer matrix and/or gel.</p>
<p id="p0117" num="0117">Suitable devices for use in delivering intradermal pharmaceutical compositions described herein include short needle devices. Intradermal compositions can be administered by devices which limit the effective penetration length of a needle into the skin. Alternatively or additionally, conventional syringes can be used in the classical mantoux method of intradermal administration. Jet injection devices which deliver liquid formulations to the dermis <i>via</i> a liquid jet injector and/or <i>via</i> a needle which pierces the stratum corneum and produces a jet which reaches the dermis are suitable. Ballistic powder/particle delivery devices which use compressed gas to accelerate the compound in powder form through the outer layers of the skin to the dermis are suitable.</p>
<p id="p0118" num="0118">Formulations suitable for topical administration include, but are not limited to, liquid and/or semi-liquid preparations such as liniments, lotions, oil-in-water and/or water-in-oil emulsions such as creams, ointments, and/or pastes, and/or solutions and/or suspensions. Topically administrable formulations may, for example, comprise from about 1% to about 10% (w/w) active ingredient, although the concentration of the active ingredient can be as high as the solubility limit of the active ingredient in the solvent. Formulations for topical administration may further comprise one or more of the additional ingredients described herein.</p>
<p id="p0119" num="0119">A pharmaceutical composition described herein can be prepared, packaged, and/or sold in a formulation suitable for pulmonary administration <i>via</i> the buccal cavity. Such a formulation may comprise dry particles which comprise the active ingredient and which have a diameter in the range from about 0.5 to about 7 nanometers, or from about 1 to about 6 nanometers. Such compositions are conveniently in the form of dry powders for administration using a device comprising a dry powder reservoir to which a stream of propellant can be directed to disperse the powder and/or using a self-propelling solvent/powder dispensing container such as a device comprising the active ingredient dissolved and/or suspended in a low-boiling propellant in a sealed container. Such powders<!-- EPO <DP n="53"> --> comprise particles wherein at least 98% of the particles by weight have a diameter greater than 0.5 nanometers and at least 95% of the particles by number have a diameter less than 7 nanometers. Alternatively, at least 95% of the particles by weight have a diameter greater than 1 nanometer and at least 90% of the particles by number have a diameter less than 6 nanometers. Dry powder compositions may include a solid fine powder diluent such as sugar and are conveniently provided in a unit dose form.</p>
<p id="p0120" num="0120">Low boiling propellants generally include liquid propellants having a boiling point of below 65 °F at atmospheric pressure. Generally the propellant may constitute 50 to 99.9% (w/w) of the composition, and the active ingredient may constitute 0.1 to 20% (w/w) of the composition. The propellant may further comprise additional ingredients such as a liquid non-ionic and/or solid anionic surfactant and/or a solid diluent (which may have a particle size of the same order as particles comprising the active ingredient).</p>
<p id="p0121" num="0121">Pharmaceutical compositions described herein formulated for pulmonary delivery may provide the active ingredient in the form of droplets of a solution and/or suspension. Such formulations can be prepared, packaged, and/or sold as aqueous and/or dilute alcoholic solutions and/or suspensions, optionally sterile, comprising the active ingredient, and may conveniently be administered using any nebulization and/or atomization device. Such formulations may further comprise one or more additional ingredients including, but not limited to, a flavoring agent such as saccharin sodium, a volatile oil, a buffering agent, a surface active agent, and/or a preservative such as methylhydroxybenzoate. The droplets provided by this route of administration may have an average diameter in the range from about 0.1 to about 200 nanometers.</p>
<p id="p0122" num="0122">Formulations described herein as being useful for pulmonary delivery are useful for intranasal delivery of a pharmaceutical composition described herein. Another formulation suitable for intranasal administration is a coarse powder comprising the active ingredient and having an average particle from about 0.2 to 500 micrometers. Such a formulation is administered by rapid inhalation through the nasal passage from a container of the powder held close to the nares.</p>
<p id="p0123" num="0123">Formulations for nasal administration may, for example, comprise from about as little as 0.1% (w/w) to as much as 100% (w/w) of the active ingredient, and may comprise one or more of the additional ingredients described herein. A pharmaceutical composition described herein can be prepared, packaged, and/or sold in a formulation for buccal administration. Such formulations may, for example, be in the form of tablets and/or lozenges made using conventional methods, and may contain, for example, 0.1 to 20% (w/w) active<!-- EPO <DP n="54"> --> ingredient, the balance comprising an orally dissolvable and/or degradable composition and, optionally, one or more of the additional ingredients described herein. Alternately, formulations for buccal administration may comprise a powder and/or an aerosolized and/or atomized solution and/or suspension comprising the active ingredient. Such powdered, aerosolized, and/or aerosolized formulations, when dispersed, may have an average particle and/or droplet size in the range from about 0.1 to about 200 nanometers, and may further comprise one or more of the additional ingredients described herein.</p>
<p id="p0124" num="0124">A pharmaceutical composition described herein can be prepared, packaged, and/or sold in a formulation for ophthalmic administration. Such formulations may, for example, be in the form of eye drops including, for example, a 0.1-1.0% (w/w) solution and/or suspension of the active ingredient in an aqueous or oily liquid carrier or excipient. Such drops may further comprise buffering agents, salts, and/or one or more other of the additional ingredients described herein. Other opthalmically-administrable formulations which are useful include those which comprise the active ingredient in microcrystalline form and/or in a liposomal preparation. Ear drops and/or eye drops are also contemplated as being within the scope of this disclosure.</p>
<p id="p0125" num="0125">Although the descriptions of pharmaceutical compositions provided herein are principally directed to pharmaceutical compositions which are suitable for administration to humans, such compositions are generally suitable for administration to animals of all sorts. Modification of pharmaceutical compositions suitable for administration to humans in order to render the compositions suitable for administration to various animals is well understood, and the ordinarily skilled veterinary pharmacologist can design and/or perform such modification with ordinary experimentation.</p>
<p id="p0126" num="0126">The compounds provided herein are typically formulated in dosage unit form for ease of administration and uniformity of dosage. It will be understood, however, that the total daily usage of the compositions described herein will be decided by a physician within the scope of sound medical judgment. The specific therapeutically effective dose level for any particular subject or organism will depend upon a variety of factors including the disease being treated and the severity of the disorder; the activity of the specific active ingredient employed; the specific composition employed; the age, body weight, general health, sex, and diet of the subject; the time of administration, route of administration, and rate of excretion of the specific active ingredient employed; the duration of the treatment; drugs used in combination or coincidental with the specific active ingredient employed; and like factors well known in the medical arts.<!-- EPO <DP n="55"> --></p>
<p id="p0127" num="0127">The compounds and compositions provided herein can be administered by any route, including enteral (<i>e.g.,</i> oral), parenteral, intravenous, intramuscular, intra-arterial, intramedullary, intrathecal, subcutaneous, intraventricular, transdermal, interdermal, rectal, intravaginal, intraperitoneal, topical (as by powders, ointments, creams, and/or drops), mucosal, nasal, bucal, sublingual; by intratracheal instillation, bronchial instillation, and/or inhalation; and/or as an oral spray, nasal spray, and/or aerosol. Specifically contemplated routes are oral administration, intravenous administration (<i>e.g</i>., systemic intravenous injection), regional administration <i>via</i> blood and/or lymph supply, and/or direct administration to an affected site. In general, the most appropriate route of administration will depend upon a variety of factors including the nature of the agent (<i>e.g.,</i> its stability in the environment of the gastrointestinal tract), and/or the condition of the subject (<i>e.g</i>., whether the subject is able to tolerate oral administration). In certain embodiments, the compound or pharmaceutical composition described herein is suitable for topical administration to the eye of a subject.</p>
<p id="p0128" num="0128">The exact amount of a compound required to achieve an effective amount will vary from subject to subject, depending, for example, on species, age, and general condition of a subject, severity of the side effects or disorder, identity of the particular compound, mode of administration, and the like. An effective amount may be included in a single dose (<i>e.g.,</i> single oral dose) or multiple doses (<i>e.g</i>., multiple oral doses). In certain embodiments, when multiple doses are administered to a subject or applied to a biological sample, tissue, or cell, any two doses of the multiple doses include different or substantially the same amounts of a compound described herein. In certain embodiments, when multiple doses are administered to a subject or applied to a biological sample, tissue, or cell, the frequency of administering the multiple doses to the subject or applying the multiple doses to the tissue or cell is three doses a day, two doses a day, one dose a day, one dose every other day, one dose every third day, one dose every week, one dose every two weeks, one dose every three weeks, or one dose every four weeks. In certain embodiments, the frequency of administering the multiple doses to the subject or applying the multiple doses to the tissue or cell is one dose per day. In certain embodiments, the frequency of administering the multiple doses to the subject or applying the multiple doses to the tissue or cell is two doses per day. In certain embodiments, the frequency of administering the multiple doses to the subject or applying the multiple doses to the tissue or cell is three doses per day. In certain embodiments, when multiple doses are administered to a subject or applied to a biological sample, tissue, or cell, the duration between the first dose and last dose of the multiple doses is one day, two days, four days, one<!-- EPO <DP n="56"> --> week, two weeks, three weeks, one month, two months, three months, four months, six months, nine months, one year, two years, three years, four years, five years, seven years, ten years, fifteen years, twenty years, or the lifetime of the subject, biological sample, tissue, or cell. In certain embodiments, the duration between the first dose and last dose of the multiple doses is three months, six months, or one year. In certain embodiments, the duration between the first dose and last dose of the multiple doses is the lifetime of the subject, biological sample, tissue, or cell. In certain embodiments, a dose (<i>e.g.,</i> a single dose, or any dose of multiple doses) described herein includes independently between 0.1 µg and 1 µg, between 0.001 mg and 0.01 mg, between 0.01 mg and 0.1 mg, between 0.1 mg and 1 mg, between 1 mg and 3 mg, between 3 mg and 10 mg, between 10 mg and 30 mg, between 30 mg and 100 mg, between 100 mg and 300 mg, between 300 mg and 1,000 mg, or between 1 g and 10 g, inclusive, of a compound described herein. In certain embodiments, a dose described herein includes independently between 1 mg and 3 mg, inclusive, of a compound described herein. In certain embodiments, a dose described herein includes independently between 3 mg and 10 mg, inclusive, of a compound described herein. In certain embodiments, a dose described herein includes independently between 10 mg and 30 mg, inclusive, of a compound described herein. In certain embodiments, a dose described herein includes independently between 30 mg and 100 mg, inclusive, of a compound described herein.</p>
<p id="p0129" num="0129">Dose ranges as described herein provide guidance for the administration of provided pharmaceutical compositions to an adult. The amount to be administered to, for example, a child or an adolescent can be determined by a medical practitioner or person skilled in the art and can be lower or the same as that administered to an adult.</p>
<p id="p0130" num="0130">A compound or composition, as described herein, can be administered in combination with one or more additional pharmaceutical agents (<i>e.g.</i>, therapeutically and/or prophylactically active agents) useful in treating and/or preventing a proliferative disease. The compounds or compositions can be administered in combination with additional pharmaceutical agents that improve their activity (<i>e.g.,</i> activity (<i>e.g.,</i> potency and/or efficacy) in treating a proliferative disease in a subject in need thereof, and/or in preventing a proliferative disease in a subject in need thereof), improve bioavailability, improve safety, reduce drug resistance, reduce and/or modify metabolism, inhibit excretion, and/or modify distribution in a subject, biological sample, tissue, or cell. It will also be appreciated that the therapy employed may achieve a desired effect for the same disorder, and/or it may achieve different effects. In certain embodiments, a pharmaceutical composition described herein including a compound described herein and an additional pharmaceutical agent shows a<!-- EPO <DP n="57"> --> synergistic effect that is absent in a pharmaceutical composition including one of the compound and the additional pharmaceutical agent, but not both.</p>
<p id="p0131" num="0131">The compound or composition can be administered concurrently with, prior to, or subsequent to one or more additional pharmaceutical agents, which may be useful as, <i>e.g.,</i> combination therapies in treating and/or preventing a proliferative disease. Pharmaceutical agents include therapeutically active agents. Pharmaceutical agents also include prophylactically active agents. Pharmaceutical agents include small organic molecules such as drug compounds (<i>e.g</i>., compounds approved for human or veterinary use by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration as provided in the Code of Federal Regulations (CFR)), peptides, proteins, carbohydrates, monosaccharides, oligosaccharides, polysaccharides, nucleoproteins, mucoproteins, lipoproteins, synthetic polypeptides or proteins, small molecules linked to proteins, glycoproteins, steroids, nucleic acids, DNAs, RNAs, nucleotides, nucleosides, oligonucleotides, antisense oligonucleotides, lipids, hormones, vitamins, and cells. In certain embodiments, the additional pharmaceutical agent is a pharmaceutical agent useful in treating a proliferative disease. In certain embodiments, the additional pharmaceutical agent is a pharmaceutical agent useful in preventing a proliferative disease. In certain embodiments, the additional pharmaceutical agent is a pharmaceutical agent approved by a regulatory agency (<i>e.g.,</i> the US FDA) for treating and/or preventing a proliferative disease. Each additional pharmaceutical agent may be administered at a dose and/or on a time schedule determined for that pharmaceutical agent. The additional pharmaceutical agents may also be administered together with each other and/or with the compound or composition described herein in a single dose or administered separately in different doses. The particular combination to employ in a regimen will take into account compatibility of the compound described herein with the additional pharmaceutical agent(s) and/or the desired therapeutic and/or prophylactic effect to be achieved. In general, it is expected that the additional pharmaceutical agent(s) in combination be utilized at levels that do not exceed the levels at which they are utilized individually. In some embodiments, the levels utilized in combination will be lower than those utilized individually.</p>
<p id="p0132" num="0132">In certain embodiments, the additional pharmaceutical agent is an anti-proliferative agent (<i>e.g</i>., anti-cancer agent). In certain embodiments, the additional pharmaceutical agent is an anti-angiogenesis agent, anti-inflammatory agent, immunosuppressant, anti-bacterial agent, anti-viral agent, cardiovascular agent, cholesterol-lowering agent, anti-diabetic agent, anti-allergic agent, pain-relieving agent, or a combination thereof. In certain embodiments, the compounds described herein or pharmaceutical compositions can be administered in<!-- EPO <DP n="58"> --> combination with an anti-cancer therapy including, but not limited to, transplantation (e.g., bone marrow transplantation, stem cell transplantation), surgery, radiation therapy, immunotherapy, and chemotherapy.</p>
<p id="p0133" num="0133">Also encompassed by the disclosure are kits (<i>e.g</i>., pharmaceutical packs). The kits provided may comprise a pharmaceutical composition or compound described herein and a container (<i>e.g</i>., a vial, ampule, bottle, syringe, and/or dispenser package, or other suitable container). In some embodiments, provided kits may optionally further include a second container comprising a pharmaceutical excipient for dilution or suspension of a pharmaceutical composition or compound described herein. In some embodiments, the pharmaceutical composition or compound described herein provided in the first container and the second container are combined to form one unit dosage form.</p>
<p id="p0134" num="0134">In certain embodiments, a kit described herein includes a first container comprising a compound or pharmaceutical composition described herein. In certain embodiments, a kit described herein is useful in treating a proliferative disease (<i>e.g</i>., metastatic cancer) in a subject in need thereof, and/or preventing a proliferative disease in a subject in need thereof.</p>
<p id="p0135" num="0135">In certain embodiments, a kit described herein further includes instructions for using the compound or pharmaceutical composition included in the kit. A kit described herein may also include information as required by a regulatory agency such as the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA). In certain embodiments, the information included in the kits is prescribing information. In certain embodiments, the kits and instructions provide for treating a proliferative disease in a subject in need thereof, and/or preventing a proliferative disease in a subject in need thereof. A kit described herein may include one or more additional pharmaceutical agents described herein as a separate composition.</p>
<heading id="h0009"><i>Methods of Treatment</i></heading>
<p id="p0136" num="0136">The compounds described herein may:
<ul id="ul0010" list-style="bullet" compact="compact">
<li>exhibit cytotoxic or growth inhibitory effect on cancer cell lines maintained <i>in vitro</i> or in animal studies using a scientifically acceptable cancer cell xenograft model;</li>
<li>exhibit a therapeutic profile (<i>e.g</i>., optimum safety and curative effect) that is superior to existing chemotherapeutic agents; and/or</li>
<li>exhibit a pharmacokinetic profile (<i>e.g</i>., increased solubility and increased bioavailability) that is superior to existing chemotherapeutic agents.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0137" num="0137">The present disclosure provides methods of treating a proliferative disease in a subject in need thereof, the methods comprising administering to the subject an effective<!-- EPO <DP n="59"> --> amount (<i>e.g</i>., therapeutically effective amount) of a compound, or pharmaceutical composition thereof, described herein.</p>
<p id="p0138" num="0138">Another aspect of the present disclosure relates to methods of preventing proliferative disease in a subject in need thereof, the methods comprising administering to the subject an effective amount (<i>e.g</i>., prophylactically effective amount) of a compound, or pharmaceutical composition thereof, described herein.</p>
<p id="p0139" num="0139">The compounds and pharmaceutical compositions described herein are useful in treating and/or preventing proliferative diseases. In certain embodiments, the proliferative disease is cancer. In certain embodiments, the proliferative disease is metastatic cancer. In certain embodiments, the proliferative disease is an inflammatory disease. In certain embodiments, the proliferative disease is an autoimmune disease.</p>
<p id="p0140" num="0140">In certain embodiments, the method described herein further includes administering to the subject an additional pharmaceutical agent. In certain embodiments, the method described herein further includes contacting the biological sample with an additional pharmaceutical agent. In certain embodiments, the method described herein further includes contacting the tissue with an additional pharmaceutical agent. In certain embodiments, the method described herein further includes contacting the cell with an additional pharmaceutical agent. In certain embodiments, the method described herein further includes radiotherapy, immunotherapy, and/or transplantation (<i>e.g</i>., bone marrow transplantation).</p>
<heading id="h0010"><i>Uses</i></heading>
<p id="p0141" num="0141">In another aspect, the present disclosure provides the compounds described herein for a method of treating a proliferative disease in the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p0142" num="0142">In still another aspect, the present disclosure provides the pharmaceutical compositions described herein for use in a method of treating a proliferative disease in the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p0143" num="0143">In still another aspect, the present disclosure provides uses of the compounds described herein in a method of treating a proliferative disease in the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p0144" num="0144">In further another aspect, the present disclosure provides uses of the pharmaceutical compositions described herein in a method of treating a proliferative disease in the disclosure.</p>
<heading id="h0011">EXAMPLES</heading>
<p id="p0145" num="0145">In order that the present disclosure may be more fully understood, the following examples are set forth. The synthetic and biological examples described in this application<!-- EPO <DP n="60"> --> are offered to illustrate the compounds, pharmaceutical compositions, and methods provided herein and are not to be construed in any way as limiting their scope.</p>
<heading id="h0012"><i>Example 1A. Selected Compounds and Biological Activity</i></heading>
<p id="p0146" num="0146">Table 1 below shows the results of a viability assay: the effect of selected exemplary compounds at concentrations of 1.0 µM and 10 µM on viability.
<tables id="tabl0001" num="0001">
<table frame="all">
<title><i>Table 1.</i> Viability Assay: Effect of Selected Compounds on Viability</title>
<tgroup cols="4">
<colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="25mm"/>
<colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="82mm"/>
<colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="14mm"/>
<colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="16mm"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="col1" nameend="col2" align="left" valign="top"/>
<entry namest="col3" nameend="col4" align="center" valign="top"><b>% viability</b></entry></row>
<row>
<entry valign="top"><b>Compound #</b></entry>
<entry valign="top"><b>Structure</b></entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top"><b>10 µm</b></entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top"><b>1.0 µM</b></entry></row></thead>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry>9<br/>
<b>(I-1)</b> OBD9</entry>
<entry>
<chemistry id="chem0054" num="0054"><img id="ib0054" file="imgb0054.tif" wi="69" he="24" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></entry>
<entry align="center">34.3</entry>
<entry align="center">34.9</entry></row>
<row>
<entry>12<br/>
<b>(I-2)</b></entry>
<entry>
<chemistry id="chem0055" num="0055"><img id="ib0055" file="imgb0055.tif" wi="76" he="27" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></entry>
<entry align="center">35.2</entry>
<entry align="center">94.5</entry></row>
<row>
<entry>13<br/>
<b>(I-3)</b></entry>
<entry>
<chemistry id="chem0056" num="0056"><img id="ib0056" file="imgb0056.tif" wi="72" he="27" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></entry>
<entry align="center">49.1</entry>
<entry align="center">80.9</entry></row>
<row>
<entry>15<br/>
<b>(I-4)</b></entry>
<entry>
<chemistry id="chem0057" num="0057"><img id="ib0057" file="imgb0057.tif" wi="65" he="29" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></entry>
<entry align="center">35.3</entry>
<entry align="center">97.4</entry></row>
<row>
<entry>16<br/>
<b>(I-5)</b></entry>
<entry>
<chemistry id="chem0058" num="0058"><img id="ib0058" file="imgb0058.tif" wi="67" he="29" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></entry>
<entry align="center">90.3</entry>
<entry align="center">90.1</entry></row>
<row>
<entry>17<br/>
<b>(I-6)</b> OBD17</entry>
<entry>
<chemistry id="chem0059" num="0059"><img id="ib0059" file="imgb0059.tif" wi="72" he="29" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></entry>
<entry align="center">84.8</entry>
<entry align="center">93.9</entry></row><!-- EPO <DP n="61"> -->
<row>
<entry>51<br/>
<b>(I-7)</b></entry>
<entry>
<chemistry id="chem0060" num="0060"><img id="ib0060" file="imgb0060.tif" wi="58" he="27" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></entry>
<entry/>
<entry/></row>
<row>
<entry>54<br/>
<b>(I-8)</b></entry>
<entry>
<chemistry id="chem0061" num="0061"><img id="ib0061" file="imgb0061.tif" wi="64" he="24" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></entry>
<entry/>
<entry/></row>
<row>
<entry>58<br/>
<b>(I-9)</b></entry>
<entry>
<chemistry id="chem0062" num="0062"><img id="ib0062" file="imgb0062.tif" wi="58" he="27" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></entry>
<entry/>
<entry/></row>
<row>
<entry>66<br/>
<b>(I-10)</b></entry>
<entry>
<chemistry id="chem0063" num="0063"><img id="ib0063" file="imgb0063.tif" wi="58" he="27" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></entry>
<entry/>
<entry/></row></tbody></tgroup>
</table>
</tables></p>
<heading id="h0013"><i>Preparation of the Compounds</i></heading>
<p id="p0147" num="0147">The compounds of Formula (I) provided herein can be prepared from readily available starting materials using the following general methods and procedures (e.g., Examples 1 to 9). Where typical or preferred process conditions (<i>i.e.,</i> reaction temperatures, times, mole ratios of reactants, solvents, pressures, <i>etc.</i>) are given, other process conditions can also be used unless otherwise stated. Optimum reaction conditions may vary with the particular reactants or solvents used, but such conditions can be determined by those skilled in the art by routine optimization procedures.<!-- EPO <DP n="62"> --></p>
<heading id="h0014"><i>Example 1. Preparation of Methy N-(5-{4-[methyl(oxetan-3-yl)amino]benzoyl}-1H-1,3-benzodiazol-2-yl)carbamate</i></heading>
<p id="p0148" num="0148">
<chemistry id="chem0064" num="0064"><img id="ib0064" file="imgb0064.tif" wi="165" he="79" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></p>
<heading id="h0015">N-[4-(3,4-dinitrobenzoyl)phenyl]-N-methylacetamide</heading>
<p id="p0149" num="0149">
<chemistry id="chem0065" num="0065"><img id="ib0065" file="imgb0065.tif" wi="52" he="24" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></p>
<p id="p0150" num="0150">To a solution of 3,4-dinitrobenzoic acid (750 mg, 3.54 mmol) in DCM (8 mL) was added (COCl<sub>2</sub>)<sub>2</sub> (2.04 g, 16.08 mmol) and a drop of DMF at 0 °C; the resulting mixture was stirred at room temperature for 1 h, and thin layer chromatography (TLC) showed the reaction was over. The reaction mixture was concentrated to give an oil. Then, N-methyl-N-phenylacetamide (0.479 g, 3.21 mmol) and AlCl<sub>3</sub> (1.6 g) was added, and the resulting mixture was stirred at 100 °C for 4 h. The reaction mixture was diluted with water, extracted with DCM, dried over Na<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub>, concentrated and purified by silica gel (PE: ethyl acetate =1:1) to give a yellow oil (240mg, 22% yield). <sup>1</sup>H NMR (400 MHz, CDCl<sub>3</sub>): δ 8.33 (1H), 8.17 (1H), 8.05 (d, 1H), 7.85 (d, 2H), 7.42 (d, 2H), 3.35 (s, 3H), 2.05 (s, 3H). MS (ES): 344.2 (M+H)<sup>+</sup>.<!-- EPO <DP n="63"> --></p>
<heading id="h0016">4-(3,4-dinitrobenzoyl)-N-methylaniline</heading>
<p id="p0151" num="0151">
<chemistry id="chem0066" num="0066"><img id="ib0066" file="imgb0066.tif" wi="47" he="24" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></p>
<p id="p0152" num="0152">To a solution of N-[4-(3,4-dinitrobenzoyl)phenyl]-N-methylacetamide (250 mg, 0.73 mmol) in water (2 mL) was added concentrated HCl (2 mmol) at 0 °C, the resulting mixture was stirred at reflux overnight TLC showed the reaction was over. The reaction mixture was adjusted pH to 8 with aqueous NaOH, extracted with DCM, dried over Na<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub>, concentrated and purified by silica gel (PE: ethyl acetate =3:1) to afford the titled compound as a yellow solid (150 mg, 68% yield). <sup>1</sup>H NMR (400 MHz, CDCl<sub>3</sub>): δ 8.21 (1H), 8.05-8.0 (m, 2H), 7.70 (d, 2H), 6.61 (d, 2H), 4.5 (br s, 1H), 2.95 (d, 3H). MS (ES): 302.3 (M+H)<sup>+</sup>.</p>
<heading id="h0017"><b>(3,4-dinitrophenyl)[4-(methylamino)phenyl]methanol</b></heading>
<p id="p0153" num="0153">
<chemistry id="chem0067" num="0067"><img id="ib0067" file="imgb0067.tif" wi="48" he="24" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></p>
<p id="p0154" num="0154">To a solution of <b>4-(3,4-dinitrobenzoyl)-N-methylaniline</b> (500 mg, 0.166 mmol) in MeOH (8 mL) was added NaBH<sub>4</sub> (123 mg, 3.22 mmol). The resulting mixture was stirred at room temperature for 1 h. TLC showed the reaction was over. The reaction was diluted with water, extracted with DCM, dried over Na<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub>, and concentrated to give the titled compound as a solid. (500 mg, 100% yield). <sup>1</sup>H NMR (400 MHz, CDCl<sub>3</sub>): δ 7.94 (1H), 7.88 (d, 1H), 7.72 (d, 1H), 7.11 (d, 2H), 6.58 (d, 2H), 5.80 (br s, 1H), 3.70 (br s, 1H), 2.83 (d, 3H). MS (ES): 304.0 (M+H)<sup>+</sup>.</p>
<heading id="h0018"><b>(3,4-dinitrophenyl)({4-[methyl(oxetan-3-yl)amino]phenyl})methanol</b></heading>
<p id="p0155" num="0155">
<chemistry id="chem0068" num="0068"><img id="ib0068" file="imgb0068.tif" wi="56" he="24" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></p>
<p id="p0156" num="0156">To a solution of (3,4-dinitrophenyl)[4-(methylamino)phenyl]methanol (50 mg, 0.166 mmol) in MeOH (1.5 mL) was added oxetan-3-one (30 mg, 0.415 mmol) and acetic acid (21 mg, 0.332 mmol). The resulting mixture was stirred at room temperature for 1 h. Then, NaBH<sub>3</sub>(CN) (36 mg, 0.332 mmol) was added to the mixture and stirred at room temperature<!-- EPO <DP n="64"> --> overnight. LC-MS (Lot#: MC0968-024-R1) showed desired product was found. The reaction was diluted with water, extracted with DCM, dried over Na<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub>, concentrated and purified by silica gel to give the titled compound as a solid. (22 mg, 38% yield). <sup>1</sup>H NMR (400 MHz, CDCl<sub>3</sub>): δ 7.91 (m, 2H), 7.73 (d, 1H), 7.16 (d, 2H), 6.60 (d, 2H), 5.83 (d, 1H), 4.85 (m, 2H), 4.70 (m, 3H), 2.94 (s, 3H). MS (ES): 360.1 (M+H)<sup>+</sup>.</p>
<heading id="h0019">N-[4-(3,4-dinitrobenzoyl)phenyl]-N-methyloxetan-3-amine</heading>
<p id="p0157" num="0157">
<chemistry id="chem0069" num="0069"><img id="ib0069" file="imgb0069.tif" wi="56" he="24" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></p>
<p id="p0158" num="0158">To a solution of (3,4-dinitrophenyl)({4-[methyl(oxetan-3-yl)amino]phenyl})methanol (250 mg, 0.696 mmol) in DCM (5 mL) was added DMP (590 mg, 1.39 mmol). The resulting mixture was stirred at room temperature for 1 h. The reaction was diluted with water, extracted with DCM, dried over Na<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub>, concentrated and purified by silica gel (PE: ethyl acetate = 1:1) to give the titled compound as a yellow solid. (0.130 g, 52% yield). MS (ES): 358.1 (M-H)<sup>-</sup>.</p>
<heading id="h0020"><b>4-{4-[methyl(oxetan-3-yl)amino]benzoyl}benzene-1,2-diamine</b></heading>
<p id="p0159" num="0159">
<chemistry id="chem0070" num="0070"><img id="ib0070" file="imgb0070.tif" wi="55" he="24" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></p>
<p id="p0160" num="0160">To a solution of N-[4-(3,4-dinitrobenzoyl)phenyl]-N-methyloxetan-3-amine (100 mg, 0.280 mmol) in MeOH (1.5 mL) and THF (1 mL) was added Pd/C (10 mg, wet, 10%). The mixture was stirred at room temperature for 1 h. The reaction mixture was filtered and the filtrate was concentrated to give the titled compound as a solid (Lot: mc0968-033-1, 90 mg, 100% yield, confirmed by HNMR). <sup>1</sup>H NMR (400 MHz, CDCl<sub>3</sub>): δ 7.74 (d, 2H),7.25-7.22 (m, 2H), 6.70 (d, 1H), 6.60 (d, 2H). MS (ES): 298.1 (M+H)<sup>+</sup>.<!-- EPO <DP n="65"> --></p>
<heading id="h0021"><b>Methyl N-(5-{4-[methyl(oxetan-3-yl)amino]benzoyl}-1H-1,3-benzodiazol-2-yl)carbamate</b></heading>
<p id="p0161" num="0161">
<chemistry id="chem0071" num="0071"><img id="ib0071" file="imgb0071.tif" wi="69" he="24" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></p>
<p id="p0162" num="0162">To a solution of 4-{4-[methyl(oxetan-3-yl)amino]benzoyl}benzene-1,2-diamine (90 mg, 0.303 mmol) in EtOH (2 mL) was added 1,3-bis(methoxycarbonyl)-2-methyl-2-thiopseudourea (80 mg, 0.394 mmol). The mixture was stirred at reflux overnight. TLC showed the reaction was completed. The reaction mixture was concentrated and purified by silica gel (DCM: MeOH = 15:1) to give the titled compound as a white solid (12 mg, 10% yield, confirmed by LC-MS, HNMR and HPLC). <sup>1</sup>H NMR (400 MHz, CDCl<sub>3</sub>) 3.09 (s, 3H), 3.88 (s, 3H), 4.81-4.92 (m, 5 H), 6.64 (d, 2H), 7.44-8.11 (m, 6H), 10.74 (brs, 1H). MS (ES): 281.1 (M+H)<sup>+</sup>.</p>
<heading id="h0022"><i>Example 2. Preparation of (3-methyloxetan-3-yl)methyl N-[5-(propylsulfanyl)-1H-1,3-benzodiazol-2-yl]carbamate</i></heading>
<p id="p0163" num="0163">
<chemistry id="chem0072" num="0072"><img id="ib0072" file="imgb0072.tif" wi="65" he="24" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></p>
<p id="p0164" num="0164">The mixture of albendazole (530 mg) and 3-hydroxyl-3-methyl-oxetane (1 mL) in triethylamine (15 mL) was heated at 90 °C overnight. The solvent was removed under vacuum. The desired product was isolated by silica gel chromatography (hexanes: ethyl acetate = 1:1) as a white solid. MS (ES): 336.5 (M+H)<sup>+</sup>.</p>
<heading id="h0023"><i>Example 3. Preparation of Oxetan-3-yl-N-(5-benzoyl-1H-1,3-benzodiazol-2-yl)carbamate</i></heading>
<p id="p0165" num="0165">
<chemistry id="chem0073" num="0073"><img id="ib0073" file="imgb0073.tif" wi="58" he="27" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></p>
<p id="p0166" num="0166">The mixture of mebendazole (295 mg), 3-hydroxyloxetane (370 mg), and triethylamine (0.5 mL) in DMF (15 mL) was heated in a microwave synthesizer at 60 °C for 15 minutes, then 70 °C for 5 minutes. The solvent was removed under vacuum. The desired<!-- EPO <DP n="66"> --> product was isolated by silica gel chromatography (dichloromethane: methanol = 3:1) as a white solid (180 mg, 53%). MS (ES): 338.5 (M+H)<sup>+</sup>.</p>
<heading id="h0024"><i>Example 4. Preparation of Oxetan-3-yl-N-[5-(phenylsuffanyl)-1H-1,3-benzodiazol-2-yl]carbamate</i></heading>
<p id="p0167" num="0167">
<chemistry id="chem0074" num="0074"><img id="ib0074" file="imgb0074.tif" wi="58" he="27" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></p>
<p id="p0168" num="0168">The mixture of fenbendazole (299mg), 3-hydroxyloxetane (370mg), and triethylamine (0.5mL) in DMF (15mL) was heated in a microwave synthesizer at then 70 °C for 5 minutes. The solvent was removed under vacuum. The desired product was isolated by silica gel chromatography (dichloromethane: methanol = 9:1) as a white solid. MS (ES): 342.4 (M+H)<sup>+</sup>.</p>
<heading id="h0025"><i>Example 5. Preparation of Oxetan-3-yl N-[5-(propylsuffanyl)-1H-1,3-benzodiazol-2-yl]carbamate</i></heading>
<p id="p0169" num="0169">
<chemistry id="chem0075" num="0075"><img id="ib0075" file="imgb0075.tif" wi="58" he="27" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></p>
<p id="p0170" num="0170">The mixture of albendazole (530mg) and 3-hydroxyloxetane (740mg) in triethylamine was heated at 90 °C overnight. The solvent was removed under vacuum. The desired product was isolated by silica gel chromatography (dichloromethane: methanol = 40:1) as a white solid. MS (ES): 308.6 (M+H)<sup>+</sup>.</p>
<heading id="h0026"><i>Example 5. Preparation of 2-(Dimethylamino)ethyl N-[5-(propylsuffanyl)-1H-1,3-benzodiazol-2-yl]carbamate</i></heading>
<p id="p0171" num="0171">
<chemistry id="chem0076" num="0076"><img id="ib0076" file="imgb0076.tif" wi="66" he="29" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></p>
<p id="p0172" num="0172">The mixture of albenzadole (265 mg, 1.0 mmol) and 2-(N,N-dimethylamino)ethanol (2.0 mL) in pyridine (15 mL) was heated to 90-100 °C for 3 hours. The desired product was<!-- EPO <DP n="67"> --> isolated by silica gel chromatography (dichloromethane: methanol = 3:1) as a yellow solid. MS (ES): 323.6 (M+H)<sup>+</sup>.</p>
<heading id="h0027"><i>Example 6. Preparation of 3-(dimethylamino)propyl N-[5-(propylsulfanyl)-1H-1,3-benzodiazol-2-yl]carbamate</i></heading>
<p id="p0173" num="0173">
<chemistry id="chem0077" num="0077"><img id="ib0077" file="imgb0077.tif" wi="68" he="29" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></p>
<p id="p0174" num="0174">The mixture of albenzadole (530 mg, 2.0 mmol) and 3-(N,N-dimethylamino)propanol (2.0 mL) in pyridine (15 mL) was heated to 90-100 °C for 3 hours. The desired product was isolated by silica gel chromatography (dichloromethane: methanol = 3:1) as a yellow solid. MS (ES): 337.6 (M+H)<sup>+</sup>.</p>
<heading id="h0028"><i>Example 7. Preparation of 3-(dimethylamino)propyl N-[5-(4-fluorobenzoyl)-1H-1,3-benzodiazol-2-yl]carbamate</i></heading>
<p id="p0175" num="0175">
<chemistry id="chem0078" num="0078"><img id="ib0078" file="imgb0078.tif" wi="72" he="29" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></p>
<p id="p0176" num="0176">The mixture of flubendazole (626 mg, 2.0 mmol) and 3-(N,N-dimethylamino)propanol (2.0 mL) in pyridine (15 mL) was heated to 90-100 °C for 3 hours. The desired product was isolated by silica gel chromatography (dichloromethane: methanol = 2:1) as a solid. MS (ES): 385.6 (M+H)<sup>+</sup>.<!-- EPO <DP n="68"> --></p>
<heading id="h0029"><i>Example 8. Preparation of methyl N-{5-[3-(4-methylpiperazin-1-yl)phenoxy]-1H-1,3-benzodiazol-2-yl}carbamate</i></heading>
<p id="p0177" num="0177">
<chemistry id="chem0079" num="0079"><img id="ib0079" file="imgb0079.tif" wi="165" he="53" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></p>
<heading id="h0030"><b>3-(4-methylpiperazin-1-yl)phenol</b></heading>
<p id="p0178" num="0178">
<chemistry id="chem0080" num="0080"><img id="ib0080" file="imgb0080.tif" wi="38" he="21" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></p>
<p id="p0179" num="0179">To a stirred solution of 3-bromophenol (0.6 g, 3.5 mmol) in anhydrous toluene (12 mL) was added N-methylpiperazine (0.5 mL, 4.2 mmol), Pd<sub>2</sub>(dba)<sub>3</sub> (79 mg, 0.087 mmol), <sup>t</sup>BuONa (0.933 g, 9.7 mmol) and BINAP (0.216 g, 0.35 mmol) in this sequence. The resulting solution was heated to reflux under the protection of argon for 1 hour. HPLC indicated the reaction is complete. After cooling to room temperature (rt), 20 mL of ethyl acetate and 20 mL of water were added to the reaction mixture, and the black precipitate was filtered. After separation of the filtrate, the water phase was extracted with ethyl acetate (20 mL X 5). The combined organic phase was washed with brine, dried over Na<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub>, and concentrated under reduced pressure to give the crude product, which was purified by column chromatography (DCM: MeOH = 20:1 ∼15:1 ∼10:1) to give the titled compound (376 mg, 56%).</p>
<heading id="h0031"><b>5-[3-(4-methylpiperazin-1-yl)phenoxy]-2-nitroaniline</b></heading>
<p id="p0180" num="0180">
<chemistry id="chem0081" num="0081"><img id="ib0081" file="imgb0081.tif" wi="57" he="22" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></p>
<p id="p0181" num="0181">To a stirred solution of 3-(4-methylpiperazin-1-yl)phenol (360 mg, 1.87 mmol) in anhydrous DMF (1.5 mL) was added 60% NaH (54 mg, 2.24 mmol) slowly, followed by 5-chloro-2-nitroaniline (323 mg, 1.87 mmol) under argon. The resulting mixture was heated to<!-- EPO <DP n="69"> --> 120 °C and kept overnight. The reaction was not yet complete indicated by TLC. Additional 5-chloro-2-nitroaniline (968 mg) and NaH (135 mg) were added to the reaction mixture. The reaction was complete after one hour. After cooling, 30 mL of cold water and 30 mL of ethyl acetate were added to the reaction mixture. The organic layer was separated and the aqueous layer was extracted with ethyl acetate twice (30 mL, 20 mL). The combined organic phase was washed with brine, dried over Na<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub>, and filtered. After solvent removal, purification on a silica gel column chromatography (DCM: MeOH = 50:1 ∼40:1 ∼30:1 ∼20:1 ∼10:1) was used to afford the titled compound (406 mg, 66%).</p>
<heading id="h0032"><b>4-[3-(4-methylpiperazin-1-yl)phenoxy]benzene-1,2-diamine</b></heading>
<p id="p0182" num="0182">
<chemistry id="chem0082" num="0082"><img id="ib0082" file="imgb0082.tif" wi="57" he="22" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></p>
<p id="p0183" num="0183">The substrate 5-[3-(4-methylpiperazin-1-yl)phenoxy]-2-nitroaniline (297 mg, 0.9 mmol) was treated with zinc dust (414 mg, 6.3 mmol) in acetic acid (19 mL) for one hour at room temperature (rt). The mixture was filtered through celite and the filter cake was washed with DCM. The filtrate was then concentrated under reduced pressure. 5N NaOH was added to the residue to pH 13, followed by DCM. The resulting precipitate was filtered and dried in vacuo to give the first batch product (72 mg). The filtrate was separated and the aqueous layer was extracted with DCM. The combined organic phase was dried over Na<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub>, concentrated under reduced pressure to give the second batch product (79 mg). HPLC indicated the two batches of product have similar purity. The two batches of product were combined (151 mg, 42%) for the next step.</p>
<heading id="h0033"><b>Methyl N-{5-[3-(4-methylpiperazin-1-yl)phenoxy]-1H-1,3-benzodiazol-2-yl}carbamate</b></heading>
<p id="p0184" num="0184">
<chemistry id="chem0083" num="0083"><img id="ib0083" file="imgb0083.tif" wi="71" he="24" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></p>
<p id="p0185" num="0185">To a stirred solution of 4-[3-(4-methylpiperazin-1-yl)phenoxy]benzene-1,2-diamine (139 mg, 0.46 mmol) in acetic acid (4 mL) was added 1,3-bis(methoxycarbonyl)-2-methyl-2-thiopseudourea (240 mg, 1.16 mmol) under argon. The resulting solution was heated to 85 °C and kept for one hour. HPLC indicated the reaction is complete. After cooling to room<!-- EPO <DP n="70"> --> temperature (rt), the solvent was removed under reduced pressure. 9 mL of 2N HCl was added to the residue and the mixture was stirred at room temperature for one hour. The mixture was then neutralized to pH 13 with aqueous 5N NaOH solution. The resulting aqueous phase was extracted with ethyl acetate three times. The combined organic phase was washed with brine, dried over Na<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub>. After solvent removal, sequence purification on a silica gel column chromatography (DCM: MeOH = 50:1 ∼40:1 ∼30:1 ∼20:1 ∼10:1) was used to afford the titled compound as a pale yellow solid. <sup>1</sup>H NMR (400 MHz, CD<sub>6</sub>OD): δ 7.40 (m, 1H), 7.20 (m, 1H), 7.09 (s, 1H), 6.86 (d, 1H), 6.71 (d, 1H), 6.60 (s, 1H), 6.45 (d, 1H), 3.86 (s, 3H), 3.22 (m, 4H), 2.75 (m, 4H), 2.46 (s, 3H). MS (ES): 382.2 (M+H)<sup>+</sup>.</p>
<heading id="h0034"><i>Example 9. Preparation of methyl N-(5-{[6-(4-methylpiperazin-1yl)pyridin-2-yl]oxy}-1H-1,3-benzodiazol-2-yl)carbamate</i></heading>
<p id="p0186" num="0186">
<chemistry id="chem0084" num="0084"><img id="ib0084" file="imgb0084.tif" wi="165" he="54" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></p>
<heading id="h0035">4-[(6-chloropyridin-2-yl)oxy]-2-nitroaniline</heading>
<p id="p0187" num="0187">
<chemistry id="chem0085" num="0085"><img id="ib0085" file="imgb0085.tif" wi="46" he="17" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></p>
<p id="p0188" num="0188">To a stirred solution of 2,6-dichloropyridine (0.48 g, 3.24 mmol), 4-amino-3-nitrophenol (0.5 g, 3.24 mmol) in anhydrous DMF (15 mL) was added potassium carbonate (0.67 g, 4.87 mmol) under argon. The resulting mixture was heated to 120 °C overnight. After cooling, 35 mL of water and 35 mL of ethyl acetate were added to the reaction mixture. After separation of the organic layer, the aqueous layer was extracted with ethyl acetate twice (100 mL, 50 mL). The combined organic phase was washed with brine, dried over Na<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub>, and concentrated under reduced pressure to give the titled compound (750 mg, 87%).<!-- EPO <DP n="71"> --></p>
<heading id="h0036"><b>4-{[6-(4-methylpiperazin-1-yl)pyridin-2-yl]oxy}-2-nitroaniline</b></heading>
<p id="p0189" num="0189">
<chemistry id="chem0086" num="0086"><img id="ib0086" file="imgb0086.tif" wi="57" he="22" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></p>
<p id="p0190" num="0190">The substrate 4-[(6-chloropyridin-2-yl)oxy]-2-nitroaniline (0.44 g, 1.5 mmol) was dissolved in 8.8 mL of N-methylpiperazine. The resulting solution was heated to reflux under argon for three hours. After cooling to room temperature (rt), 30 mL of aqueous saturated NH<sub>4</sub>Cl solution was added slowly to the mixture. The resulting mixture was then extracted with ethyl acetate (20 mL X 4). The combined organic phase was dried over Na<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub>, and concentrated under reduced pressure to give the titled compound for the next step.</p>
<heading id="h0037"><b>4-{[6-(4-methylpiperazin-1-yl)pyridin-2-yl]oxy}benzene-1,2-diamine</b></heading>
<p id="p0191" num="0191">
<chemistry id="chem0087" num="0087"><img id="ib0087" file="imgb0087.tif" wi="57" he="22" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></p>
<p id="p0192" num="0192">The substrate 4-{[6-(4-methylpiperazin-1-yl)pyridin-2-yl]oxy}-2-nitroaniline (595 mg, 1.8 mmol) was treated with zinc dust (827 mg, 12.6 mmol) in acetic acid (39 mL) for 10 hours at room temperature (rt) The mixture was filtered through celite and the filter cake was washed with ethyl acetate. The filtrate was then concentrated under reduced pressure. 29 mL of 5N NaOH was added to the residue, followed by 20 mL of ethyl acetate. The resulting precipitate was filtered and dried in vacuo to give the first batch product (395 mg). The filtrate was separated and the aqueous layer was extracted with ethyl acetate (20 mL X 2). The combined organic phase was dried over Na<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub>, and concentrated under reduced pressure to give the second batch product (267 mg). HPLC indicated the two batch product have similar purity. The two batches of product was combined (654 mg) for the next step.</p>
<heading id="h0038"><b>Methyl N-(5-{[6-(4-methylpiperazin-1-yl)pyridin-2-yl]oxy}-1H-1,3-benzodiazol-2-yl)carbamate</b></heading>
<p id="p0193" num="0193">
<chemistry id="chem0088" num="0088"><img id="ib0088" file="imgb0088.tif" wi="71" he="24" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry><!-- EPO <DP n="72"> --></p>
<p id="p0194" num="0194">To a stirred solution of 4-{[6-(4-methylpiperazin-1-yl)pyridin-2-yl]oxy}benzene-1,2-diamine (290 mg, 0.97 mmol) in acetic acid (8 mL) was added 1,3-bis(methoxycarbonyl)-2-methyl-2-thiopseudourea (499 mg, 2.42 mmol) under argon. The resulting solution was heated to 85 °C and kept for 30 min. HPLC indicated the reaction is complete. After cooling to room temperature (rt), the solvent was removed under reduced pressure. 15 mL of 2N HCl was added to the residue and the mixture was stirred at room temperature (rt) for one hour. The mixture was then neutralized to pH 13 with aqueous 5N NaOH solution. The resulting aqueous phase was extracted with ethyl acetate three times. The combined organic phase was dried over Na<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub>, and concentrated under reduced pressure to give the crude product, which was purified by sequential column chromatography (DCM: MeOH = 50:1 ∼40:1 ∼30:1 ∼20:1 -10:1) to afford the titled compound (94 mg, 25%) as a pale yellow solid. <sup>1</sup>H NMR (400 MHz, CD<sub>6</sub>OD): δ 7.65 (m, 2H), 7.40 (s, 1H), 7.24 (d, 1H), 6.62 (d, 1H), 6.40 (d, 1H), 4.24 (d, 2H), 3.98 (s, 3H), 3.50 (m, 2H), 3.10 (m, 4H), 2.90 (s, 3H). MS (ES): 383.2 (M+H)<sup>+</sup>.</p>
<heading id="h0039">EQUIVALENTS AND SCOPE</heading>
<p id="p0195" num="0195">In the claims, articles such as "a," "an," and "the" may mean one or more than one unless indicated to the contrary or otherwise evident from the context. Claims or descriptions that include "or" between one or more members of a group are considered satisfied if one, more than one, or all of the group members are present in, employed in, or otherwise relevant to a given product or process unless indicated to the contrary or otherwise evident from the context. The invention includes embodiments in which exactly one member of the group is present in, employed in, or otherwise relevant to a given product or process. The invention includes embodiments in which more than one, or all of the group members are present in, employed in, or otherwise relevant to a given product or process.</p>
<p id="p0196" num="0196">Furthermore, the invention encompasses all variations, combinations, and permutations in which one or more limitations, elements, clauses, and descriptive terms from one or more of the listed claims is introduced into another claim. For example, any claim that is dependent on another claim can be modified to include one or more limitations found in any other claim that is dependent on the same base claim. Where elements are presented as lists, <i>e.g.,</i> in Markush group format, each subgroup of the elements is also disclosed, and any element(s) can be removed from the group. It should it be understood that, in general, where the invention, or aspects of the invention, is/are referred to as comprising particular elements and/or features, certain embodiments of the invention or aspects of the invention consist, or consist essentially of, such elements and/or features. For purposes of simplicity, those<!-- EPO <DP n="73"> --> embodiments have not been specifically set forth <i>in haec verba</i> herein. It is also noted that the terms "comprising" and "containing" are intended to be open and permits the inclusion of additional elements or steps. Where ranges are given, endpoints are included. Furthermore, unless otherwise indicated or otherwise evident from the context and understanding of one of ordinary skill in the art, values that are expressed as ranges can assume any specific value or sub-range within the stated ranges in different embodiments of the invention, to the tenth of the unit of the lower limit of the range, unless the context clearly dictates otherwise.</p>
<p id="p0197" num="0197">This application refers to various issued patents, published patent applications, journal articles, and other publications, all of which are incorporated herein by reference. If there is a conflict between any of the incorporated references and the instant specification, the specification shall control. In addition, any particular embodiment of the present invention that falls within the prior art may be explicitly excluded from any one or more of the claims. Because such embodiments are deemed to be known to one of ordinary skill in the art, they may be excluded even if the exclusion is not set forth explicitly herein. Any particular embodiment of the invention can be excluded from any claim, for any reason, whether or not related to the existence of prior art.</p>
<p id="p0198" num="0198">Those skilled in the art will recognize or be able to ascertain using no more than routine experimentation many equivalents to the specific embodiments described herein. The scope of the present embodiments described herein is not intended to be limited to the above Description, but rather is as set forth in the appended claims. Those of ordinary skill in the art will appreciate that various changes and modifications to this description may be made without departing from the spirit or scope of the present invention, as defined in the following claims.</p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="74"> -->
<claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>A compound of Formula (I):
<chemistry id="chem0089" num="0089"><img id="ib0089" file="imgb0089.tif" wi="49" he="24" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein:
<claim-text>R<sup>1</sup> is substituted or unsubstituted alkyl, substituted or unsubstituted carbocyclyl, or substituted or unsubstituted heterocyclyl;</claim-text>
<claim-text>R<sup>2</sup> is of the formula selected from (i), (ii) or (iii):
<claim-text>(i)
<chemistry id="chem0090" num="0090"><img id="ib0090" file="imgb0090.tif" wi="32" he="22" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
wherein:
<claim-text>R<sup>A2</sup> is -N(R<sup>C</sup>)<sub>2</sub>; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>each instance of R<sup>C</sup> is independently substituted or unsubstituted alkyl, or substituted or unsubstituted heterocyclyl; or</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii)
<chemistry id="chem0091" num="0091"><img id="ib0091" file="imgb0091.tif" wi="32" he="16" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
wherein:
<claim-text>R<sup>A3</sup> is -N(R<sup>A4</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>two instances of R<sup>A4</sup> are joined to form a substituted or unsubstituted, heterocyclic ring, or substituted or unsubstituted, heteroaryl ring, or</claim-text>
<claim-text>R<sup>A4</sup> is independently substituted or unsubstituted alkyl, substituted or unsubstituted carbocyclyl, substituted or unsubstituted heterocyclyl, substituted or unsubstituted aryl, or substituted or unsubstituted heteroaryl; or</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>(iii)
<chemistry id="chem0092" num="0092"><img id="ib0092" file="imgb0092.tif" wi="32" he="16" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
wherein:
<claim-text>R<sup>A3</sup> is -N(R<sup>A4</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, and<!-- EPO <DP n="75"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>two instances of R<sup>A4</sup> are joined to form a substituted or unsubstituted, heterocyclic ring, or substituted or unsubstituted, heteroaryl ring;</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>R<sup>3</sup> is independently hydrogen, substituted or unsubstituted C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl, or a nitrogen protecting group; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>R<sup>4</sup> is independently hydrogen, substituted or unsubstituted C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl, or a nitrogen protecting group.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>The compound of claim 1, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>1</sup> is:
<claim-text>(i) substituted C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl; or</claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) unsubstituted C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>The compound of claim 1 or claim 2, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof,<br/>
wherein R<sup>1</sup> is:
<claim-text>(i) methyl; or</claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) ethyl; or</claim-text>
<claim-text>(iii) propyl; or</claim-text>
<claim-text>(iv) butyl.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>The compound of claim 3, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>1</sup> is methyl.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>The compound of any preceding claim, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>A2</sup> is -N(R<sup>C</sup>)<sub>2</sub> and:
<claim-text>(i) at least one instance of R<sup>C</sup> is substituted or unsubstituted C<sub>1-6</sub> alkyl; and/or</claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) at least one instance of R<sup>C</sup> is substituted or unsubstituted heterocyclyl.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>The compound of claim 5, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein:
<claim-text>(i) at least one instance of R<sup>C</sup> is methyl; and/or</claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) at least one instance of R<sup>C</sup> is substituted or unsubstituted, 3- to 9-membered, monocyclic heterocyclyl.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="76"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>The compound of claim 6, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>A2</sup> is selected from:
<claim-text>(i) the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0093" num="0093"><img id="ib0093" file="imgb0093.tif" wi="23" he="18" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
or</claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0094" num="0094"><img id="ib0094" file="imgb0094.tif" wi="23" he="20" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>The compound of any preceding claim, wherein R<sup>A3</sup> is -N(R<sup>A4</sup>)<sub>2</sub>, and<br/>
two instances of R<sup>A4</sup> are joined to form:
<claim-text>(i) a substituted or unsubstituted, 5- to 6- membered, monocyclic heterocyclic ring; or</claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) a substituted or unsubstituted, 5- to 6-membered, monocyclic heteroaryl ring.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>The compound of claim 8, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein R<sup>A3</sup> is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0095" num="0095"><img id="ib0095" file="imgb0095.tif" wi="29" he="17" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>The compound of any preceding claim, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, wherein:
<claim-text>(i) R<sup>3</sup> is hydrogen; and/or</claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) R<sup>4</sup> is hydrogen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>The compound of claim 1, wherein the compound is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0096" num="0096"><img id="ib0096" file="imgb0096.tif" wi="151" he="36" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry><!-- EPO <DP n="77"> -->
<chemistry id="chem0097" num="0097"><img id="ib0097" file="imgb0097.tif" wi="71" he="33" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>The compound of claim 1, wherein the compound is of the formula:
<chemistry id="chem0098" num="0098"><img id="ib0098" file="imgb0098.tif" wi="69" he="32" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry>
or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>A pharmaceutical composition comprising a compound of any one of claims 1 to 12, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and optionally a pharmaceutically acceptable excipient.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>A compound according to any one of claims 1 to 12, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, or a pharmaceutical composition according to claim 13, for use in a method of treating a proliferative disease in a subject in need thereof, the method comprising administering to the subject an effective amount of said compound, a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, or said pharmaceutical composition.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0015" num="0015">
<claim-text>The compound for use of claim 14, wherein the proliferative disease is cancer, optionally wherein the cancer is:
<claim-text>(i) metastatic cancer; or</claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) lung cancer; or</claim-text>
<claim-text>(iii) prostate cancer.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="78"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="118" he="178" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="79"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="123" he="183" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="80"> -->
<figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="146" he="229" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="81"> -->
<figure id="f0004" num="3"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="146" he="231" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="82"> -->
<figure id="f0005" num="3"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="146" he="230" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="83"> -->
<figure id="f0006" num="4"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="109" he="200" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<search-report-data id="srep" lang="en" srep-office="EP" date-produced=""><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="151" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="151" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0003" file="srep0003.tif" wi="155" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data><search-report-data date-produced="20210609" id="srepxml" lang="en" srep-office="EP" srep-type="ep-sr" status="n"><!--
 The search report data in XML is provided for the users' convenience only. It might differ from the search report of the PDF document, which contains the officially published data. The EPO disclaims any liability for incorrect or incomplete data in the XML for search reports.
 -->

<srep-info><file-reference-id>P256883EPD1</file-reference-id><application-reference><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>21156104.8</doc-number></document-id></application-reference><applicant-name><name>The Children's Medical Center Corporation</name></applicant-name><srep-established srep-established="yes"/><srep-invention-title title-approval="yes"/><srep-abstract abs-approval="yes"/><srep-figure-to-publish figinfo="by-applicant"><figure-to-publish><fig-number>1</fig-number></figure-to-publish></srep-figure-to-publish><srep-info-admin><srep-office><addressbook><text>MN</text></addressbook></srep-office><date-search-report-mailed><date>20210618</date></date-search-report-mailed></srep-info-admin></srep-info><srep-for-pub><srep-fields-searched><minimum-documentation><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr><text>C07D</text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr><text>A61P</text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr><text>A61K</text></classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr></minimum-documentation></srep-fields-searched><srep-citations><citation id="sr-cit0001"><nplcit id="sr-ncit0001" npl-type="s"><article><author><name>CHEONG ET AL.</name></author><atl>Synthesis and anticancer activity of novel water soluble benzimidazole carbamates</atl><serial><sertitle>EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF MEDICINAL CHEMISTRY</sertitle><imprint><text>FR</text></imprint><pubdate>20171214</pubdate><vid>144</vid><doi>10.1016/j.ejmech.2017.11.037</doi><issn>0223-5234</issn></serial><location><pp><ppf>372</ppf><ppl>385</ppl></pp></location><refno>XP055580141</refno></article></nplcit><category>T</category><rel-passage><passage>* the whole document *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0002"><nplcit id="sr-ncit0002" npl-type="s"><article><author><name>WANG ET AL.</name></author><atl>New benzimidazole-2-urea derivates as tubulin inhibitors</atl><serial><sertitle>BIOORG. MED. CHEM. LETT.</sertitle><imprint><text>Amsterdam , NL</text></imprint><pubdate>20140901</pubdate><vid>24</vid><ino>17</ino><doi>10.1016/j.bmcl.2014.07.035</doi><issn>0960-894X</issn></serial><location><pp><ppf>4250</ppf><ppl>4253</ppl></pp></location><refno>XP055420536</refno></article></nplcit><category>A</category><rel-claims>1-15</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* Title; abstract; scheme 1: compounds 5a, 8a-d; figure 2: mebendazole and compound 5a. *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0003"><nplcit id="sr-ncit0003" npl-type="s"><article><author><name>HASEGAWA ET AL.</name></author><atl>Discovery of novel benzimidazoles as potent inhibitors of TIE-2 and VEGFR-2 tyrosine kinase receptors</atl><serial><sertitle>J. MED. CHEM.</sertitle><pubdate>20070906</pubdate><vid>50</vid><ino>18</ino><doi>10.1021/JM0611051</doi><issn>0022-2623</issn></serial><location><pp><ppf>4453</ppf><ppl>4470</ppl></pp></location><refno>XP002513776</refno></article></nplcit><category>X</category><rel-claims>1-6,10,13-15</rel-claims><category>A</category><rel-claims>7-9,11,12</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* Title; abstract; page 4456, scheme 5: compounds 13b, 37. *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0004"><patcit dnum="WO2010135534A2" id="sr-pcit0001" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=WO2010135534&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2010135534</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><name>CHILDRENS MEDICAL CENTER [US]; ZETTER BRUCE [US] ET AL.</name><date>20101125</date></document-id></patcit><category>A</category><rel-claims>1-15</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* Title; abstract; claims 1-25; in particular claim 2: flubendazole and mebendazole. *</passage></rel-passage></citation></srep-citations><srep-admin><examiners><primary-examiner><name>Weisbrod, Thomas</name></primary-examiner></examiners><srep-office><addressbook><text>Munich</text></addressbook></srep-office><date-search-completed><date>20210609</date></date-search-completed></srep-admin><!--							The annex lists the patent family members relating to the patent documents cited in the above mentioned European search report.							The members are as contained in the European Patent Office EDP file on							The European Patent Office is in no way liable for these particulars which are merely given for the purpose of information.							For more details about this annex : see Official Journal of the European Patent Office, No 12/82						--><srep-patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2010135534</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20101125</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2432451</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20120328</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2012064008</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20120315</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2010135534</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20101125</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family></srep-patent-family></srep-for-pub></search-report-data>
<ep-reference-list id="ref-list">
<heading id="ref-h0001"><b>REFERENCES CITED IN THE DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0001" num=""><i>This list of references cited by the applicant is for the reader's convenience only. It does not form part of the European patent document. Even though great care has been taken in compiling the references, errors or omissions cannot be excluded and the EPO disclaims all liability in this regard.</i></p>
<heading id="ref-h0002"><b>Patent documents cited in the description</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0002" num="">
<ul id="ref-ul0001" list-style="bullet">
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0001" dnum="US62261240B"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>62261240</doc-number><kind>B</kind><date>20151130</date></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0001">[0001]</crossref></li>
</ul></p>
<heading id="ref-h0003"><b>Non-patent literature cited in the description</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0003" num="">
<ul id="ref-ul0002" list-style="bullet">
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0001" npl-type="b"><article><atl/><book><book-title>Cancer, A Comprehensive Treatise</book-title><imprint><name>Plenum Press</name><pubdate>19750000</pubdate></imprint><vid>4</vid></book></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0001">[0002]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0002" npl-type="b"><article><atl/><book><book-title>Handbook of Chemistry and Physics</book-title></book></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0002">[0018]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0003" npl-type="b"><article><atl/><book><author><name>THOMAS SORRELL</name></author><book-title>Organic Chemistry</book-title><imprint><name>University Science Books</name><pubdate>19990000</pubdate></imprint></book></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0003">[0018]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0004" npl-type="b"><article><atl/><book><author><name>SMITH</name></author><author><name>MARCH</name></author><book-title>March's Advanced Organic Chemistry</book-title><imprint><name>John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc.</name><pubdate>20010000</pubdate></imprint></book></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0004">[0018]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0005" npl-type="b"><article><atl/><book><author><name>LAROCK</name></author><book-title>Comprehensive Organic Transformations</book-title><imprint><name>VCH Publishers, Inc.</name><pubdate>19890000</pubdate></imprint></book></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0005">[0018]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0006" npl-type="b"><article><atl/><book><author><name>CARRUTHERS</name></author><book-title>Some Modern Methods of Organic Synthesis</book-title><imprint><name>Cambridge University Press</name><pubdate>19870000</pubdate></imprint></book></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0006">[0018]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0007" npl-type="b"><article><atl/><book><author><name>JACQUES et al.</name></author><book-title>Enantiomers, Racemates and Resolutions</book-title><imprint><name>Wiley Interscience</name><pubdate>19810000</pubdate></imprint></book></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0007">[0019]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0008" npl-type="s"><article><author><name>WILEN et al.</name></author><atl/><serial><sertitle>Tetrahedron</sertitle><pubdate><sdate>19770000</sdate><edate/></pubdate><vid>33</vid></serial><location><pp><ppf>2725</ppf><ppl/></pp></location></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0008">[0019]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0009" npl-type="b"><article><atl/><book><author><name>ELIEL</name></author><book-title>Stereochemistry of Carbon Compounds</book-title><imprint><name>McGraw-Hill</name><pubdate>19620000</pubdate></imprint></book></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0009">[0019]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0010" npl-type="b"><article><atl/><book><author><name>WILEN</name></author><book-title>Tables ofResolving Agents and Optical Resolutions</book-title><imprint><name>Univ. of Notre Dame Press</name><pubdate>19720000</pubdate></imprint><location><pp><ppf>268</ppf><ppl/></pp></location></book></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0010">[0019]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0011" npl-type="b"><article><atl/><book><author><name>T. W. GREENE</name></author><author><name>P. G. M. WUTS</name></author><book-title>Protecting Groups in Organic Synthesis</book-title><imprint><name>John Wiley &amp; Sons</name><pubdate>19990000</pubdate></imprint></book></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0011">[0047]</crossref><crossref idref="ncit0012">[0052]</crossref><crossref idref="ncit0013">[0053]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0012" npl-type="s"><article><author><name>BERGE et al.</name></author><atl>pharmaceutically acceptable salts</atl><serial><sertitle>J. Pharmaceutical Sciences</sertitle><pubdate><sdate>19770000</sdate><edate/></pubdate><vid>66</vid></serial><location><pp><ppf>1</ppf><ppl>19</ppl></pp></location></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0014">[0056]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0013" npl-type="b"><article><atl/><book><author><name>BUNDGARD, H.</name></author><book-title>Design of Prodrugs</book-title><imprint><name>Elsevier</name><pubdate>19850000</pubdate></imprint><location><pp><ppf>7</ppf><ppl>9</ppl></pp><pp><ppf>21</ppf><ppl>24</ppl></pp></location></book></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0015">[0063]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0014" npl-type="b"><article><atl/><book><author><name>WALKER</name></author><book-title>Cambridge Dictionary of Biology</book-title><imprint><name>Cambridge University Press</name><pubdate>19900000</pubdate></imprint></book></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0016">[0076]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0015" npl-type="b"><article><atl/><book><book-title>Stedman's Medical Dictionary</book-title><imprint><name>Williams &amp; Wilkins</name><pubdate>19900000</pubdate></imprint></book></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0017">[0079]</crossref></li>
</ul></p>
</ep-reference-list>
</ep-patent-document>
