<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP20166625A1" file="EP20166625NWA1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3889881" kind="A1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSKBAHRIS..MTNORSMESMMAKHTNMD..........</B001EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  1100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3889881</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT APPLICATION</B121></B120><B130>A1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>20166625.2</B210><B220><date>20200330</date></B220><B240><B241><date>20200330</date></B241></B240><B250>en</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B430></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>G06T   5/00        20060101AFI20200722BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="2"><text>G06T   5/20        20060101ALI20200722BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>G06T2207/20084     20130101 LA20200707BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>G06T2207/20081     20130101 LA20200707BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="3"><text>G06T   5/002       20130101 FI20200707BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="4"><text>G06T   5/20        20130101 LI20200707BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="5"><text>G06T2207/10072     20130101 LA20200707BHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>VERFAHREN, VORRICHTUNG UND SYSTEM ZUR ERZEUGUNG EINES ENTRAUSCHTEN MEDIZINISCHEN BILDES</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>METHOD, DEVICE AND SYSTEM FOR GENERATING A DENOISED MEDICAL IMAGE</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>PROCÉDÉ, DISPOSITIF ET SYSTÈME POUR GÉNÉRER UNE IMAGE MÉDICALE DÉBRUITÉE</B542></B540><B590><B598>1</B598></B590></B500><B700><B710><B711><snm>Siemens Healthcare GmbH</snm><iid>101524364</iid><irf>SHC20006PEP</irf><adr><str>Henkestraße 127</str><city>91052 Erlangen</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B711></B710><B720><B721><snm>KUMAR, Thanuja</snm><adr><str>4175, 13th main, e-block, 2nd Stage, Rajajinagar</str><city>560010 Bangalore, Karnataka</city><ctry>IN</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B740><B741><snm>Horn Kleimann Waitzhofer 
Patentanwälte PartG mbB</snm><iid>101259778</iid><adr><str>Ganghoferstrasse 29a</str><city>80339 München</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840><B844EP><B845EP><ctry>BA</ctry></B845EP><B845EP><ctry>ME</ctry></B845EP></B844EP><B848EP><B849EP><ctry>KH</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>MA</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>MD</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>TN</ctry></B849EP></B848EP></B800></SDOBI>
<abstract id="abst" lang="en">
<p id="pa01" num="0001">A method (200), device and system (100) for generating a denoised medical image is provided. In one aspect, the method (200) includes obtaining a medical image from a medical imaging device. Further, the method (200) includes extracting at least one category of medical information associated with the medical image. Additionally, the method (200) includes processing the medical image using at least one trained machine learning model to obtain pixel information associated with the medical image. The method (200) also includes retrieving at least one pre-defined pixel matrix from a database (107), wherein the pre-defined pixel matrix is identified based on the at least one category of medical information and the pixel information associated with the medical image. Furthermore, the method (200) includes correcting the pixel information associated with the medical image using the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix so as to generate a denoised medical image.
<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="127" he="100" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p>
</abstract>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a method, device and system for processing medical images. In particular, the invention relates to a method, device and system for generating a denoised medical image.</p>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">Accurate image acquisition using medical imaging devices is essential for effective diagnosis and prognosis of medical conditions that a patient may be suffering from. The image acquisition process, for example, magnetic resonance imaging may sometimes require patients to remain steady and motionless for long durations. This may be difficult for the patient, particularly if the patient is in pain or is young. Medical images are often deteriorated due to presence of noise that may be included in the medical image during the image acquisition process or image reconstruction process. This may be due to disorientation of the patient inside the medical acquisition device or system such as magnetic resonance imaging systems or computed tomography devices. Such noise may degrade the quality of the acquired medical images and cause blurring of one or more features in the medical images. This may require the patient to undergo the image acquisition process again. Therefore, there also exists a risk of increased dosage of radiation to the patient. Removal of noise or denoising of medical images is essential so as to ensure precise and timely diagnosis of medical conditions in the patient.</p>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">Currently, if the acquired medical image includes noise beyond a threshold, the patients may be advised to undergo a re-scan or an image acquisition with higher radiation dose. Alternatively, the patients may also be suggested to acquire medical images using a different medical imaging modality.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> Exposure to radiation for long durations may be detrimental to health of the patient. Additionally, multiple image acquisition processes may cause undue delay in providing necessary medical support to the patient in cases of emergency.</p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">The object of the invention is therefore to provide a method, device and system that enables accurate removal of noise from a medical image and eliminates the need for the patient to undergo multiple image acquisition processes.</p>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">The invention achieves the object by a method of generating a denoised medical image as claimed in claim 1, device as claimed in claim 13, a system as claimed in claim 14, a computer program product as claimed in claim 15 and a computer readable medium as claimed in claim 16.</p>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">The present invention describes a method of generating a denoised medical image. The method includes obtaining by a processing unit, a medical image from a medical imaging device. The medical imaging device may include, for example, but not limited to, magnetic resonance imaging device, computed tomography device, X-ray imaging device, ultrasound imaging device, etc. The medical image may include one or more objects associated with a patient. The objects may be in particular one or more body parts associated with the patient that may have been imaged. The objects may include, but not be limited to, one or more imaged organs, tissues, skeletal information, associated with the patient. In an embodiment, the obtained medical image may include noise that may affect clarity of the medical image. The noise may be introduced in the medical image, for example, if a patient moves during the image acquisition process, or if a fault exists in the medical imaging device, etc. The presence of noise in the medical image may hamper diagnosis of a medical condition that may be associated with the patient. Additionally, the patient may have<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> to undergo the image acquisition process multiple times, resulting in increase in the radiation dose exposure and loss of time. The method further includes extracting at least one category of medical information associated with the medical image. The at least one category of medical information may include one or more medical details associated with the medical image and/or the patient. In an embodiment, the category of medical information may include a medical procedure that the patient may be undergoing. In another embodiment, the category of medical information may include the body part of the patient that has been imaged. The category of the medical information may enable classification of the medical image. The method further includes identifying pixel information associated with the medical image. In an embodiment, the identified pixel information may depict noise in the medical image. Processing of the medical image may be performed using at least one trained machine learning model. The pixel information associated with the medical image may include one or more pixel intensity values associated with the medical image. The at least one trained machine learning model may be configured to analyze each pixel of the medical image to extract pixel intensity values. The method further includes retrieving at least one pre-defined pixel matrix from a database. The pre-defined pixel matrix may be identified based on the at least one category of medical information and pixel information associated with the medical image. In an embodiment, there may be at least one pre-defined pixel matrix stored in the database. Each of the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix may be associated with at least one category of medical information. Such pre-defined pixel matrix may include pixel information corresponding to the category of the medical information associated with the pre-defined pixel matrix. The method further includes correcting the pixel information associated with the medical image using the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix so as to generate a denoised<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> medical image. The denoised medical image may have more clarity in comparison with the medical image. Advantageously, the invention enables removal of noise from the acquired medical image. Therefore, accuracy of the medical image is improved. The objects imaged in the medical image are visualized with improved clarity. Furthermore, the need for multiple image acquisitions is eliminated.</p>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">According to an embodiment, identifying the pixel information associated with the medical image includes identifying at least one portion of the medical image that comprises noise. The noise in the at least one portion of the medical image may include one or more artefacts that may cause distortion of the imaged objects in the medical image or may affect the clarity of the imaged object sin the medical image. In an embodiment, the noise may be limited only to a portion of the medical image. Therefore, the portion of the medical image which comprises the noise may be identified. The method further includes extracting the pixel information associated with the identified at least one portion of the medical image. Advantageously, the at least one portion of the medical image that include noise may be corrected. Therefore, clarity of the medical image may be improved thereby increasing the accuracy of medical diagnosis.</p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">According to an embodiment, extracting the pixel information associated with the at least one portion of the medical image includes constructing at least one pixel matrix of the medical image. The pixel matrix may be a matrix of equal number of rows and columns which enables identification of pixel intensity values associated with the medical image. The method further includes determining one or more pixel intensity values for the at least one pixel matrix of the at least one portion of the medical image. In an embodiment, the medical image may include a plurality of pixel matrices so as to obtain<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> the pixel intensity values associated with the entire medical image. In another embodiment, a pixel matrix may be constructed only for a portion of the medical image. Advantageously, determination of pixel intensity values associated with a plurality of pixels in the medical image enables efficient and accurate modification of the medical image. Therefore, portions of the medical image that include noise maybe easily determined and corrected.</p>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">According to a further embodiment, the at least one pixel matrix associated with the at leas tone portion of the medical image and the pre-defined matrix is composed of at least three rows and columns.</p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">According to yet another embodiment, the at least one category of medical information associated with the medical image may include medical study description associated with the medical image, examined body part associated with the medical image, and/or medical procedure associated with the medical image. Advantageously, the category of medical information enables effective classification of medical images based on which the pre-defined pixel matrix for the medical image may be identified.</p>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">According to an embodiment, correcting the pixel information associated with the medical image includes applying the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix to the at least one portion of the medical image. The pre-defined pixel matrix may include pixel intensity values determined by the at least one trained machine learning model. The pixel intensity values may depict one or more differences between one or more portions of reference noisy medical images and corresponding one or more portions of non-noisy medical images. In a further embodiment, the one or more pixel intensity values of the at least one portion of the first medical image may be increased<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> if the one or more pixel intensity values of the at least one portion of the first medical image is less than the one or more pixel intensity values of the pre-defined matrix. Similarly, if the one or more pixel intensity values of the at least one portion of the first medical image is more than the one or more pixel intensity values of the pre-defined matrix, the one or more pixel intensity values of the at least one portion of the first medical image are decreased. Advantageously, noise in the medical image may be reduced or eliminated. Furthermore, the need for multiple image acquisitions is avoided. Thus, diagnosis of an associated medical condition is faster.</p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">According to a further embodiment, the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix is generated by the at least one trained machine learning model for each category of medical information. In an embodiment, the at least one trained machine learning model may be a convolutional neural network model. The convolutional neural network model may be trained using noisy medical images and non-noisy medical images. Non-noisy medical images are images in which one or more imaged objects may be clear and free of noise. Noisy medical images may include one or more medical images which include noise along with the imaged objects. The noise may include any blur or other artefacts in the imaged object caused by patient movement or vibrations in the medical imaging unit. Alternatively, the noise may also include radiometric noise such as scattering, Poisson noise, Gaussian noise, etc.</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">The object of the invention is also achieved by a method of training at least one machine learning model to generate a denoised medical image. The method includes receiving by a processing unit a reference medical image. The reference medical image may depict a body part associated with a patient. For example, the reference medical image may include imaging<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> information associated with one or more organs, tissue, bone or any other body part of the patient. In an embodiment, the reference medical image may be received from a database known to comprise a plurality of medical images. The method further includes obtaining by the processing unit a noisy medical image corresponding to the reference medical image. The noisy medical image may depict similar image information as the reference medical image. The noisy medical image may include a noise level higher than the reference medical image. Therefore, the noisy medical image may include more noise artefacts in comparison to the reference medical image. The method further includes receiving by the processing unit, a machine learning model. In an embodiment, the machine learning model may be configured to analyze the reference medical image and the noisy medical image to generate a denoised medical image. One or more portions of the noisy medical image are identified which may include noise. Such identification of one or portions of the noisy medical image may be performed by applying the machine learning model to the noisy medical image. The machine learning model may analyze the pixel information associated with the noisy medical image to identify one or more portions of the noisy medical image that comprise noise. Further, the method includes retrieving, using the machine learning model, at least one pre-defined pixel matrix from a database, based on the one or more portions of the noisy medical image. In an embodiment, the at least one pre-defined matrix may have one or more pixel information similar to that of the identified one or more portions of the noisy medical image. The method further includes correcting by the processing unit, the one or more portions of the noisy medical image by applying the at least one portion of the pre-defined pixel matrix to the noisy medical image using the machine learning model. Therefore, a denoised medical image is generated from the noisy medical image. The method further includes adjusting the machine learning model based on a comparison<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> of the denoised medical image with the reference medical image. The adjustment of the machine learning model enables the training of the machine learning model to effectively denoise the medical images.</p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">Advantageously, training of the machine learning model enables improvement in the accuracy of denoising of medical images. Furthermore, training of the machine learning model makes the machine learning model more robust and effective.</p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">According to an embodiment, the method further includes extracting at least one category of medical information associated with the noisy medical image. Each medical image may have an associated at least one category of medical information. Such medical information may include at least one of medical study description associated with the medical image, examined body part associated with the medical image, and medical procedure associated with the medical image. The method further includes retrieving the at least one pre-defined matrix from the database based on the at least one category of medical information associated with the noisy medical image. Advantageously, the at least category of medical information enables effective mapping of the pre-defined pixel matrix to the one or more portions of the noisy medical image.</p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">According to a further embodiment, the method includes constructing at least one pixel matrix of the reference medical image and the noisy medical image, wherein the at least one pixel matrix comprises equal number of rows and columns. The at least one pixel matrix of the reference image corresponds to the at least one pixel matrix of the noisy medical image. The pixel matrix associated with the reference medical image and the noisy medical image may be constructed by, for example, portioning the reference medical image and the noisy<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> medical image into a plurality of rows and columns. Each matrix may include equal number of rows and columns. In the embodiment, the pixel matrix associated with the reference medical image may correspond to the pixel matrix associated with the noisy medical image. Therefore, an area covered by the pixel matrix associated with the reference medical image may be similar to an area covered by the pixel matrix associated with the noisy medical image. The method further includes determining one or more pixel intensity values of the at least one pixel matrix associated with the reference medical image and the at least one pixel matrix associated with the noisy medical image. A deviation between the at least one pixel matrix associated with the reference medical image and the at least one pixel matrix associated with the noisy medical image is determined. The deviation may reflect the difference in the pixel intensity values associated with the at least one pixel matrix of the reference medical image and the at least one pixel matrix of the noisy medical image. Further, the method includes generating the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix which comprises one or more pixel intensity values. The one or more pixel intensity values in the pre-defined pixel matrix may be obtained by subtracting the one or more pixel intensity values associated with the at least one pixel matrix of the reference medical image and the at least one noisy medical image. The at least one pre-defined pixel matrix may be archived in the database. Advantageously, the generated pre-defined pixel matrix may be effectively used to correct the noisy medical image to obtain denoised medical image. The pre-defined pixel matrix may include information associated with delta pixel intensity values which may correspond to a correction factor that may be applied to noisy medical images.</p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">According to another embodiment, the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix is mapped to the at least one category of medical<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> information. Mapping of the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix to the at least one category of medical information enables effective identification of the at least one pixel matrix to be applied to a noisy image for generation of a denoised medical image. The correction of the noisy medical image may be performed by applying the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix of a defined category of medical information that may correspond to the at least one category of medical information associated with the noisy medical image. In an embodiment, the archived at least one pre-defined pixel matrix is associated with at least one category of medical information.</p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">The object of the invention is also achieved by a medical imaging device for generating a denoised medical image. The medical imaging device includes one or more processing units, a scanner unit configured to capture one or more medical images and a memory coupled to the one or more processing units. The memory includes a denoising module configured to perform the method steps of denoising a medical image using at least one trained machine learning model. The denoising module may be configured to obtain a medical image from the scanner unit of the medical imaging device. The medical imaging device may include, for example, but not limited to, magnetic resonance imaging device, computed tomography device, X-ray imaging device, ultrasound imaging device, etc. The medical image may include one or more objects associated with a patient. The objects may be in particular one or more body parts associated with the patient that may have been imaged. The objects may include, but not be limited to, one or more imaged organs, tissues, skeletal information, associated with the patient. In an embodiment, the obtained medical image may include noise that may affect clarity of the medical image. Noise may include any blur or other artefacts in the imaged object caused by patient movement or vibrations in the medical<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> imaging unit. Alternatively, the noise may also include radiometric noise such as scattering, Poisson noise, Gaussian noise, etc. The noise may be introduced in the medical image, for example, if a patient moves during the image acquisition process, a fault that may exist in the medical imaging device, etc. The presence of noise in the medical image may hamper diagnosis of a medical condition that may be associated with the patient. Additionally, the patient may have to undergo the image acquisition process multiple times, resulting in increase in the radiation dose exposure and loss of time. The denoising module is further configured to extract at least one category of medical information associated with the medical image. The at least one category of medical information may include one or more medical details associated with the medical image and/or the patient. In an embodiment, the category of medical information may include a medical procedure that the patient may be undergoing. In another embodiment, the category of medical information may include the body part of the patient that has been imaged. The category of the medical information may enable classification of the medical image. The denoising module may be further configured to identify pixel information associated with the medical image. The pixel information may depict noise in the medical image. The processing of the medical image may be performed using at least one trained machine learning model. The pixel information associated with the medical image may include one or more pixel intensity values associated with the medical image. The at least one trained machine learning model may be configured to analyze each pixel of the medical image to extract pixel intensity values. The denoising module may further be configured to retrieve at least one pre-defined pixel matrix from a database. The pre-defined pixel matrix may be identified based on the at least one category of medical information and pixel information associated with the medical image. In an embodiment, there may be at least one pre-defined<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> pixel matrix stored in the database. Each of the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix may be associated with at least one category of medical information. Such pre-defined pixel matrix may include pixel information corresponding to the category of the medical information associated with the pre-defined pixel matrix. The denoising module may further be configured to correct the pixel information associated with the medical image using the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix so as to generate a denoised medical image. The denoised medical image may have an improved clarity over the medical image. Advantageously, the invention enables removal of noise from the acquired medical image. Therefore, accuracy of the medical image is improved. The objects imaged in the medical image are visualized with improved clarity. Furthermore, the need for multiple image acquisitions is eliminated.</p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">According to an embodiment, in processing the medical image to obtain pixel information associated with the medical image, the denoising module may be configured to identify at least one portion of the medical image that comprises noise. The noise in the at least one portion of the medical image may include one or more artefacts that may cause distortion of the imaged objects in the medical image or may affect the clarity of the imaged object sin the medical image. In an embodiment, the noise may be limited only to a portion of the medical image. Therefore, the portion of the medical image which comprises the noise may be identified. The denoising module may further be configured to extract the pixel information associated with the identified at least one portion of the medical image. Advantageously, the at least one portion of the medical image that include noise may be corrected. Therefore, clarity of the medical image may be improved thereby increasing the accuracy of medical diagnosis.<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> According to an embodiment, in extracting the pixel information associated with the at least one portion of the medical image, the denoising module may be configured to construct at least one pixel matrix of the medical image. The pixel matrix may be a matrix of equal number of rows and columns which enables identification of pixel intensity values associated with the medical image. The denoising module may further be configured to determine one or more pixel intensity values for the at least one pixel matrix of the at least one portion of the medical image. In an embodiment, the medical image may include a plurality of pixel matrices so as to obtain the pixel intensity values associated with the entire medical image. In another embodiment, a pixel matrix may be constructed only for a portion of the medical image. Advantageously, determination of pixel intensity values associated with a plurality of pixels in the medical image enables efficient and accurate modification of the medical image. Therefore, portions of the medical image that include noise maybe easily determined and corrected.</p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">According to a further embodiment, the at least one pixel matrix associated with the at leas tone portion of the medical image and the pre-defined matrix is composed of at least three rows and columns.</p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">According to yet another embodiment, the at least one category of medical information associated with the medical image may include medical study description associated with the medical image, examined body part associated with the medical image, and/or medical procedure associated with the medical image. Advantageously, the category of medical information enables effective classification of medical images based on which the pre-defined pixel matrix for the medical image may be identified.<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></p>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">According to an embodiment, in correcting the pixel information associated with the medical image, the denoising module may be configured to apply the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix to the at least one portion of the medical image. The pre-defined pixel matrix may include pixel intensity values determined by the at least one trained machine learning model. The pixel intensity values may depict one or more differences between one or more portions of reference noisy medical images and corresponding one or more portions of non-noisy medical images. In a further embodiment, the one or more pixel intensity values of the at least one portion of the first medical image may be increased if the one or more pixel intensity values of the at least one portion of the first medical image is less than the one or more pixel intensity values of the pre-defined matrix. Similarly, if the one or more pixel intensity values of the at least one portion of the first medical image is more than the one or more pixel intensity values of the pre-defined matrix, the one or more pixel intensity values of the at least one portion of the first medical image are decreased. Advantageously, noise in the medical image may be reduced or eliminated. Furthermore, the need for multiple image acquisitions is avoided. Thus, diagnosis of an associated medical condition is faster.</p>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">According to a further embodiment, the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix is generated by the at least one trained machine learning model for each category of medical information. In an embodiment, the at least one trained machine learning model may be a convolutional neural network model. The convolutional neural network model may be trained using noisy medical images and non-noisy medical images. Non-noisy medical images are images in which one or more imaged objects may be clear and free of noise. Noisy medical images may include one or more medical images which include noise along with the imaged objects. The noise may include any blur or<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> other artefacts in the imaged object caused by patient movement or vibrations in the medical imaging unit. Alternatively, the noise may also include radiometric noise such as scattering, Poisson noise, Gaussian noise, etc.</p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">The invention relates in another aspect to a system for generating a denoised medical image. According to an embodiment, the system includes one or more processing units, a medical database coupled to the one or more processing units, wherein the medical database is configured to receive the plurality of medical images from a medical imaging device. The system further includes a memory coupled to the one or more processing units, the memory comprising a denoising module. The denoising module may be configured to perform the method steps as claimed in claims 1 to 8 using at least one trained machine learning model.</p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">The invention relates in one aspect to a computer program product comprising a computer program, the computer program being loadable into a storage unit of a system, including program code sections to make the system execute the method according to an aspect of the invention when the computer program is executed in the system.</p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">The invention relates in one aspect to a computer-readable medium, on which program code sections of a computer program are saved, the program code sections being loadable into and/or executable in a system to make the system execute the method according to an aspect of the invention when the program code sections are executed in the system.</p>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">The realization of the invention by a computer program product and/or a computer-readable medium has the advantage that already existing management systems can be easily adopted by<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> software updates in order to work as proposed by the invention.</p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">The computer program product can be, for example, a computer program or comprise another element apart from the computer program. This other element can be hardware, for example a memory device, on which the computer program is stored, a hardware key for using the computer program and the like, and/or software, for example a documentation or a software key for using the computer program.</p>
<p id="p0029" num="0029">The present invention is further described hereinafter with reference to illustrated embodiments shown in the accompanying drawings, in which:
<dl id="dl0001" compact="compact">
<dt>FIG 1</dt><dd>illustrates a block diagram of a data processing system in which an embodiment for generating a denoised medical image can be implemented.</dd>
<dt>FIG 2</dt><dd>illustrates a flowchart of a method of generating a denoised medical image, according to an embodiment.</dd>
<dt>FIG 3</dt><dd>illustrates a flowchart of a method of processing a medical image to obtain pixel information, according to an embodiment.</dd>
<dt>FIG 4</dt><dd>illustrates a medical image n which a plurality of pixel matrices are constructed, according to an embodiment.</dd>
<dt>FIG 5</dt><dd>illustrates pixel information associated with a set of medical images, according to an embodiment.</dd>
<dt>FIG 6</dt><dd>illustrates a flowchart of a method of training a machine learning model to generate a denoised medical image, according to an embodiment.</dd>
<dt>FIG 7</dt><dd>illustrates a flowchart of a method of retrieving the pre-defined pixel matrix from a database, according to an embodiment.<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></dd>
<dt>FIG 8</dt><dd>illustrates a flowchart of a method of generating a pre-defined pixel matrix for a medical image, according to an embodiment.</dd>
<dt>FIG 9</dt><dd>illustrates a table depicting archived pre-defined pixel matrices associated with at least one category of medical information, according to the embodiment.</dd>
<dt>FIG 10</dt><dd>illustrates a set of medical images depicting a noisy medical image and a denoised medical image, according to the embodiment.</dd>
<dt>FIG 11</dt><dd>illustrates a working of the machine learning model for processing the medical images, according to an embodiment.</dd>
</dl></p>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">Hereinafter, embodiments for carrying out the present invention are described in detail. The various embodiments are described with reference to the drawings, wherein like reference numerals are used to refer to like elements throughout. In the following description, for purpose of explanation, numerous specific details are set forth in order to provide a thorough understanding of one or more embodiments. It may be evident that such embodiments may be practiced without these specific details.</p>
<p id="p0031" num="0031"><figref idref="f0001">FIG 1</figref> is a block diagram of a data processing system 100 in which an embodiment can be implemented, for example, as a system 100 for generating a denoised medical image, configured to perform the processes as described therein. In <figref idref="f0001">FIG 1</figref>, said data processing system 100 comprises a processing unit 101, a memory 102, a storage unit 103, an input unit 104, an output unit 106, a bus 105, and a network interface 108.</p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032">The processing unit 101, as used herein, means any type of computational circuit, such as, but not limited to, a<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> microprocessor, microcontroller, complex instruction set computing microprocessor, reduced instruction set computing microprocessor, very long instruction word microprocessor, explicitly parallel instruction computing microprocessor, graphics processor, digital signal processor, or any other type of processing circuit. The processing unit 101 may also include embedded controllers, such as generic or programmable logic devices or arrays, application specific integrated circuits, single-chip computers, and the like.</p>
<p id="p0033" num="0033">The memory 102 may be volatile memory and non-volatile memory. The memory 102 may be coupled for communication with said processing unit 101. The processing unit 101 may execute instructions and/or code stored in the memory 102. A variety of computer-readable storage media may be stored in and accessed from said memory 102. The memory 102 may include any suitable elements for storing data and machine-readable instructions, such as read only memory, random access memory, erasable programmable read only memory, electrically erasable programmable read only memory, a hard drive, a removable media drive for handling compact disks, digital video disks, diskettes, magnetic tape cartridges, memory cards, and the like. In the present embodiment, the memory 201 includes a denoising module 110 stored in the form of machine-readable instructions on any of said above-mentioned storage media and may be in communication to and executed by processor 101. When executed by the processor 101, the denoising module 110 causes the processor 101 to denoise one or more medical images. Method steps executed by the processor 101 to achieve the abovementioned functionality are elaborated upon in detail in <figref idref="f0002">FIG 2</figref>, <figref idref="f0003">3</figref>, <figref idref="f0006">6</figref>, <figref idref="f0007">7</figref> and <figref idref="f0008">8</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0034" num="0034">The storage unit 103 may be a non-transitory storage medium which stores a medical database 107. The medical database 107 is a repository of medical images and associated medical data<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> sets related to one or more patients that is maintained by a healthcare service provider. The medical database 107 may further include at least one pre-defined pixel matrix associated with at least one category of medical information, for correcting one or more noisy medical images. The input unit 104 may include input means such as keypad, touch-sensitive display, camera (such as a camera receiving gesture-based inputs), etc. capable of receiving input signal such as a medical image. The bus 105 acts as interconnect between the processor 101, the memory 102, the storage unit 103, the input unit 104, the output unit 106 and the network interface 108.</p>
<p id="p0035" num="0035">Those of ordinary skilled in the art will appreciate that said hardware depicted in <figref idref="f0001">FIG 1</figref> may vary for particular implementations. For example, other peripheral devices such as an optical disk drive and the like, Local Area Network (LAN)/ Wide Area Network (WAN)/ Wireless (e.g., Wi-Fi) adapter, graphics adapter, disk controller, input/output (I/O) adapter also may be used in addition or in place of the hardware depicted. Said depicted example is provided for the purpose of explanation only and is not meant to imply architectural limitations with respect to the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">A data processing system 100 in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure includes an operating system employing a graphical user interface. Said operating system permits multiple display windows to be presented in the graphical user interface simultaneously with each display window providing an interface to a different application or to a different instance of the same application. A cursor in said graphical user interface may be manipulated by a user through a pointing device. The position of the cursor may be changed and/or an event such as clicking a mouse button,<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> generated to actuate a desired response.</p>
<p id="p0037" num="0037">One of various commercial operating systems, such as a version of Microsoft Windows™, a product of Microsoft Corporation located in Redmond, Washington may be employed if suitably modified. Said operating system is modified or created in accordance with the present disclosure as described.</p>
<p id="p0038" num="0038">Disclosed embodiments provide systems and methods for processing medical images. In particular, the systems and methods may generate a denoised medical image.</p>
<p id="p0039" num="0039"><figref idref="f0002">FIG 2</figref> illustrates a flowchart of a method 200 of generating a denoised medical image, according to an embodiment of the present invention. The method 200 includes a step 201 of obtaining a medical image from a medical imaging device. The medical imaging device may include an X-ray imaging unit, a magnetic resonance imaging unit, a PET imaging unit, an ultrasound imaging unit, a computed tomography unit, or any other radiological imaging device. The medical image includes imaging information associated with a patient. The imaging information may include at least one of examined body part or organ associated with the patient. The medical image is further associated with at least one category of medical information. The medical information may include medical study description associated with the medical image, medical procedure performed on the patient and examined body part associated with the medical image. The method 200 further includes a step 202 of extracting the at least one category of medical information associated with the medical image. The at least one category of medical information enables effective classification of the medical image. The method 200 may further include a step 203 of processing the medical image using at least one machine learning model to obtain pixel information<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> associated with the medical image. The pixel information may be one or more pixel intensity values associated with the medical image. Such pixel intensity values may be obtained from at least one portion of the medical image. The pixel information enables identification of presence of noise in the medical image. The method steps of processing the medical image is further elaborated in <figref idref="f0003">FIG 3</figref>. The method 200 further includes a step 204 of retrieving at least one pre-defined pixel matrix from the medical database 107. Such pre-defined pixel matrix may be identified from the medical database 107 based on the at least one category of medical information and the pixel information associated with the medical image. In an embodiment, the medical database 107 may include a plurality of pre-defined pixel matrices which may be classified based on categories of medical information. Therefore, for a medical image associated with a given category of medical information, a pre-defined pixel matrix is retrieved from the medical database 107. The method further includes a step 205 of correcting the pixel information associated with the medical image using the at least one pre-defined matrix so as to generate a denoised medical image. In an embodiment, the pixel intensity values associated with the pre-defined pixel matrix may be different in comparison to the pixel intensity values associated with the medical image. Therefore, the pixel intensity values associated with the pre-defined pixel matrix may be applied to the medical image to correct the pixel information associated with the medical image. Advantageously, the invention enables removal of noise from the medical image thereby improving the clarity of the medical image. Therefore, the accuracy of medical diagnosis is improved. Furthermore, the need for frequent image acquisition is avoided.</p>
<p id="p0040" num="0040"><figref idref="f0003">FIG 3</figref> illustrates a flowchart of a method 300 of processing a medical image to obtain pixel information, according to an<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> embodiment. The method 300 includes a step 301 of identifying the at least one portion of the medical image which comprises noise. The medical image may be divided into one or more portions of equal sizes and analyzed to identify presence of noise. The noise in the medical image may be present in the form of blur or one or more artefacts that may affect the clarity of the medical image. Such noise may be present in the entire medical image or in at least one portion of the medical image. On identifying the at least one portion of the medical image comprising noise, the method includes a step 302 of constructing at least one pixel matrix of the at least one portion of the medical image. The at least one pixel matrix includes equal number of rows and columns. In an embodiment, the rows and columns of the pixel matrix enable portioning the medical image into equal areas for further analysis. In an embodiment, the number of pixel matrices constructed may depend on the size of the at least one portion of the medical image which is to be further analyzed. The construction of the pixel matrices is illustrated in <figref idref="f0004">FIG 4</figref>. Referring to <figref idref="f0004">FIG 4</figref>, a medical image 400 is illustrated on which a plurality of pixel matrices 401A-N are constructed, according to an embodiment. The pixel matrices 401A-N may depict at least a portion of medical information 402 associated with the medical image 400. The pixel matrices 401A-N include equal number of rows and columns. In the embodiment, the pixel matrices 401A-N include three rows and three columns. The method 300 further includes a step 303 of determining one or more pixel intensity values for the at least one pixel matrix of the at least one portion of the medical image. The pixel information may include one or more pixel intensity values associated with the at least one portion of the medical image. The pixel intensity values may be determined from each of the pixel forming a part of the at least one portion of the medical image. Advantageously, determination of pixel information enables effective identification of noise in the<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> medical image. The pixel information may further be used to denoise the medical image.</p>
<p id="p0041" num="0041">In an embodiment, the method steps of processing the medical image may be performed by a machine learning model. The working of the machine learning model has been elaborated in further detail in <figref idref="f0011">FIG 11</figref>. Referring to <figref idref="f0011">FIG 11</figref>, an embodiment of processing one or more medical images using a machine learning model is described. The system 100 uses neural networks to identify and extract pixel information from the one or more medical images. In the present embodiment, convolutional neural networks are used to identify and extract the pixel information associated with the medical image. As shown in the figure, a medical image 1150 is taken. The convolutional neural network extracts relevant information from pixels of the medical image 1150 and inputs the same into a fully-connected neural network with an output layer 1112 yielding noise information associated with the at least one portion of the medical image. The convolutional neural network is trained on a set of example medical images which may include noise and which may not include noise. Data augmentation may be performed by applying blurring algorithms to normal medical image dataset to increase the size of the training set. In an embodiment, approximately 80% of the medical image dataset may be used for training of the machine learning model and approximately 20% of the medical image dataset may be used for evaluation of the machine learning model. The evaluation of the machine learning model may be performed to determine an accuracy rate of the machine learning model.</p>
<p id="p0042" num="0042">In particular, the medical image 1150 is represented as a two-dimensional array of pixel intensities for three array dimensions for feature maps including height and width. The medical image 1150 is transformed through convolutional feature extraction layers according to the following equation:<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> <maths id="math0001" num=""><math display="block"><mrow><msubsup><mi>h</mi><mrow><mi>l</mi><mo>,</mo><mi mathvariant="italic">ij</mi></mrow><mrow><mfenced><mi>k</mi></mfenced></mrow></msubsup><mo>=</mo><mi>Ø</mi><mrow><msub><mrow><mo>(</mo><mfenced separators=""><msubsup><mi>W</mi><mi>l</mi><mrow><mfenced><mi>k</mi></mfenced></mrow></msubsup><mo>∗</mo><msub><mi>h</mi><mrow><mi>l</mi><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msub></mfenced></mrow><mi mathvariant="italic">ij</mi></msub><mo>+</mo><msubsup><mi>b</mi><mi>l</mi><mrow><mfenced><mi>k</mi></mfenced></mrow></msubsup><mo>)</mo></mrow></mrow></math><img id="ib0001" file="imgb0001.tif" wi="60" he="9" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> where <i>l</i> denotes the layer index, <i>k</i> denotes the feature map index, <i>h</i><sub>0</sub> corresponds to the image pixel array, <maths id="math0002" num=""><math display="inline"><mrow><msubsup><mi>W</mi><mi>l</mi><mrow><mfenced><mi>k</mi></mfenced></mrow></msubsup></mrow></math><img id="ib0002" file="imgb0002.tif" wi="11" he="9" img-content="math" img-format="tif" inline="yes"/></maths> and <maths id="math0003" num=""><math display="inline"><mrow><msubsup><mi>b</mi><mi>l</mi><mrow><mfenced><mi>k</mi></mfenced></mrow></msubsup></mrow></math><img id="ib0003" file="imgb0003.tif" wi="9" he="8" img-content="math" img-format="tif" inline="yes"/></maths> are the filters and biases, which correspond to the <i>l</i>-th layer and k-th feature map, learned from training examples, and φ is an element wise activation function such as sigmoid(x) or max(0,x) (rectified linear unit, ReLU).</p>
<p id="p0043" num="0043">As shown in <figref idref="f0011">FIG 11</figref>, pooling layers 1104 and 1108 are used subsequent to convolutional layers 1102, 1106 and 1110. The pooling layers 1104 and 1108 aggregate spatially local regions using a max-function i.e. the maximum value of the spatial local region is selected. For example, spatially local regions of size 2x2 may be aggregated using the max-function, i.e. the maximum value of the 2x2 region is selected. Common aggregation functions are the maximum or average function, but other functions are possible. Spatial dropouts with a dropout rate of 0.3 are introduced between consecutive convolutions. In the present invention, the processing of medical image may consist of three convolution layers of kernel size 2x2 and one max pooling layer. Each convolution operation may be followed by batch normalization and ReLU. The output layer 1112 yields classification of the at least one portion of the medical image as noisy or non-noisy.</p>
<p id="p0044" num="0044">The method steps associated with training of the machine learning model is described further in <figref idref="f0006">FIG 6</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0045" num="0045"><figref idref="f0006">FIG 6</figref> illustrates a flowchart of a method 600 of training at least one machine learning model to generate a denoised medical image. The method 600 includes a step 601 of receiving a reference medical image depicting a body part of a patient. In an embodiment, the reference medical image may be received from a source such as the medical database 107. Alternatively,<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> the reference medical image may also be obtained from the medical image acquisition device. The reference medical image may be a medical image which may not include noise. The method 600 further includes a step of obtaining a noisy medical image corresponding to the reference medical image. Therefore, the noisy medical image may depict the same body part as that in the reference medical image. In an embodiment, the noise level of the noisy medical image may be higher than that of the reference medical image. At step 603, the machine learning model may be received by the processing unit from the memory. At step 604, one or more portions of the noisy medical image are identified using the machine learning model. The one or more portions of the noisy medical image may include noise. In an embodiment, the identification of one or more portions of the medical imaging comprising noise may be performed by analysis of pixel information associated with the noisy medical image. The method 600 further includes a step 604 of retrieving using the machine learning model at least one pre-defined pixel matrix from the database based on the one or more portions of the noisy medical image. At least one pre-defined pixel matrix may be generated for each of the one or more portions of the medial image. The pre-defined pixel matrices may be classified based on the one or more medical information associated with the medical image. The method steps of generating/constructing the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix is elaborated in further detail in <figref idref="f0008">FIG 8</figref>. The pre-defined pixel matrix may include one or more pixel information associated with the one or more portions of the medical image. In an embodiment, the pre-defined pixel matrix may be used to remove noise from the noisy medical image. The method 600 further includes a step 605 of correcting the one or more portions of the noisy medical image by applying the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix to the noisy medical image. The machine learning model may be configured to apply the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix to the one or more<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> portions of the noisy medical image to correct the one or more portions of the noisy medical image. In an embodiment, the pixel intensity values of the pre-defined pixel matrix maybe applied to the one or more portions of the noisy medical image so as to correct the pixel intensity values associated with the one or more portions of the noisy medical image. On application of the pixel intensity values associated with the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix to the one or more portions of the noisy medical image, a denoised medical image may be generated. The method 600 further includes a step 606 of adjusting the machine learning model based on a comparison of the denoised medical image with the reference medical image. In a further embodiment, the corrected or denoised medical image may be compared with the reference medical image. On comparison, one or more differences in the pixel intensity values between the reference medical image and the denoised medical image may be identified. If such differences are identified, the machine learning model may be adjusted such that the differences in the pixel intensity values may be overcome to generate a better denoised medical image. In an embodiment, the one or more differences in the pixel intensity values may indicate presence of noise in the denoised medical image. Therefore, the machine learning model may be further improved to overcome the differences in the pixel intensity values between the reference image and the denoised medical image. Advantageously, training of the machine learning model enables effective functioning of the machine learning model. Therefore, denoising of the medical images may be performed with greater accuracy.</p>
<p id="p0046" num="0046"><figref idref="f0007">FIG 7</figref> illustrates a flowchart of a method 700 of retrieving the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix from the database, according to an embodiment. At step 701, at least one category of medical information associated with the noisy medical image is extracted. The category of medical information may<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --> include, for example, medical study description associated with the medical image, examined body part associated with the medical image and medical procedure associated with the medical image. The medical information associated with the medical image enables efficient categorization of the medical images. At step 702, the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix is retrieved from the medical database 107 based on the at least one category of medical information associated with the noisy medical image. Advantageously, the pre-defined pixel matrix associated with the noisy medical image is accurately chosen based on the at least one category of medical information associated with the noisy medical image and the pre-defined pixel matrix. Therefore, errors in correcting the noisy medical image is avoided.</p>
<p id="p0047" num="0047"><figref idref="f0008">FIG 8</figref> illustrates a flowchart of a method 800 of generating the pre-defined pixel matrix for a medical image. At step 801, at least one pixel matrix is constructed for the reference medical image and the noisy medical image. The pixel matrix includes equal number of rows and columns. The pixel matrix enables capture of pixel intensity values associated with the medical images. In the embodiment, the at least one pixel matrix of the reference medical image corresponds to the at least one pixel matrix of the noisy medical image. Therefore, the portion of the reference medical image chosen is similar to the portion of the noisy medical image which may require correction. The method 800 further includes a step 802 of determining one or more pixel intensity values for the at least one pixel matrix of the reference medical image and the at least one pixel matrix of the noisy medical image. The one or more pixel intensity values may correspond to one or more pixels that form a part of the at least one pixel matrix of the reference medical image and the noisy medical image. The pixel intensity values may enable determination of presence of noise in the noisy medical image. At<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --> step 803, a deviation between the at least pixel matrix associated with the reference medical image and the at least one pixel matrix of the noisy medical image is determined. The deviation may be identified based on a difference between the pixel intensity values of the at least one matrix of the reference medical image and the at least one pixel matrix of the noisy medical image. The determination of deviation in pixel intensities of the reference medical image and the noisy medical image is described in further detail in <figref idref="f0005">FIG 5</figref>. At step 804, at least one pre-defined pixel matrix is generated which may include one or more pixel intensity values obtained by subtracting the one or more pixel intensity values associated with the at least one pixel matrix of the reference medical image and the at least one noisy medical image. Therefore, the pre-defined pixel matrix includes pixel information required to correct the noisy medical image. The method 800 further includes a step 805 of archiving the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix in the database. In a further embodiment, the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix is mapped to the at least one category of medical information associated with the reference medical image and the noisy medical image. Therefore, advantageously, the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix maybe retrieved from the database using the category of medical information. Advantageously, the pre-defined pixel matrix enables accurate correction of the noisy medical image by applying the difference of the pixel intensity values between the reference medical image and the noisy medical image to the noisy medical image. Furthermore, the need for multiple medical scans is avoided.</p>
<p id="p0048" num="0048"><figref idref="f0005">FIG 5</figref> illustrates pixel information associated with a set of medical images, according to an embodiment. Image set 501 depicts one or more pixel intensity values associated with a noisy medical image. Image set 502 depicts one or more pixel intensity values associated with a reference medical image.<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --> Image set 503 depicts the difference in the pixel intensity values associated with the reference medical image and the noisy medical image.</p>
<p id="p0049" num="0049"><figref idref="f0009">FIG 9</figref> illustrates a table 900 depicting archived pre-defined pixel matrices associated with at least one category of medical information, according to the embodiment. The table 900 includes pixel information associated with a reference medical image (illustrated as Correct grid' in the figure), pixel information associated with noisy medical image (illustrated as 'Blur grid' in the figure) and categories of medical information associated with the reference medical image and the noisy medical image. For example, the category of medical information in the embodiment include medical study description, body part depicted in the medical image and medical procedure associated with the medical images. Advantageously, the pre-defined pixel matrix can be made available for various categories of medical information. Therefore, the pre-defined matrices may be easily applied to the noisy medical images to perform denoising.</p>
<p id="p0050" num="0050"><figref idref="f0010">FIG 10</figref> illustrates a set of medical images depicting a noisy medical image 1001 and a denoised medical image 1002. One or more portions of the medical image 1001 include noise thereby affecting the clarity of the medical image. The medical image 1002 is a denoised medical image generated on application of the pre-defined pixel matrix associated with the noisy medical image. The noise affecting the clarity of the medical image 1001 is eliminated in the medical image 1002.</p>
<p id="p0051" num="0051">The advantage of the invention is that requirement of the patient to undergo multiple medical scans is eliminated. Therefore, the noisy medical images may still be used for further analysis as they can be denoised using the invention. Furthermore, diagnosis of medical condition associated with the<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --> patient is faster as additional expenditure of time in repeated medical scan procedures is avoided. Yet another advantage of the invention is increase in the cost efficiency of the process of diagnosis.</p>
<p id="p0052" num="0052">The foregoing examples have been provided merely for the purpose of explanation and are in no way to be construed as limiting of the present invention disclosed herein. While the invention has been described with reference to various embodiments, it is understood that the words, which have been used herein, are words of description and illustration, rather than words of limitation. Further, although the invention has been described herein with reference to particular means, materials, and embodiments, the invention is not intended to be limited to the particulars disclosed herein; rather, the invention extends to all functionally equivalent structures, methods and uses, such as are within the scope of the appended claims. Those skilled in the art, having the benefit of the teachings of this specification, may effect numerous modifications thereto and changes may be made without departing from the scope and spirit of the invention in its aspects.</p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> -->
<claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>A method (200) of generating a denoised medical image, the method (200) comprising:
<claim-text>receiving, by a processing unit (101), a medical image generated by a medical imaging device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>extracting, by the processing unit (101), at least one category of medical information associated with the medical image;</claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying, by the processing unit (101), pixels associated with a noise in the medical image using at least one trained machine learning model;</claim-text>
<claim-text>retrieving, by the processing unit (101), at least one pre-defined pixel matrix from a database (107), wherein the pre-defined pixel matrix is identified based on the at least one category of medical information and the pixel information associated with the pixels identified from the medical image; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>correcting, by the processing unit (101), the pixel information associated with the identified pixels in the medical image using the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix so as to generate a denoised medical image, wherein the denoised medical image has improved clarity over the medical image.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>The method (200) according to claim 1, wherein identifying the pixel information associated with the medical image comprises:
<claim-text>identifying, by the processing unit (101), at least one portion of the medical image that comprises noise; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>extracting, by the processing unit (101), the pixel information associated with the identified at least one portion of the medical image.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>The method (200) according to claim 2, wherein extracting the pixel information associated with the at least one portion of the medical image comprises:
<claim-text>constructing, by the processing unit (101), at least one pixel matrix (401A-N) of the at least one portion of the medical image, wherein the at least one pixel matrix (401A-N) comprises equal number of rows and columns; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining, by the processing unit (101), one or more pixel intensity values for the at least one pixel matrix (401A-N) of the at least one portion of the medical image.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>The method (200) according to any of the aforementioned claims, wherein the at least one pixel matrix (401A-N) associated with the at least one portion of the medical image and the pre-defined pixel matrix is composed of at least three rows and three columns.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>The method (200) according to any of the aforementioned claims, wherein the at least one category of medical information associated with the medical image comprises at least one of medical study description associated with the medical image, examined body part associated with the medical image, and medical procedure associated with the medical image.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>The method (200) according to claims 1 to 6, wherein correcting the pixel information associated with the medical image comprises applying, by the processing unit (101), the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix to the at least one portion of the medical image, wherein the pre-defined pixel matrix is a pixel matrix comprising pixel intensity values determined by the at least one trained machine learning model,<!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --> wherein the pixel intensity values depict one or more differences between one or more portions of reference noisy medical images and corresponding one or more portions of non-noisy medical images.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>The method (200) according to any of the aforementioned claims, wherein the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix is generated by the at least one trained machine learning model for each category of medical information.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>The method (200) according to any of the aforementioned claims, wherein the at least one trained machine learning model is a convolutional neural network model.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>A method (600) of training at least one machine learning model to generate a denoised medical image, the method comprising:
<claim-text>receiving, by a processing unit (101), a reference medical image depicting a body part of a patient;</claim-text>
<claim-text>obtaining, by the processing unit (101), a noisy medical image corresponding to the reference medical image, the noisy medical image depicting the body part of the patient and having a noise level higher than the reference medical image;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving, by the processing unit (101), a machine learning model;</claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying, by the processing unit (101), one or more portions of the noisy medical image comprising noise by applying the machine learning model to the noisy medical image;</claim-text>
<claim-text>retrieving, by the processing unit(101), using the machine learning model, at least one pre-defined pixel matrix from a database (107) based on the one or more portions of the noisy medical image;<!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>correcting, by the processing unit (101), the one or more portions of the noisy medical image by applying the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix to the noisy medical image using the machine learning model so as to generate a denoised medical image from the noisy medical image; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>adjusting, by the processing unit (101), the machine learning model based on a comparison of the denoised medical image with the reference medical image.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>The method (600) according to claim 9, further comprising:
<claim-text>extracting, by the processing unit (101), at least one category of medical information associated with the noisy medical image; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>retrieving, by the processing unit (101), the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix from the database based on the at least one category of medical information associated with the noisy medical image.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>The method (600) according to claims 9 and 10, further comprising:
<claim-text>constructing, by the processing unit (101), at least one pixel matrix of the reference medical image and the noisy medical image, wherein the at least one pixel matrix comprises equal number of rows and columns, wherein the at least one pixel matrix of the reference image corresponds to the at least one pixel matrix of the noisy medical image;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining, by the processing unit (101), one or more pixel intensity values for the at least one pixel matrix of the reference medical image and the at least one pixel matrix of the noisy medical image;</claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying, by the processing unit (101), a deviation between the at least one pixel matrix associated<!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --> with the reference medical image and the at least one pixel matrix of the noisy medical image;</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating, by the processing unit (101), the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix, wherein the pre-defined pixel matrix comprises one or more pixel intensity values obtained by subtracting the one or more pixel intensity values associated with the at least one pixel matrix of the reference medical image and the at least one noisy medical image; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>archiving, by the processing unit (101), the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix in a database.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>The method (600) according to claims 10 and 11, wherein the at least one pre-defined pixel matrix is mapped to the at least one category of medical information, wherein the archived at least one pre-defined pixel matrix is associated with the at least one category of medical information.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>A medical imaging device for generating a denoised medical image, the device comprising:
<claim-text>one or more processing units (101);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a scanner unit configured to capture one or more medical images; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a memory (102) coupled to the one or more processing units (101), the memory (102) comprising a denoising module (110) configured to perform the method steps as claimed in any one of claims 1 to 8 using at least one trained machine learning model.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>A system (100) for generating a denoised medical image, the system (100) comprising:
<claim-text>one or more processing units (101);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a medical database (107) coupled to the one or more processing units (101), wherein the medical database<!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --> (107) is configured to receive the plurality of medical images from a medical imaging device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a memory (102) coupled to the one or more processing units (101), the memory (102) comprising a denoising module (110) configured to perform the method steps as claimed in any one of claims 1 to 8 using at least one trained machine learning model.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0015" num="0015">
<claim-text>A computer program product comprising machine readable instructions, that when executed by a processing unit (101), cause the processing unit (101) to perform a method according to any one of claims 1 to 8.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0016" num="0016">
<claim-text>A computer readable medium on which program code sections of a computer program are saved, the program code sections being loadable into and/or executable in a system (100) to make the system (100) execute the method of any one of the claims 1 to 8 when the program code sections are executed in the system (100).</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="37"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="148" he="114" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="38"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="82" he="169" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="39"> -->
<figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="82" he="107" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="40"> -->
<figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="141" he="137" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="41"> -->
<figure id="f0005" num="5"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="98" he="211" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="42"> -->
<figure id="f0006" num="6"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="82" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="43"> -->
<figure id="f0007" num="7"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="82" he="74" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="44"> -->
<figure id="f0008" num="8"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="82" he="169" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="45"> -->
<figure id="f0009" num="9"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="109" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="46"> -->
<figure id="f0010" num="10"><img id="if0010" file="imgf0010.tif" wi="130" he="221" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="47"> -->
<figure id="f0011" num="11"><img id="if0011" file="imgf0011.tif" wi="129" he="226" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<search-report-data id="srep" lang="en" srep-office="EP" date-produced=""><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="157" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="155" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data><search-report-data date-produced="20200709" id="srepxml" lang="en" srep-office="EP" srep-type="ep-sr" status="n"><!--
 The search report data in XML is provided for the users' convenience only. It might differ from the search report of the PDF document, which contains the officially published data. The EPO disclaims any liability for incorrect or incomplete data in the XML for search reports.
 -->

<srep-info><file-reference-id>SHC20006PEP</file-reference-id><application-reference><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>20166625.2</doc-number></document-id></application-reference><applicant-name><name>Siemens Healthcare GmbH</name></applicant-name><srep-established srep-established="yes"/><srep-invention-title title-approval="yes"/><srep-abstract abs-approval="yes"/><srep-figure-to-publish figinfo="by-applicant"><figure-to-publish><fig-number>1</fig-number></figure-to-publish></srep-figure-to-publish><srep-info-admin><srep-office><addressbook><text>MN</text></addressbook></srep-office><date-search-report-mailed><date>20200728</date></date-search-report-mailed></srep-info-admin></srep-info><srep-for-pub><srep-fields-searched><minimum-documentation><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr><text>G06T</text></classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr></minimum-documentation></srep-fields-searched><srep-citations><citation id="sr-cit0001"><patcit dnum="WO2017191643A1" id="sr-pcit0001" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=WO2017191643&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2017191643</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>TEL HASHOMER MEDICAL RES INFRASTRUCTURE &amp; SERVICES LTD [IL] ET AL.</name><date>20171109</date></document-id></patcit><category>X</category><rel-claims>1-5,7-10,13-16</rel-claims><category>A</category><rel-claims>6,11,12</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* abstract *</passage></rel-passage><rel-passage><passage>* paragraphs [0009],  [0023],  [0024] *</passage><passage>* paragraph [0027] - paragraph [0034] *</passage><passage>* paragraph [0064] *</passage><passage>* paragraph [0071] - paragraph [0072]; figure 2 *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0002"><patcit dnum="US2019377978A1" id="sr-pcit0002" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=US2019377978&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2019377978</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>RAO BIMBA [US] ET AL</name><date>20191212</date></document-id></patcit><category>A</category><rel-claims>1-5,7-10,13-16</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* abstract *</passage><passage>* paragraph [0018] - paragraph [0019] *</passage><passage>* paragraph [0047] - paragraph [0044] *</passage><passage>* paragraph [0054] *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0003"><nplcit id="sr-ncit0001" npl-type="s"><article><author><name>ANWAR SAEED ET AL</name></author><atl>Category-Specific Object Image Denoising</atl><serial><sertitle>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON IMAGE PROCESSING, IEEE SERVICE CENTER, PISCATAWAY, NJ, US</sertitle><pubdate>20171101</pubdate><vid>26</vid><ino>11</ino><doi>10.1109/TIP.2017.2733739</doi><issn>1057-7149</issn></serial><location><pp><ppf>5506</ppf><ppl>5518</ppl></pp></location><refno>XP011659815</refno></article></nplcit><category>A</category><rel-claims>1-12</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* abstract; figure 2 *</passage></rel-passage></citation></srep-citations><srep-admin><examiners><primary-examiner><name>Katsoulas, Dimitrios</name></primary-examiner></examiners><srep-office><addressbook><text>Munich</text></addressbook></srep-office><date-search-completed><date>20200709</date></date-search-completed></srep-admin><!--							The annex lists the patent family members relating to the patent documents cited in the above mentioned European search report.							The members are as contained in the European Patent Office EDP file on							The European Patent Office is in no way liable for these particulars which are merely given for the purpose of information.							For more details about this annex : see Official Journal of the European Patent Office, No 12/82						--><srep-patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2017191643</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20171109</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>3452983</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20190313</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>IL</country><doc-number>262693</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20190331</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2019139202</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20190509</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2017191643</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20171109</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2019377978</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20191212</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>CN</country><doc-number>106204465</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20161207</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>DE</country><doc-number>102016108737</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20161201</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>6367261</doc-number><kind>B2</kind><date>20180801</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2016221264</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20161228</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>KR</country><doc-number>20160140465</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20161207</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2016350620</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20161201</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2019377978</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20191212</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family></srep-patent-family></srep-for-pub></search-report-data>
</ep-patent-document>
