<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP18191195B1" file="EP18191195NWB1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3617596" kind="B1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSK..HRIS..MTNORS..SM..................</B001EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  2100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3617596</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT SPECIFICATION</B121></B120><B130>B1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>18191195.9</B210><B220><date>20180828</date></B220><B240><B241><date>20200903</date></B241></B240><B250>en</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20200304</date><bnum>202010</bnum></B430><B450><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B450><B452EP><date>20210707</date></B452EP></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>F23N   1/06        20060101AFI20210111BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="2"><text>F23N   5/12        20060101ALI20210111BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="3"><text>F23D  14/04        20060101ALI20210111BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>F23N   5/123       20130101 LI20190129BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>F23D  14/045       20130101 FI20190129BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="3"><text>F23N2227/20        20200101 LA20200103RHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="4"><text>F23N   1/062       20130101 LI20190129BHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>VERFAHREN ZUM BETRIEB EINES GASBRENNERGERÄTS</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>METHOD FOR OPERATING A GAS BURNER APPLIANCE</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>PROCÉDÉ DE FONCTIONNEMENT D'UN APPAREIL À BRÛLEUR À GAZ</B542></B540><B560><B561><text>EP-A1- 2 667 097</text></B561><B561><text>EP-B1- 1 183 483</text></B561><B561><text>WO-A1-2016/181212</text></B561><B561><text>JP-A- S62 178 815</text></B561></B560></B500><B700><B720><B721><snm>Blaauwwiekel, Piet</snm><adr><str>Anssenstraat 30</str><city>7841 EB Sleen, Drenthe</city><ctry>NL</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B730><B731><snm>Ademco Inc.</snm><iid>101796498</iid><irf>HONE.318.09 EP</irf><adr><str>1985 Douglas Drive N.</str><city>Golden Valley, MN 55422</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B731></B730><B740><B741><snm>Sturm, Christoph</snm><iid>101891382</iid><adr><str>Patentanwälte Sturm Weilnau Franke 
Partnerschaft mbB 
Unter den Eichen 5 (Haus C-Süd)</str><city>65195 Wiesbaden</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840></B800></SDOBI>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<p id="p0001" num="0001">The present patent application relates to a method for operating a gas burner appliance.</p>
<p id="p0002" num="0002"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="EP2667097A1"><text>EP 2 667 097 A1</text></patcit> discloses a method for operating a gas burner appliance. During burner-on-phases, a defined gas/air mixture having a defined mixing ratio of gas and air is provided to a burner chamber for combusting the defined gas/air mixture. The defined gas/air mixture is provided by a mixing device mixing an air flow provided by an air duct with a gas flow provided by a gas duct. The mixing device is provided by a Venturi nozzle. The air flow flowing through the air duct is provided by fan in such a way that the fan speed of the fan depends on a desired burner load of the gas burner appliance, wherein the fan speed range of the fan defines a so-called modulation range of the gas burner appliance.</p>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">According to <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="EP2667097A1"><text>EP 2 667 097 A1</text></patcit> the defined mixing ratio of gas and air of the defined gas/air mixture is kept constant over the entire modulation range of the gas burner appliance by a pneumatic controller of a gas regulation valve being positioned with the gas duct. The pneumatic controller uses a pressure difference between the gas pressure of the gas flow in the gas pipe and a reference pressure, wherein either the air pressure of the air flow in the air duct or the ambient pressure is used as reference pressure, and wherein the pressure difference between the gas pressure of the gas flow in the gas pipe and the reference pressure is determined and controlled pneumatically. The combustion quality is monitored on basis of a signal provided by a combustion quality sensor like a flame ionization sensor.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">According to <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="EP2667097A1"><text>EP 2 667 097 A1</text></patcit>, during burner-on-phases of the gas burner appliance, the mixing ratio of the gas/air mixture can be calibrated to different gas qualities on basis of the signal provided by the flame ionization sensor. The flame ionization sensor is used to calibrate the gas/air mixture to different gas qualities. The control of the mixing ratio of the gas/air mixture over the modulation range of the gas burner is independent from the flame ionization current.</p>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">As mentioned above, <patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="EP2667097A1"><text>EP 2 667 097 A1</text></patcit> discloses a method for operating a gas burner appliance in which the defined mixing ratio of the gas/air mixture is kept constant over the entire modulation range of the gas burner. Only in a calibration mode of the gas burner appliance during a burner-on-phase, the mixing ratio of the gas/air mixture is changed to compensate for a changing gas quality. After a calibration has been executed, the mixing ratio of the gas/air mixture is kept constant over the entire modulation range in a regular combustion mode of the gas burner appliance.</p>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">For calibration a position of a throttle positioned within the gas duct becomes adjusted with an offset value determined during calibration. Said throttle may be an integral element of the gas regulation valve.</p>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">The capacity range of such a burner appliance is limited due to the constraint that the maximum opening of the throttle positioned within the gas duct does not allow sufficient gas flow if the gas/air mixing device does not generate sufficient pressure drop.</p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">If the gas/air mixing device does not generate a sufficient pressure drop, the pressure differential is not sufficient to provide a gas flow through the throttle needed for calibration even if the throttle is completely opened.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">To increase the capacity range of such a burner appliance, according to the state of the art the throttle being positioned within the gas duct is adapted in size. However, using a bigger throttle within the gas duct increases the costs for the gas burner appliance. If the throttle is an integral element of the gas regulation valve, according to the state of the art the entire gas regulation valve is adapted in size.</p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010"><patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="EP1183483B1"><text>EP 1 183 483 B1</text></patcit> discloses a mixing device for a gas burner appliance having two Venturi nozzles being connected in parallel. At least one of the Venturi nozzles can be shut off by a flap.</p>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">Other prior art is disclosed by <patcit id="pcit0006" dnum="WO2016181212A1"><text>WO 2016/181212 A1</text></patcit> and <patcit id="pcit0007" dnum="JPS62178815A"><text>JP S62 178815 A</text></patcit>.</p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">It is desired to increase the capacity range of a burner appliance without the need for a bigger throttle or without the need for a bigger gas regulation valve within the gas duct.</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">Against this background a novel method for operating a gas burner is provided. The method for operating a gas burner according to the invention is defined in the claim 1.</p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">The mixing device of the gas burner appliance to be operated in accordance with the present invention has at least at least two Venturi nozzles being connected in parallel.</p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">The calibration of the gas/air mixture is performed in such a way that for calibration at least one of the Venturi nozzles of the mixing device is closed while at least one of the Venturi nozzles of the mixing device is opened.</p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">With the invention relatively small throttles or gas regulation valves with relatively small throttles which are used in burner appliances with relatively low capacity can be used in burner appliances with increased capacity. In this way there is no need for bigger throttles or gas regulation valves with bigger throttles.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">Existing throttles or existing gas regulation valves with an integral throttle can be used avoiding the need for the development of bigger throttles or gas regulation valves with a bigger throttle.</p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">During a regular combustion mode of the gas burner appliance - meaning in burner-on-phases in which no calibration is performed - the number of opened and closed Venturi nozzles of the mixing device may depend on the burner load. At relatively high burner loads more Venturi nozzles of the mixing device may be opened than at relatively low burner loads.</p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">During calibration an offset value is determined to adjust the position of the throttle within the gas duct. Said offset value is determined during a calibration mode of the gas burner appliance - meaning in a burner-on-phase in which calibration is performed - with a defined number of the Venturi nozzles of the mixing device being closed and a defined number of the Venturi nozzles of the mixing device being opened. Said offset value is used without adjustment for a regular combustion mode of the gas burner appliance in which the same number of the Venturi nozzles of the mixing device is closed and the same defined number of the Venturi nozzles of the mixing device is opened as in the calibration mode of the gas burner appliance in which the offset value has been determined. Said offset value is used with adjustment for a regular combustion mode of the gas burner appliance in which a different number of the Venturi nozzles of the mixing device is closed and a different number of the Venturi nozzles of the mixing device is opened as in the calibration mode of the gas burner appliance in which the off-set value has been determined. This allows a very beneficial operation of a burner appliance with an increased capacity range but making use of throttles known from burner appliances having a lower capacity.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">For the adjustment of said offset value the offset value may be multiplied with a factor depending from the ratio between the flow section provided by the Venturi nozzles being opened during the regular combustion mode of the gas burner appliance and the flow section provided by the Venturi nozzles be opened during the calibration mode of the gas burner appliance in which the offset value has been determined. This adjustment of the offset value is preferred and can be done in a very simple and reliable way.</p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">Preferred developments of the invention are provided by the dependent claims and the description which follows. Exemplary embodiments are explained in more detail on the basis of the drawing, in which:
<dl id="dl0001" compact="compact">
<dt>Figure 1</dt><dd>shows a schematic view of a gas burner appliance;</dd>
<dt>Figure 2</dt><dd>shows a detail of the gas burner appliance of <figref idref="f0001">Figure 1</figref>.</dd>
</dl></p>
<p id="p0022" num="0022"><figref idref="f0001">Figure 1</figref> shows a schematic view of a gas burner appliance 10. The same comprises a gas burner chamber 11 with a gas burner surface 25 in which combustion of a defined gas/air mixture having a defined mixing ratio of gas and air takes place during burner-on phases of the gas burner appliance 10.</p>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">The combustion of the gas/air mixture results into flames 12 monitored by a combustion quality sensor, namely by a flame rod 13.</p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">The defined gas/air mixture is provided to the burner chamber 11 of the gas burner appliance 10 by mixing an air flow with a gas flow.</p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">A fan 14 sucks in air flowing through an air duct 15 and gas flowing though a gas duct 16.</p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">A gas regulating valve 18 for adjusting the gas flow through the gas duct 16 and preferably a gas safety valve 19 are assigned to the gas duct 16.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">The defined gas/air mixture having the defined mixing ratio of gas and air is provided to the burner chamber 11 of the gas burner appliance 10. The defined gas/air mixture is provided by mixing the air flow provided by an air duct 15 with a gas flow provided by a gas duct 16. The air flow and the gas flow become preferably mixed by a mixing device 23.</p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">The quantity of the air flow and thereby the quantity of the gas/air mixture flow is adjusted by the fan 14, namely by the speed of the fan 14. The fan speed can be adjusted by an actuator 22 of the fan 14. The fan speed of the fan 14 is controlled by a controller 20 generating a control variable for the actuator 22 of the fan 14.</p>
<p id="p0029" num="0029">The defined mixing ratio of the defined gas/air mixture is controlled by the gas regulating valve 18, namely by a pneumatic controller 24 of the same. The pneumatic controller 24 of the gas regulating valve 18 controls the opening/closing position of the gas valve 18.</p>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">The position of the gas valve 18 is adjusted by the pneumatic controller 24 on basis of a pressure difference between the gas pressure of the gas flow in the gas pipe 16 and a reference pressure. The gas regulating valve 18 is controlled by the pneumatic controller 24 in such a way that at the outlet pressure of the gas valve 18 is equal to the reference pressure.</p>
<p id="p0031" num="0031">In <figref idref="f0001">Figure 1</figref>, the ambient pressure serves as reference pressure. However, it is also possible to use the air pressure of the air flow in the air duct 15 as reference pressure.</p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032">The pressure difference between the gas pressure and the reference pressure is determined pneumatically by pneumatic sensor of the pneumatic controller 24.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p>
<p id="p0033" num="0033">The mixing ratio of the defined gas/air mixture is controlled by the pneumatic controller 24 in such a way that over the entire modulation range of the gas burner appliance 10 the defined mixing ratio of the defined gas/air mixture is kept constant.</p>
<p id="p0034" num="0034">A modulation of "1" means that the fan 14 is operated at maximum fan speed (100% of maximum fay speed) and thereby at full-load of the gas burner appliance 10. A modulation of "2" means that the fan 14 is operated at 50% of the maximum fan speed and a modulation of "5" means that the fan 14 is operated at 20% of the maximum fan speed.</p>
<p id="p0035" num="0035">By changing the fan speed of the fan 14, the load of the gas burner appliance 10 can be adjusted. Over the entire modulation range of the gas burner appliance 10 the defined mixing ratio of the defined gas/air mixture is kept constant.</p>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">As described above, the mixing ratio of the defined gas/air mixture is controlled during burner-on phases by the pneumatic controller 24 so that over the entire modulation range of the gas burner appliance 10 the defined mixing ratio of the gas/air mixture is kept constant.</p>
<p id="p0037" num="0037">During burner-on phases the defined mixing ratio of gas and air of the defined gas/air mixture can be calibrated.</p>
<p id="p0038" num="0038">The calibration is performed by adjusting a position of a throttle 17 within the gas duct 16.</p>
<p id="p0039" num="0039">The throttle 17 may be an integral element of the gas regulation valve 18. The throttle position of the throttle 17 can be adjusted by an actuator 21 assigned to the throttle 17. The controller 20 controls the actuator 21 and thereby the throttle position of the throttle 17 during calibration.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></p>
<p id="p0040" num="0040">The absolute throttle position of the throttle 17 after calibration can be determined in different ways. With use of a stepper motor as actuator 21, the actual absolute throttle position of the throttle 17 can be determined by counting steps of the stepper motor. With use of a solenoid as actuator 21, the actual absolute throttle position of the throttle 17 can be determined by measuring/controlling the electrical current of the same. It is also possible to determine the absolute throttle position of the throttle 17 after calibration by using a position feedback provided by a sensing element like a Hall sensor assigned to the throttle 17.</p>
<p id="p0041" num="0041">Independent from how the absolute throttle position of the throttle 17 after calibration is determined, during calibration an offset value is determined to adjust the position of the throttle 17 within the gas duct 16.</p>
<p id="p0042" num="0042">As explained above, during burner-on-phases of the gas burner appliance 10 a defined gas/air mixture is combusted with the gas burner chamber 11 of the gas burner appliance 10. During a regular combustion mode of the gas burner appliance 10 - in which no calibration takes place - the fan speed is adjusted to the desired burner load and the mixing ratio of the gas/air mixture is controlled, namely kept constant, by the pneumatic controller 24 of the gas regulation valve 18. The combustion quality is motioned by a sensor.</p>
<p id="p0043" num="0043">The combustion quality can be monitored by the ionization sensor 13. Alternatively, combustion quality can be monitored by an exhaust gas sensor 27 assigned to an exhaust gas chimney 26 of the gas burner appliance 10.</p>
<p id="p0044" num="0044">If combustion quality becomes poor, the mixing ratio of the gas/air mixture becomes calibrated in a calibration mode of the gas burner appliance 10. The regular combustion mode and the calibration mode belong both to burner-on-phases of the gas burner appliance 10.<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></p>
<p id="p0045" num="0045">The mixing device 23 of the gas burner appliance 10 has at least two Venturi nozzles 28 being connected in parallel.</p>
<p id="p0046" num="0046"><figref idref="f0001">Fig. 2</figref> shows an example of such a mixing device 23 having four Venturi nozzles 28 being connected in parallel. The number of Venturi nozzles 28 being connected in parallel is of exemplary nature only. As mentioned above, the mixing device 23 has at least two Venturi nozzles 28 being connected in parallel.</p>
<p id="p0047" num="0047">The mixing device 23 has a housing 29. The Venturi nozzles 28 are all connected in parallel and are positioned side-by-side in a row with the housing 29.</p>
<p id="p0048" num="0048">The housing 29 provides an air inlet opening 30 being in communication with air inlet openings 31 of the Venturi nozzles 28. The air inlet opening 30 of the housing 29 is connected the air duct 15 or is part of the air duct 15 provided by the housing 29. The housing 29 further provides gas inlet openings 32. The gas inlet openings 32 of the housing 29 are in communication with gas inlet openings (not visible) of the Venturi nozzles 28. The different gas inlet openings 32 are provided to allow different installation scenarios for the gas/air mixing device 23. In each installation scenarios one of said gas inlet openings 32 is connected to the gas duct 16 while the other gas inlet openings 32 are inactive. The housing 29 of the mixing device 23 further provide an outlet opening (not visible) for the gas/air mixture.</p>
<p id="p0049" num="0049">At least one of the Venturi nozzles 28 can be closed and opened by an actuator (not visible).</p>
<p id="p0050" num="0050">In case of the mixing device 23 shown in <figref idref="f0001">Figure 2</figref> having four Venturi nozzles 28, three of the four Venturi nozzles 28 may be individually closable and openable by a respective actuator (not visible) while one of the Venturi nozzles 28 is permanently opened.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></p>
<p id="p0051" num="0051">In this case the mixing device 23 shown in <figref idref="f0001">Figure 2</figref> can be operated with all four Venturi nozzles 28 being opened, or with three Venturi nozzles 28 being opened and one Venturi nozzle 28 being closed, or with two Venturi nozzles 28 being opened and two Venturi nozzles 28 being closed, or with one Venturi nozzle 28 being opened and three Venturi nozzles 28 being closed.</p>
<p id="p0052" num="0052">In case of the mixing device 23 shown in <figref idref="f0001">Figure 2</figref> it is also possible and preferred that two of the four Venturi nozzles 28 are permanently opened while two other Venturi nozzles 28 can be opened and closed jointly by a common actuator. In this case the mixing device 23 shown in <figref idref="f0001">Figure 2</figref> can be operated with all four Venturi nozzles 28 being opened, or with two Venturi nozzles 28 being opened and two Venturi nozzles 28 being closed.</p>
<p id="p0053" num="0053">During a regular combustion mode of the gas burner appliance 10 - in which no calibration takes place - the number of opened Venturi nozzles 28 of the mixing device 23 depends on the burner load.</p>
<p id="p0054" num="0054">At relatively high burner loads more Venturi nozzles 28 of the mixing device 23 are opened than at relatively low burner loads. E.g. at full or maximum burner load corresponding to a modulation of "1" all Venturi nozzles 28 of the mixing device 23 may be opened. At or near 50% of the full or maximum burner load half of the Venturi nozzles 28 of the mixing device 23 may be opened and half of the Venturi nozzles 28 of the mixing device 23 may be closed.</p>
<p id="p0055" num="0055">For calibration of such a gas burner appliance 10, namely for calibrating the mixing ratio of gas and air of the gas/air mixture to different gas qualities during a calibration mode of the gas burner appliance 10, the calibration is performed in such a way that for calibration at least one of the Venturi nozzles 28 of the mixing device 23 is closed while at least one of the Venturi nozzles 28 of the mixng device 23 is opened.<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></p>
<p id="p0056" num="0056">In case of the mixing device 23 shown in <figref idref="f0001">Figure 2</figref> having four Venturi nozzles 28, if three of the four Venturi nozzles 28 can be individually closed and opened, for calibration preferably one Venturi nozzle 28 is opened and three Venturi nozzles 28 are closed.</p>
<p id="p0057" num="0057">In case of the mixing device 23 shown in <figref idref="f0001">Figure 2</figref> having four Venturi nozzles 28, if two of the four Venturi nozzles 28 can jointly be closed and opened, for calibration two Venturi nozzles 28 are opened and two Venturi nozzles 28 are closed.</p>
<p id="p0058" num="0058">As mentioned above, during calibration an offset value is determined to adjust the position of the throttle 17 within the gas duct 16.</p>
<p id="p0059" num="0059">Said offset value is determined during a calibration mode of the gas burner appliance 10 with a defined number of the Venturi nozzles 28 of the mixing device 23 being closed and a defined number of the Venturi nozzles 28 of the mixing device 23 being opened.</p>
<p id="p0060" num="0060">Said offset value is used without adjustment for a regular combustion mode of the gas burner appliance 10 in which the same number of the Venturi nozzles 28 of the mixing device 23 is closed and the same defined number of the Venturi nozzles 28 of the mixing device 23 is opened as in the calibration mode of the gas burner appliance 10 in which the offset value has been determined.</p>
<p id="p0061" num="0061">Said offset value is used with adjustment for a regular combustion mode of the gas burner appliance 10 in which a different number of the Venturi nozzles 28 of the mixing device 23 is closed and a different number of the Venturi nozzles 28 of the mixing device 23 is opened as in the calibration mode of the gas burner appliance 10 in which the off-set value has been determined.<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></p>
<p id="p0062" num="0062">For the adjustment of the offset value the offset value is multiplied with a factor. Said factor depends from the ratio between the flow section provided by the Venturi nozzles 28 being open during the regular combustion mode of the gas burner appliance 10 and the flow section provided by the or each Venturi nozzles be open during the calibration mode of the gas burner appliance 10 in which the offset value has been determined.</p>
<p id="p0063" num="0063">In case of the mixing device 23 shown in <figref idref="f0001">Figure 2</figref> having four Venturi nozzles 28, if two of the four Venturi nozzles 28 can jointly be closed and opened, for calibration two Venturi nozzles 28 are opened and two Venturi nozzles 28 are closed. The offset determined during said calibration with two Venturi nozzles 28 being opened and two Venturi nozzles 28 being closed will be used without adjustment for a regular combustion mode in which also two Venturi nozzles 28 are opened and two Venturi nozzles 28 are closed.</p>
<p id="p0064" num="0064">However, for a regular combustion mode in which all four Venturi nozzles 28 are opened, an adjusted offset will be used. For adjustment of the offset value the same is multiplied with a factor. Said factor depends then from the ratio between the flow section provided by all four Venturi nozzles 28 and the flow section provided by two Venturi nozzles be opened during the calibration. If the ratio of the between the flow section provided by all four Venturi nozzles 28 and the flow section provided by two Venturi nozzles be opened during the calibration is 2,0, then the factor may be 2,0.</p>
<p id="p0065" num="0065">As mentioned above, the use of a mixing device having four Venturi nozzles in parallel is only an example. The mixing device may have only two Venturi nozzles in parallel. In this case, for calibration one Venturi nozzle is closed and one Venturi nozzle is opened. In this case, during a regular combustion mode with one Venturi nozzle may be opened or two Venturi nozzles may be opened, depending on the burner load.<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></p>
<p id="p0066" num="0066">If during a regular combustion mode one Venturi nozzle is opened while the other Venturi nozzle is closed, the offset determined during calibration can be used without adjustment of the same. However, if during a regular combustion mode two Venturi nozzle are, the offset determined during calibration will adjusted by a factor as described above.</p>
<p id="p0067" num="0067">With the present invention, the throttle valve limitation will longer be an issue. Since the calibration will be done with at least one Venturi nozzle being closed, a higher pressure drop can be provided at the mixing device allowing a gas flow high enough to allow calibration.<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></p>
<heading id="h0001">List of reference signs</heading>
<p id="p0068" num="0068">
<dl id="dl0002" compact="compact">
<dt>10</dt><dd>gas burner appliance</dd>
<dt>11</dt><dd>gas burner chamber</dd>
<dt>12</dt><dd>flame</dd>
<dt>13</dt><dd>flame rod</dd>
<dt>15</dt><dd>air duct</dd>
<dt>16</dt><dd>gas duct</dd>
<dt>17</dt><dd>throttle</dd>
<dt>18</dt><dd>gas valve / regulating valve</dd>
<dt>19</dt><dd>gas valve / safety valve</dd>
<dt>20</dt><dd>controller</dd>
<dt>21</dt><dd>actuator</dd>
<dt>22</dt><dd>actuator</dd>
<dt>23</dt><dd>mixing device</dd>
<dt>24</dt><dd>pneumatic controller</dd>
<dt>25</dt><dd>gas burner surface</dd>
<dt>26</dt><dd>exhaust gas chimney</dd>
<dt>27</dt><dd>exhaust gas sensor</dd>
<dt>28</dt><dd>Venturi nozzle</dd>
<dt>29</dt><dd>housing</dd>
<dt>30</dt><dd>air inlet opening of housing</dd>
<dt>31</dt><dd>air inlet opening of Venturi nozzle</dd>
<dt>32</dt><dd>gas inlet opening of housing</dd>
</dl></p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> -->
<claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Method for operating a gas burner appliance (10), wherein
<claim-text>during burner-on-phases a defined gas/air mixture having a defined mixing ratio of gas and air is provided to a burner chamber (11) of the gas burner appliance (10) for combusting the defined gas/air mixture within the burner chamber (11);</claim-text>
<claim-text>said defined gas/air mixture is provided by a mixing device (23) mixing an air flow with a gas flow,<br/>
wherein said mixing device (23) has at least two Venturi nozzles being connected in parallel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said air flow is provided by a fan (14) in such a way that the fan speed of the fan (14) depends on a desired burner load of the gas burner appliance (10),<br/>
wherein the fan speed range of the fan (14) defines a modulation range of the gas burner appliance (10);</claim-text>
<claim-text>said defined mixing ratio of gas and air of the gas/air mixture is controlled over the modulation range of the gas burner appliance (10) by a gas regulating valve (18),
<claim-text>wherein said gas regulating valve (18) has a pneumatic controller (24) controlling the mixing ratio of gas and air on basis of a pressure difference between the gas pressure of the gas flow in the gas pipe (16) and a reference pressure,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein either the air pressure of the air flow or the ambient pressure is used as reference pressure, wherein the pressure difference between the gas pressure and the reference pressure is determined and controlled pneumatically;</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>during burner-on-phases the combustion quality is monitored on basis of a signal provided by a combustion quality sensor like a flame ionization sensor (13),<br/>
wherein the defined mixing ratio of gas and air of the defined gas/air mixture can be calibrated on basis of the signal provided by the combustion quality sensor, namely by adjusting during calibration a position of a throttle (17);</claim-text>
<claim-text>the calibration of the gas/air mixture is performed in such a way that for calibration at least one of the Venturi nozzles (28) of the mixing device (23) is closed while at least one of the Venturi nozzles (28) of the mixing device (23) is opened.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Method as claimed in claim 1, wherein during a regular combustion mode of the gas burner appliance (10) the number of opened Venturi nozzles (28) of the mixing device (23) depends on the burner load.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Method as claimed in claim 2, wherein at relatively high burner loads more Venturi nozzles (28) of the mixing device (23) are opened than at relatively low burner loads.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Method as claimed in one of claims 1 to 3, wherein during calibration an offset value is determined to adjust the position of the throttle (17).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Method as claimed in claim 4, wherein
<claim-text>said offset value is determined during a calibration mode of the gas burner appliance (10) with a defined number of the Venturi nozzles (28) of the mixing device (23) being closed and a defined number of the Venturi nozzles (28) of the mixing device (23) being opened,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said offset value is used without adjustment for a regular combustion mode of the gas burner appliance (10) in which the same number of the Venturi nozzles (28) of the mixing device (23) is closed and the same<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> defined number of the Venturi nozzles (28) of the mixing device (23) is opened as in the calibration mode of the gas burner appliance (10) in which the offset value has been determined,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said offset value is used with adjustment for a regular combustion mode of the gas burner appliance (10) in which a different number of the Venturi nozzles (28) of the mixing device (23) is closed and a different number of the Venturi nozzles (28) of the mixing device (23) is opened as in the calibration mode of the gas burner appliance (10) in which the off-set value has been determined.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Method as claimed in claim 5, wherein<br/>
for the adjustment of said offset value the offset value is multiplied with a factor depending from the ratio between the flow section provided by the Venturi nozzles being open during the regular combustion mode of the gas burner appliance (10) and the flow section provided by the or each Venturi nozzle be open during the calibration mode of the gas burner appliance (10) in which the offset value has been determined.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Method as claimed in one of claims 1-6, wherein
<claim-text>the air flow is provided by an air duct (15) and a gas flow is provided by a gas duct (16),</claim-text>
<claim-text>the fan sucks in the air flowing through the air duct (15) and the gas flowing through the gas duct (16),</claim-text>
<claim-text>the gas regulating valve (18) and the throttle (17) are positioned within the gas duct (16).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims02" lang="de"><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> -->
<claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Verfahren zum Betreiben eines Gasbrennergeräts (10), wobei
<claim-text>während Brenner-Ein-Phasen einer Brennerkammer (11) des Gasbrennergeräts (10) eine definierte Gas/Luft-Mischung mit einem definierten Mischungsverhältnis von Gas und Luft zum Verbrennen der definierten Gas/Luft-Mischung in der Brennerkammer (11) bereitgestellt wird;</claim-text>
<claim-text>die definierte Gas/Luft-Mischung durch eine Mischvorrichtung (23) bereitgestellt wird, die einen Luftstrom mit einem Gasstrom mischt,
<claim-text>wobei die Mischvorrichtung (23) zumindest zwei Venturi-Düsen aufweist, die parallel verbunden sind; der Luftstrom durch ein Gebläse (14) auf eine derartige Weise bereitgestellt wird, dass die Gebläsegeschwindigkeit des Gebläses (14) von einer erwünschten Brennerlast des Gasbrennergeräts (10) abhängt,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei der Gebläsegeschwindigkeitsbereich des Gebläses (14) einen Modulationsbereich des Gasbrennergeräts (10) definiert;</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>das definierte Mischungsverhältnis von Gas und Luft der Gas/Luft-Mischung über den Modulationsbereich des Gasbrennergeräts (10) durch ein Gasregulierventil (18) geregelt wird,
<claim-text>wobei das Gasregulierventil (18) eine pneumatische Regelvorrichtung (24) aufweist, die das Mischungsverhältnis von Gas und Luft auf Basis<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> einer Druckdifferenz zwischen dem Gasdruck des Gasstroms in dem Gasrohr (16) und einem Referenzdruck regelt,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei entweder der Luftdruck des Luftstroms oder der Umgebungsdruck als Referenzdruck verwendet wird, wobei die Druckdifferenz zwischen dem Gasdruck und dem Referenzdruck pneumatisch bestimmt und geregelt wird;</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>während Brenner-Ein-Phasen des die Verbrennungsqualität auf Basis eines Signals überwacht wird, das durch einen Verbrennungsqualitätssensor, wie einem Flammenionisierungssensor (13), bereitgestellt wird,<br/>
wobei das definierte Mischungsverhältnis von Gas und Luft der definierten Gas/Luft-Mischung auf Basis des Signals kalibriert werden kann, das durch den Verbrennungsqualitätssensor bereitgestellt wird, namentlich durch Einstellen einer Position einer Drossel (17) während einer Kalibrierung;</claim-text>
<claim-text>die Kalibrierung der Gas/Luft-Mischung in einer derartigen Weise durchgeführt wird, dass für eine Kalibrierung zumindest eine der Venturi-Düsen (28) der Mischvorrichtung (23) geschlossen ist, während zumindest eine der Venturi-Düsen (28) der Mischvorrichtung (23) geöffnet ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, wobei<br/>
während einer normalen Verbrennungsbetriebsart des Gasbrennergeräts (10) die Anzahl geöffneter Venturi-Düsen (28) der Mischvorrichtung (23) von der Brennerlast abhängt.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 2, wobei<br/>
bei relativ hoher Brennerlast mehr Venturi-Düsen (28) der Mischvorrichtung (23) geöffnet sind als bei relativ niedriger Brennerlast.<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 3, wobei während einer Kalibrierung ein Offsetwert bestimmt wird, um die Position der Drossel (17) einzustellen.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 4, wobei
<claim-text>der Offsetwert während einer Kalibrierungsbetriebsart des Gasbrennergeräts (10) bestimmt wird, in der eine definierte Anzahl der Venturi-Düsen (28) der Mischvorrichtung (23) geschlossen ist und eine definierte Anzahl der Venturi-Düsen (28) der Mischvorrichtung (23) geöffnet ist,</claim-text>
<claim-text>der Offsetwert ohne Einstellung für eine normale Verbrennungsbetriebsart des Gasbrennergeräts (10) verwendet wird, in der die gleiche Anzahl der Venturi-Düsen (28) der Mischvorrichtung (23) geschlossen ist und die gleiche definierte Anzahl der Venturi-Düsen (28) der Mischvorrichtung (23) geöffnet ist wie in der Kalibrierungsbetriebsart des Gasbrennergeräts (10), in welcher der Offsetwert bestimmt wurde,</claim-text>
<claim-text>der Offsetwert mit Einstellung für eine normale Verbrennungsbetriebsart des Gasbrennergeräts (10) verwendet wird, in der eine verschiedene Anzahl der Venturi-Düsen (28) der Mischvorrichtung (23) geschlossen ist und eine verschiedene Anzahl der Venturi-Düsen (28) der Mischvorrichtung (23) geöffnet ist wie in der Kalibrierungsbetriebsart des Gasbrennergeräts (10), in welcher der Offsetwert bestimmt wurde.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 5, wobei<br/>
für die Einstellung des Offsetwerts der Offsetwert mit einem Faktor multipliziert wird, der von dem Verhältnis zwischen dem Strömungsquerschnitt, der durch die Venturi-Düsen bereitgestellt wird, die während der normalen Verbrennungsbetriebsart des Gasbrennergeräts (10) offen sind, und dem Strömungsquerschnitt abhängt, der durch die oder jede Venturi-Düse bereitgestellt wird, die während der Kalibrierungsbetriebsart des Gasbrennergeräts (10) offen ist, in welcher der Offsetwert bestimmt wurde.<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 6, wobei
<claim-text>der Luftstrom durch einen Luftkanal (15) bereitgestellt wird und ein Gasstrom durch einen Gaskanal (16) bereitgestellt wird,</claim-text>
<claim-text>das Gebläse die Luft, die durch den Luftkanal (15) strömt, und das Gas ansaugt, das durch den Gaskanal (16) strömt,</claim-text>
<claim-text>das Gasregulierventil (18) und die Drossel (17) in dem Gaskanal (16) positioniert sind.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims03" lang="fr"><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> -->
<claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Procédé pour faire fonctionner un appareil à brûleur à gaz (10), dans lequel
<claim-text>durant des phases à brûleur allumé, un mélange gaz/air défini ayant un rapport de mélange défini de gaz et d'air est fourni à une chambre de brûleur (11) de l'appareil à brûleur à gaz (10) pour effectuer la combustion du mélange gaz/air défini à l'intérieur de la chambre de brûleur (11) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>ledit mélange gaz/air défini est fourni par un dispositif de mélange (23) mélangeant un écoulement d'air avec un écoulement de gaz,<br/>
dans lequel ledit dispositif de mélange (23) a au moins deux tuyères de type venturi étant raccordées en parallèle ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>ledit écoulement d'air est fourni par un ventilateur (14) de manière telle que la vitesse de ventilateur du ventilateur (14) dépende d'une charge de brûleur souhaitée de l'appareil à brûleur à gaz (10),<br/>
dans lequel la gamme de vitesse de ventilateur du ventilateur (14) définit une gamme de modulation de l'appareil à brûleur à gaz (10) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>ledit rapport de mélange défini de gaz et d'air du mélange gaz/air est commandé à travers la gamme de modulation de l'appareil à brûleur à gaz (10) par une valve de régulation de gaz (18),
<claim-text>dans lequel ladite valve de régulation de gaz (18) a une dispositif de commande pneumatique (24)<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> commandant le rapport de mélange de gaz et d'air sur la base d'une différence de pression entre la pression de gaz de l'écoulement de gaz dans le tuyau de gaz (16) et une pression de référence,</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel soit la pression d'air de l'écoulement d'air soit la pression ambiante est utilisée en tant que pression de référence, dans lequel la différence de pression entre la pression de gaz et la pression de référence est déterminée et commandée de façon pneumatique ;</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>durant des phases à brûleur allumé, la qualité de combustion est surveillée sur la base d'un signal fourni par un capteur de qualité de combustion, comme un capteur d'ionisation de flamme (13),<br/>
dans lequel le rapport de mélange défini de gaz et d'air du mélange gaz/air défini peut être calibré sur la base du signal fourni par la capteur de qualité de combustion, à savoir en ajustant, durant le calibrage, une position d'un organe d'étranglement (17) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>le calibrage du mélange gaz/air est réalisé de manière telle que, pour le calibrage, au moins une des tuyères de type venturi (28) du dispositif de mélange (23) est fermée alors qu'au moins une des tuyères de type venturi (28) du dispositif de mélange (23) est ouverte.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, dans lequel, durant un mode de combustion régulier de l'appareil à brûleur à gaz (10), le nombre de tuyères de type venturi ouvertes (28) du dispositif de mélange (23) dépend de la charge de brûleur.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 2, dans lequel, à des charges de brûleur relativement hautes, plus de tuyères de type venturi (28) du dispositif de mélange (23) sont ouvertes qu'à des charges de brûleur relativement basses.<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Procédé selon l'une des revendications 1 à 3, dans lequel, durant le calibrage, une valeur de décalage est déterminée pour ajuster la position de l'organe d'étranglement (17).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 4, dans lequel ladite valeur de décalage est déterminée durant un mode de calibrage de l'appareil à brûleur à gaz (10) avec un nombre défini des tuyères de type venturi (28) du dispositif de mélange (23) fermées et un nombre défini des tuyères de type venturi (28) du dispositif de mélange (23) ouvertes,
<claim-text>ladite valeur de décalage est utilisée sans ajustement pour un mode de combustion régulier de l'appareil à brûleur à gaz (10) dans lequel le même nombre des tuyères de type venturi (28) du dispositif de mélange (23) sont fermées et le même nombre défini des tuyères de type venturi (28) du dispositif de mélange (23) sont ouvertes que dans le mode de calibrage de l'appareil à brûleur à gaz (10) dans lequel la valeur de décalage a été déterminée,</claim-text>
<claim-text>ladite valeur de décalage est utilisée avec ajustement pour un mode de combustion régulier de l'appareil à brûleur à gaz (10) dans lequel un nombre différent des tuyères de type venturi (28) du dispositif de mélange (23) sont fermées et un nombre différent des tuyères de type venturi (28) du dispositif de mélange (23) sont ouvertes par rapport au mode de calibrage de l'appareil à brûleur à gaz (10) dans lequel la valeur de décalage a été déterminée.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 5, dans lequel, pour l'ajustement de ladite valeur de décalage, la valeur de décalage est multipliée avec un facteur dépendant du rapport entre la section d'écoulement fournie par les tuyères de type venturi ouvertes durant le mode de combustion régulier de l'appareil à brûleur à gaz (10) et la section d'écoulement fournie par la ou chaque tuyère de type venturi ouverte durant le mode de<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> calibrage de l'appareil à brûleur à gaz (10) dans lequel la valeur de décalage a été déterminée.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Procédé selon l'une des revendications 1 à 6, dans lequel l'écoulement d'air est fourni par une conduite d'air (15) et un écoulement de gaz est fourni par une conduite de gaz (16),
<claim-text>le ventilateur aspire l'air s'écoulant à travers la conduite d'air (15) et le gaz s'écoulant à travers la conduite de gaz (16),</claim-text>
<claim-text>la valve de régulation de gaz (18) et l'organe d'étranglement (17) sont positionnés à l'intérieur de la conduite de gaz (16).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="26"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1,2"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="154" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<ep-reference-list id="ref-list">
<heading id="ref-h0001"><b>REFERENCES CITED IN THE DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0001" num=""><i>This list of references cited by the applicant is for the reader's convenience only. It does not form part of the European patent document. Even though great care has been taken in compiling the references, errors or omissions cannot be excluded and the EPO disclaims all liability in this regard.</i></p>
<heading id="ref-h0002"><b>Patent documents cited in the description</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0002" num="">
<ul id="ref-ul0001" list-style="bullet">
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0001" dnum="EP2667097A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2667097</doc-number><kind>A1</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0001">[0002]</crossref><crossref idref="pcit0002">[0003]</crossref><crossref idref="pcit0003">[0004]</crossref><crossref idref="pcit0004">[0005]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0002" dnum="EP1183483B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>1183483</doc-number><kind>B1</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0005">[0010]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0003" dnum="WO2016181212A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2016181212</doc-number><kind>A1</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0006">[0011]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0004" dnum="JPS62178815A"><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>S62178815</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0007">[0011]</crossref></li>
</ul></p>
</ep-reference-list>
</ep-patent-document>
