<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP19891038A1" file="EP19891038NWA1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3889218" kind="A1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSKBAHRIS..MTNORSMESMMAKHTNMD..........</B001EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  1100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3889218</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT APPLICATION</B121><B121EP>published in accordance with Art. 153(4) EPC</B121EP></B120><B130>A1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>19891038.2</B210><B220><date>20191127</date></B220><B240><B241><date>20210607</date></B241></B240><B250>ko</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B300><B310>20180151203</B310><B320><date>20181129</date></B320><B330><ctry>KR</ctry></B330></B300><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B430></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>C08L  69/00        20060101AFI20200605BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="2"><text>C08L  25/12        20060101ALI20200605BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="3"><text>C08L  67/02        20060101ALI20200605BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="4"><text>C08L  51/04        20060101ALI20200605BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="5"><text>C08K   5/521       20060101ALI20200605BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="6"><text>C08K   3/013       20180101ALI20200605BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>C08K   5/521       20130101 LI20200625BCEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>C08L  69/00        20130101 LI20200625BCEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="3"><text>C08L  51/04        20130101 LI20200625BCEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="4"><text>C08L  25/12        20130101 LI20200625BCEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="5"><text>C08K   3/013       20180101 LI20200625BCEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="6"><text>C08L  67/02        20130101 LI20200625BCEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>THERMOPLASTISCHE HARZZUSAMMENSETZUNG UND FORMARTIKEL MIT VERWENDUNG DAVON</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>THERMOPLASTIC RESIN COMPOSITION AND MOLDED ARTICLE USING SAME</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>COMPOSITION DE RÉSINE THERMOPLASTIQUE ET ARTICLE MOULÉ UTILISANT CELLE-CI</B542></B540><B590><B598>1</B598></B590></B500><B700><B710><B711><snm>Lotte Chemical Corporation</snm><iid>101729323</iid><irf>BR115193/MDI/CCU</irf><adr><str>300, Olympic-ro 
Songpa-gu</str><city>Seoul, 05551</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B711></B710><B720><B721><snm>KIM, Myunghun</snm><adr><str>56 Gosan-ro</str><city>Uiwang-si, Gyeonggi-do 16073</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>KWON, Keehae</snm><adr><str>56 Gosan-ro</str><city>Uiwang-si, Gyeonggi-do 16073</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>HONG, Jaekeun</snm><adr><str>56 Gosan-ro</str><city>Uiwang-si, Gyeonggi-do 16073</city><ctry>KR</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B740><B741><snm>Germain Maureau</snm><iid>101908200</iid><adr><str>12, rue Boileau</str><city>69006 Lyon</city><ctry>FR</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840><B844EP><B845EP><ctry>BA</ctry></B845EP><B845EP><ctry>ME</ctry></B845EP></B844EP><B848EP><B849EP><ctry>KH</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>MA</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>MD</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>TN</ctry></B849EP></B848EP><B860><B861><dnum><anum>KR2019016482</anum></dnum><date>20191127</date></B861><B862>ko</B862></B860><B870><B871><dnum><pnum>WO2020111778</pnum></dnum><date>20200604</date><bnum>202023</bnum></B871></B870></B800></SDOBI>
<abstract id="abst" lang="en">
<p id="pa01" num="0001">The present invention relates to a thermoplastic resin composition and a molded article using same, the thermoplastic resin composition comprising: (D) 4 to 12 parts by weight of a methyl methacrylate-butadiene-styrene graft copolymer; (E) 0.1 to 0.3 parts by weight of a phosphate-based heat stabilizer; and (F) 25 to 35 parts by weight of an inorganic filler having an average particle diameter (D50) of 1 to 5 µm, with respect to 100 parts by weight of a basic resin including (A) 65 to 75 wt% of a polycarbonate, (B) 20 to 30 wt% of an aromatic vinyl-cyanized vinyl copolymer; and (C) 1 to 10 wt% of a polyethylene terephthalate resin.<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="85" he="79" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p>
</abstract>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<heading id="h0001"><b>[Technical Field]</b></heading>
<p id="p0001" num="0001">A thermoplastic resin composition and a molded article using the same are disclosed.</p>
<heading id="h0002"><b>[Background Art]</b></heading>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">A polycarbonate resin is one of engineering plastics, which is a material widely used in the plastic industry.</p>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">As the polycarbonate resin has a glass transition temperature (Tg) of about 150 °C due to the bulk molecular structure such as bisphenol-A, which shows a high heat resistance, and the carbonyl group of the carbonate group has a high rotational mobility to provide the polycarbonate resin with flexibility and rigidity. In addition, it is an amorphous polymer having excellent transparency.</p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">Furthermore, although having excellent impact resistance and compatibility with other resins, the polycarbonate resin has a drawback of low fluidity, so it is frequently used in a form of an alloy with the various resins for complementing moldability and post-processability.</p>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">Among them, a polycarbonate/acrylonitrile-butadiene-styrene copolymer (PC/ABS) alloy has excellent durability, moldability, heat resistance, impact resistance, dimensional stability, and the like, and thus may be applied in a wide<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> range of applications such as electric/electronic field, automobile field, construction field, and other living materials.</p>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">Meanwhile, an inorganic filler is sometimes added to the PC/ABS alloy in order to enhance a dimensional stability, causing that metal ions included in the inorganic filler may decompose the PC resin, so as to deteriorate appearance and impact resistance of the PC/ABS alloy.</p>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">Accordingly, in order to solve the problem, it is needed to develop a thermoplastic resin composition having improved impact resistance, appearance, and dimensional stability, compared with the conventional PC/ABS alloy including inorganic filler.</p>
<heading id="h0003"><b>[Disclosure]</b></heading>
<heading id="h0004">[Technical Problem]</heading>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">A thermoplastic resin composition having improved impact resistance, heat resistance, appearance, and dimensional stability, and a molded article using the same are provided.</p>
<heading id="h0005">[Technical Solution]</heading>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">According to an embodiment, a thermoplastic resin composition comprises 100 parts by weight of a base resin comprising (A) 65 to 75 wt% of a polycarbonate resin; (B) 20 to 30 wt% of an aromatic vinyl-vinyl cyanide copolymer; and (C) 1 to 10 wt% of a polyethylene terephthalate resin and (D) 4 to 12 parts by weight of a methyl methacrylate-butadiene-styrene graft copolymer; (E) 0.1 to 0.3 parts by weight of a phosphate-based heat stabilizer and (F) 25 to<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> 35 parts by weight of an inorganic filler having an average particle diameter (D50) of 1 to 5 µm based on 100 parts by weight of the base resin.</p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">The (A) polycarbonate resin may have a melt flow index of 15 to 25 g/10min measured under the condition of 300 °C and 1.2 kg load according to ASTM D1238.</p>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">The (B) aromatic vinyl-vinyl cyanide copolymer may be a copolymer of a monomer mixture including 60 to 80 wt% of an aromatic vinyl compound and 20 to 40 wt% of a vinyl cyanide compound.</p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">The (B) aromatic vinyl-vinyl cyanide copolymer may have a weight average molecular weight of 80,000 to 200,000 g/mol.</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">The (B) aromatic vinyl-vinyl cyanide copolymer may be a styrene-acrylonitrile copolymer.</p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">The (C) polyethylene terephthalate resin may have an intrinsic viscosity measured according to ASTM D2857 of less than or equal to 1.0 dl/g.</p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">The (D) methyl methacrylate-butadiene-styrene graft copolymer may have a core-shell structure including a core composed of a butadiene-based rubbery polymer, and a shell formed by graft polymerization of methyl methacrylate and/or styrene on the core.</p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">The butadiene-based rubbery polymer of the (D) methyl methacrylate-butadiene-styrene graft copolymer may have an average particle diameter of 100 to 400 nm.</p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">The (E) phosphate-based heat stabilizer may include dihydrogen phosphate, stearyl phosphate, trimethyl phosphate, triethyl phosphate, triphenyl phosphate, or a combination thereof.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">The (F) inorganic filler may include montmorillonite, talc, kaolin, zeolite, vermiculite, aluminum oxide, silica, magnesium hydroxide, aluminum hydroxide, glass flakes, or a combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">The thermoplastic resin composition may further include at least one additive selected from a flame retardant, a nucleating agent, a coupling agent, a glass fiber, a plasticizer, a lubricant, an antibacterial agent, a release agent, an antioxidant, an ultraviolet stabilizer, an antistatic agent, a pigment, and a dye.</p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">Meanwhile, a molded article using a thermoplastic resin composition according to an embodiment may be provided.</p>
<heading id="h0006">[Advantageous Effects]</heading>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">The thermoplastic resin composition according to an embodiment and a molded article using the same may be widely applied to the molding of various products used for painting or non-painting due to improved impact resistance, heat resistance, appearance and dimensional stability. In particular, it may be usefully used for applications such as automobile interior/exterior materials.</p>
<heading id="h0007"><b>[Description of the Drawings]</b></heading>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li><figref idref="f0001 f0002">FIGS. 1 to 3</figref> are images for showing the criteria for evaluating initial appearance of molded article specimens using the thermoplastic resin composition according to an embodiment, respectively, Grade 1 (<figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>), Grade 2 (<figref idref="f0001">FIG. 2</figref>), and Grade 3 (<figref idref="f0002">FIG. 3</figref>), and</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002 f0003">FIGS. 4 to 6</figref> are images for showing the criteria for evaluating the thermal stability appearance of molded article specimens using a thermoplastic resin composition according to an embodiment, respectively, Grade 1 (<figref idref="f0002">FIG. 4</figref>), Grade<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> 2 (<figref idref="f0003">FIG. 5</figref>), and Grade 3 (<figref idref="f0003">FIG. 6</figref>).</li>
</ul></p>
<heading id="h0008"><b>[Mode for Invention]</b></heading>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">Hereinafter, embodiments of the present invention are described in detail. However, these embodiments are exemplary, the present invention is not limited thereto, and the present invention is defined by the scope of claims.</p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">In the present invention, unless otherwise mentioned, the average particle diameter refers to a volume average diameter, and means a Z-average particle diameter measured using a dynamic light scattering analyzer.</p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">A thermoplastic resin composition includes 100 parts by weight of a base resin comprising (A) 65 to 75 wt% of a polycarbonate resin; (B) 20 to 30 wt% of an aromatic vinyl-vinyl cyanide copolymer; and (C) 1 to 10 wt% of a polyethylene terephthalate resin and (D) 4 to 12 parts by weight of a methyl methacrylate-butadiene-styrene graft copolymer; (E) 0.1 to 0.3 parts by weight of a phosphate-based heat stabilizer and (F) 25 to 35 parts by weight of an inorganic filler having an average particle diameter (D50) of 1 to 5 µm based on 100 parts by weight of the base resin.</p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">Hereinafter, each component included in the thermoplastic resin composition will be described in detail.</p>
<heading id="h0009"><b><u>(A) Polycarbonate Resin</u></b></heading>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">The polycarbonate resin is a polyester having a carbonate bond but has no particular limit in its type, and may include any polycarbonate resin usable in resin composition field.</p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">For example, it may be prepared by reacting diphenols represented by<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> Chemical Formula 1 with a compound selected from phosgene, halogen acid esters, carbonate esters, and a combination thereof.
<chemistry id="chem0001" num="0001"><img id="ib0001" file="imgb0001.tif" wi="62" he="38" img-content="chem" img-format="tif"/></chemistry></p>
<p id="p0029" num="0029">In Chemical Formula 1,<br/>
A is a linking group selected from a single bond, a substituted or unsubstituted C1 to C30 alkylene group, a substituted or unsubstituted C2 to C5 alkenylene group, a substituted or unsubstituted C2 to C5 alkylidene group, a substituted or unsubstituted C1 to C30 haloalkylene group, a substituted or unsubstituted C5 to C6 cycloalkylene group, a substituted or unsubstituted C5 to C6 cycloalkenylene group, a substituted or unsubstituted C5 to C10 cycloalkylidene group, a substituted or unsubstituted C6 to C30 arylene group, a substituted or unsubstituted C1 to C20 alkoxylene group, a halogenic acid ester group, carbonate ester group, CO, S, and SO<sub>2</sub>, R<sup>1</sup> and R<sup>2</sup> are each independently a substituted or unsubstituted C1 to C30 alkyl group or a substituted or unsubstituted C6 to C30 aryl group, and n1 and n2 are each independently an integer of 0 to 4.</p>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">Two or more types of the diphenols represented by Chemical Formula 1 may be combined to constitute a repeating unit of the polycarbonate resin.</p>
<p id="p0031" num="0031">Specific examples of the diphenols may be hydroquinone, resorcinol, 4,4'-dihydroxydiphenyl, 2,2-bis(4-hydroxyphenyl)propane (also referred to as<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> "bisphenol-A"), 2,4-bis(4-hydroxyphenyl)-2-methylbutane, bis(4-hydroxyphenyl)methane, 1,1-bis(4-hydroxyphenyl)cyclohexane, 2,2-bis(3-chloro-4-hydroxyphenyl)propane, 2,2-bis(3-methyl-4-hydroxyphenyl)propane, 2,2-bis(3,5-dimethyl-4-hydroxyphenyl)propane, 2,2-bis(3,5-dichloro-4-hydroxyphenyl)propane, 2,2-bis(3,5-dibromo-4-hydroxyphenyl)propane, bis(4-hydroxyphenyl)sulfoxide, bis(4-hydroxyphenyl)ketone, bis(4-hydroxyphenyl)ether, and the like. Of the diphenols, 2,2-bis(4-hydroxyphenyl)propane, 2,2-bis(3-methyl-4-hydroxyphenyl)propane, 2,2-bis(3,5-dimethyl-4-hydroxyphenyl)propane, 2,2-bis(3,5-dichloro-4-hydroxyphenyl)propane, or 1,1-bis(4-hydroxyphenyl)cyclohexane may be desirably used. 2,2-bis(4-hydroxyphenyl)propane may be more desirably used.</p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032">The polycarbonate resin may be a mixture of copolymers obtained using two or more dipenols.</p>
<p id="p0033" num="0033">In addition, the polycarbonate resin may be a linear polycarbonate resin, a branched polycarbonate resin, a polyestercarbonate copolymer resin, and the like.</p>
<p id="p0034" num="0034">Specific examples of the linear polycarbonate resin may be a bisphenol-A polycarbonate resin. Specific examples of the branched polycarbonate resin may be a resin prepared by reacting a multi-functional aromatic compound such as trimellitic anhydride, trimellitic acid, and the like with diphenols and a carbonate. The polyestercarbonate copolymer resin may be prepared by reacting bifunctional carboxylic acid with diphenols and carbonate, wherein the used carbonate is diaryl carbonate such as diphenyl carbonate or ethylene carbonate.</p>
<p id="p0035" num="0035">The polycarbonate resin may have a weight average molecular weight of<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> 10,000 to 200,000 g/mol, and for example, the polycarbonate resin may have a weight average molecular weight of 14,000 to 40,000 g/mol. When the weight average molecular weight of the polycarbonate resin is within the above range, a molded article using the same may obtain excellent impact resistance and fluidity.</p>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">The polycarbonate resin may be included in an amount of 65 to 75 wt%, and for example, may be included in an amount of 68 to 73 wt% based on 100 wt% of the base resin. When the polycarbonate resin is less than 65 wt%, mechanical strength is not good, and when it exceeds 75 wt%, moldability may be deteriorated.</p>
<p id="p0037" num="0037">The polycarbonate resin may have a melt flow index of 15 to 25 g/10min, for example greater than or equal to 15 g/10min, for example greater than or equal to 16 g/10min, and for example less than or equal to 25 g/10min, for example less than or equal to 20 g/10min, for example 15 to 25 g/10min, for example 16 to 20 g/10min, which is measured under the condition of 300 °C and 1.2 kg load according to ASTM D1238. When the polycarbonate resin having a melt flow index within the above range is used, a molded article using the same may obtain excellent impact resistance and fluidity.</p>
<p id="p0038" num="0038">However, an embodiment is not necessarily limited thereto. For example, the polycarbonate resin may be used by mixing two or more types of polycarbonate resins having different weight average molecular weight or melt flow index. By mixing and using polycarbonate resins of different weight average molecular weight or melt flow index, the thermoplastic resin composition may be controlled to have desired fluidity.</p>
<heading id="h0010"><b>(B) <u>Aromatic Vinyl-Vinyl Cyanide Copolymer</u></b></heading><!-- EPO <DP n="9"> -->
<p id="p0039" num="0039">In an embodiment, the aromatic vinyl-vinyl cyanide copolymer performs a function of improving the fluidity of the thermoplastic resin composition and maintaining compatibility between components at a certain level.</p>
<p id="p0040" num="0040">In an embodiment, the aromatic vinyl-cyanide vinyl copolymer may be a copolymer of an aromatic vinyl compound and a vinyl cyanide compound. The aromatic vinyl-vinyl cyanide copolymer may have a weight average molecular weight of greater than or equal to 80,000 g/mol, for example greater than or equal to 85,000 g/mol, for example greater than or equal to 90,000 g/mol, and for example less than or equal to 200,000 g/mol, for example less than or equal to 150,000 g/mol, for example 80,000 g/mol to 200,000 g/mol, for example 80,000 g/mol to 150,000 g/mol.</p>
<p id="p0041" num="0041">In the present invention, the weight average molecular weight is measured by dissolving a powder sample in tetrahydrofuran (THF) and then using Agilent Technologies' 1200 series gel permeation chromatography (GPC) (column is LF-804 of Shodex and the standard sample is polystyrene of Shodex).</p>
<p id="p0042" num="0042">The aromatic vinyl compound may be at least one selected from styrene, α-methylstyrene, p-methylstyrene, p-t-butylstyrene, 2,4-dimethylstyrene, chlorostyrene, vinyltoluene, and vinylnaphthalene.</p>
<p id="p0043" num="0043">The vinyl cyanide compound may be at least one selected from acrylonitrile, methacrylonitrile, and fumaronitrile.</p>
<p id="p0044" num="0044">In an embodiment, the aromatic vinyl-vinyl cyanide copolymer may be a copolymer of a monomer mixture including an aromatic vinyl compound and a vinyl cyanide compound.</p>
<p id="p0045" num="0045">In this case, based on 100 wt% of the aromatic vinyl-vinyl cyanide<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> copolymer, the component derived from the aromatic vinyl compound may be included, for example, in an amount of greater than or equal to 60 wt%, for example, greater than or equal to 65 wt%, and for example less than or equal to 80 wt%, for example, less than or equal to 75 wt%, for example, 60 to 80 wt%, for example 65 to 75 wt%.</p>
<p id="p0046" num="0046">In addition, based on 100 wt% of the aromatic vinyl-vinyl cyanide copolymer, the component derived from the vinyl cyanide compound may be invcluded, for example, greater than or equal to 20 wt%, for example, greater than or equal to 25 wt%, and for example less than or equal to 40 wt%, for example, less than or equal to 35 wt%, for example, 20 to 40 wt%, for example, 25 to 35 wt%.</p>
<p id="p0047" num="0047">In an embodiment, the aromatic vinyl-vinyl cyanide copolymer may be a styrene-acrylonitrile copolymer (SAN).</p>
<p id="p0048" num="0048">In an embodiment, the aromatic vinyl-vinyl cyanide copolymer may be included in an amount of greater than or equal to 20 wt%, for example greater than or equal to 22 wt%, and for example, less than or equal to 30 wt%, for example less than or equal to 29 wt%, for example, less than or equal to 28 wt%, for example, 20 to 30 wt%, for example 22 to 29 wt%, for example 22 to 28 wt% based on 100 wt% of the base resin.</p>
<p id="p0049" num="0049">If the aromatic vinyl-vinyl cyanide copolymer is less than 20 wt%, the moldability of the thermoplastic resin composition may be deteriorated, while if it exceeds 30 wt%, the impact resistance of the molded article using the thermoplastic resin composition may be deteriorated.</p>
<heading id="h0011"><b><u>(C) Polyethylene Terephthalate Resin</u></b></heading><!-- EPO <DP n="11"> -->
<p id="p0050" num="0050">The polyethylene terephthalate resin according to the embodiment may be added together with a phosphate-based heat stabilizer to be described later to mitigate the appearance characteristics and impact resistance deterioration due to the inorganic filler.</p>
<p id="p0051" num="0051">In an embodiment, the polyethylene terephthalate resin may have an intrinsic viscosity of less than or equal to 1.0 dl/g, for example less than or equal to 0.9 dl/g, for example less than or equal to 0.8 dl/g, as measured according to ASTM D2857. When the intrinsic viscosity of the polyethylene terephthalate resin exceeds 1.0 dl/g, the appearance of a thermoplastic resin composition including the same and a molded article using the same may be deteriorated.</p>
<p id="p0052" num="0052">In an embodiment, the polyethylene terephthalate resin may have a weight average molecular weight of 10,000 to 80,000 g/mol, for example, 15,000 to 75,000 g/mol. When the weight average molecular weight of the polyethylene terephthalate resin satisfies the above range, the molded article using the thermoplastic resin composition may exhibit excellent appearance and impact resistance despite the addition of the inorganic filler.</p>
<p id="p0053" num="0053">The polyethylene terephthalate resin may be included in an amount of 1 to 10 wt%, for example 1 to 8 wt%, for example 1 to 6 wt%, based on 100 wt% of the base resin. When the polyethylene terephthalate resin is included in the above ranges, it is possible to alleviate deterioration in appearance characteristics and impact resistance due to an inorganic filler together with a phosphate-based heat stabilizer that will be described later.</p>
<p id="p0054" num="0054">On the other hand, if the polyethylene terephthalate resin is included in an amount of less than 1 wt%, the effect of improving the appearance of the<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> molded article using the thermoplastic resin composition may be insufficient, while if it exceeds 10 wt%, various physical properties such as heat resistance, impact resistance, and appearance characteristics of the molded article using the thermoplastic resin composition may be deteriorated.</p>
<heading id="h0012"><b><u>(D) Methyl methacrylate-Butadiene-Styrene Graft Copolymer</u></b></heading>
<p id="p0055" num="0055">The methyl methacrylate-butadiene-styrene graft copolymer according to an embodiment imparts impact resistance of the thermoplastic resin composition, while contributing to improvement of dimensional stability and appearance characteristics of a molded article using the thermoplastic resin composition.</p>
<p id="p0056" num="0056">In an embodiment, the methyl methacrylate-butadiene-styrene graft copolymer may have a core-shell structure including a shell by graft polymerization of methyl methacrylate and/or styrene to a core made of a butadiene-based rubbery polymer component.</p>
<p id="p0057" num="0057">The methyl methacrylate-butadiene-styrene graft copolymer according to an embodiment may be prepared by adding methyl methacrylate and/or styrene to a butadiene-based rubbery polymer, and performing a graft copolymerization using a conventional polymerization method such as emulsion polymerization and bulk polymerization.</p>
<p id="p0058" num="0058">The butadiene-based rubbery polymer may be selected from a butadiene rubbery polymer, a butadiene-styrene rubbery polymer, a butadiene-acrylonitrile rubbery polymer, a butadiene-acrylate rubbery polymer, and a mixture thereof.</p>
<p id="p0059" num="0059">The methyl methacrylate-butadiene-styrene graft copolymer may be included in an amount of 4 to 12 parts by weight, for example, 4 to 10 parts by weight, based on 100 parts by weight of the base resin.<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></p>
<p id="p0060" num="0060">The butadiene-based rubber polymer core may be included in an amount of 20 to 80 wt% based on 100 wt% of the methyl methacrylate-butadiene-styrene graft copolymer.</p>
<p id="p0061" num="0061">In addition, the methyl methacrylate-butadiene-styrene graft copolymer may desirably have an average particle diameter of the butadiene-based rubbery polymer ranging from 100 to 400 nm, and, for example, 120 to 380 nm.</p>
<p id="p0062" num="0062">If the methyl methacrylate-butadiene-styrene graft copolymer is included in an amount of less than 4 parts by weight, the impact resistance of the molded article using the thermoplastic resin composition may be lowered, while if it exceeds 12 parts by weight, dimensional stability and appearance characteristics of the molded article using the thermoplastic resin composition may be deteriorated.</p>
<heading id="h0013"><b><u>(E) Phosphate-based Heat Stabilizer</u></b></heading>
<p id="p0063" num="0063">The phosphate-based heat stabilizer according to an embodiment prevents a thermal decomposition reaction of the polycarbonate resin from occurring in the preparation process of the thermoplastic resin composition and/or the manufacturing process of the molded article using the thermoplastic resin composition. In addition, when an inorganic filler is added in order to further enhance the dimensional stability of the thermoplastic resin composition, the thermal decomposition of the polycarbonate resin is prevented from accelerating by the metal ions contained in the inorganic filler. The thermal decomposition reaction of the polycarbonate resin is not desirable because various physical properties (impact resistance, dimensional stability, appearance) of the thermoplastic resin composition may be deteriorated. Thus, the<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> phosphate-based thermal stabilizer imparts thermal stability to the thermoplastic resin composition by inhibiting thermal decomposition of the polycarbonate resin.</p>
<p id="p0064" num="0064">In addition, when the phosphate-based heat stabilizer is added together with the aforementioned polyethylene terephthalate resin, both the appearance characteristics and thermal stability of the thermoplastic resin composition may be maintained excellently, despite the addition and/or increase in the amount of the inorganic filler.</p>
<p id="p0065" num="0065">In an embodiment, as the phosphate-based heat stabilizer, dihydrogen phosphate, stearyl phosphate, trimethyl phosphate, triethyl phosphate, triphenyl phosphate, or a combination thereof may be used, and specifically stearyl phosphate may be used.</p>
<p id="p0066" num="0066">The phosphate-based heat stabilizer may be included in a relatively small amount based on 100 parts by weight of the base resin. Specifically, it may be included in an amount of 0.1 to 0.3 parts by weight, for example, 0.1 to 0.2 parts by weight.</p>
<p id="p0067" num="0067">When the phosphate-based heat stabilizer is out of the above range, various physical properties such as impact resistance and appearance characteristics of the thermoplastic resin composition and the molded article using the same may be rather deteriorated, and it may be difficult to balance target physical properties.</p>
<heading id="h0014"><b><u>(F) Inorganic Filler</u></b></heading>
<p id="p0068" num="0068">The inorganic filler according to an embodiment may improve dimensional stability of a molded article using a thermoplastic resin composition. The inorganic filler may be, for example, in the form of particulates or flakes. As a<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> non-limiting example, mica, a quartz powder, titanium dioxide, silicate, or aluminosilicate may be used. In addition, for example, chalk, wollastonite, mica layered clay mineral, montmorillonite, especially montmorillonite in an organophilic form modified by ion exchange, talc, kaolin, zeolite, vermiculite, aluminum oxide, silica, magnesium hydroxide, aluminum hydroxide, glass flakes, or the like. Mixtures of different inorganic fillers may also be used.</p>
<p id="p0069" num="0069">Preferred examples according to an embodiment may be talc, mica, and a combination thereof, and more preferably talc.</p>
<p id="p0070" num="0070">The inorganic filler may have an average particle diameter (D50) measured by a laser particle size analyzer (Malvern Panalytical Ltd., Mastersizer 3000) of, for example, greater than or equal to 1 µm, for example, greater than or equal to 2 µm, for example, greater than or equal to 3 µm, and for example, less than or equal to 5 µm, for example, less than or equal to 4 µm, and for example, 1 to 5 µm, for example, 2 to 4 µm. When the average particle diameter of the inorganic filler is out of the above range, mechanical strength and appearance characteristics of the molded article using the thermoplastic resin composition may be deteriorated.</p>
<p id="p0071" num="0071">The inorganic filler may be included in an amount of, for example, greater than or equal to 25 parts by weight, for example, greater than or equal to 28 parts by weight, and for example, less than or equal to 35 parts by weight, for example, less than or equal to 32 parts by weight, and for example, 25 to 35 parts by weight, for example 28 to 35 parts by weight, for example 28 to 32 parts by weight. When the content of the inorganic filler is out of the above range, the dimensional stability, heat resistance, mechanical strength, and appearance characteristics of<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> the thermoplastic resin composition and the molded article using the same may be deteriorated.</p>
<heading id="h0015"><b><u>(G) Other Additives</u></b></heading>
<p id="p0072" num="0072">In addition to the components (A) to (F), the thermoplastic resin composition according to an embodiment may further include one or more additives required in order to balance physical properties under conditions that maintain excellent heat resistance, impact resistance, dimensional stability, and appearance characteristics, or required according to final uses of the thermoplastic resin composition.</p>
<p id="p0073" num="0073">Specifically, the additives may include a flame retardant, a nucleating agent, a coupling agent, a glass fiber, a plasticizer, a lubricant, an antibacterial agent, a releasing agent, an antioxidant, a ultraviolet stabilizer, an antistatic agent, a pigment, a dye, etc., and these may be used alone or in a combination of two or more.</p>
<p id="p0074" num="0074">These additives may be appropriately included within a range that does not impair the physical properties of the thermoplastic resin composition, and specifically, may be included in an amount of less than or equal to 20 parts by weight based on 100 parts by weight of the base resin, but is not limited thereto.</p>
<p id="p0075" num="0075">The thermoplastic resin composition according to the present invention may be prepared by a known method for preparing a thermoplastic resin composition.</p>
<p id="p0076" num="0076">For example, the thermoplastic resin composition according to the present invention may be prepared in the form of pellets by simultaneously mixing the components of the present invention and other additives and then melt-kneading<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> in an extruder.</p>
<p id="p0077" num="0077">A molded article according to an embodiment of the present invention may be manufactured from the aforementioned thermoplastic resin composition. The thermoplastic resin composition has excellent heat resistance, impact resistance, dimensional stability, and appearance, and may be widely applied to the molding of various products used for painting or non-painting due to excellent moldability. Specifically, it may be usefully used for applications such as automobile interior/exterior materials.</p>
<p id="p0078" num="0078">Hereinafter, preferred examples of the present invention will be described. These examples, however, are not in any sense to be interpreted as limiting the scope of the invention.</p>
<heading id="h0016"><b><u>Examples 1 and 2 and Comparative Examples 1 to 6</u></b></heading>
<p id="p0079" num="0079">The thermoplastic resin compositions of Examples 1 and 2 and Comparative Examples 1 to 6 were prepared according to the component content ratios shown in Table 1.</p>
<p id="p0080" num="0080">In Table 1, (A), (B), and (C) which are included in the base resin are expressed in weight percent (wt%) based on the total weight of the base resin, and (D), (D'), (E), and (F) which are added to the base resin are expressed in parts by weight based on 100 parts by weight of the base resin.</p>
<p id="p0081" num="0081">The components shown in Table 1 were dry-mixed, and quantitatively and continuously put into the feeding section of a twin-screw extruder (L/D=29, Φ=45 mm), and melted/kneaded. At this time, the barrel temperature of the twin screw extruder was set to 250 °C. Subsequently, after drying the pelletized thermoplastic resin compositions at about 100 °C for about 2 hours through a twin<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> screw extruder, specimens for measuring physical properties, 50 mm (horizontal) × 200 mm (vertical) specimens for verifying the appearance having 3 mm thickness, and 10 mm (horizontal) × 15 mm (vertical) specimens for verifying the dimensional stability having 3 mm thickness were injection-molded, respectively, using a 6 oz injection molding machine set to a cylinder temperature of about 290 °C and a mold temperature of about 60 °C.
<tables id="tabl0001" num="0001">
<table frame="all">
<title>[Table 1]</title>
<tgroup cols="10">
<colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="19mm"/>
<colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="8mm"/>
<colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="10mm"/>
<colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="10mm"/>
<colspec colnum="5" colname="col5" colwidth="20mm"/>
<colspec colnum="6" colname="col6" colwidth="20mm"/>
<colspec colnum="7" colname="col7" colwidth="20mm"/>
<colspec colnum="8" colname="col8" colwidth="20mm"/>
<colspec colnum="9" colname="col9" colwidth="20mm"/>
<colspec colnum="10" colname="col10" colwidth="20mm"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="col1" nameend="col2" align="center" valign="top"/>
<entry align="center" valign="top">Ex. 1</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top">Ex. 2</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top">Comp. Ex. 1</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top">Comp. Ex. 2</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top">Comp. Ex. 3</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top">Comp. Ex. 4</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top">Comp. Ex. 5</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top">Comp. Ex. 6</entry></row></thead>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry morerows="2" align="center">Ba se re sin</entry>
<entry align="center">(A)</entry>
<entry align="center">70</entry>
<entry align="center">70</entry>
<entry align="center">70</entry>
<entry align="center">70</entry>
<entry align="center">70</entry>
<entry align="center">70</entry>
<entry align="center">60</entry>
<entry align="center">70</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center">(B)</entry>
<entry align="center">28</entry>
<entry align="center">26</entry>
<entry align="center">26</entry>
<entry align="center">26</entry>
<entry align="center">30</entry>
<entry align="center">30</entry>
<entry align="center">28</entry>
<entry align="center">28</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center">(C)</entry>
<entry align="center">2</entry>
<entry align="center">4</entry>
<entry align="center">4</entry>
<entry align="center">4</entry>
<entry align="center">-</entry>
<entry align="center">-</entry>
<entry align="center">12</entry>
<entry align="center">2</entry></row>
<row>
<entry namest="col1" nameend="col2" align="center">(D)</entry>
<entry align="center">8</entry>
<entry align="center">8</entry>
<entry align="center">8</entry>
<entry align="center">-</entry>
<entry align="center">8</entry>
<entry align="center">8</entry>
<entry align="center">8</entry>
<entry align="center">8</entry></row>
<row>
<entry namest="col1" nameend="col2" align="center">(D')</entry>
<entry align="center">-</entry>
<entry align="center">-</entry>
<entry align="center">-</entry>
<entry align="center">8</entry>
<entry align="center">-</entry>
<entry align="center">-</entry>
<entry align="center">-</entry>
<entry align="center">-</entry></row>
<row>
<entry namest="col1" nameend="col2" align="center">(E)</entry>
<entry align="center">0.1</entry>
<entry align="center">0.1</entry>
<entry align="center">-</entry>
<entry align="center">0.1</entry>
<entry align="center">0.1</entry>
<entry align="center">0.1</entry>
<entry align="center">0.1</entry>
<entry align="center">6</entry></row>
<row>
<entry namest="col1" nameend="col2" align="center">(F)</entry>
<entry align="center">30</entry>
<entry align="center">30</entry>
<entry align="center">30</entry>
<entry align="center">30</entry>
<entry align="center">30</entry>
<entry align="center">20</entry>
<entry align="center">30</entry>
<entry align="center">30</entry></row></tbody></tgroup>
</table>
</tables></p>
<p id="p0082" num="0082">Descriptions of each component in Table 1 are as follows.</p>
<heading id="h0017"><u>(A) Polycarbonate Resin</u></heading>
<p id="p0083" num="0083">Polycarbonate resin having a melt flow index of about 18 g/10min measured under the condition of 300 °C and 1.2 kg load according to ASTM D1238 standard (Lotte Advanced Materials Co., Ltd.)</p>
<heading id="h0018"><u>(B) Aromatic Vinyl-Vinyl Cyanide Copolymer</u></heading><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> -->
<p id="p0084" num="0084">Styrene-acrylonitrile copolymer (Lotte Advanced Materials Co., Ltd.) having a weight average molecular weight of about 100,000 g/mol copolymerized from a monomer mixture including about 28 wt% of acrylonitrile and about 72 wt% of styrene</p>
<heading id="h0019"><u>(C) Polyethylene Terephthalate Resin</u></heading>
<p id="p0085" num="0085">Polyethylene terephthalate resin (BCN76, Lotte Chemical Corp.) having an intrinsic viscosity of about 0.8 dl/g measured according to ASTM D2857</p>
<heading id="h0020"><u>(D) Methyl Methacrylate-Butadiene-Styrene Graft Copolymer</u></heading>
<p id="p0086" num="0086">Methyl methacrylate-butadiene-styrene graft copolymer (C223-A, MRC) having a core-shell structure obtained by graft polymerization of methyl methacrylate on a butadiene-styrene rubber polymer core</p>
<heading id="h0021"><u>(D') Acrylonitrile-Butadiene-Styrene Graft Copolymer</u></heading>
<p id="p0087" num="0087">Acrylonitrile-butadiene-styrene graft copolymer (Lotte Advanced Materials Co., Ltd.) having a core-shell structure including about 45 wt% of a butadiene rubbery polymer core having an average particle diameter of about 300 nm, and the shell is styrene-acrylonitrile copolymer in which styrene and acrylonitrile are grafted in a weight ratio of about 7:3.</p>
<heading id="h0022"><u>(E) Phosphate-based Heat Stabilizer</u></heading>
<p id="p0088" num="0088">Stearyl Phosphate (Adeka Corp.)</p>
<heading id="h0023"><u>(F) Inorganic Filler</u></heading>
<p id="p0089" num="0089">Talc (Imerys S.A.) having an average particle diameter (D50) of about 3.9 µm measured by a laser particle size analyzer (Malvern Panalytical Ltd., Mastersizer 3000)</p>
<heading id="h0024"><b><u>Experimental Examples</u></b></heading><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> -->
<p id="p0090" num="0090">The experimental results are shown in Table 2.
<ol id="ol0001" compact="compact" ol-style="">
<li>(1) Impact resistance (kgf·cm/cm): A notched Izod impact strength was measured at room temperature (23° C) according to ASTM D256 for a 1/8"-thick specimen.</li>
<li>(2) Dimensional stability (µm/m·°C): After removing the stress from the specimen for dimensional stability verification in a range of -50 °C to 130 °C using a thermomechanical analysis device (TA Instruments, Q400) in a direction of the resin flow, a coefficient of linear expansion was measured in a temperature range of 40 °C to 40 °C. As the coefficient of linear expansion is lower, the dimensional stability is better.</li>
<li>(3) Initial appearance: For specimens for verifying an appearance, it was evaluated by an area of gas generated in a standard area (50 mm width × 50 mm height) centered on an injection gate located in the center of upper end of the specimen as in images shown in <figref idref="f0001 f0002">FIGS 1 to 3</figref>. It was specifically classified as follows: Grade 1 when no gas was generated in a standard area, Grade 2 when gas was generated in less than or equal to 1/4 of the standard area, and Grade 3 when gas was generated in greater than 1/4 of the standard area.
<br/>
<figref idref="f0001 f0002">FIGS. 1 to 3</figref> are images for showing the criteria for evaluating initial of molded article specimens using the thermoplastic resin composition according to an embodiment, respectively, Grade 1 (<figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>), Grade 2 (<figref idref="f0001">FIG. 2</figref>), and Grade 3 (<figref idref="f0002">FIG. 3</figref>).
</li>
<li>(4) Thermal stability appearance: For the specimens for appearance<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> verification obtained by injection-molding after the resin composition pellets were kept in the cylinder of the injection molding machine set at the cylinder temperature of 290 °C for 4 minutes, it was evaluated as the area of the gas generated in the standard area (50 mm width × 50 mm height) centered on an injection gate in the center of upper end of the specimen as shown in the images shown in <figref idref="f0002 f0003">FIGS. 4 to 6</figref>. It was specifically classified as follows: Grade 1 when no gas was generated in a standard area, Grade 2 when gas was generated in less than or equal to 1/2 of the standard area, and Grade 3 when gas was generated in greater than 1/2 of the standard area.
<br/>
<figref idref="f0002 f0003">FIGS. 4 to 6</figref> are images for showing the criteria for evaluating the thermal stability appearance of molded article specimens using a thermoplastic resin composition according to an embodiment, respectively, Grade 1 (<figref idref="f0002">FIG. 4</figref>), Grade 2 (<figref idref="f0003">FIG. 5</figref>), and Grade 3 (<figref idref="f0003">FIG. 6</figref>).
</li>
<li>(5) Heat resistance (°C): The heat deflection temperature (HDT) was measured under 18.5 kg load condition according to ASTM D648.</li>
</ol>
<tables id="tabl0002" num="0002">
<table frame="all">
<title>[Table 2]</title>
<tgroup cols="9">
<colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="24mm"/>
<colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="13mm"/>
<colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="13mm"/>
<colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="20mm"/>
<colspec colnum="5" colname="col5" colwidth="20mm"/>
<colspec colnum="6" colname="col6" colwidth="20mm"/>
<colspec colnum="7" colname="col7" colwidth="20mm"/>
<colspec colnum="8" colname="col8" colwidth="20mm"/>
<colspec colnum="9" colname="col9" colwidth="20mm"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry align="center" valign="middle"/>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Ex. 1</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Ex. 2</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Comp. Ex. 1</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Comp. Ex. 2</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Comp. Ex. 3</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Comp. Ex. 4</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Comp. Ex. 5</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Comp. Ex. 6</entry></row></thead>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Impact strength</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">6</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">6</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">5</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">6</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">6</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">10</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">4</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">4</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Coefficient of linear expansion</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">40</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">40</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">40</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">40</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">40</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">45</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">40</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">40</entry></row><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> -->
<row>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Initial appearance</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">1</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">1</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">3</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">2</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">2</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">1</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">1</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">3</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Thermal stability appearance</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">2</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">1</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">3</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">3</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">3</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">2</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">1</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">3</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Heat deflection temperature</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">118</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">117</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">118</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">118</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">118</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">118</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">108</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">113</entry></row></tbody></tgroup>
</table>
</tables></p>
<p id="p0091" num="0091">From Tables 1 and 2, the thermoplastic resin compositions and the molded articles using the same exhibited excellent impact resistance, heat resistance, dimensional stability, and appearance characteristics by using the polycarbonate resin, aromatic vinyl-vinyl cyanide copolymer, polyethylene terephthalate resin, methyl methacrylate-styrene-acrylonitrile graft copolymer, phosphate-based heat stabilizer, and inorganic filler in the optimal contents.<br/>
As described above, the present invention has been described through preferred embodiments, but a person having ordinary skill would understand easily that the present invention is not limited thereto, and various modifications and variations may be possible without departing from the concept and scope of the following claims.</p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> -->
<claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>A thermoplastic resin composition, comprising<br/>
100 parts by weight of a base resin which comprises
<claim-text>(A) 65 to 75 wt% of a polycarbonate resin;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(B) 20 to 30 wt% of an aromatic vinyl-vinyl cyanide copolymer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(C) 1 to 10 wt% of a polyethylene terephthalate resin, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(D) 4 to 12 parts by weight of a methyl methacrylate-butadiene-styrene graft copolymer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(E) 0.1 to 0.3 parts by weight of a phosphate-based heat stabilizer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(F) 25 to 35 parts by weight of an inorganic filler having an average particle diameter (D50) of 1 to 5 µm based on 100 parts by weight of the base resin.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>The thermoplastic resin composition of claim 1, wherein the (A) polycarbonate resin has a melt flow index of 15 to 25 g/10min measured under the condition of 300 °C and 1.2 kg load according to ASTM D1238.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>The thermoplastic resin composition of claim 1 or claim 2, wherein the (B) aromatic vinyl-vinyl cyanide copolymer is a copolymer of a monomer mixture<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> including 60 to 80 wt% of an aromatic vinyl compound and 20 to 40 wt% of a vinyl cyanide compound.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>The thermoplastic resin composition of any one of claim 1 to claim 3, wherein the (B) aromatic vinyl-vinyl cyanide copolymer has a weight average molecular weight of 80,000 to 200,000 g/mol.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>The thermoplastic resin composition of any one of claim 1 to claim 4, wherein the (B) aromatic vinyl-vinyl cyanide copolymer is a styrene-acrylonitrile copolymer.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>The thermoplastic resin composition of any one of claim 1 to claim 5, wherein the (C) polyethylene terephthalate resin has an intrinsic viscosity measured according to ASTM D2857 of less than or equal to 1.0 dl/g.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>The thermoplastic resin composition of any one of claim 1 to claim 6, wherein the (D) methyl methacrylate-butadiene-styrene graft copolymer comprises a core composed of a butadiene-based rubbery polymer, and a shell<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> formed by graft polymerization of methyl methacrylate and/or styrene on the core.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>The thermoplastic resin composition of claim 7, wherein the (D) butadiene-based rubbery polymer of the (D) methyl methacrylate-butadiene-styrene graft copolymer has an average particle diameter of 100 to 400 nm.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>The thermoplastic resin composition of any one of claim 1 to claim 8, wherein the (E) phosphate-based heat stabilizer comprises dihydrogen phosphate, stearyl phosphate, trimethyl phosphate, triethyl phosphate, triphenyl phosphate, or a combination thereof.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>The thermoplastic resin composition of any one of claim 1 to claim 9, wherein the (F) inorganic filler comprises montmorillonite, talc, kaolin, zeolite, vermiculite, aluminum oxide, silica, magnesium hydroxide, aluminum hydroxide, glass flakes, or a combination thereof.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>The thermoplastic resin composition of any one of claim 1 to claim 10, which further comprises at least one additive selected from a flame retardant, a<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> nucleating agent, a coupling agent, a glass fiber, a plasticizer, a lubricant, an antibacterial agent, a release agent, an antioxidant, an ultraviolet stabilizer, an antistatic agent, a pigment, and a dye.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>A molded article using the thermoplastic resin composition of any one of claim 1 to claim 11.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1,2"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="100" he="202" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="28"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="3,4"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="103" he="218" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="29"> -->
<figure id="f0003" num="5,6"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="99" he="214" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<search-report-data id="srep" lang="en" srep-office="EP" date-produced=""><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="152" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="152" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0003" file="srep0003.tif" wi="152" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data>
</ep-patent-document>
