<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP18177480B1" file="EP18177480NWB1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3398577" kind="B1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSK..HRIS..MTNO....SM..................</B001EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  2100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3398577</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT SPECIFICATION</B121></B120><B130>B1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>18177480.3</B210><B220><date>20100830</date></B220><B240><B241><date>20190507</date></B241><B242><date>20191015</date></B242></B240><B250>en</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B300><B310>238655 P</B310><B320><date>20090831</date></B320><B330><ctry>US</ctry></B330></B300><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20181107</date><bnum>201845</bnum></B430><B450><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B450><B452EP><date>20210517</date></B452EP></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>A61G   7/057       20060101AFI20180830BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="2"><text>A47C  21/04        20060101ALI20180830BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>A61G2203/46        20130101 LA20140715BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>A47C  21/044       20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="3"><text>A61G   7/05769     20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>KLIMAKONTROLLIERTES AUFLAGEELEMENT FÜR MEDIZINISCHE BETTEN</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>CLIMATE-CONTROLLED TOPPER MEMBER FOR MEDICAL BEDS</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>ÉLÉMENT DE CHAPEAU CLIMATISÉ POUR LITS MÉDICAUX</B542></B540><B560><B561><text>EP-A2- 0 878 150</text></B561><B561><text>US-A- 3 653 083</text></B561><B561><text>US-A- 3 778 851</text></B561><B561><text>US-A- 5 350 417</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2005 086 739</text></B561></B560></B500><B600><B620><parent><pdoc><dnum><anum>16171639.4</anum><pnum>3111904</pnum></dnum><date>20160527</date></pdoc><pdoc><dnum><anum>10812717.6</anum><pnum>2473147</pnum></dnum><date>20100830</date></pdoc></parent></B620></B600><B700><B720><B721><snm>Marquette, David</snm><adr><str>32552 Oakwood Court</str><city>Farmington Hills, MI 48334</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>Brykalski, Michael J</snm><adr><str>23343 Spy Glass Hill North</str><city>South Lyon, MI 48178</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>Terech, John</snm><adr><str>10261 Ridgeline Drive</str><city>Milan, MI 48160</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>Vidojevski, Robert</snm><adr><str>25176 Brookview Boulevard</str><city>Brownstown, MI 48134</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B730><B731><snm>Sleep Number Corporation</snm><iid>101713806</iid><irf>39870-0226EP3</irf><adr><str>1001 Third Avenue South</str><city>Minneapolis, Minnesota 55404</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B731></B730><B740><B741><snm>Fish &amp; Richardson P.C.</snm><iid>101869757</iid><adr><str>Highlight Business Towers 
Mies-van-der-Rohe-Straße 8</str><city>80807 München</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840></B800></SDOBI>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<p id="p0001" num="0001">This application claims the priority benefit under 35 U.S.C. §119(e) of <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US61238655" dnum-type="L"><text>U.S. Provisional Patent Application No. 61/238,655, filed August 31, 2009</text></patcit>.</p>
<heading id="h0001"><u>Background</u></heading>
<heading id="h0002"><u>Field</u></heading>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">This application relates to climate control, and more specifically, to climate control of medical beds, hospital beds, other types of beds and similar devices.</p>
<heading id="h0003"><u>Description of the Related Art</u></heading>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">Pressure ulcers, which are also commonly referred as decubitus ulcers or bed sores, are lesions that form on the body as a result of prolonged contact with a bed or other surface. Bed sores typically result from exposure to one or more factors, such as, for example, unrelieved pressure, friction or other shearing forces, humidity (e.g., moisture caused by perspiration, incontinence, exudate, etc.), elevated temperatures, age and/or the like. Although such ulcers may occur to any part of the body, they normally affect bony and cartilaginous areas (e.g., the sacrum, elbows, knees, ankles, etc.).</p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">One known method of preventing decubitus ulcers for patients who are confined to beds or other seating assemblies for prolonged time periods includes pressure redistribution or pressure reduction. Pressure redistribution generally involves spreading the forces created by an occupant's presence on a bed over a larger area of the occupant-bed interface. Thus, in order to accomplish pressure redistribution, a bed or other support structure can be designed with certain immersion and envelopment characteristics. For example, a desired depth of penetration (e.g., sinking level) can be provided along the upper surface of the bed when an occupant is situated thereon. Relatedly, an upper portion of a bed can be adapted to generally conform to the various irregularities of the occupant's body.</p>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">In order to help prevent the occurrence of decubitus ulcers, one or more other factors may also be targeted, either in addition to or in lieu of pressure redistribution. For example, lower shear materials can be used at the occupant-bed interface. Further,<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> temperature and moisture levels along certain areas of an occupant's body can be reduced. In addition, the control of certain factors, such as high pressure, temperature, friction, moisture and/or the like, may improve the general comfort level of an occupant, even where decubitus ulcers are not a concern. Accordingly, a need exists to provide a conditioner mat or topper member for a bed (e.g., hospital or other medical bed) or other seating assembly that provides certain climate-control features to help prevent bed sores and/or help enhance comfort.</p>
<p id="p0006" num="0006"><patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="EP878150A2"><text>EP 878150 A2</text></patcit> discloses an inflatable support comprising a plurality of elongate inflatable cells containing a solid deformable material. <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="US20050086739A1"><text>US 2005/0086739 A1</text></patcit> describes a ventilation mattress that is constructed to include an outer bag, the outer bag having air vents in a top fabric sheet layer thereof and an air inlet.</p>
<heading id="h0004"><u>Summary</u></heading>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">The invention is defined in the claims.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p>
<heading id="h0005"><u>Brief Description of the Drawings</u></heading>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">These and other features, aspects and advantages of the present inventions are described with reference to drawings of certain preferred embodiments, which are intended to illustrate, but not to limit, the present inventions. It is to be understood that the attached drawings are provided for the purpose of illustrating concepts of the present inventions and may not be to scale.
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li><figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates an exploded perspective view of one embodiment of a conditioner mat or topper member configured for placement on a bed assembly;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates a perspective view of a conditioner mat or topper member according to one embodiment;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref> illustrates a partial cross-sectional view of a conditioner mat or topper member according to one embodiment, which does not form part of the invention;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3B</figref> illustrates another partial cross-sectional view of a conditioner mat or topper member according to one embodiment, which does not form part of the invention;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3C</figref> illustrates yet another partial cross-sectional view of a conditioner mat or topper member according to one embodiment, which does not form part of the invention;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0004">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref> schematically illustrate plan views of a conditioner mat or topper member according to one embodiment, which does not form part of the invention;<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></li>
<li><figref idref="f0005">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates a partial bottom view of one embodiment which doesn't form part of the invention, of a conditioner mat or topper member secured to a mattress, pad or other support member of a bed assembly;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0005">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates a perspective view of a conditioner mat or topper member secured to a bed mattress or other support structure according to another embodiment, which doesn't form part of the invention;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0006">FIG. 8</figref> illustrates a perspective view of a conditioner mat or topper member according to one embodiment; embodiment, which doesn't form part of the invention;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0006">FIG. 9</figref> illustrates a perspective view of a conditioner mat or topper member according to another embodiment;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0007">FIG. 10A</figref> illustrates a perspective view of a conditioner mat or topper member according to one embodiment;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0008">FIG. 10B</figref> illustrates a partial perspective view of the conditioner mat or topper member of <figref idref="f0007">FIG. 10A</figref>;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0009">FIG. 11A</figref> illustrates a perspective view of a conditioner mat or topper member according to one embodiment, which doesn't form part of the invention;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0010">FIG. 11B</figref> illustrates a partial perspective view of the conditioner mat or topper member of <figref idref="f0009">FIG. 11A</figref>;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0011">FIG. 12A</figref> illustrates a perspective view of a conditioner mat or topper member according to one embodiment, which doesn't form part of the invention;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0012">FIG. 12B</figref> illustrates a partial perspective view of the conditioner mat or topper member of <figref idref="f0011">FIG. 12A</figref>;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0013">FIG. 13A</figref> illustrates a perspective view of a conditioner mat or topper member according to one embodiment, which doesn't form part of the invention;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0014">FIG. 13B</figref> illustrates a partial perspective view of the conditioner mat or topper member of <figref idref="f0013">FIG. 13A</figref>;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0015">FIG. 14</figref> illustrates a perspective view of a conditioner mat or topper member according to another embodiment;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0016">FIG. 15</figref> schematically illustrates possible positions for a fluid module relative to a conditioner mat or topper according to one embodiment, which doesn't form part of the invention;<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></li>
<li><figref idref="f0017">FIG. 16A</figref> illustrates a top view of a conditioner mat or topper member according to another embodiment;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0018">FIG. 16B</figref> illustrates a perspective view of one embodiment which doesn't form part of the invention, of a conditioner mat or topper member positioned on a mattress or other support structure of a bed;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0019">FIG. 16C</figref> illustrates a perspective view of another embodiment of a conditioner mat or topper member positioned on a mattress or other support structure of a bed;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0020">FIG. 16D</figref> illustrates a perspective view of yet another embodiment of a conditioner mat or topper member positioned on a mattress or other support structure of a bed;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0021">FIG. 17A</figref> illustrates a perspective view of one embodiment which doesn't form part of the invention, of a conditioner mat or topper member positioned on a medical bed;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0021">FIG. 17B</figref> illustrates a partial cross-sectional view of the conditioner mat and medical bed of <figref idref="f0021">FIG. 17A</figref>;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0022">FIGS. 17C and 17D</figref> illustrate perspective views of another embodiment which doesn't form part of the invention, of a conditioner mat or topper member positioned on a medical bed;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0023">FIGS. 18A</figref> and <figref idref="f0024">18B</figref> illustrate different perspective views of a conditioner mat or topper member according to one embodiment, which doesn't form part of the invention;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0025">FIG. 18C</figref> illustrates a cross-sectional view of the conditioner mat of <figref idref="f0023">FIGS. 18A</figref> and <figref idref="f0024">18B</figref>;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0026">FIG. 18D</figref> illustrates another perspective view of the conditioner mat of <figref idref="f0023 f0024 f0025">FIGS. 18A-18C</figref>;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0027">FIG. 18E</figref> illustrates another cross-sectional view of the conditioner mat of <figref idref="f0023 f0024 f0025 f0026">FIGS. 18A-18D</figref>;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0028">FIG. 19A</figref> illustrates a perspective view of a fluid box according to one embodiment;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0029">FIGS. 19B</figref> and <figref idref="f0030">20</figref> illustrate front views of an interior of the fluid box of <figref idref="f0028">FIG. 19A</figref>;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0030">FIG. 21</figref> illustrates various embodiments of outlet fittings, which don't form part of the invention;<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></li>
<li><figref idref="f0031">FIG. 22</figref> illustrates a perspective view of a fluid box according to another embodiment, which doesn't form part of the invention;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0032">FIG. 23A</figref> illustrates a front view of the fluid box of <figref idref="f0031">FIG. 22</figref>;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0032">FIG. 23B</figref> illustrates a front view of the interior of the box of <figref idref="f0031">FIGS. 22</figref> and <figref idref="f0032">23A</figref>;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0033">FIG. 24</figref> schematically illustrates fluid diagram within a fluid box comprising two fluid modules, in accordance with one embodiment, which doesn't form part of the invention;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0034">FIG. 25</figref> illustrates a plan view of an insulated conduit in fluid communication with a conditioner mat or topper member according to one embodiment, which doesn't form part of the invention;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0035">FIG. 26</figref> illustrates a plan view of a conduit system in fluid communication with a conditioner mat or topper member according to another embodiment, which doesn't form part of the invention;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0036">FIG. 27</figref> illustrates a plan view of the interface of a fluid inlet and a conditioner mat or topper member according to one embodiment, which doesn't form part of the invention; and</li>
<li><figref idref="f0037">FIGS. 28A-28C</figref> illustrates flow diagrams representing various methods of balancing airflow into the various fluid zones of a conditioner mat or topper member, in accordance with one embodiment, which doesn't form part of the invention.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0038">FIGS. 29A and 29B</figref> illustrate different perspective views of a conditioner mat or topper member according to another embodiment, which doesn't form part of the invention;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0039">FIG. 30</figref> illustrates a perspective view of a spacer material or other fluid distribution member configured for use within a conditioner mat or topper member according to one embodiment, which doesn't form part of the invention;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0040">FIG. 31</figref> illustrates a perspective view of a fluid nozzle or other inlet of a conditioner mat or topper member according to one embodiment, which doesn't form part of the invention;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0040">FIG. 32</figref> illustrates a perspective view of a fluid nozzle or other inlet of a conditioner mat or topper member according to another embodiment, which doesn't form part of the invention;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0040">FIG. 33</figref> illustrates a cross-sectional view of the fluid nozzle of <figref idref="f0040">FIG. 32</figref>; and</li>
<li><figref idref="f0041">FIG. 34</figref> schematically illustrates one embodiment which doesn't form part of the invention, of a control scheme for the operation of a climate controlled topper member.</li>
</ul><!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p>
<heading id="h0006"><u>Detailed Description of the Preferred Embodiments</u></heading>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">This application is generally directed to climate control systems for beds or other seating assemblies. More specifically, in certain arrangements, the present application discloses climate controlled fluid conditioner members or topper members that are configured to be selectively positioned on top of hospital beds, medical beds, other types of beds and/or other seating assemblies (e.g., chairs, wheelchairs, other seats, etc.). Thus, the topper members or conditioner mats and the various systems and features associated with them are described herein in the context of a bed assembly (e.g., medical bed) because they have particular utility in this context. However, the devices, systems and methods described herein, can be used in other contexts as well, such as, for example, but without limitation, seat assemblies for automobiles, trains, planes, motorcycles, buses, other types of vehicles, wheelchairs, other types of medical chairs, beds and seating assemblies, sofas, task chairs, office chairs, other types of chairs and/or the like.</p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">One embodiment of a conditioner mat 20 or topper member adapted to be attached to or otherwise positioned on top of a medical bed 8 is illustrated in <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>. As shown, the mat 20 can be positioned on a mattress, pad, cushion or other support member 10 of a bed 8. According to certain embodiments, the mattress 10 or other support member comprises foam, viscoelastic, air chambers, gel, springs and/or any other resilient materials to give it a desired or required feel. For example, the firmness, pliability and other physical characteristics of the mattress or other support member can be selected so as to enhance pressure redistribution when an occupant is positioned thereon. As discussed in greater detail herein, this can assist in preventing decubitus ulcers for bed occupants.</p>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">As discussed in greater detail herein, the conditioner mat 20 can be releasably secured to a mattress 10 or other portion of a bed using one or more attachment methods or devices. For example, as illustrated in <figref idref="f0005">FIG. 6</figref>, the mat 20 can comprise a peripheral skirt that is configured to fit around a portion of the mattress (e.g., like a fitted sheet, other encapsulating member, etc.). The skirt can include one or more elasticized portions or members to facilitate its securement to and/or removal from the mattress. Such a design can also provide a more secure connection between the mat 20 and the mattress, pad, cushion or other support member 10. In other arrangements, the position of the separate<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> topper member 20 is maintained relative to the mattress 10 using one or more straps (<figref idref="f0005">FIG. 7</figref>), zippers, hook-and-loop type fasteners, buttons, snap connections, friction surfaces and/or the like, as desired or required. In one embodiment, the straps 21' are elastic or otherwise expandable. Alternatively, the topper or mat 20 can be permanently attached to a support member 10 (e.g., mattress, pad, cushion, etc.) or other portion of a bed 8.</p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">With continued reference to <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, one or more portions of the conditioner mat 20 can be selectively supplied with ambient and/or thermally-conditioned (e.g., heated, cooled, etc.) air or other fluid. According to certain arrangements, such fluids are generated by one or more fluid modules located within a separate fluid box 60. A fluid module can include a blower, fan or other fluid transfer device. In certain embodiments, the fluid module can additionally include a thermoelectric device (e.g., Peltier circuit), a convective heater, other types of heating or cooling devices, dehumidifier and/or any other environmentally conditioning device. A fluid module can also include one or more of the following, as desired or required: fluid transfer members (e.g., fins), a sensor (e.g., temperature, humidity, condensation, etc.), a controller and the like.</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">As illustrated in <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, fluid exiting a fluid module, which in some embodiments is housed within a fluid box 60 or other enclosure, can be advantageously routed to the mat or topper member 20 using one or more ducts or other fluid conduits 72, 74. The ducts can include one or more flexible, semi-rigid and/or rigid materials, such as, for example, plastic, rubber and the like. In some embodiments, such ducts or conduits are at least partially insulated to prevent or reduce the likelihood of thermal losses between the fluid module and the topper member 20. As discussed in greater detail herein, a fluid module that supplies air or other fluid to a conditioner mat 20 need not be positioned within a separate box 60. For instance, a fluid module can be incorporated within, adjacent to or near a main portion of the topper member. Alternatively, a fluid module can be configured to hang off one or more edges of the topper member and/or the like. Additional disclosure regarding fluid modules is provided in <patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="US04707705" dnum-type="L"><text>U.S. Patent Application No. 11/047,077, filed January 31, 2005</text></patcit> and issued on <patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="US758790A" dnum-type="L"><text>September 15, 2009 as U.S. Patent Application No. 7,587,90</text></patcit>.<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">Regardless of the exact configuration of the topper member and fluid modules that are in fluid communication with it, the topper member 20 can include one or more fluid zones 34, 36, 44, 46 into which thermally-conditioned or ambient air can be selectively delivered. For example, the conditioner mat 20 illustrated in <figref idref="f0001">FIGS. 1</figref> and <figref idref="f0002">2</figref> comprises a total of four climate control zones 34, 36, 44, 46. The mat 20 can be designed so that two or more zones are in fluid communication with one another. Consequently, air or other fluid having a first type of ventilation or thermal conditioning properties can be provided to certain portions of the mat 20, while air or fluid having a second type of ventilation or thermal conditioning properties can be provided to other portions of the mat, as desired or required. For example, one set of fluid zones 34, 36 can be supplied with relatively cool air, while another set of fluid zones 44, 46 can be supplied with relative warm air, or vice versa.</p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">In other arrangements, a mat or topper member 20 can include additional or fewer fluid zones, as desired or required. For instance, the mat 20 can include only a single conditioning zone (e.g., extending, at least partially, across some or most of the mat's surface area) such as the arrangement illustrated in <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 8</figref>. In certain embodiments which do not form part of the invention, two or more zones of the topper member or mat 20 are fluidly isolated from each other. Thus, air or other fluid entering one zone (or one set of zones) can be kept substantially separate and distinct from air or fluid entering another zone (or another set of zones). This can help ensure that fluid streams having varying properties and other characteristics (e.g., type or composition of fluid, temperature, relative humidity level, flowrate, etc.) can be delivered to targeted portions of a conditioner mat 20 in a desired manner.</p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">According to certain embodiments, as discussed in greater detail herein, air or other fluid delivered into a zone 34, 36, 44, 46 exits through one or more openings 24 (e.g., holes, apertures, slits, etc.) located along an upper layer or other upper surface of the mat 20. Thus, ambient and/or environmentally-conditioned (e.g., cooled, heated, dehumidified, etc.) air can be advantageously directed to targeted portions of an occupant's body. For example, in the topper member 20 illustrated in <figref idref="f0001">FIGS. 1</figref> and <figref idref="f0002">2</figref>, the zones 34, 36, 44, 46 are arranged in a manner to generally target an occupant's head (zone 34), shoulders (zone 44), ischial region (zone 36) and heels (zone 46). However, a conditioner mat 20 in<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> accordance with any of the embodiments disclosed herein can be modified to include more or fewer zones to target these and/or other body portions of an occupant.</p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">In certain embodiments, the fluid zones 34, 36, 44, 46 of a conditioner mat or topper member 20 are strategically positioned to target portions of the anatomy that are susceptible to decubitus ulcers, other ailments, general discomfort and/or other problems resulting from prolonged contact with a bed surface. As noted above, reducing the temperature and/or moisture levels in such susceptible anatomical regions can help prevent (or reduce the likelihood of) bed sores and help improve the comfort level of an occupant. For example, with respect to the hospital or medical bed 8 illustrated in <figref idref="f0001">FIGS. 1</figref> and <figref idref="f0002">2</figref>, the fluid zones 34, 36, 44, 46 can be arranged so that ambient and/or conditioned (e.g., heated, cooled, dehumidified, etc.) air or other fluids are selectively delivered through the topper member 20 toward an occupant's back of the head, shoulders, upper back, elbows, lower back, hips, heels and/or any other target anatomical region.</p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">With continued reference to <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>, air or other fluid can be directed from the fluid module(s) (e.g., stand-alone unit(s), unit(s) located within a fluid box 60, etc.) to the conditioner mat 20 through one or more ducts 72, 74. The ducts 72, 74 can include standard or non-standard conduits. For instance, a duct can include flexible 2,54 cm (1-inch) diameter rubber tubing having a generally circular cross-section. However, the materials of constructions, cross-sectional size or shape, flexibility or rigidity and other details regarding the ducts 72, 74 or other fluid conduits can vary, as desired or required.</p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">In addition, according to certain arrangements, fluid is supplied to the conditioner mat 20 from both the left and right sides of the bed 8. However, the number, location and other details regarding the fluid inlets into the mat 20 can vary, as desired or required. In <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>, the fluid box 60 is secured to or near the headboard of the bed assembly 8. However, as discussed in greater detail herein, the fluid box 60 can be positioned at any other location relative to the bed, such as, for example, along the footboard, one of the sides and/or the like. Positioning the fluid modules away from the occupant head, regardless of whether or not the fluid modules are included within a fluid box 60, can reduce the noise levels perceived by the occupant. Additional details regarding the fluid modules and the ducts are provided herein.<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">According to certain arrangements, one or more fittings 76, 78 are situated at the interface of the topper member 20 and a fluid conduit 72, 74. As discussed in greater detail herein, such fittings 76, 78 can advantageously facilitate the connection of the conduits 72, 74 to (and/or disconnection from) the mat or topper member 20. This can be beneficial whenever there is a need or desire to remove the mat 20 from the adjacent mattress, pad, cushion or other support member 10 for cleaning, servicing, replacement and/or any other purpose. The fittings 76, 78 can also help reduce the likelihood that fluids inadvertently leak prior to their delivery into an interior space (e.g., passages 32, 42, zones 34, 36, 44, 46, etc.) of the mat 20.</p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">As illustrated in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref>, the mat 20 can include an upper layer 22 and a lower layer 26 that together generally define a space S therebetween. According to certain arrangements, the upper and lower layers 22, 26 comprise one or more fluid impermeable or substantially fluid impermeable materials and/or conductive materials, such as, for example, vinyl, other plastics, fabric and/or the like. In order to allow air or other fluids to exit the interior space S (e.g., in the direction of a bed occupant), the upper layer 22 can include a plurality of openings 24 (e.g., holes, orifices, etc.) along its upper layer 22. The quantity, shape, size, spacing, orientation, location and other details of the openings 24 can be varied to achieve a desired or required airflow scheme along the top of the mat or topper member 20 during use.</p>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">In other arrangements, the upper layer 22 and/or the lower layer 26 of the mat conditioner mat 20 comprise a generally fluid impermeable lining, coating or other member along at least a portion (e.g., some or all) of its surface area in order to provide the mat with the desired air permeability or conductive characteristics or properties. Alternatively, one or more portions of the mat's upper surface (e.g., upper layer 22) can be at least partially fluid permeable. Thus, air or other fluids delivered within an interior space S of a topper member 20 may diffuse through such air permeable portions, toward a bed occupant.</p>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">According to certain configurations, as illustrated, for example, in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref>, one or more fluid distribution members 28 or spacer materials can be positioned within an interior space S of the conditioner mat 20. Such fluid distribution members can provide<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> desired structural characteristics to the mat 20 so that the integrity of the space S is sufficiently maintained during use. In addition, the fluid distribution member 28 or spacer material can help distribute air or other fluids within the interior space S. Consequently, air or other fluids delivered to the conditioner mat or topper member 20 can be advantageously distributed within the interior spaces S of the various zones. This can help ensure that ambient and/or conditioned (e.g., cooled, heated, dehumidified, etc.) fluids are properly delivered through the openings 24 along the top surface of the mat 20.</p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">With continued reference to <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref>, the conditioner mat 20 can be shaped, sized and generally configured to receive a fluid distribution member 28 within the interior space (e.g., generally between the upper and lower layers 22, 26). As noted above, the fluid distribution member 28 can include one or more spacer materials that are adapted to generally maintain their shape when subjected to compressive forces and other loads (e.g., from an occupant seated thereon or thereagainst). For example, in some embodiments, the fluid distribution member 28 comprises a spacer fabric, open cell or other porous foam, a mesh, honeycomb or other porous structure, other materials that are generally air permeable and/or conductive or that have an open structure through which fluids may pass and/or the like. Such spacer fabrics or other spacer materials can be configured to maintain a minimum clearance between the upper and lower layers 22, 26 so that air or other fluid entering the mat 20 can be at least partially distributed within the interior space S before exiting the openings 24. As discussed in greater detail herein, in certain arrangements, the mat or topper member 20 is configured to be selectively removed from the interior space S for replacement, cleaning, repair or for any other purpose.</p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">In some embodiments, the mat or topper member comprises a spacer fabric that is configured to generally retain its three-dimensional shape when subjected to compressive and/or other types of forces. The spacer fabric can advantageously include internal pores or passages that permit air or other fluid to pass therethrough. For example, the spacer fabric can comprise an internal lattice or other structure which has internal openings at least partially extending from the top surface to the bottom surface of the spacer fabric. In some embodiments, the thickness of the spacer fabric or other fluid distribution member is approximately 6-14 mm (e.g., about 6 mm, 8 mm, 10 mm, 12 mm, 14 mm, values<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> between such ranges, etc.). In other arrangements, the thickness of the spacer fabric or other fluid distribution member of the mat is less than approximately 6 mm (e.g., about 5 mm, 4 mm, 3 mm, 2 mm, 1 mm, less than 1 mm, values between such ranges, etc.) or greater than approximately 14 mm (e.g., about 15 mm, 16 mm, 18 mm, 20 mm, 24 mm, 28 mm, 36 mm, greater than 36 mm, values between such ranges, etc.). The spacer fabric or other fluid distribution member can be manufactured from one or more durable materials, such as, for example, foam, plastic, other polymeric materials, composites, ceramic, rubber and/or the like. The rigidity, elasticity, strength and/or other properties of the spacer fabric can be selectively modified to achieve a target spacing within an interior of the mat or topper member, a desired balance between comfort and durability and/or the like. In some embodiments, the spacer fabric can comprise woven textile, nylon mesh material, reticulated foam, open-cell foam and/or the like. The spacer fabric can be advantageously breathable, resistant to crush and air permeable. However, in other embodiments, a spacer fabric can be customized to suit a particular application. Therefore, the breathability, air permeability and/or crush resistance of a spacer fabric can vary.</p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026"><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3B</figref> illustrates a partial cross-sectional view of one embodiment of a conditioner mat 20, which does not form part of the invention, which includes a boundary or node N across or through which air or other fluid is generally not permitted to pass. In the illustrated arrangement, the mat comprises fluid impermeable or substantially fluid impermeable upper and lower layers 22, 26 (e.g., vinyl or other thermoplastic sheet, tight-woven fabric, etc.) that define a first interior space S1. As shown in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3B</figref> and noted above with reference to <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref>, the mat or topper member 20 can be sized, shaped and generally configured to removably or permanently receive a fluid distribution member 28 within such a first interior space S1.</p>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">In certain configurations, the upper and lower layers 22, 26 are formed from a unitary sheet or member of plastic, fabric and/or other material that has been wrapped around an edge 25 to form a bag-like structure. Alternatively, as illustrated in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3C</figref>, an edge 25' of the mat 20 can be formed by attaching the free ends of the layers 22, 26 to each other, using one or more connection methods or devices, such as, for example, hot melting, stitching, glues or other adhesives, crimping, clips or other fasteners and/or the like.<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">With continued reference to <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3B</figref>, the conditioner mat 20 can include one or more intermediate fluid boundaries or nodes N that act to block or substantially block air flow. Such nodes N can help maintain air or other fluids within certain desired portions or zones of the mat 20. For example, in the arrangement of <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3B</figref>, the fluid boundary or node N helps to generally prevent air from passing from the first interior space S1 to the second interior space S2 located immediately adjacent to it. Alternatively, in other arrangements, the second interior space S2 also comprises a fluid distribution member (not shown in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3B</figref>) that is, at least partially, thermally and/or fluidly isolated from the fluid distribution member 28. Under certain circumstances, the mat or topper member 20 comprises one or more interior spaces that are configured to not receive fluids, and thus, to not distribute fluids through the upper layer 22 defining their upper surface. For example, such non-fluid zones can be located along bodily portions of the occupant that are less susceptible to ulcer-formation, other ailments, discomfort and/or other undesirable conditions resulting from prolonged contact with a bed surface.</p>
<p id="p0029" num="0029">Relatedly, a mat 20 can include one or more non-fluid zones 50, 52 (<figref idref="f0001">FIGS. 1</figref> and <figref idref="f0002">2</figref>) where air flow to an occupant is undesirable, unnecessary or otherwise unwanted. In other arrangements, non-fluid zones 50, 52 can provide one or more other functions or benefits. For example, a non-fluid zone can help reduce manufacturing costs, as the cost of relatively expensive spacer fabric and/or other spacer materials is reduced. Further, the use of non-fluid zones 50, 52 can provide an additional level of thermal isolation and/or fluid isolation, with respect to adjacent fluid zones 34, 36, 44, 46. As discussed in greater detail herein, a pad, cushion, gel or similar member comprising foam (e.g., closed-cell, open-cell, viscoelastic, etc.), rubber, fabric, natural or synthetic filler material and/or any other material or substance can be positioned within the second interior space S2. The pad or other member positioned within a non-fluid zone can be air-permeable or non-air permeable, as desired or required. In addition, in some embodiments, the pad or other member or material that is positioned within a non-fluid zone 50, 52 is selected so that the overall firmness, flexibility and/or other characteristics of the non-fluid zones 50, 52 match or substantially match the corresponding properties of one or more adjacent fluid zones.<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --></p>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">For any of the embodiments of a conditioner mat or topper member disclosed herein, the mat can have a generally flexible configuration in order to help it conform to the shape of the mattress, pad, cushion or other support member of the bed on which it may be placed. Moreover, a mat or topper member can be designed with certain immersion and envelopment characteristics in mind to assist with pressure redistribution. Such characteristics can further enhance a topper member's ability to help prevent or reduce the likelihood of pressure ulcers, other ailments, general discomfort and/or other undesirable conditions to an occupant positioned thereon.</p>
<p id="p0031" num="0031">To further improve the immersion and envelopment characteristics of any of the embodiments of a conditioner mat or topper member disclosed herein, one or more additional layers, cushions or other comfort members can be selectively positioned beneath the mat (e.g., between the mat and the mattress or other support structure of a bed). Such additional layers and/or other members can further enhance the ability of the mat and adjacent surfaces to generally conform to an occupant's anatomy and body contours and shape.</p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032">As illustrated in <figref idref="f0001">FIGS. 1</figref> and <figref idref="f0002">2</figref>, the conditioner mat 20 can include one or more main passages 32, 42 that receive ambient or thermally conditioned air from the fluid modules (e.g., the inlet fittings 76, 78) and distribute it to one or more fluid zones 34, 36, 44, 46. In the depicted embodiment, the mat 20 includes two main passages 32, 42 that extend longitudinally along opposite sides of the mat 20 (e.g., at or near what would be the edge of the bed's mattress or other upper support structure). As discussed in greater detail herein, the passages 32, 42 can be configured to direct air or other fluid to different zones 34, 36, 44, 46 of the mat or topper member 20. A mat 20 can include more or fewer passages 32, 42, as desired or required for a particular design or application. The size, shape, location, spacing, orientation, general configuration and/or other details regarding the passages 32, 42 can also be modified.</p>
<p id="p0033" num="0033">The passages 32, 42 can comprise upper and lower layers of plastic, fabric or other material, as discussed herein with reference to <figref idref="f0003">FIGS. 3A-3C</figref>. In some embodiments, which do not form part of the invention, the upper and lower layers that define the passages 32, 42 are the same layers that also define the interior spaces of the fluid zones and/or the non-fluid zones. In such designs, the<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> conditioner mat can include one or more fluid boundaries (e.g., nodes) which help to direct air or other fluids toward specific portions of the mat interior. Such a fluid boundary can include a continuous or substantially continuous line that strategically extends along one or more portions of the mat or topper member (e.g., to define passages 32, 42, fluid zones 34, 36, 44, 46, non-fluid zones 50, 52 and/or the like). As discussed herein with reference to <figref idref="f0003">FIGS. 3B and 3C</figref>, such fluid boundaries can be established by joining the upper and lower layers 22, 26 of the mat 20 to each other, using, for example, hot melting, stitching, adhesives and/or the like. In other embodiments, which do not form part of the invention, as depicted in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3B</figref>, a fluid boundary is created by wrapping a layer around an edge (e.g., bag-like design). As with the fluid zones, one or more spacer materials (e.g., spacer fabric, open cell foam, other porous foam, honeycomb or other porous structure, etc.) can be positioned within the passages 32, 42 to help ensure that the integrity of the passages (e.g., the passage height) is maintained during use. Fluid flow within the passages 32, 42 can be controlled by creating one or more boundary lines (e.g., nodes that extend across a portion of the mat).</p>
<p id="p0034" num="0034">With continued reference to the conditioner mat 20 of <figref idref="f0001">FIGS. 1</figref> and <figref idref="f0002">2</figref>, a first passage 32 is configured to receive fluid (e.g., ambient or conditioned air) from one or more conduits 72 and deliver it to two zones 34, 36, each of which is located along a different region of the mat 20. Likewise, a second passage 42 is configured to receive fluid from one or more conduits and deliver it to two other zones 44, 46. Thus, the conditioning (e.g., cooling, heating, ventilation, etc.) for each set of zones 34, 36 or 44, 46 can be advantageously controlled separately. For example, in one embodiment, relatively cool air is directed to zones 34, 36 (e.g., intended to target a bed occupant's head, shoulders, hips, ischial region, lower back, etc.), while relatively warm air is directed to zones 44, 46 (e.g., intended to target a bed occupant's main torso and feet), or vice versa. In other arrangements, both sets of zones 34, 36 and 44, 46 are subjected to the same or similar type of ventilation or conditioning (e.g., heating, cooling, dehumidification, etc.). Further, the rate of fluid flow into each fluid zone (or set of fluid zones) can be separately adjusted in order to achieve a desired or required effect along the top surface of the mat or topper member 20. For instance, the rate of fluid flow into (and thus, out of the corresponding openings 24) of the first set of zones 34, 36 can be greater or less than the fluid flow into the second set of zones 44, 46.<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> Alternatively, each passage 72, 74 can be configured to selectively delivery air or other fluid to fewer (e.g., one) or more (e.g., three, four, more than four) zones, as desired or required.</p>
<p id="p0035" num="0035">As discussed in greater detail herein, a conditioner mat or topper member 20 can include one or more generally air-impermeable portions or non-fluid zones 50, 52 which can assist in establishing physical and/or thermal boundaries. Further, such non-fluid zones 50, 52 can be used to help to create a substantially even and continuous thickness and/or indentation force along the mat 20, especially in regions that do not include a spacer material (e.g., the areas located between adjacent climate controlled zones). Thus, such non-fluid zones can help maintain a generally continuous thickness and feel to the mat or topper member. This can help improve an occupant's comfort level. In addition, the incorporation of non-fluid zones into a mat or topper member design can help reduce manufacturing costs, as the spacer materials that are typically positioned within the fluid zones materials tend to be relatively expensive.</p>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">A plan view of one embodiment, which does not form part of the invention, of a conditioner mat or topper member 20A is schematically illustrated in <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 4</figref>. As in the arrangement of <figref idref="f0001">FIGS. 1</figref> and <figref idref="f0002">2</figref>, the depicted mat 20A comprises two passages 32, 42 which are generally located along opposite edges of the mat 20A and which extend, at least partially, in the longitudinal direction of the mat. In other embodiments, however, a mat or topper member can include fewer or more passages, which may be positioned along or near different portions of the mat (e.g., near the edges, away from edges, near the middle, etc.). Arrows included in <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 4</figref> illustrate the general direction of fluid flow through the passages 32, 42 and into (and/or out of) the respective fluid zones 34, 36, 44, 46. For example, ambient and/or conditioned (e.g., cooled, heated, dehumidified, etc.) air or other fluid entering a first passage 32 is generally directed to zones 34 and 36, whereas air or other fluid entering a second passage 42 is generally directed to zones 44 and 46. As noted above, such a configuration can allow air to be distributed to and within certain target regions or areas of the conditioner mat 20A, and thus, the bed (e.g., hospital bed, medical bed, other bed or seating assembly, etc.) on which the mat is positioned. The ability to deliver ambient and/or conditioned (e.g., cooled, heated, etc.) air can help provide one or more benefits to a bed's occupant. For example, as discussed in greater detail herein, such a scheme can help reduce the likelihood of bed sores resulting from<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> heat, friction, moisture, prolonged contact and/or other factors. In addition, such embodiments can improve the general comfort level of the occupant, especially in difficult environmental conditions (e.g., extreme heat or cold, excessively high relative humidity levels, etc.).</p>
<p id="p0037" num="0037">With continued reference to <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 4</figref>, the mat is designed such that adjacent fluid zones (e.g., zones 34 and 44, zones 44 and 36, zones 36 and 46, etc.) are not in fluid communication with the same main passage 32, 42. In addition, as shown in <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 4</figref>, adjacent zones are generally separated by one or more air-impermeable or substantially air-impermeable zones 50. In certain embodiments, interior spaces of one or more non-fluid zones 50 comprise foam (e.g., closed-cell, open-cell, viscoelastic, etc.), one or more natural or synthetic filler materials or some other generally air-impermeable pad or material.</p>
<p id="p0038" num="0038"><figref idref="f0004">FIG. 5</figref> schematically illustrates another embodiment of a conditioner mat, which does not form part of the invention, 20B that comprises two main passages 32, 42. A conditioner mat can include additional non-fluid zones 52, which in the illustrated arrangement, are oriented along one edge of a zone and perpendicularly extend between the main non-fluid zones 50. As discussed herein, the various generally air-impermeable zones (e.g., non-fluid zones) 50, 52 included within a conditioner mat can help create thermal and/or fluid barriers between adjacent climate controlled zones 34, 36, 44, 46 (e.g., fluid zones). Accordingly, the function of the conditioner mat can be improved, as the specific zones can operate closer to a target cooling, heating, ventilation or other environmentally-controlled effect.</p>
<p id="p0039" num="0039">According to certain arrangements, a conditioner mat, such as any of those disclosed herein, can be approximately 91,44 cm (3 feet) wide by 213,36 cm (7 feet) long. However, depending on the size, shape and general design of the bed (e.g., hospital bed, other medical bed, etc.) or other seating assembly on which a mat is configured to be positioned, the dimensions (e.g., length, width, etc.) of the mat can be larger or smaller than noted above. For example, a mat or topper member can be about 91,44 cm (3 feet) wide by 193,04 cm (6 foot-4 inches) or 203,2 cm (6 foot-8 inches) long. In some embodiments, the mat or topper member is sized to fit a standard sized bed (e.g., single, twin, queen, king, etc.) or a custom-designed (e.g., non-standard sized) bed. Thus, conditioner mats or topper members can be specially designed (e.g., non-standard shapes, sizes, etc.) according to a specific bed with which they will be used. Possible shapes include,<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> but are not limited to, other triangular, square, other polygonal, circular, oval, irregular, etc. In addition, the mat can encompass all or substantially all of the top surface area of the mattress or other support member of a bed. Alternatively, the mat or topper member can encompass only a fraction of a mattress's total top surface area, such as, for example, 95%, 90%, 80%, 70%, 60%, 50%, 40%, 30%, 20%, more than 95%, less than 20%, ranges between these values, and/or the like.</p>
<p id="p0040" num="0040">In some arrangements, the length and width of the fluid zones 34, 36, 44, 46 of a conditioner mat 20 are approximately 30,48 cm (12 inches) and 78,74 cm (31 inches), respectively. Further, in certain embodiments, the length of the main non-fluid zones 50 is approximately 20,32 cm (8 inches). However, the dimensions of the fluid zones and/or the non-fluid zones can vary, as desired or required by a particular application or use. For example, in one arrangement, the length of one or more fluid zones is approximately 20,32 cm (8 inches) or 40,64 cm (16 inches), while the length of the non-fluid zones 50 is approximately 10,16 cm (4 inches). In other embodiments, the length, width, shape, location along the mat, orientation, spacing and/or other details of the various portions and components of a conditioner mat may be greater or less than indicated herein. For instance, in some embodiments, the length of a fluid zone or a non-fluid zone is between about 2,54 cm (1 inch) and 60,96 cm (24 inches) (e.g., approximately 2, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12, 14, 16, 18, 20, 22, 24, ranges between such values, etc.) less than about 2,54 cm (1 inch), more than about 60,96 cm (24 inches), etc.</p>
<p id="p0041" num="0041"><figref idref="f0005">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates a bottom view of a conditioner mat 20 positioned on a mattress 10, cushion or other support member (e.g., foam pad). As shown, the mat 20 can include a lower skirt portion 21 or other securement device that is configured to at least partially wrap around the mattress 10 in order to secure the mat 20 to a bed (e.g., hospital or medical bed) or other seating assembly. Thus, the conditioner mat or topper member 20 can be generally designed like a fitted sheet, allowing it to be conveniently attached to and/or removed from a mattress or other upper support member of a bed assembly. In certain arrangements, the bottom skirt portion 21 extends continuously around the entire mattress 10 or other support member. Alternatively, the skirt portion 21 can be intermittently or at only partially positioned around the periphery of the mat 20, as desired or required. The skirt portion 21 can include one or more elasticized portions or regions to help accommodate for<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> variations in the dimensions of mattresses or other support members and/or to provide for a more snug fit.</p>
<p id="p0042" num="0042">As illustrated in <figref idref="f0005">FIG. 7</figref>, a conditioner mat 20 can include one or more straps 21', bands, belts or other securement devices to help secure the mat 20 to a mattress, pad or other support structure 10 of a bed. For example, in the depicted embodiment, the mat 20 comprises a total of two securement devices 21' that are shaped, sized and otherwise adapted to partially or completely surround the mattress 10. The securement devices 21' can include flexible straps that comprise an elastic structure and/or one or more elastic, stretchable or other flexible materials or members. Consequently, in such configurations, a user can conveniently pass the straps 21' underneath a mattress 10 or other support structure of a bed in order to properly position the conditioner mat 20 on a bed assembly. Alternatively, each strap, band or other securement device 21' can include two or more loose ends that are configured to be selectively attached to each other using a connection device or method (e.g., belt-like connection, mating clip portions, hook-and-loop fasteners, zippers, buttons, other mechanical fastener systems, a simple tie or knot system and/or the like). Further, regardless of their exact configuration, one or more properties of the securement devices 21' can be modifiable to accommodate mattresses and other bed support structures of various sizes, shaped and types. For instance, in some embodiments, the length of a strap is adjustable.</p>
<p id="p0043" num="0043">Any of the embodiments of a conditioner mat or topper member 20 disclosed herein, can be configured to include a fitted sheet design (e.g., <figref idref="f0005">FIG. 6</figref>), a strap or other securement device (e.g., <figref idref="f0005">FIG. 7</figref>) and/or any other device or method for temporary or permanent attachment to one or more portions of a bed (e.g., upper mattress or other support structure or member). Alternatively, a mat can be positioned adjacent to a mattress or other portion of a bed without being attached to it. In certain arrangements, a bottom surface of a conditioner mat or topper member includes one or more tactile or non-slip features or properties that are configured to increase the friction between the mat and the adjacent support structure, and thus, reduce the likelihood of movement of the mat relative to the bed, especially when an occupant is positioned thereon. For example, the mat can include a generally unsmooth surface (e.g., a surface having bumps, other<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> projections or other tactile features, recesses or cavities, etc.), one or more relatively high friction regions (e.g., areas having rubber or relatively high-friction layers or strips) and/or the like. In other embodiments, the conditioner mat or other topper member are incorporated into a unitary structure with the bed's mattress or other support structure.</p>
<p id="p0044" num="0044">According to certain embodiments, for example, which do not form part of the invention, such as disclosed in <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 8</figref>, a conditioner mat 120 or topper member includes only a single zone 130 through which ambient and/or conditioned (e.g., cooled, heated, dehumidified, etc.) air or other fluid is selectively delivered. As discussed with reference to other arrangements herein, such a fluid zone 130 can extend along one or more regions or areas of the mat 120 in order to target specific portions of an occupant's body (e.g., head, shoulders, hips, heels, etc.).</p>
<p id="p0045" num="0045">Within the fluid zone 130 of the mat illustrated in <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 8</figref>, an upper surface (e.g., upper fabric, layer, film, other member, etc.) of the mat 120 can include a plurality of openings 124. As discussed herein with reference to other configurations (e.g., those illustrated in <figref idref="f0001">FIGS. 1</figref>, <figref idref="f0002">2</figref>, <figref idref="f0003">3A-3C</figref>, etc.), such openings 124 can be configured to allow air or other fluid that enters into an interior space of the mat's fluid zone (e.g., through a spacer fabric, fluid distribution member, etc.). In certain embodiments, the quantity, size, shape, location, density, spacing, orientation and/or other characteristics of the openings 124 are selected to direct the fluid exiting the conditioner mat 120 in targeted regions or areas of the occupant's body, such as, for example, high pressure, temperature, friction and/or moisture regions that are susceptible to decubitus ulcers, other ailments, general discomfort and/or the like.</p>
<p id="p0046" num="0046">As shown in <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 8</figref>, the mat or topper member 120 can include one or more non-fluid zones or areas 150, 152 that are configured to prevent or substantially prevent air and other fluids from entering therein. According to some arrangements, such non-fluid zones 150, 152 comprise a foam (e.g., closed-cell, open-cell, viscoelastic, etc.) pad, other polymeric or other type of pad, filler materials, other layers or members and/or the like. As discussed herein with reference to other embodiments, which do not form part of the invention, such as, for example, those illustrated in <figref idref="f0003">FIGS. 3A-3C</figref>, the upper and lower layers (e.g., vinyl, other plastic, fabric, etc.) of a mat or topper member can be advantageously attached adjacent to such non-fluid zones or portions 50, 52, thereby forming fluid boundaries that block or substantially block fluid flow. In the<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> embodiment, which does not form part of the invention, illustrated in <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 8</figref>, the conditioner mat 120 includes non-fluid zones or portions 150, 152 along the bottom and one of the sides of the bed 100. However, such zones 150, 152 or portions that are generally configured to not receive fluids can be positioned at, along or near additional and/or different areas of the mat 120. Further, the respective surface areas of the mat 120 covered by fluid zones 130 and non-fluid zones 150, 152 can be varied to accomplish a desired ventilation and/or conditioning (e.g., cooling, heating, dehumidification, etc.) effect above the mat 120.</p>
<p id="p0047" num="0047"><figref idref="f0006">FIG. 9</figref> illustrates another embodiment of a conditioner mat or topper member 220 secured to a medical bed 200 or other bed assembly. As shown, the mat 220 includes two fluid zones 234, 236 that are in fluid communication with a main passage 232 which extends along one of the mat's sides. In some arrangements, ambient and/or conditioned air is delivered from one or more fluid modules (not shown in <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 9</figref>) into the main passage 232 via one or more ducts 272 or fluid conduits. The conditioner mat 220 can include one or more additional fluid zones 244 that are generally not in fluid communication with the first set of fluid zones 234, 236. Accordingly, as discussed herein with reference to the arrangements of <figref idref="f0001">FIGS. 1</figref> and <figref idref="f0002">2</figref>, separate fluid zones (or sets of fluid zones) that are fluidly, hydraulically and/or thermally isolated from each other can be used to vary the ventilation and/or thermal conditioning effects along the top of a mat. Thus, fluid zones 234, 236 of the conditioner mat or topper member 220 can be cooled, while fluid zone 244 is heated, or vice versa. Alternatively, the type of fluid (e.g., ambient air, heated or cooled air, etc.) being delivered to all the fluid zones 234, 236, 244 of a mat 220 can be similar or substantially similar. In other embodiments, although the distinct fluid zones 234, 236, 244 are configured to receive the same or similar types of fluids, the flowrate of fluid delivery can be varied between fluid zones, as desired or required.</p>
<p id="p0048" num="0048">Another embodiment of a conditioner mat or topper member 320 is illustrated in <figref idref="f0007">FIGS. 10A</figref> and <figref idref="f0008">10B</figref>. As shown, the main portion 330 of the mat or topper member 320 can have a generally rectangular shape. In some arrangements, the dimensions, shape and other properties of the mat 320 are selected to generally match corresponding characteristics of the bed on which the mat will be positioned. As discussed herein with reference to other embodiments, the mat 320 of <figref idref="f0007">FIG. 10A</figref> can include one or more fluid<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> zones (e.g., regions having an interior space that is configured to receive air or other fluids) and/or non-fluid zones (e.g., regions having an interior space that is not configured to receive fluids) to achieve a desired fluid discharge pattern, and thus a desired climate control scheme, along a top portion of the mat 320.</p>
<p id="p0049" num="0049">With continued reference to <figref idref="f0007">FIGS. 10A</figref> and <figref idref="f0008">10B</figref>, the mat or topper member 320 can include a fluid module 380 that is in fluid communication with one or more fluid zones of the mat's main portion 330. As shown, the fluid module 380 can include a blower, fan or other fluid transfer device 382 that selectively delivers/draws air or other fluids to/from the main portion 330 of the mat 320. The fluid module 380, which in the illustrated arrangement is configured to hang off one side of the mat's main portion 330, can also include an inlet fitting 386 that is fluidly coupled to an inlet 321 of the main portion 330. Alternatively, as illustrated in other arrangements herein, a fluid module can be designed to hang from an end of the bed (e.g., a top or bottom end), along another side and/or any other location on, within or near the bed assembly. The fluid transfer device 382 can be placed in fluid communication with the downstream inlet fitting 386 using one or more conduits 384 or other passages.</p>
<p id="p0050" num="0050">According to certain embodiments, the fluid module 380 is configured to selectively heat and/or cool the fluid being transferred by the blower 382 toward the main portion 330 of the topper member 320. For example, the fluid transfer device 382 can be placed in fluid communication with one or more thermoelectric devices (e.g., Peltier circuits), convective heaters and/or other conditioning (e.g., heating, cooling, dehumidifying, etc.) devices to selectively heat, cool and/or otherwise condition a fluid passing from the fluid module 380 to the main portion 330 of the mat 320. For example, a thermoelectric device, which may be positioned within an inlet fitting 386, can selectively heat or cool air or other fluid being transferred by the fluid module 380 to the main portion 330 of the mat or topper member 320. As discussed in greater detail herein, fluid modules comprising blowers or other fluid transfer devices, thermoelectric devices or other conditioning devices and/or the like can be incorporated into any of the embodiments of a conditioner mat or topper member disclosed herein.<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --></p>
<p id="p0051" num="0051"><figref idref="f0009">FIGS. 11A</figref> and <figref idref="f0010">11B</figref> illustrate another embodiment of a topper member or mat 420, which does not form part of the invention, configured to be removably secured to the top of a medical bed, other type of bed or other seating assembly. As discussed herein with reference to other arrangements, the main portion 430 can include one or more fluid zones and/or non-fluid zones (not shown in <figref idref="f0009">FIGS. 11A</figref> and <figref idref="f0010">11B</figref>) that are configured to direct ambient and/or conditioned air or other fluid to targeted regions of an occupant's anatomy. In the configuration depicted in <figref idref="f0009">FIGS. 11A</figref> and <figref idref="f0010">11B</figref>, the fluid module 480 is conveniently positioned within an interior cavity 432 or recessed portion of the topper member 420. The cavity or recess 432 can be formed along an end (e.g., top or bottom) of the mat's main portion 430. Alternatively, such a cavity or other space 432 can be included along a side, middle and/or any other location of the conditioner mat 420, as desired or required.</p>
<p id="p0052" num="0052">With continued reference to <figref idref="f0009">FIGS. 11A</figref> and <figref idref="f0010">11B</figref>, the cavity 432 can be defined, at least in part, by a pair of oppositely-mounted enclosure members 434. Regardless of its exact details, the cavity 432 can be configured to advantageously hide all or most (or at least some) of the fluid module 480 and related components, such as, for example, the blower, fan or fluid transfer device 482, the one or more conduits 484 that place the fluid transfer device 482 in fluid communication with the mat's main portion 430, the fluid inlet fitting 486 that establishes an interface with one or more interior spaces of the mat's fluid zones and/or the like. As illustrated in <figref idref="f0009">FIGS. 11A</figref> and <figref idref="f0010">11B</figref>, the cavity 432 can also be provided with a vent 438 that permits ambient air to enter the cavity so as to avoid a negative pressure being created therein.</p>
<p id="p0053" num="0053">The various embodiments of a conditioner mat or topper member disclosed herein, can include one or more electrical connections for supplying electrical power to the fluid module(s) and/or any other electric components or devices included and/or associated with the mat. The electrical power supplied to a conditioner mat can come in any form, including AC or DC power, as desired or required. Therefore, a mat can comprise a power supply, a power transformer, a power cord, an electrical port configured to receive a cord and/or the like for electrically connecting the mat's electrical components to a facility's power system. Alternatively, the mat can be supplied with one or more batteries to eliminate the need for a hardwired connection into an<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> electrical outlet while the mat is in use. According to certain embodiments, the battery comprises a rechargeable battery that can be easily and conveniently recharged while the mat is not in use. In some configurations, the battery can be separated and removed from the mat for replacement, recharging (e.g., using a separate charging station or device), repair or servicing, inspection and/or for any other purpose.</p>
<p id="p0054" num="0054">A mat can also include one or more wires and/or other electrical connections for incorporating other components into the mat's control system. For example, as discussed in greater detail herein, a mat can be equipped with one or more sensors (e.g., temperature, humidity, condensation, pressure, occupant detection, etc.). In some embodiments, a fluid module, power supply, sensor, other electrical component, device or connection and/or any other sensitive item can be separated and removed from the mat prior to a potentially damaging operation (e.g., washing or cleaning or the mat). For instance, the cavity 432 of <figref idref="f0009">FIGS. 11A</figref> and <figref idref="f0010">11B</figref> can comprise a housing that is detachable from and re-attachable to the mat 420.</p>
<p id="p0055" num="0055">Another embodiment of a conditioner mat or topper member 520 is illustrated in <figref idref="f0011">FIGS. 12A</figref> and <figref idref="f0012">12B</figref>. As shown, the main portion 530 of the mat 520 can include a cutout 532 or other feature that is sized, shaped and otherwise configured to accommodate a fluid module 580. Accordingly, similarly to the arrangement of <figref idref="f0009">FIGS. 11A</figref> and <figref idref="f0010">11B</figref>, the fluid module 580 can be contained within an outer periphery of a bed when the mat 520 is positioned thereon. The cutout or recess 532 can be positioned along any portion of the mat and need not be confined to a particular corner or region of a main portion 530. The cutout 532 can be situated along a different corner, along a side (e.g., generally between two corners), within an interior region of the main portion 530 and/or the like, as desired. By way of example, the conditioner mat 620 illustrated in <figref idref="f0013">FIG. 13A</figref> and <figref idref="f0014">13B</figref> comprises a cutout 632 along its front or back end and generally between its two sides. As shown in <figref idref="f0014">FIG. 13B</figref>, the fluid module 680 can be at least partially situated within the cutout 632. In addition, at least some of the components and portions of a fluid module 680 that selectively supply fluid to the mat 620 can hang along an end or side of the mat 620. For example, in the depicted arrangement, the fluid transfer device 682 and a portion of the conduit 684 are oriented generally perpendicularly relative to the main portion 630.<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --></p>
<p id="p0056" num="0056"><figref idref="f0015">FIG. 14</figref> illustrates a perspective view of another embodiment of a conditioner mat 720 configured to be positioned along the top of a mattress 10, pad, cushion or other support structure of a bed. As shown, one or more fluid modules 780 can be connected to a main portion 730 along one of the sides of the mat 720. As discussed with reference to other arrangements herein, a fluid module can be positioned along any other portion of the mat 720, either in lieu of or in addition to one of its sides. Similarly to the conditioner mat 620 of <figref idref="f0013">FIGS. 13A</figref> and <figref idref="f0014">13B</figref>, in some embodiments, which do not form part of the invention, at least a portion of the fluid module 780 in the depicted embodiment is generally perpendicular to the mat 720. Therefore, for any of the embodiments disclosed herein, a fluid module can be configured to hang along a side or an end of a conditioner mat. In such arrangements, one or more portions or components of the fluid module can be secured, temporarily or permanently, to an adjacent surface, such as, for example, a portion of a mattress or other support structure, a bed headboard or footboard, a bed guardrail, another portion of a bed assembly, the floor or a wall, other equipment located within a hospital room and/or the like.</p>
<p id="p0057" num="0057">As illustrated schematically in <figref idref="f0016">FIG. 15</figref>, a fluid module 80 can be positioned at any location within a main portion 30 of a conditioner mat 20 or at any location adjacent to or near the main portion 30. For example, one or more fluid modules can be situated within a cavity or recess (<figref idref="f0009">FIGS. 11A</figref> and <figref idref="f0010">11B</figref>) or a cutout (<figref idref="f0011 f0012 f0013 f0014">FIGS. 12A-13B</figref>) of the main portion 30 along the top 80A, bottom 80C and/or the sides 80B, 80D of the mat 20. Alternatively, one or more fluid modules can extend away from the main portion 30 of a mat 20 (e.g., along the top 80A', bottom 80C' and/or the sides 80B', 80D'). For instance, a fluid module can generally hang off the side of the mat and the bed (<figref idref="f0013">FIGS. 13A</figref>, <figref idref="f0014">13B</figref> and <figref idref="f0015">14</figref>). In any of the embodiments disclosed herein, a fluid module can be removably or permanently secured to a bed assembly (e.g., mattress or other support member, footboard or headboard, side rail) and/or any other device or surface.</p>
<p id="p0058" num="0058"><figref idref="f0017">FIG. 16A</figref> schematically illustrates a plan view of another conditioner mat or topper member 820. As shown, the mat 820 includes four separate fluid zones 832, 834, 836, 838 that are positioned immediately adjacent to each other. One or more non-fluid zones (not shown) can be situated between the fluid zones to provide thermal or fluid<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --> isolation, to reduce costs and/or to provide any other benefit, as desired. In <figref idref="f0017">FIG. 16A</figref>, each fluid zone 832, 834, 836, 838 is supplied ambient and/or conditioned (e.g., cooled, heated, dehumidified, etc.) air or other fluid by one or more dedicated fluid modules 880A, 880B, 880C, 880D. In the illustrated embodiment, the fluid modules are positioned along a side of the mat 820. The fluid modules can be located within a cavity or cutout. Alternatively, the fluid modules 880A, 880B, 880C, 880D can generally form a side edge of the mat 820, can extend outwardly from the mat (e.g., past the outer periphery of the mattress on which the mat is positioned), can hang off the side of the mat 820 and/or the like. In other configurations, the fluid modules can be positioned in a location generally separate and remote from the mat 820. For example, one or more of the fluid modules are located within a fluid box or other container that can be conveniently mounted on the bed assembly (e.g., to, along or near a headboard, footboard, guardrail, etc.), a wall, the floor and/or the like. In such embodiments, the fluid modules can be placed in fluid communication with the respective fluid zones of the mat's main portion 830 using one or more conduits. Additional details regarding fluid boxes are provided herein with reference to the arrangements illustrated in, inter alia, <figref idref="f0021">FIGS. 17A, 17B</figref> and <figref idref="f0028 f0036">19A-27</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0059" num="0059">Additional embodiments of a conditioner mat or topper member 820B-820C configured to be positioned on a medical bed, other type of bed or other seating assembly are illustrated in <figref idref="f0018 f0019 f0020">FIGS. 16B-16D</figref>. As depicted in <figref idref="f0018">FIG. 16B</figref>, the conditioner mat 820B can include a single fluid zone 832B and may be bordered by one or more adjacent non-fluid zones 850B, as desired or required to achieve a particular fluid delivery scheme along an upper portion the bed 800B. The non-fluid zones 850B located at the upper and lower ends of the mat or topper member 820B can have a generally tapered profile to improve the feel and general comfort level to an occupant. Fluid (e.g., ambient and/or conditioned air) is selectively supplied to the fluid zone 832B of the conditioner mat 820B using one or more fluid modules (e.g., blowers or other fluid transfer devices, thermoelectric devices, convective heaters, other thermal conditioning devices, dehumidifiers, etc.), which in some embodiments, are positioned within a fluid box 880, or other enclosure and/or the like.<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --></p>
<p id="p0060" num="0060">As discussed in greater detail with reference to other arrangements disclosed herein, the conditioner mat or topper member 820B can be removably attachable to a mattress 810B or other support structure (e.g., pad, cushion, box spring, etc.) of a bed assembly 800B (e.g., hospital or medical bed, typical bed for home use, futon, etc.) using one or more connection devices or methods, such as, for example, straps, hook-and-loop fasteners, zippers, clips, buttons and/or the like. Alternatively, the position of the mat 820B can be maintained relative to the top of a mattress 810B or other support structure by friction (e.g., the use of non-skid surfaces, without the use of separate connection devices or features, etc.). Regardless of how the topper member is secured or otherwise maintained relative to a bed assembly, its size, shape, location relative to the mattress and an occupant positioned thereon and/or other details can be different than disclosed herein, as desired or required.</p>
<p id="p0061" num="0061"><figref idref="f0019">FIG. 16C</figref> illustrates another embodiment of a conditioner mat or topper member 820C for a medical bed, other type of bed or other seating assembly. As shown, the mat 820C can comprise more than one (e.g., two, three, four, more than four, etc.) separate fluid zones 832C, 834C. As discussed in greater detail herein, each fluid zone 832C, 834C can be configured to receive fluid having the same or a different properties (e.g., type, temperature, humidity, flowrate, etc.) than another zone. This can help provide customized ventilation, heating, cooling and/or other environmentally-conditioned schemes to a seated occupant. In the arrangement depicted in <figref idref="f0019">FIG. 16C</figref>, air or other fluid is selectively delivered to the fluid zones 832C, 834C by one or more fluid modules (not shown) positioned within a fluid box 880. Alternatively, one or more fluid modules providing conditioned and/or unconditioned fluid to the conditioner mat 820C need not be positioned within a fluid box 880 or other enclosure. In addition, as illustrated in <figref idref="f0020">FIG. 16D</figref>, a conditioner mat 820D can include two or more fluid boxes 880A, 880B, as desired or required. For example, in the depicted embodiment, air from one or more fluid modules housed within a first fluid box 880A is selectively delivered to a first fluid zone 832D of the mat 820D. Likewise, air from one or more fluid modules housed within a second fluid box 880B can be selectively delivered to a second fluid zone 834D. Thus, the type, flowrate, temperature and/or other properties or characteristics of the fluid being delivered to each zone 832D, 834D can be<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --> varied in order to achieve a desired ventilation, cooling and/or heating effect along the top surface of the mat or topper member 820C.</p>
<p id="p0062" num="0062">As illustrated in the embodiments of <figref idref="f0018 f0019 f0020">FIGS. 16B-16D</figref>, which do not form part of the invention, the conditioner mat or topper member can be configured to only partially cover the underlying mattress or other support structure of a bed assembly. For example, the topper member can be positioned so that air can be selectively delivered to targeted areas of an occupant's anatomy. In any of the embodiments disclosed herein, the mat or topper member can extend partially or completely across the length and/or the width of the mattress, pad or other bed support member situated therebelow.</p>
<p id="p0063" num="0063"><figref idref="f0021">FIGS. 17A and 17B</figref> illustrate a hospital med or other medical bed 900 that is configured to receive one embodiment of a conditioner mat or topper member 920. As shown, the conditioner mat 920 is positioned along the top of a mattress 10, pad, cushion or other support structure of the bed 900. The mat 920 can be removably or temporarily secured to the mattress or other support structure 710 using one or more securement devices 921 (e.g., a bottom skirt member such as included in a fitted sheet design), straps (<figref idref="f0005">FIG. 7</figref>) and/or the like. Further, as with other arrangements disclosed herein, the depicted mat 920 can include one or more fluid zones into which ambient and/or environmentally-conditioned (e.g., cooled, heated, dehumidified, etc.) air or other fluids can be selectively delivered. The fluid zones can comprise spacer materials 928 (e.g., spacer fabric, other porous members or material, etc.) that are generally positioned within a interior space defined by upper and lower layers 922, 926.</p>
<p id="p0064" num="0064">With continued reference to <figref idref="f0021">FIGS. 17A and 17B</figref>, one or more of the bed's guardrails 904, frame members or other support structures can be advantageously configured to receive a fluid conduit 972, 974. Such guardrails 904 or other members can include one or more internal channels or passages through which air or other fluid may pass. Thus, air or other fluid discharged from one or more fluid modules (e.g., located within the fluid box 960 in the depicted embodiment) can be routed through one or more hoses or other conduits 972, 974 to such guardrails 904. Thus, as illustrated in <figref idref="f0021">FIGS. 17A and 17B</figref>, the hoses or other conduits 972, 974 can be placed in fluid communication with corresponding conduits 972', 974' formed within one or more portions of a guardrail or similar structure. Accordingly,<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --> ambient and/or environmentally-conditioned air or other fluids exiting the fluid box 960 can be selectively routed to the guardrail conduits 972', 974'. Air or other fluid entering the fluid passages of the guardrails 904 can be distributed to the interior spaces of the various fluid zones of the mat 920 using one or more intermediate fluid connectors 976 or other fluid branches.</p>
<p id="p0065" num="0065">In the arrangement illustrated in <figref idref="f0021">FIGS. 17A and 17B</figref>, the fluid box 960 is mounted to the footboard 906 of the bed assembly 900. Alternatively, the fluid box 960, and thus the one or more fluid modules positioned therein, can be mounted to the headboard 902, on one of the guardrails 904 and/or any other location (e.g., either on the bed or away from the bed), as desired or required. In addition, as discussed herein with reference to other embodiments, the conditioner mat 920 of <figref idref="f0021">FIGS. 17A and 17B</figref> can be configured so that it is removable from the mattress 10, the fluid connectors 976 that place the mat 920 in fluid communication with the guardrail conduits 972', 974' and/or any other portion of the bed assembly, for cleaning, other maintenance and/or any other purpose.</p>
<p id="p0066" num="0066"><figref idref="f0022">FIGS. 17C and 17D</figref> illustrate another embodiment of a medical bed 900', which does not form part of the invention, configured to selectively provide conditioned and/or unconditioned air or other fluid toward an occupant positioned thereon. As shown, the bed 900' can comprise a conditioner mat or topper member 920' positioned, at least partially, along its top surface. The conditioner mat 920' can include one or more fluid zones 932', 934', 936', 938' and/or non-fluid zones, allowing for customized ventilation and/or thermal or environmental conditioning (e.g., cooling, heating, etc.) schemes along the upper surface of the bed 900'. In the depicted arrangement, air or other fluid is provided to the various fluid zones 932', 934', 936', 938' of the topper member 920' using one or more fluid modules (e.g., blowers or other fluid transfer devices, thermoelectric devices, convective heaters and/or other thermal conditioning devices, dehumidifying devices, etc.) that may be located within, along or near a fluid box 960', another type of enclosure or device, an adjacent surface (e.g., wall, floor, etc.) and/or the like. In <figref idref="f0022">FIGS. 17C and 17D</figref>, the bed 900' comprises a single fluid box 960' that is removably secured to the footboard 906'. However, the quantity, type, size, shape, location and/or other details of the fluid box 960' and/or the various components located therein can vary, as desired or required.<!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --></p>
<p id="p0067" num="0067">With continued reference to <figref idref="f0022">FIG. 17C</figref>, conditioned and/or unconditioned fluid exiting the fluid box 960' can be delivered to the various fluid zones of the conditioner mat 920' using one or more delivery conduits 972'. As discussed in greater detail with reference to other embodiments discussed herein, such delivery conduits 972' can be incorporated into the design of the mat 920' itself. Alternatively, one or more delivery conduits 972' can be physically separated from the conditioner mat 920'. For example, in certain arrangements, the delivery conduits 972' are incorporated into and/or positioned adjacent to a side guardrail 904', footboard 906', headboard 902' and/or any other portion of the bed 900' or other seating assembly. Thus, air or other fluid (e.g., having a general direction of flow schematically represented by arrows A in <figref idref="f0022">FIG. 17D</figref>) can be selectively transferred from one or more delivery conduits into one or more fluid zones 932', 934', 936', 938'. Air or other fluid can enter an interior space of the conditioner mat 920' along one or more other portions of the bed assembly 900' (e.g., the opposite side, top, bottom, etc.), as desired or required.</p>
<p id="p0068" num="0068"><figref idref="f0023 f0024 f0025 f0026 f0027">FIGS. 18A-18E</figref> illustrate various views of another embodiment of a conditioned mat or topper member 1020, which does not form part of the invention. The mat 1020 can include a main portion 1030 that comprises one or more fluid zones and/or non-fluid zones (not shown). The main portion 1030 can include upper and lower layers or members 1022, 1026 that generally define one or more interior spaces S1, S2, S3. A spacer material or other fluid distribution member 1028 can be positioned within one or more of the interior spaces defined by the upper and lower layers of the mat's main portion 1030. Such spacer materials or other members can help maintain the shape and integrity of the interior spaces, especially when the mat or topper member 1020 is subjected to compressive loads during use. In addition, as discussed with reference to other configurations herein, the mat 1020 can include one or more fluid boundaries or nodes N that generally create separate fluid zones and/or non-fluid zones within the mat.</p>
<p id="p0069" num="0069">With continued reference to <figref idref="f0023 f0024 f0025 f0026 f0027">FIGS. 18A-18E</figref>, the conditioner mat 1020 can include a fluid header 1072 through which ambient and/or environmentally-conditioned (e.g., cooled, heated, dehumidified, etc.) air or other fluid is selectively conveyed. In certain arrangements, such a header 1072 can at least partially form or can be incorporated, at least in<!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --> part, into a guardrail or other portion of a bed assembly (e.g., hospital bed, other medical bed, other type of bed, other seating assembly, etc.). Thus, as discussed herein with reference to the assembly of <figref idref="f0021">FIGS. 17A and 17B</figref>, the depicted embodiment, which does not form part of the invention, can provide a relatively simple and convenient way of delivering fluids to a conditioner mat 1020.</p>
<p id="p0070" num="0070">According to certain arrangements, the fluid header 1072 comprises a multi-piece design that allows the internal passage P of the header 1072 to be conveniently accessed by a user. For example, by removing one or more end pieces 1073 and/or other fasteners (not shown), the fluid header 1072 can be opened along a seam 1075 to expose its internal passage P. Thus, one or more intermediate fluid connectors 1076 can be positioned within such a seam, prior re-attaching the adjacent components of the header 1072 to each other. Consequently, the openings within the intermediate fluid connectors 1076 can advantageously place the internal passage P of the header 1072 in fluid communication with one or more fluid zones of the mat's main portion 1030. Thus, as air is delivered from a fluid module into the fluid header 1072, such air can be conveyed to the various fluid zones of the mat 1020 via the fluid connectors 1076. Such a design allows for the conditioner mat or topper member 1020 to be conveniently modified as desired or required by a particular application or use. For example, intermediate fluid connectors 1076 can be quickly and reliably added to or removed from the system. Further, the main portion 1030 of the mat 1020 can be easily removed for cleaning, maintenance, replacement, inspection and/or any other purpose. The fluid header can comprise one or more materials, such as for example, foam, plastic, wood, paper-based materials and/or the like.</p>
<p id="p0071" num="0071">As discussed with reference to other configurations herein, the upper and lower layers 1022, 1026 of the conditioner mat 1020 can include plastics (e.g., vinyl), tight-woven fabrics, specially-engineered materials and/or the like. However, in one simplified arrangement, the layers 1022, 1026 of the mat 1020 comprise cotton, linen, satin, silk, rayon, bamboo fiber, polyester, other textiles, blends or combinations thereof and/or other materials typically used in bed sheets and similar bedding fabrics. In some embodiments, such fabrics have a generally tight weave to reduce the passage of fluids thereacross. In one embodiment, one or more coatings, layers and/or other additives can be added to such fabrics and other materials to improve their overall fluid impermeability. Thus, such readily accessible<!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --> materials can be used to manufacture a relatively simple and inexpensive version of a conditioner mat or topper member 1020. For example, the upper and lower layers can be easily secured to each other (e.g., using stitching, glue lines or other adhesives, mechanical fasteners, etc.) to form the desired interior spaces S1, S2, S3 of the fluid zones. Spacer fabric 1028 or other spacer or distribution materials can be inserted within one or more of the fluid zones, as desired or required. In some embodiments, foam pads, other filler materials and/or the like can be inserted into spaces or chambers of the mat 1020 to create corresponding non-fluid zones.</p>
<p id="p0072" num="0072">As with any of the embodiments discussed herein, the spacer fabric 1028 or other spacer materials can be easily removed from the interior spaces prior to washing or otherwise cleaning the mat 1020. However, the spacer fabric 1028 can be left within the corresponding space or pocket of the mat during such cleaning, maintenance, repair, inspection and/or other procedures.</p>
<p id="p0073" num="0073">For any of the embodiments of a conditioner mat or topper member disclosed herein, one or more additional layers or members can be positioned on top of the mat. For example, as shown in the exploded perspective view of <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, a fluid distribution and conditioning member 90 may be situated along the upper surface of the mat 20. Such a conditioning member 90 can help provide a more uniform distribution of fluid flow toward an occupant. In addition, the conditioning member 90 can improve the comfort level to the occupant (e.g., by providing a softer, more consistent feel).</p>
<p id="p0074" num="0074">In addition, for any of the topper member arrangements disclosed herein, one or more layers can be positioned immediately beneath the fluid zones to enhance the operation of the topper member. For instance, in one embodiment, a lower portion of the mat (or alternatively, an upper portion of the mattress or other support structure on which the mat is positioned) can comprise one or more layers of foam (e.g., closed-cell foam), other thermoplastics and/or other materials that have advantageous thermal insulation and air-flow resistance properties. Thus, such underlying layers can help reduce or eliminate the loss of thermally-conditioned fluids being delivered into the fluid zones through the bottom of the mat or topper member. Such a configuration can also help to reduce the likelihood of<!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --> inadvertent mixing of different fluid streams being delivered in adjacent or nearby fluid zones.</p>
<p id="p0075" num="0075">According to some embodiments, any of the conditioner mats or topper members disclosed herein, are configured to selectively receive non-ambient air within one or more of their fluid zones, either in lieu of or in addition to environmentally or thermally-conditioned (e.g., heated, cooled, dehumidified, etc.) air or other fluids. For example, a header or other conduit in fluid communication with one or more of the mat's fluid zones can be connected to a vent or register that is configured to deliver fluids from a facility's main HVAC system. Alternatively, a facility can have a dedicated fluid system for delivering air and other fluids to the various topper members and/or other climate controlled seating assemblies. In other arrangements, one or more medicaments or other substances can be added to the ambient and/or conditioned (e.g., heated, cooled, dehumidified, etc.) air or other fluids being delivered (e.g., by a fluid module, HVAC system, etc.) into a topper member. For example, medicines, pharmaceuticals, other medicaments and/or the like (e.g., bed sore medications, asthma or other respiratory-related medications, anti-bacterial medications or agents, anti-fungal medications or agents, anesthetics, other therapeutic agents, insect repellents, fragrances and/or the like). In some embodiments, a climate conditioned bed additionally includes at least one humidity or moisture sensor and/or any other type of sensor that are intended to help prevent or reduce the likelihood of pressure ulcers can be selectively delivered to a patient through a conditioner mat or topper member. In other embodiments, such medicaments or other substances can be adapted to treat, mitigate or otherwise deal with any related symptoms.</p>
<p id="p0076" num="0076">In addition, in some embodiments, it may be beneficial to cycle the operation of one or more fluid modules to reduce noise and/or power consumption or to provide other benefits. For example, fluid modules can be cycled (e.g., turned on or off) to remain below such a threshold noise level or power consumption level. In some embodiments, the threshold or maximum noise level is determined by safety and health standards, other regulatory requirements, industry standards and/or the like. In other arrangements, an occupant is permitted to set the threshold or maximum noise level, at least to the extent provided by standards and other regulations, according to his or her own<!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --> preferences. Such a setting can be provided by the user to the climate control system (e.g., control module) using a user input device. Additional details for such power conservation and/or noise abatement embodiments are provided in <patcit id="pcit0006" dnum="US20825408" dnum-type="L"><text>U.S. Patent No. 12/208,254, filed September 10, 2008</text></patcit>, titled OPERATIONAL CONTROL SCHEMES FOR VENTILATED SEAT OR BED ASSEMBLIES and published on <patcit id="pcit0007" dnum="US20090064411A"><text>March 12, 2009 as U.S. Publication No. 2009/0064411</text></patcit>.</p>
<p id="p0077" num="0077">One embodiment of a control scheme for operation of one or more fluid modules configured to provide environmentally-conditioned (e.g., heated, cooled, dehumidified, etc.) and/or ambient air to a topper member or mat is schematically and generally represented by the wiring diagram 1500 illustrated in <figref idref="f0041">FIG. 34</figref>. As shown, in order to reduce power consumption of the climate controlled topper member, to improve its performance, enhance the occupant's comfort level and/or for any other purpose, the system's control unit 1510 (e.g., electronic control unit, control module, etc.) can be adapted to regulate the operation of a fluid module (e.g., a blower or other fluid transfer device, a thermoelectric device, a convective heater or other thermal conditioning device, etc.) and/or any other electric component of device of the system based on, at least in part, input from a moisture sensor 1530 and/or any other type of sensor (e.g., temperature sensor, pressure sensor, occupant-detection sensor, humidity sensor, condensation sensor, etc.). Such control schemes can help avoid excessive use of battery power, over cooling or over heating of the topper member and/or any other undesirable conditions.</p>
<p id="p0078" num="0078">With continued reference to the schematic of <figref idref="f0041">FIG. 34</figref>, a moisture sensor 1530 located on or near the topper member or the bed assembly on which the topper member is positioned can advantageously determine if excessive humidity or moisture is present near the occupant. Accordingly, the sensor 1530 can provide a corresponding feedback signal to the control unit 1510 in order to determine if, when and how the fluid module should be activated or deactivated. For example, is some embodiments, a fluid module can be operated only when a threshold level of moisture, humidity and/or temperature has been detected by one or more sensors 1530. Such a scheme can help extend the useful charge period of a battery or other power source 1520 that supplies electrical power to one or more fluid modules of the system. Such control schemes can also help ensure that potentially dangerous<!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --> and/or uncomfortable over-temperature or under-temperature conditions do not result when operating a climate controlled conditioner mat or topper member. In addition, such control methods, which in some arrangements incorporate one or more other devices or components (e.g., an electrical load detection device, an occupant detection switch or sensor 1550, other switches or sensors, etc.), can be incorporated into any of the topper embodiments disclosed herein.</p>
<p id="p0079" num="0079">In some embodiments, a climate-controlled mat or topper member can include a timer configured to regulate the fluid module(s) based on a predetermined time schedule. For example, such a timer feature can be configured to regulate when a blower or other fluid transfer device, a thermoelectric device, a convective heater or other thermal conditioning device and/or any other electrical device or component is turned on or off, modulated and/or the like. Such timer-controlled schemes can help reduce power consumption, enhance occupant safety, improve occupant comfort and/or provide any other advantage or benefit.</p>
<p id="p0080" num="0080">Relatedly, one or more of the components (e.g., fluid transfer device, thermoelectric device, etc.) that can be included in fluid modules, which supply air and other fluids to corresponding mats or topper members, can also be configured to cycle (e.g., turn on or off, modulate, etc.) according to a particular algorithm or protocol to achieve a desired level of power conservation. Regardless of whether the fluid module cycling is performed for noise reduction, power conservation and/or any other purpose, the individual components of a fluid module, such as, for example, a blower, fan or other fluid transfer device, a thermoelectric device, a convective heater and/or the like, can be controlled independently of each other.</p>
<p id="p0081" num="0081">Additional details regarding the incorporation of a separate HVAC system into an individualized climate control system (e.g., topper member), the injection of medicaments and/or other substances into a fluid stream and the cycling of fluid modules are provided in: <patcit id="pcit0008" dnum="US77534710" dnum-type="L"><text>U.S. Provisional Application No. 12/775,347, filed May 6, 2010</text></patcit> and titled CONTROL SCHEMES AND FEATURES FOR CLIMATE-CONTROLLED BEDS; <patcit id="pcit0009" dnum="US50535509" dnum-type="L"><text>U.S. Patent Application No. 12/505,355, filed July 17, 2009</text></patcit>, titled CLIMATE CONTROLLED BED ASSEMBLY and published on <patcit id="pcit0010" dnum="US20100011502A"><text>January 21, 2010 as U.S. Publication No.<!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --> 2010/0011502</text></patcit>; and <patcit id="pcit0011" dnum="US20825409" dnum-type="L"><text>U.S. Patent Application No. 12/208,254, filed September 10, 2009</text></patcit>, titled OPERATIONAL CONTROL SCHEMES FOR VENTILATED SEAT OR BED ASSEMBLIES and published on <patcit id="pcit0012" dnum="US20090064411A"><text>March 12, 2009 as U.S. Publication No. 2009/006441 1</text></patcit>.</p>
<p id="p0082" num="0082"><figref idref="f0028">FIGS. 19A</figref> and <figref idref="f0029">19B</figref> illustrate one embodiment of a fluid box 60 that is sized, shaped and otherwise designed to house one or more fluid modules 62A, 62B, 64A, 64B. The depicted fluid box 60 includes a total of four fluid modules within its interior I. As shown, the fluid modules are grouped into two pairs (e.g., a first module pair 62A, 62B and a second module pair 64A, 64B). In some embodiments, such as the one illustrated in <figref idref="f0029">FIG. 19B</figref>, the first pair (or other grouping) of fluid modules 62A, 62B is configured to selectively deliver ambient and/or environmentally-conditioned air to one side of a conditioner mat (see <figref idref="f0001">FIGS. 1</figref> and <figref idref="f0002">2</figref>), while the second pair (or other grouping) of fluid modules 64A, 64B is configured to selectively deliver ambient and/or environmentally-conditioned air to the opposite side of a conditioner mat. However, the quantity, spacing, orientation, grouping and/or other details associated with the inclusion of fluid modules within a fluid box can be different than illustrated and discussed herein, as desired or required. For example, each fluid module can be configured to deliver ambient and/or conditioned fluid into only a single fluid zone. In other arrangements, fluid exiting two or more modules can be combined and delivered simultaneously into one or more fluid zones of a conditioner mat.</p>
<p id="p0083" num="0083">With continued reference to <figref idref="f0029">FIG. 19B</figref>, the interior of a fluid box 60 can include one or more layers of insulating materials 68 that are configured to reduce temperature fluctuations within certain portions of the fluid box interior I and/or reduce the noise levels emanating from the fluid box 60 when the fluid modules are operating. In some embodiments, the fluid box can include one or more noise reduction layers, materials, devices or features, either in lieu of or in addition to thermal insulating materials. In some arrangements, the same layers, devices or members are used to provide a desired level of thermal insulation and a desired amount of noise reduction. As shown, a power supply 61, which provides electrical power to the fluid modules 62A, 62B, 64A, 64B and/or any other electrical component associated with the mat's climate control system, can be positioned within an interior I of the fluid box 60. Alternatively, the power supply 61 can be moved<!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --> outside the box 60 to avoid high heat conditions and other potentially damaging temperature fluctuations resulting from the operation of the fluid modules (e.g., fluid transfer devices, thermoelectric devices, etc.). For example, in one embodiment, the system includes a power supply 61 that is physically separated from the box or other enclosure. In such arrangements, one or more electrical cables, wires and/or other connections are provided to properly connect a power supply to the fluid modules and/or any other electrical components.</p>
<p id="p0084" num="0084">With continued reference to <figref idref="f0029">FIG. 19B</figref>, each thermoelectric housing 66, 67 and/or any other portion or component of the fluid module 62A, 62B, 64A, 64B can comprise its own outlet fitting 63A, 63B, 65A, 65B, which, in some embodiments, serves as an interface between the fluid transfer device and the conduit 72, 74 that places the corresponding fluid module in fluid communication with at least a portion of a conditioner mat or topper member. Various non-limiting embodiments, which do not form part of the invention, of an outlet fitting 63A-63E are illustrated in <figref idref="f0030">FIG. 21</figref>. As shown, the outlet fittings 63A-63E can include any shape, size, general configuration and/or other features or characteristics, as desired or required for a particular application or use. For example, two of the fittings 63B, 63D comprise bellows, while one of the fittings 63D is configured to accommodate a thermoelectric device.</p>
<p id="p0085" num="0085">In some embodiments, such as those illustrated in <figref idref="f0029">FIGS. 19B</figref> and <figref idref="f0030">20</figref>, the outlet fittings 63A, 63B, 65A, 65B comprise a thermoelectric device 66, 67 (or a convective heater or any other type of thermal conditioning device) positioned therein. Thus, air and other fluids passing from the respective fluid transfer devices to the outlet fittings can be advantageously heated or cooled, as desired or required. The waste air stream from the thermoelectric devices 66, 67 can be routed to the space generally outside the insulation layer 68 where it can be more effectively and conveniently eliminated from the outlet vents V2 located along the top of the fluid box 60. As shown in <figref idref="f0029">FIG. 19B</figref>, ambient air can be drawn into an interior I of the fluid box 60 through one or more inlet vents V1 located along the bottom of the box. Further, in order to increase the use of generally less-expensive, commercially-available materials, the downstream end of the outlet fittings 63A-63E (see, e.g., <figref idref="f0030">FIG. 21</figref>) can include standard 2,54 cm (1-inch) or 5,08 cm (2-inch) diameter rubber tubing or other commercially available conduits. This can help reduce manufacturing and maintenance costs. In other embodiments, however, one or more non-standard conduits can be used. In<!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --> addition, as shown in <figref idref="f0030">FIG. 20</figref>, a fluid box 60 can include a hinged door 69 or similar device to facilitate access to its interior I.</p>
<p id="p0086" num="0086">Another embodiment of a fluid box 60', which does not form part of the invention, is illustrated in <figref idref="f0031">FIGS. 22</figref>, <figref idref="f0032">23A and 23B</figref>. The depicted fluid box 60' is generally smaller than the box 60 of <figref idref="f0028">FIGS. 19A</figref> and <figref idref="f0029">19B</figref>. As illustrated in <figref idref="f0032">FIG. 23B</figref>, the fluid box 60' includes only a single fluid module 62'. Thus, such a smaller fluid box 60' can be utilized when the fluid demand for a conditioner mat or topper member is relatively small. The fluid box 60' can include one or more buttons 94 or other controllers that help regulate the operation of the fluid module(s) positioned therein. For example, in one embodiment, the box 60' includes a red button or other controller, which the user presses or otherwise manipulates to direct relatively warm air to the topper member, and a blue button or other controller, which the user presses or otherwise manipulates to direct relatively cool air to the topper member. A fluid box (or a separate controller or control panel) can include additional buttons, knobs, dials, keypads, touchscreens and/or other controllers, as desired.</p>
<p id="p0087" num="0087">With continued reference to <figref idref="f0031">FIG. 22</figref>, a channel 96 or other hooking device located along the rear surface of the fluid box 60' can help mount the box 60' to a headboard, footboard, a side rail, a side panel, a frame or other support structure and/or any other portion of a bed (e.g., hospital or medical bed, conventional bed, other type of bed, other seating assembly, etc.) and/or any other surface or location (e.g., wall, floor, an adjacent medical device, other hospital equipment, etc.).</p>
<p id="p0088" num="0088">In certain embodiments where fluid modules 62, 64 located within a single fluid box 60 are configured to both heat and cool a fluid being delivered to a conditioner mat, the waste streams of the respective thermoelectric devices 65, 66 can be used to help improve the overall thermal-conditioning efficiency of the system. For example, assuming that the first fluid module 62 schematically illustrated in <figref idref="f0033">FIG. 24</figref> is operating in a cooling mode, the waste fluid W1 exiting the first thermoelectric device 65 will be warm relative to ambient air. Thus, at least a portion of this relatively "warm" fluid stream can be directed into the inlet of the second fluid module 64, which is operating in a heating mode. Thus, it will be generally easier and more cost effective to heat the air exiting the second fluid module 64 under such a scheme (e.g., because the starting temperature of the fluid to be heated is generally higher<!-- EPO <DP n="40"> --> than ambient air). Likewise, the efficiency of the first fluid module 62 can be improved if a portion of the relatively cool waste fluid W2 exiting the second thermoelectric device 66 is directed to the inlet of the first fluid module 62.</p>
<p id="p0089" num="0089">As noted above and illustrated in <figref idref="f0034">FIG. 25</figref>, a conduit 72 that delivers thermally-conditioned fluid from the fluid modules (e.g., located within a fluid box) to a conditioner mat or topper member 20 can be partially or completed covered with one or more layers of thermal insulation 73. Such a configuration, which may be incorporated into any of the embodiments disclosed herein, can help reduce or prevent undesirable heat transfer (e.g., either to or from the fluid being delivered to the mat). As a result, the temperature of the fluids being delivered to the fluid zones of a mat or topper member can be more accurately maintained within the desired range.</p>
<p id="p0090" num="0090">In certain arrangements, two or more outlet fittings 63 can be used to deliver ambient and/or conditioned fluid from one or more fluid modules to an inlet of a conditioner mat 20. With reference to <figref idref="f0035">FIG. 26</figref>, such a dual conduit design can help reduce fluid headlosses through the system, thereby lowering the backpressure experienced by the blowers and other components of the fluid modules. With reference to <figref idref="f0036">FIG. 27</figref>, a fitting 76 can be used at the inlets of a conditioner mat or topper member 20. Such a fitting 76 can help prevent or reduce the likelihood of leaks as air or other fluid is transferred from the upstream conduit 72 to the mat 20. In addition, such a fitting 76 can make it easier for a user to connect (or disconnect) a mat from the upstream fluid delivery system (e.g., conduit 72). Such features can be incorporated into any of the mat or topper member embodiments disclosed herein.</p>
<p id="p0091" num="0091"><figref idref="f0037">FIGS. 28A-28C</figref> illustrate different embodiments, which do not form part of the invention, of ensuring that the desired volume or flowrate of fluid is delivered to each fluid zone of a conditioner mat or topper member. For example, in the arrangement depicted in <figref idref="f0037">FIG. 28A</figref>, the upstream fluid zone 34A (e.g., the fluid zone closest to the inlet fitting 76A) comprises a gate 51A at or near the interface of the fluid zone 34A and the main passage 32A. According to some embodiments, the gate 51A comprises one or more foam pieces or any other flow blocking or diversion members that can regulate the rate of fluid flowrate from the passage 32A to the upstream fluid zone 34A. The gate can include one or more other materials other than foam,<!-- EPO <DP n="41"> --> such as, for example, other polymeric or elastomeric materials, paper or wood-based materials, metals, alloys, composites, textiles, fabrics, other natural or synthetic materials and/or the like. In other embodiments, the gates are created by strategically attaching the upper and lower portions (e.g., using stitching, adhesives, hot melting, crimping, other fasteners, any other connection method or device) to each other, either in lieu of or in addition to including flow blocking or diverting members (e.g., foam or other materials, etc.). Thus, regardless of how the gates are configured, as flow into the upstream fluid zone 34A becomes restricted, more fluid will be delivered to downstream fluid zones (zone 36, see, e.g., <figref idref="f0001">FIGS. 1</figref>, <figref idref="f0002">2</figref>, <figref idref="f0004">4 and 5</figref>).</p>
<p id="p0092" num="0092">In <figref idref="f0037">FIG. 28B</figref>, the main passage 32B includes one or more fluid boundaries 33B that help ensure that a particular portion of the fluid entering the conditioner mat 20B enters the upstream fluid zone 34B. As discussed in greater detail herein, such fluid boundaries or nodes can be created using various devices or methods, such as, for example, hot melting, gluing or otherwise joining the upper and lower sheets of the mat together. Alternatively, in order to ensure more accurate flow balancing between the various fluid zones, separate passages (e.g., in the form of conduits) can be used to feed individual fluid zones.</p>
<p id="p0093" num="0093">Another embodiment of improving or enhancing flow balancing into the various fluid zones, which does not form part of the invention, is illustrated in <figref idref="f0037">FIG. 28C</figref>. As shown, the inlet fitting 76C can be positioned further into the passage 32C or conduit of the conditioner mat 20C or topper member. Such a feature can help direct additional fluid past the upstream fluid zone 34C and into downstream fluid zones, as fluid is less likely, hydraulically, to enter into the most upstream zone 34C. One or more additional ways of balancing fluid flow into the various fluid zones can also be used, either in lieu of or in addition to those specifically disclosed herein. For example, the quantity, size, shape, density, spacing and other details of the outlet openings located within each fluid zone can affect how well fluid flows are balanced. In some embodiments, the size (e.g., width, length, height, cross-sectional area, etc.), location and other details of the gates or other inlets into each of the gates can be adjustable, allowing a user to modify flow distribution according to a desired or required scheme. For example, in one embodiment, the length of a blocking member that helps define a gate 51A, 51B can be<!-- EPO <DP n="42"> --> shortened or lengthened (e.g., using a telescoping design, by removing or adding portions, etc.).</p>
<p id="p0094" num="0094"><figref idref="f0038">FIGS. 29A and 29B</figref> illustrate another embodiment of a conditioner mat, which does not form part of the invention, or topper member 1120 that is configured to be positioned, at least partially, along an upper portion of a medical bed, other type of bed or other seating assembly. As with other embodiments disclosed herein, the depicted conditioner mat 1120 comprises one or more fluid zones 1132, 1142 that are configured to selectively receive thermally or environmentally conditioned and/or unconditioned fluid (e.g., ambient, heated and/or cooled air from one or more fluid modules).</p>
<p id="p0095" num="0095">As illustrated in the partial perspective view of <figref idref="f0038">FIG. 29B</figref>, the conditioner mat 1120 can include one or more spacer material portions 1128A-1128E positioned between a generally fluid impermeable bottom layer 1124 (e.g., vinyl sheet or layer, tight-woven fabric, lining, etc.) and an upper scrim layer 1180. For clarity, at least some of the layers and other components of the mat 1120 are shown separated from each other in <figref idref="f0038">FIG. 29B</figref>. The generally fluid impermeable bottom layer 1124 and an upper scrim layer 1180 can be selectively and strategically attached to each other to form continuous or intermittent fluid barriers 1184 or borders that prevent or reduce the likelihood of fluid flow thereacross. Consequently, fluid zones, non-fluid zones, chambers, passages and other features can be advantageously provided within a conditioner mat 1120. According to certain arrangements, the barriers 1184 can be formed using stitching, fusion, adhesives, heat staking, other bonding agents or techniques and/or any other attachment method or device. Such fluid barriers 1184 can help direct fluid into targeted fluid zones, through specific passages or openings and/or as otherwise desired or required. For example, in the arrangement illustrated in <figref idref="f0038">FIGS. 29A and 29B</figref>, fluid barriers 1184 are used to create a plurality of passages 1128B-1128E located along the sides of the mat 1120.</p>
<p id="p0096" num="0096">With continued reference to <figref idref="f0038">FIGS. 29A and 29B</figref>, as with any other embodiments disclosed herein, the conditioner mat 1120 can additionally include a comfort layer 1190 and/or any other layer generally above (and/or below) the scrim layer 1180. Such an air permeable comfort layer 1190 (e.g., quilt layer, soft air permeable or perforated foam, etc.) can further enhance the comfort level of an occupant positioned along the top of the<!-- EPO <DP n="43"> --> conditioner mat 1120. In some arrangements, the scrim layer 1180, and/or any other layers or components positioned between the upper comfort layer 1190 and the spacer material 1128A-1128E (e.g., spacer fabric, air permeable structure, woven polyester or other material, etc.) or other fluid distribution member, are configured to help distribute the air or other fluid being delivered to the mat or topper member 1120. The use of heat staking, stitching, fusion, other types of bonding and/or any other attachment method or device can be incorporated into any embodiments of a conditioner mat or topper member disclosed herein, including those illustrated in <figref idref="f0001 f0002 f0003 f0004 f0005 f0006 f0007 f0008 f0009 f0010 f0011 f0012 f0013 f0014 f0015 f0016 f0017 f0018 f0019 f0020 f0021 f0022 f0023 f0024 f0025 f0026 f0027 f0028 f0029 f0030 f0031 f0032 f0033 f0034 f0035 f0036 f0037 f0038 f0039 f0040">FIGS. 1-33</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0097" num="0097">A partial perspective view of one embodiment of a spacer material 1200, which does not form part of the invention, configured for use in a conditioner mat or topper member is illustrated in <figref idref="f0039">FIG. 30</figref>. As shown, the spacer material 1200 can comprise one or more fluid permeable materials and/or structures. For example, the spacer material can include a spacer fabric, a porous foam, a honeycomb or other porous structure, other materials or members that are generally air permeable or that have an open structure through which fluids may pass and/or the like. As with the arrangement of <figref idref="f0038">FIGS. 29A and 29B</figref>, the spacer material or member 1200 depicted in <figref idref="f0039">FIG. 30</figref> can include one or more fluid barriers 1284 that are continuously or intermittently positioned so as to create separate fluid passageways 1212, 1214, 1222, 1224, fluid zones 1204, non-fluid zones and/or other fluid boundaries, as desired or required. The barriers 1284 can be formed using stitching, heat staking, adhesives, crimping, clips, other fasteners, bonding or other fusion techniques and/or the like. In some embodiments, which do not form part of the invention, as illustrated in <figref idref="f0039">FIG. 30</figref>, a mat comprises a spacer 1200 that includes generally tubular spacer members 1212, 1214, 1222, 1224 and/or generally flat spacer members 1204. The tubular spacer members, which in some arrangements serve as main conduits, can be positioned along the sides of the mat (as illustrated in <figref idref="f0039">FIG. 30</figref>) and/or any other mat portion (e.g., middle, away from the sides, etc.), as desired or required.</p>
<p id="p0098" num="0098">One embodiment of a fluid nozzle or other inlet 1300, which does not form part of the invention, configured to be used on a conditioner mat is illustrated in <figref idref="f0040">FIG. 31</figref>. As shown, the nozzle 1300 can extend along an edge (e.g., side) of a conditioner mat or topper member 20 so as to facilitate connection to (or disconnection from) a conduit (not shown) that places the mat 20 in fluid communication with one or more fluid modules. The nozzle 1300 can include a main portion<!-- EPO <DP n="44"> --> 1310, which in some embodiments, includes a generally cylindrical shape defining an interior space 1304. Along it exterior surface, the main portion 1310 can comprise one or more alignment and/or quick-connect features 1320 (e.g., tabs, other protrusions, slots, other recesses, etc.) that are shaped, sized and otherwise configured to generally mate with corresponding mating or engaging features on the conduit (not shown) to which the fluid nozzle 1300 can be selectively connected or disconnected.</p>
<p id="p0099" num="0099">Other embodiments of a fluid nozzle 1400 for a conditioner mat or topper member 20, which do not form part of the invention, are illustrated in <figref idref="f0040">FIGS. 32 and 33</figref>. As with the nozzle of <figref idref="f0040">FIG. 31</figref>, the depicted arrangements comprise a main portion 1410 which generally extends from an edge of the mat 20 and which comprises one or more alignment and/or quick-connect features 1420. In addition, as illustrated in the cross-sectional view of <figref idref="f0040">FIG. 33</figref>, the layers and/or other components of the conditioner mat 20 that define an interior space through which air is selectively delivered can be configured to properly locate and secure the nozzle 1400 thereon. For example, fluid boundaries or barriers 1484 (e.g., stitching, heat staking, bonding, etc.) can be used to form the opening through which the nozzle 1400 can extend.</p>
<p id="p0100" num="0100">As discussed herein, control of the fluid modules and/or any other components of a conditioner mat or topper member can be based, at least partially, on feedback received from one or more sensors. For example, a mat or topper member can include one or more thermal sensors, humidity sensors, condensation sensors, optical sensors, motion sensors, audible sensors, occupant detection sensors, other pressure sensors and/or the like. In some embodiments, such sensors can be positioned on or near a surface of the mat or topper member to determine whether cooling and/or heating of the assembly is required or desired. For instance, thermal sensors can help determine if the temperature at a surface of the mat is above or below a desired level. Alternatively, one or more thermal sensors and/or humidity sensors can be positioned in or near a fluid module, a fluid conduit (e.g., fluid passageway) and/or a layer of the upper portion of the topper member (e.g., fluid distribution member, comfort layer, etc.) to detect the temperature and/or humidity of the discharged fluid. Likewise, pressure sensors can be configured to detect when a user has been in contact with a surface of the bed for a prolonged time period. Depending on their type, sensors can contact a portion of the mat or the adjacent portion of the bed assembly on which the mat has<!-- EPO <DP n="45"> --> been situated. As discussed herein, in some embodiments, sensors are located within and/or on the surface of the mat or topper member. However, in other arrangements, the sensors are configured so they do not contact any portion of the mat at all. Such operational schemes can help detect conditions that are likely to result in pressure ulcers. In addition, such schemes can help conserve power, enhance comfort and provide other advantages. For additional details regarding the use of sensors, timers, control schemes and the like for climate controlled assemblies, refer to <patcit id="pcit0013" dnum="US20825408" dnum-type="L"><text>U.S. Patent Application No. 12/208,254, filed September 10, 2008</text></patcit>, titled OPERATIONAL CONTROL SCHEMES FOR VENTILATED SEAT OR BED ASSEMBLIES and published on <patcit id="pcit0014" dnum="US20090064411A"><text>March 12, 2009 as U.S. Publication No. 2009/0064411</text></patcit>, and <patcit id="pcit0015" dnum="US50535509" dnum-type="L"><text>U.S. Patent Application No. 12/505,355, filed July 17, 2009</text></patcit>, titled CLIMATE CONTROLLED BED ASSEMBLY and published on <patcit id="pcit0016" dnum="US20100011502A"><text>January 21, 2010 as U.S. Publication No. 2010/0011502</text></patcit>.</p>
<p id="p0101" num="0101">To assist in the description of the disclosed embodiments, words such as upward, upper, downward, lower, vertical, horizontal, upstream, downstream, top, bottom, soft, rigid, simple, complex and others have and used above to discuss various embodiments and to describe the accompanying figures. It will be appreciated, however, that the illustrated embodiments, can be located and oriented in a variety of desired positions, and thus, should not be limited by the use of such relative terms.</p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="46"> -->
<claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>A conditioner mat (20, 920) comprising:
<claim-text>an upper layer (22) comprising a plurality of openings;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a lower layer (26) that is substantially fluid impermeable, the upper and lower layers forming an enclosure defining an interior chamber;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first fluid zone (34) between the upper and lower layers, the first fluid zone comprising a first spacer material configured to maintain a desired separation between the upper and lower layers, the first spacer material configured to generally distribute fluid within the first fluid zone that exits through the plurality of openings (24) along the upper layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second fluid zone (36) between the upper and lower layers, the second fluid zone comprising a second spacer material configured to maintain a desired separation between the upper and lower layers, the second spacer material configured to generally distribute fluid within the second fluid zone that exits through the plurality of openings along the upper layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first fluid passage (32) in fluid communication with the first fluid zone and configured to direct fluid to first fluid zone, the first fluid passage formed within the enclosure by attaching the upper and lower layers;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second fluid passage (42) in fluid communication with the second fluid zone and configured to direct fluid to second fluid zone, the second fluid passage formed within the enclosure by attaching the upper and lower layers,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a non-fluid zone (50, 52) comprising a fluid impermeable member, the non-fluid zone between the upper and lower layers and between the first and second fluid zones, the fluid impermeable member configured to generally prevent fluid flow through the non-fluid zone;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fluid module comprising a fluid transfer device (382); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a conduit (384) connected between an outlet of the fluid module and the first or second fluid passage.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>The conditioner mat of claim 1, wherein the first fluid passage is configured to receive fluid from the fluid module via a first inlet fitting (76), and wherein the second fluid passage is configured to receive fluid from the fluid module via a second inlet fitting (78).<!-- EPO <DP n="47"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>The conditioner mat of claim 1, wherein the fluid module is positioned along a side of the conditioner mat, preferably wherein the fluid module is positioned within a fluid box (60, 880), the fluid box positioned along the side.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>The conditioner mat of claim 1, wherein the upper layer or the lower layer comprises one or more layers of foam.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>The conditioner mat of claim 1, wherein the non-fluid zone helps maintain a generally continuous thickness of the conditioner mat.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>The conditioner mat of claim 1, wherein at least one property or characteristic of the fluid entering the first fluid zone is different than a corresponding property or characteristic of the fluid entering the second fluid zone.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>The conditioner mat of claim 1 or 6, wherein each of the first fluid zone and the second fluid zone is supplied fluid by one or more dedicated fluid modules.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>The conditioner mat of claim 7, wherein the conduit comprises a first conduit and a second conduit, wherein the fluid module comprises a first fluid module and a second fluid module, and wherein the outlet comprises a first outlet of the first fluid module and a second outlet of the second fluid module, and wherein the first conduit is connected between the first outlet of the first fluid module and the first fluid passage, and the second conduit connected between the second outlet of the second fluid module and the second fluid passage.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>The conditioner mat of any one of claims 1 to 5, wherein the fluid module comprises a thermoelectric device (65, 66) configured to selectively heat or cool fluid being delivered to the first or second fluid zone.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>The conditioner mat of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the first and second fluid passages extend longitudinally along opposite sides of the conditioner mat.<!-- EPO <DP n="48"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>The conditioner mat of any one of the preceding claims, further comprising one or more fluid boundaries established by joining the upper and lower layers, the one or more fluid boundaries configured to control fluid flow within the first and second fluid passages.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>The conditioner mat of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the upper and lower layers comprise at least one of a plastic or a fabric.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>The conditioner mat of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the non-fluid zone comprises foam.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>The conditioner mat of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the upper and lower layers are separate members that are permanently or removably attached to each other.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims02" lang="de"><!-- EPO <DP n="49"> -->
<claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Klimatisierungsmatte (20, 920), umfassend:
<claim-text>eine obere Schicht (22), die eine Vielzahl von Öffnungen umfasst;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine untere Schicht (26), die im Wesentlichen fluidundurchlässig ist, wobei die obere und die untere Schicht eine Umhüllung bilden, die eine Innenkammer definiert;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine erste Fluidzone (34) zwischen der oberen und der unteren Schicht, wobei die erste Fluidzone ein erstes Abstandshaltermaterial umfasst, das dafür gestaltet ist, einen gewünschten Abstand zwischen der oberen und der unteren Schicht zu halten, wobei das erste Abstandshaltermaterial dafür gestaltet ist, allgemein Fluid in der ersten Fluidzone zu verteilen, das durch die Vielzahl von Öffnungen (24) entlang der oberen Schicht austritt;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine zweite Fluidzone (36) zwischen der oberen und der unteren Schicht, wobei die zweite Fluidzone ein zweites Abstandshaltermaterial umfasst, das dafür gestaltet ist, einen gewünschten Abstand zwischen der oberen und der unteren Schicht zu halten, wobei das zweite Abstandshaltermaterial dafür gestaltet ist, allgemein Fluid in der zweiten Fluidzone zu verteilen, das durch die Vielzahl von Öffnungen entlang der oberen Schicht austritt;</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen ersten Fluidkanal (32) in Fluidkommunikation mit der ersten Fluidzone, der dafür gestaltet ist, Fluid zu der ersten Fluidzone zu leiten, wobei der erste Fluidkanal innerhalb der Umhüllung durch Befestigen der oberen und der unteren Schicht gebildet wird;</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen zweiten Fluidkanal (42) in Fluidkommunikation mit der zweiten Fluidzone, der dafür gestaltet ist, Fluid zu der zweiten Fluidzone zu leiten, wobei der zweite Fluidkanal innerhalb der Umhüllung durch Befestigen der oberen und der unteren Schicht gebildet wird;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Nichtfluid-Zone (50, 52), umfassend ein fluidundurchlässiges Element umfasst, wobei die Nichtfluid-Zone zwischen der oberen und der unteren Schicht und zwischen der ersten und der zweiten Fluidzone liegt, wobei das<!-- EPO <DP n="50"> --> fluidundurchlässige Element dafür gestaltet ist, allgemein Fluidstrom durch die Nichtfluid-Zone zu verhindern;</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Fluidmodul, das eine Fluidüberführungsvorrichtung (382) umfasst; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Leitung (384), die zwischen einem Auslass des Fluidmoduls und dem ersten oder zweiten Fluidkanal angeordnet ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Klimatisierungsmatte gemäß Anspruch 1, wobei der erste Fluidkanal dafür gestaltet ist, Fluid von dem Fluidmodul über einen ersten Einlassanschluss (76) aufzunehmen, und wobei der zweite Fluidkanal dafür gestaltet ist, Fluid von dem Fluidmodul über einen zweiten Einlassanschluss (78) aufzunehmen.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Klimatisierungsmatte gemäß Anspruch 1, wobei das Fluidmodul entlang einer Seite der Klimatisierungsmatte angeordnet ist, wobei das Fluidmodul vorzugsweise in einem Fluidkasten (60, 880) angeordnet ist, wobei der Fluidkasten entlang der Seite angeordnet ist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Klimatisierungsmatte gemäß Anspruch 1, wobei die obere Schicht oder die untere Schicht eine oder mehrere Schichten aus Schaumstoff umfasst.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Klimatisierungsmatte gemäß Anspruch 1, wobei die Nichtfluid-Zone hilft, eine allgemein kontinuierliche Dicke der Klimatisierungsmatte aufrechtzuhalten.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Klimatisierungsmatte gemäß Anspruch 1, wobei wenigstens eine Eigenschaft oder Kenngröße des Fluids, das in die erste Fluidzone eintritt, von der entsprechenden Eigenschaft oder Kenngröße des Fluids, das in die zweite Fluidzone eintritt, verschieden ist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Klimatisierungsmatte gemäß Anspruch 1 oder 6, wobei jede von der ersten Fluidzone und der zweiten Fluidzone durch ein oder mehrere zugeordnete Fluidmodule mit Fluid versorgt wird.<!-- EPO <DP n="51"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>Klimatisierungsmatte gemäß Anspruch 7, wobei die Leitung eine erste Leitung und eine zweite Leitung umfasst, wobei das Fluidmodul ein erstes Fluidmodul und ein zweites Fluidmodul umfasst und wobei der Auslass einen ersten Auslass des ersten Fluidmoduls und einen zweiten Auslass des zweiten Fluidmoduls umfasst und wobei die erste Leitung zwischen dem ersten Auslass des ersten Fluidmoduls und dem ersten Fluidkanal verbunden ist und die zweite Leitung zwischen dem zweiten Auslass des zweiten Fluidmoduls und dem zweiten Fluidkanal verbunden ist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>Klimatisierungsmatte gemäß einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 5, wobei das Fluidmodul eine thermoelektrische Vorrichtung (65, 66) umfasst, die dafür gestaltet ist, Fluid, das der ersten oder der zweiten Fluidzone zugeführt wird, selektiv zu heizen oder zu kühlen.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>Klimatisierungsmatte gemäß einem der vorstehenden Ansprüche, wobei der erste und der zweite Fluidkanal in Längsrichtung entlang gegenüberliegender Seiten der Klimatisierungsmatte verlaufen.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>Klimatisierungsmatte gemäß einem der vorstehenden Ansprüche, ferner umfassend eine oder mehrere Fluidbegrenzungen, die durch Verbinden der oberen und der unteren Schicht gebildet werden, wobei die eine oder mehreren Fluidbegrenzungen dafür gestaltet sind, Fluidstrom innerhalb des ersten und des zweiten Fluidkanals zu steuern.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>Klimatisierungsmatte gemäß einem der vorstehenden Ansprüche, wobei die obere und die untere Schicht wenigstens eines von einem Kunststoff und einem Gewebe umfassen.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>Klimatisierungsmatte gemäß einem der vorstehenden Ansprüche, wobei die Nichtfluid-Zone Schaumstoff umfasst.<!-- EPO <DP n="52"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>Klimatisierungsmatte gemäß einem der vorstehenden Ansprüche, wobei die obere und die untere Schicht getrennte Elemente sind, die dauerhaft oder entfernbar aneinander befestigt sind.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims03" lang="fr"><!-- EPO <DP n="53"> -->
<claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Natte climatisante (20, 920) comprenant :
<claim-text>une couche supérieure (22) comprenant une pluralité d'ouvertures ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une couche inférieure (26) qui est sensiblement imperméable aux fluides, les couches supérieure et inférieure formant une enveloppe définissant une chambre intérieure ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une première zone de fluide (34) entre les couches supérieure et inférieure, la première zone de fluide comprenant un premier matériau d'espacement configuré pour maintenir une séparation souhaitée entre les couches supérieure et inférieure, le premier matériau d'espacement étant configuré pour distribuer généralement un fluide à l'intérieur de la première zone de fluide qui sort par la pluralité d'ouvertures (24) le long de la couche supérieure ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une deuxième zone de fluide (36) entre les couches supérieure et inférieure, la deuxième zone de fluide comprenant un deuxième matériau d'espacement configuré pour maintenir une séparation souhaitée entre les couches supérieure et inférieure, le deuxième matériau d'espacement étant configuré pour distribuer généralement un fluide à l'intérieur de la deuxième zone de fluide qui sort par la pluralité d'ouvertures le long de la couche supérieure ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un premier passage de fluide (32) en communication fluidique avec la première zone de fluide et configuré pour diriger un fluide jusqu'à la première zone de fluide, le premier passage de fluide étant formé à l'intérieur de l'enveloppe par fixation des couches supérieure et inférieure ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un deuxième passage de fluide (42) en communication fluidique avec la deuxième zone de fluide et configuré pour diriger un fluide jusqu'à la deuxième zone de fluide, le deuxième passage de fluide étant formé à l'intérieur de l'enveloppe par fixation des couches supérieure et inférieure ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une zone sans fluide (50, 52) comprenant un élément imperméable aux fluides, la zone sans fluide se situant entre les couches supérieure et inférieure et entre les première et deuxième zones de fluide, l'élément imperméable aux fluides étant<!-- EPO <DP n="54"> --> configuré pour empêcher généralement un écoulement de fluide à travers la zone sans fluide ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un module de fluide comprenant un dispositif de transfert de fluide (382) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une conduite (384) branchée entre une sortie du module de fluide et le premier ou deuxième passage de fluide.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Natte climatisante de la revendication 1, dans laquelle le premier passage de fluide est configuré pour recevoir un fluide provenant du module de fluide par le biais d'un premier raccord d'entrée (76), et dans laquelle le deuxième passage de fluide est configuré pour recevoir un fluide provenant du module de fluide par le biais d'un deuxième raccord d'entrée (78).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Natte climatisante de la revendication 1, dans laquelle le module de fluide est positionné le long d'un côté de la natte climatisante, de préférence dans laquelle le module de fluide est positionné à l'intérieur d'une boîte à fluide (60, 880), la boîte à fluide étant positionnée le long du côté.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Natte climatisante de la revendication 1, dans laquelle la couche supérieure ou la couche inférieure comprend une ou plusieurs couches de mousse.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Natte climatisante de la revendication 1, dans laquelle la zone sans fluide aide à maintenir une épaisseur généralement continue de la natte climatisante.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Natte climatisante de la revendication 1, dans laquelle au moins une propriété ou caractéristique du fluide entrant dans la première zone de fluide est différente d'une propriété ou caractéristique correspondante du fluide entrant dans la deuxième zone de fluide.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Natte climatisante de la revendication 1 ou 6, dans laquelle la première zone de fluide et la deuxième zone de fluide sont chacune alimentées en fluide par un ou plusieurs modules de fluide dédiés.<!-- EPO <DP n="55"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>Natte climatisante de la revendication 7, dans laquelle la conduite comprend une première conduite et une deuxième conduite, dans laquelle le module de fluide comprend un premier module de fluide et un deuxième module de fluide, et dans laquelle la sortie comprend une première sortie du premier module de fluide et une deuxième sortie du deuxième module de fluide, et dans laquelle la première conduite est branchée entre la première sortie du premier module de fluide et le premier passage de fluide, et la deuxième conduite branchée entre la deuxième sortie du deuxième module de fluide et le deuxième passage de fluide.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>Natte climatisante de l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 5, dans laquelle le module de fluide comprend un dispositif thermoélectrique (65, 66) configuré pour chauffer ou refroidir sélectivement un fluide distribué à la première ou deuxième zone de fluide.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>Natte climatisante de l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans laquelle les premier et deuxième passages de fluide s'étendent longitudinalement le long de côtés opposés de la natte climatisante.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>Natte climatisante de l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, comprenant en outre une ou plusieurs limites de fluide établies par assemblage des couches supérieure et inférieure, la ou les limites de fluide étant configurées pour contrôler l'écoulement de fluide à l'intérieur des premier et deuxième passages de fluide.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>Natte climatisante de l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans laquelle les couches supérieure et inférieure comprennent un plastique et/ou un tissu.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>Natte climatisante de l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans laquelle la zone sans fluide comprend de la mousse.<!-- EPO <DP n="56"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>Natte climatisante de l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans laquelle les couches supérieure et inférieure sont des éléments séparés qui sont fixés l'un à l'autre de façon permanente ou amovible.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="57"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="145" he="201" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="58"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="128" he="218" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="59"> -->
<figure id="f0003" num="3A,3B,3C"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="151" he="220" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="60"> -->
<figure id="f0004" num="4,5"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="138" he="156" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="61"> -->
<figure id="f0005" num="6,7"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="132" he="213" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="62"> -->
<figure id="f0006" num="8,9"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="134" he="209" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="63"> -->
<figure id="f0007" num="10A"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="148" he="208" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="64"> -->
<figure id="f0008" num="10B"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="149" he="220" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="65"> -->
<figure id="f0009" num="11A"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="148" he="213" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="66"> -->
<figure id="f0010" num="11B"><img id="if0010" file="imgf0010.tif" wi="140" he="195" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="67"> -->
<figure id="f0011" num="12A"><img id="if0011" file="imgf0011.tif" wi="147" he="214" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="68"> -->
<figure id="f0012" num="12B"><img id="if0012" file="imgf0012.tif" wi="149" he="220" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="69"> -->
<figure id="f0013" num="13A"><img id="if0013" file="imgf0013.tif" wi="146" he="215" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="70"> -->
<figure id="f0014" num="13B"><img id="if0014" file="imgf0014.tif" wi="151" he="203" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="71"> -->
<figure id="f0015" num="14"><img id="if0015" file="imgf0015.tif" wi="130" he="139" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="72"> -->
<figure id="f0016" num="15"><img id="if0016" file="imgf0016.tif" wi="76" he="169" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="73"> -->
<figure id="f0017" num="16A"><img id="if0017" file="imgf0017.tif" wi="78" he="169" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="74"> -->
<figure id="f0018" num="16B"><img id="if0018" file="imgf0018.tif" wi="141" he="161" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="75"> -->
<figure id="f0019" num="16C"><img id="if0019" file="imgf0019.tif" wi="149" he="161" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="76"> -->
<figure id="f0020" num="16D"><img id="if0020" file="imgf0020.tif" wi="149" he="161" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="77"> -->
<figure id="f0021" num="17A,17B"><img id="if0021" file="imgf0021.tif" wi="143" he="181" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="78"> -->
<figure id="f0022" num="17C,17D"><img id="if0022" file="imgf0022.tif" wi="145" he="224" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="79"> -->
<figure id="f0023" num="18A"><img id="if0023" file="imgf0023.tif" wi="107" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="80"> -->
<figure id="f0024" num="18B"><img id="if0024" file="imgf0024.tif" wi="114" he="158" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="81"> -->
<figure id="f0025" num="18C"><img id="if0025" file="imgf0025.tif" wi="128" he="135" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="82"> -->
<figure id="f0026" num="18D"><img id="if0026" file="imgf0026.tif" wi="90" he="167" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="83"> -->
<figure id="f0027" num="18E"><img id="if0027" file="imgf0027.tif" wi="86" he="180" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="84"> -->
<figure id="f0028" num="19A"><img id="if0028" file="imgf0028.tif" wi="118" he="181" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="85"> -->
<figure id="f0029" num="19B"><img id="if0029" file="imgf0029.tif" wi="128" he="189" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="86"> -->
<figure id="f0030" num="20,21"><img id="if0030" file="imgf0030.tif" wi="133" he="223" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="87"> -->
<figure id="f0031" num="22"><img id="if0031" file="imgf0031.tif" wi="92" he="120" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="88"> -->
<figure id="f0032" num="23A,23B"><img id="if0032" file="imgf0032.tif" wi="147" he="172" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="89"> -->
<figure id="f0033" num="24"><img id="if0033" file="imgf0033.tif" wi="124" he="169" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="90"> -->
<figure id="f0034" num="25"><img id="if0034" file="imgf0034.tif" wi="141" he="203" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="91"> -->
<figure id="f0035" num="26"><img id="if0035" file="imgf0035.tif" wi="141" he="206" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="92"> -->
<figure id="f0036" num="27"><img id="if0036" file="imgf0036.tif" wi="132" he="196" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="93"> -->
<figure id="f0037" num="28A,28B,28C"><img id="if0037" file="imgf0037.tif" wi="127" he="227" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="94"> -->
<figure id="f0038" num="29A,29B"><img id="if0038" file="imgf0038.tif" wi="140" he="221" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="95"> -->
<figure id="f0039" num="30"><img id="if0039" file="imgf0039.tif" wi="149" he="121" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="96"> -->
<figure id="f0040" num="31,32,33"><img id="if0040" file="imgf0040.tif" wi="131" he="199" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="97"> -->
<figure id="f0041" num="34"><img id="if0041" file="imgf0041.tif" wi="140" he="152" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<ep-reference-list id="ref-list">
<heading id="ref-h0001"><b>REFERENCES CITED IN THE DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0001" num=""><i>This list of references cited by the applicant is for the reader's convenience only. It does not form part of the European patent document. Even though great care has been taken in compiling the references, errors or omissions cannot be excluded and the EPO disclaims all liability in this regard.</i></p>
<heading id="ref-h0002"><b>Patent documents cited in the description</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0002" num="">
<ul id="ref-ul0001" list-style="bullet">
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0001" dnum="US61238655" dnum-type="L"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>61238655</doc-number><date>20090831</date></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0001">[0001]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0002" dnum="EP878150A2"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>878150</doc-number><kind>A2</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0002">[0006]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0003" dnum="US20050086739A1"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>20050086739</doc-number><kind>A1</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0003">[0006]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0004" dnum="US04707705" dnum-type="L"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>04707705</doc-number><date>20050131</date></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0004">[0013]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0005" dnum="US758790A" dnum-type="L"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>758790</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20090915</date></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0005">[0013]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0006" dnum="US20825408" dnum-type="L"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>20825408</doc-number><date>20080910</date></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0006">[0076]</crossref><crossref idref="pcit0013">[0100]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0007" dnum="US20090064411A"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>20090064411</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20090312</date></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0007">[0076]</crossref><crossref idref="pcit0012">[0081]</crossref><crossref idref="pcit0014">[0100]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0008" dnum="US77534710" dnum-type="L"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>77534710</doc-number><date>20100506</date></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0008">[0081]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0009" dnum="US50535509" dnum-type="L"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>50535509</doc-number><date>20090717</date></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0009">[0081]</crossref><crossref idref="pcit0015">[0100]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0010" dnum="US20100011502A"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>20100011502</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20100121</date></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0010">[0081]</crossref><crossref idref="pcit0016">[0100]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0011" dnum="US20825409" dnum-type="L"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>20825409</doc-number><date>20090910</date></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0011">[0081]</crossref></li>
</ul></p>
</ep-reference-list>
</ep-patent-document>
