<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP11751320B1" file="EP11751320NWB1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="2543072" kind="B1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSK..HRIS..MTNORS..SM..................</B001EP><B003EP>*</B003EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  2100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>2543072</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT SPECIFICATION</B121></B120><B130>B1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>11751320.0</B210><B220><date>20110302</date></B220><B240><B241><date>20120927</date></B241><B242><date>20190605</date></B242></B240><B250>en</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B300><B310>309824 P</B310><B320><date>20100302</date></B320><B330><ctry>US</ctry></B330></B300><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20130109</date><bnum>201302</bnum></B430><B450><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B450><B452EP><date>20210517</date></B452EP></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>H01L  29/78        20060101AFI20210413BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="2"><text>H01L  21/336       20060101ALI20210413BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="3"><text>H01L  29/40        20060101ALI20210413BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="4"><text>H01L  29/417       20060101ALI20210413BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="5"><text>H01L  29/423       20060101ALI20210413BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>H01L  29/4238      20130101 LI20170413BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>H01L  29/407       20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="3"><text>H01L  29/66734     20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="4"><text>H01L  29/41741     20130101 LI20170413BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="5"><text>H01L  29/7813      20130101 FI20130101BHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>STRUKTUREN UND VERFAHREN ZUR HERSTELLUNG VON DOPPELGATE-VORRICHTUNGEN</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>STRUCTURES AND METHODS OF FABRICATING DUAL GATE DEVICES</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>STRUCTURES ET PROCÉDÉS DE FABRICATION DE DISPOSITIFS À DEUX GRILLES</B542></B540><B560><B561><text>WO-A1-02/099909</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2007 004 116</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2008 199 997</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2009 057 756</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2009 057 756</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2009 140 327</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2009 200 578</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2009 309 156</text></B561><B561><text>US-B2- 6 653 691</text></B561><B561><text>US-B2- 7 009 247</text></B561><B565EP><date>20160203</date></B565EP></B560></B500><B700><B720><B721><snm>TERRILL, Kyle</snm><adr><str>3385 Londonderry Drive</str><city>Santa Clara
California 95050</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>BAI, Yuming</snm><adr><str>34761 Klondike Drive</str><city>Union City,
California 94587</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>PATTANAYAK, Deva N.</snm><adr><str>19123 Brookhaven Drive</str><city>Saratoga,
California 95070</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>LUO, Zhiyun</snm><adr><str>1473 Shaffer Drive</str><city>San Jose
California 95132</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B730><B731><snm>Vishay-Siliconix</snm><iid>100250108</iid><irf>M 11 037</irf><adr><str>2201 Laurelwood Road</str><city>Santa Clara,
California 95054</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B731></B730><B740><B741><snm>Richards, John</snm><iid>100016366</iid><adr><str>Ladas &amp; Parry LLP</str><city>Temple Chambers
3-7 Temple Avenue
London EC4Y 0DA</city><ctry>GB</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840><B860><B861><dnum><anum>US2011026925</anum></dnum><date>20110302</date></B861><B862>en</B862></B860><B870><B871><dnum><pnum>WO2011109559</pnum></dnum><date>20110909</date><bnum>201136</bnum></B871></B870><B880><date>20111222</date><bnum>000000</bnum></B880></B800></SDOBI>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<heading id="h0001">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p0001" num="0001">To conserve power, it is important to reduce power losses in transistors. In a metal oxide semiconductor field effect transistor (MOSFET) device, power losses can be reduced by reducing the device's drain-to-source on-resistance.</p>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">In order to achieve a high breakdown voltage in a MOS device, the epitaxial (epi) layer and/or resistivity can be increased, but this can detrimentally affect on-resistance. To alleviate that problem, a modulated electric field that is vertical to the direction of the current when the device is off can be introduced. A modulated electric field in the drift region increases the breakdown voltage and allows for higher doping concentration for a given breakdown voltage relative to a more conventional MOS device. One way to generate such an electric field is to include a "split gate" alongside the drift region. In a split gate structure, a MOS structure (e.g., trench) is created alongside the drift region. A shielded polysilicon (poly) region, which is connected to the source, is placed under the gate poly inside the trench, and the gate structure is built on top of the trench. Split gate structures offer a number of advantages, including better switching and breakdown voltage and lower on-resistance, but are difficult to manufacture.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p>
<p id="p0003" num="0003"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US6653691B"><text>US6653691</text></patcit> provides integrated power devices include a plurality of field effect transistor unit cells and a Faraday shield layer that reduces parasitic gate-to-drain capacitance (Cgd) and concomitantly improves high frequency switching performance. These power devices may include a field effect transistor in an active portion of a semiconductor substrate and a gate electrode that is electrically connected to a gate of the field effect transistor. A Faraday shield layer is provided between at least a first portion of the gate electrode and a drain of the field effect transistor in order to capacitively decouple the first portion of the gate electrode from the drain. The gate electrode and drain typically extend adjacent opposing faces of the semiconductor substrate. The Faraday shield layer is preferably electrically connected to a source of the field effect transistor and provides edge termination.</p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004"><patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="US2009200578A"><text>US2009/200578</text></patcit> provides a self-repairing field effect transistor (FET) device, in accordance with one embodiment, includes a plurality of FET cells each having a fuse link. The fuse links are adapted to blow during a high current event in a corresponding cell.</p>
<p id="p0005" num="0005"><patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="US2009140327A"><text>US 2009/140327</text></patcit> provides a vertical trench MOSFET comprising an N type epitaxial region formed on an upper surface of an N<sup>+</sup> type substrate having a drain electrode on a lower surface thereof; a gate trench extending from a front surface into the N type epitaxial region; a gate electrode positioned in the gate trench so as to interpose an insulator; a channel region formed on the N type epitaxial region; a source region formed on the channel region; a source electrode formed on the source region; a source trench extending from the front surface into the N type epitaxial region; and a trench-buried source electrode positioned in the source trench so as to interpose an insulator, wherein the source electrode contacts with the trench-buried source electrode.</p>
<p id="p0006" num="0006"><patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="US7009247B"><text>US7009247</text></patcit> provides a trench MIS device including a thick dielectric layer at the bottom of the trench. The thick dielectric layer can be formed by the deposition or thermal growth of a dielectric material, such as silicon dioxide, on the bottom portion of the trench. The thick dielectric layer, which reduces the capacitance between the drain and gate of the device, can be formed in both the active areas of the device, where the switching function is performed, and in the inactive areas where, among other things, contacts are made to the gate electrode.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p>
<heading id="h0002">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">Accordingly, an improved fabrication method, and a device that lends itself to the improved method and provides advantages such as those associated with split gate devices, would be valuable.</p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">The invention is defined by the enclosed claims.</p>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">In one embodiment of this presentation, first polysilicon (poly-1) is deposited into deep trenches that have been formed in a substrate. A first polysilicon polishing process is performed to planarize the exposed surfaces of the poly-1 so that the surfaces are flush with adjacent surfaces. Then, shallow trenches are formed in the substrate between the deep trenches, and second polysilicon (poly-2) is deposited into the shallow trenches. A second polysilicon polishing process is performed to planarize the exposed surface of the poly-2 so that the surface is flush with adjacent surfaces.</p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">More specifically, in the claimed invention a first oxide layer is formed inside the deep trenches and over the mesas between the deep trenches, and then poly-1 is deposited into the deep trenches. A first polysilicon polishing process is performed to remove at least some of the poly-1, and an oxide polishing process is also performed to remove at least some of the first oxide layer from over the mesa, to form an even surface. After the first polysilicon polishing and oxide polishing processes, shallow trenches are formed in the mesa between the deep trenches. A second oxide layer is formed inside the shallow trenches and over the mesas between the deep and shallow trenches. Poly-2 is then deposited into the shallow trenches. A second polysilicon polishing process is performed to remove at least some of the poly-2.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">A first metal contact to the poly-1 and a second metal contact to the poly-2 can then be formed. The first metal contact is directly over and in contact with the poly-1, and the second metal contact is directly over and in contact with the poly-2. In one embodiment, the first metal contact is part of a first metal layer and the second metal contact is part of a second metal layer, where the first and second metal layers are in the same surface plane but are physically isolated from one another.</p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">Accordingly, in one embodiment, a semiconductor device - e.g., a dual gate structure - is formed. Such a device includes source trenches and gate trenches formed parallel to one another in alternating fashion in a substrate. The gate trenches are shallower than the source trenches. A source contact is coupled to poly-1 in the source trenches at one end of the source trenches. The source contact is directly over and in contact with the surfaces of the poly-1. A gate contact is coupled to poly-2 in the gate trenches at one end of the gate trenches (the source and gate contacts are formed at opposite ends of the trenches). The gate contact is directly over and in contact with the surfaces of the poly-2. As a result of the first and second polysilicon polishing processes, the surfaces of the poly-1 and poly-2 are flush with adjacent surfaces (e.g., flush with the mesas formed by the gate and source trenches). The source contact is part of a first metal layer and the gate contact is part of a second metal layer. The first and second metal layers are physically isolated from one another and in the same surface plane.</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">In one embodiment, the first and second polysilicon polishing processes and the oxide polishing process are chemical mechanical polishing (CMP) processes. The use of CMP facilitates the manufacture of devices such as dual<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> gate structures. The use of CMP allows for planarization of the polysilicon inside the source and gate trenches and the oxide at the top of each source trench, which results in better control over the structure and improved process margins, thereby improving performance. For example, planarization improves the depth of focus during photolithography. As a result, material can be deposited more accurately and uniformly, and shallower trenches can be formed. Consequently, device features can be scaled to smaller dimensions.</p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">These and other objects and advantages of the present invention will be recognized by one skilled in the art after having read the following detailed description, which are illustrated in the various drawing figures.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p>
<heading id="h0003">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">The accompanying drawings, which are incorporated in and form a part of this specification, illustrate embodiments of the invention and, together with the description, serve to explain the principles of the invention. Like numbers denote like elements throughout the drawings and specification.
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
<li><figref idref="f0001">Figure 1</figref> is a top-down view of one embodiment of a semiconductor device in accordance with the present invention.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">Figures 2, 3</figref>, <figref idref="f0003">4, 5</figref>, and <figref idref="f0004">6</figref> are cross-sectional views along various axes showing elements of a semiconductor device according to embodiments of the present invention.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0004">Figures 7A</figref> and <figref idref="f0005">7B</figref> illustrate a flowchart of a process that is used to fabricate semiconductor devices according to embodiments of the present invention.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0006">Figures 8, 9</figref>, <figref idref="f0007">10, 11</figref>, <figref idref="f0008">12, 13</figref>, <figref idref="f0009">14, 15</figref>, <figref idref="f0010">16, and 17</figref> are cross-sectional views showing selected stages in the fabrication of a semiconductor device according to embodiments of the present invention.</li>
</ul><!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p>
<heading id="h0004">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">In the following detailed description of the present invention, numerous specific details are set forth in order to provide a thorough understanding of the present invention. However, it will be recognized by one skilled in the art that the present invention may be practiced without these specific details. In other instances, well-known methods, procedures, components, and circuits have not been described in detail as not to unnecessarily obscure aspects of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">Some portions of the detailed descriptions that follow are presented in terms of procedures, logic blocks, processing, and other symbolic representations of operations for fabricating semiconductor devices. These descriptions and representations are the means used by those skilled in the art of semiconductor device fabrication to most effectively convey the substance of their work to others skilled in the art. In the present application, a procedure, logic block, process, or the like, is conceived to be a self-consistent sequence of steps or instructions leading to a desired result. The steps are those requiring physical manipulations of physical quantities. It should be borne in mind, however, that all of these and similar terms are to be associated with the appropriate physical quantities and are merely convenient labels applied to these quantities. Unless specifically stated otherwise as apparent from the following discussions, it is appreciated that throughout the present application, discussions utilizing terms such as "forming," "performing," "producing," "depositing," "growing," "etching" or the like, refer to actions and processes of semiconductor device fabrication.</p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">The figures are not drawn to scale, and only portions of the structures, as<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> well as the various layers that form those structures, may be shown in the figures. Furthermore, fabrication processes and steps may be performed along with the processes and steps discussed herein; that is, there may be a number of process steps before, in between and/or after the steps shown and described herein. Importantly, embodiments in accordance with the present invention can be implemented in conjunction with these other (perhaps conventional) processes and steps without significantly perturbing them. Generally speaking, embodiments in accordance with the present invention can replace portions of a conventional process without significantly affecting peripheral processes and steps.</p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">As used herein, the letter "n" refers to an n-type dopant and the letter "p" refers to a p-type dopant. A plus sign "+" or a minus sign "-" may be used to represent, respectively, a relatively high or relatively low concentration of the dopant.</p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">Some of the figures are discussed in the context of one type of device; however, embodiments according to the present invention are not so limited. That is, the features described herein can be utilized in either an n-channel device or a p-channel device. The discussion of one type of device can be readily mapped to another type of device by substituting p-type dopant and materials for corresponding n-type dopant and materials, and vice versa.</p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021"><figref idref="f0001">Figure 1</figref> is a top-down view of one embodiment of a semiconductor device 100 in accordance with the present invention. The semiconductor device 100 may be generally referred to as a dual gate structure. The semiconductor device 100 may be implemented as a metal-insulator-semiconductor (MIS)<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> device.</p>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">In <figref idref="f0001">Figure 1</figref>, multiple levels or layers of the semiconductor device 100 are illustrated. The structure illustrated in <figref idref="f0001">Figure 1</figref> includes a number of parallel trenches exemplified by the first trench 111 and the second trench 112, known as source trenches. A third trench 113, known as a gate trench, is between and parallel to the first and second trenches. There may be any number of source trenches, with a gate trench between each pair of source trenches. As described below, the trenches 111, 112, and 113 are lined with an oxide and then filled with polysilicon.</p>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">A first metal layer 121 is formed over one end of the trenches, and a second metal layer 122 is formed over the other end of the trenches, as shown in <figref idref="f0001">Figure 1</figref>. The first and second metal layers are in the same surface plane but are physically isolated from one another.</p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">The first metal layer 121 is known as the source metal layer. The source metal layer 121 is in contact with the polysilicon in the source trenches 111 and 112 at the locations identified as 131 and 132. Contact between the source metal layer 121 is directly over the polysilicon in the source trenches.</p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">The second metal layer 122 is known as the gate metal layer. The gate metal layer 122 is in contact with the polysilicon in the gate trench 113 at the location identified as 133. Contact between the gate metal layer 122 is directly over the polysilicon in the gate trenches. In one embodiment, the widths of the gate trenches are greater at the ends of the trenches that are under the second metal layer 122. That is, the gate trenches flare outward where they make<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> contact with the gate metal layer. The gate trenches are wider than the gate contact, as shown in <figref idref="f0001">Figure 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026"><figref idref="f0002">Figure 2</figref> is a cross-sectional view along the cut line A-A shown in <figref idref="f0001">Figure 1</figref>. The portion of the structure 100 shown in <figref idref="f0002">Figure 2</figref> includes source trenches 111 and 112, as well as additional source trenches (not labeled), and gate trench 113, as well as additional gate trenches (not labeled).</p>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">In the <figref idref="f0002">Figure 2</figref> embodiment, the source and gate trenches are formed in a laminate or substrate that includes an n+ region 210 and an n-doped epitaxial region 220. The source trenches are deeper than the gate trenches; the source trenches extend through the epitaxial region 220 and into the n+ region 210, while the gate trenches do not.</p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">The source and gate trenches are lined with an oxide layer 230. P-body regions, such as p-body region 240, may also be formed in the substrate between the source and gate trenches. Source regions, such as source region 250, are formed in the substrate between the source and gate trenches. A drain region (not shown) may be implemented as a layer below the n+ region 210.</p>
<p id="p0029" num="0029">In the example of <figref idref="f0002">Figure 2</figref>, the source regions are continuous n+ regions. However, in one embodiment, the n+ source regions are separated by p+ regions 350, as shown in <figref idref="f0002">Figure 3</figref>. The n+ source regions 250 and p+ regions 350 alternate with one another as shown in <figref idref="f0002">Figure 3</figref>. That is, n+ source regions 250 are located between p+ regions 350, and p+ regions are located between n+ source regions. The p+ regions 350 are used to provide electrical contact to the<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> p-body regions 240. Accordingly, the same source metal layer can be in electrical contact with both the p+ body regions 240 (via the p+ regions 350) and the n+ source regions 250.</p>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">As will be discussed in more detail below, the top surfaces of the polysilicon 260 (<figref idref="f0002">Figure 2</figref>) in the source and gate trenches, and the exposed surfaces of the oxide layers 230 at the top of the source trenches, are flush with the mesas that are between the trenches. This provides a number of benefits, also discussed below.</p>
<p id="p0031" num="0031">At the end of the structure 100 shown in <figref idref="f0002">Figure 2</figref> (that is, in the region that is under the gate metal layer 122; see <figref idref="f0001">Figure 1</figref>), oxide regions 270 are formed over the source trenches and over the mesas between the source trenches and the gate trenches, but not over the gate trenches, leaving the polysilicon 260 in the gate trenches exposed to the gate metal layer 122. Accordingly, the gate metal layer 122 can make physical and electrical contact with the polysilicon in the gate trenches, as exemplified by the gate metal contact at 133.</p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032"><figref idref="f0003">Figure 4</figref> is a cross-sectional view along the cut line B-B shown in <figref idref="f0001">Figure 1</figref>. The portion of the structure 100 shown in <figref idref="f0003">Figure 4</figref> includes the gate trench 113, source metal layer 121, gate metal layer 122, epitaxial region 220, and n+ region 210. The source and gate metal layers are in the same surface plane.</p>
<p id="p0033" num="0033">An oxide layer 410 covers the gate trenches except for a portion of the gate trenches that is under the gate metal layer 122, leaving the polysilicon 260 in the gate trenches exposed to the gate metal layer. Accordingly, the gate<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> metal layer 122 makes physical and electrical contact with the polysilicon 260 in the gate trenches, as exemplified by the gate metal contact at 133.</p>
<p id="p0034" num="0034"><figref idref="f0003">Figure 5</figref> is a cross-sectional view along the cut line C-C shown in <figref idref="f0001">Figure 1</figref>. The portion of the structure 100 shown in <figref idref="f0003">Figure 5</figref> includes source trenches 111 and 112, as well as additional source trenches (not labeled), and gate trench 113, as well as additional gate trenches (not labeled).</p>
<p id="p0035" num="0035">As will be discussed in more detail below, the top surfaces of the polysilicon 260 in the source and gate trenches, and the exposed surfaces of the oxide layers 230, are flush with the mesas that are between the trenches. This provides a number of benefits, also discussed below.</p>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">At the end of the structure 100 shown in <figref idref="f0003">Figure 5</figref> (that is, in the region that is under the source metal layer 121; see <figref idref="f0001">Figure 1</figref>), oxide regions 570 are formed over the gate trenches but not over the source trenches. Also, the oxide regions 570 are formed over the n+ source regions in the termination regions, but not over the n+ source regions in the active region. As a result, the polysilicon 260 in the source trenches, and the n+ source regions (e.g., n+ source region 250) in the active region, are exposed to the source metal layer 121. Accordingly, the source metal layer 121 makes physical and electrical contact with the polysilicon in the source trenches and with the n+ source regions, as exemplified by the source metal contact at 131 and 132.</p>
<p id="p0037" num="0037"><figref idref="f0004">Figure 6</figref> is a cross-sectional view along the cut line D-D shown in <figref idref="f0001">Figure 1</figref>. The portion of the structure 100 shown in <figref idref="f0004">Figure 6</figref> includes the source trench 111, source metal layer 121, gate metal layer 122, and n+ region 210. The<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> source and gate metal layers are in the same surface plane.</p>
<p id="p0038" num="0038">An oxide layer 610 covers the source trenches except for a portion of the trenches that is under the source metal layer 121, leaving the polysilicon 260 in the source trenches exposed to the source metal layer. Accordingly, the source metal layer 121 makes physical and electrical contact with the polysilicon 260 in the source trenches, as exemplified by the source metal contact at 131.</p>
<p id="p0039" num="0039"><figref idref="f0004">Figures 7A</figref> and <figref idref="f0005">7B</figref> illustrate a flowchart 700 of one embodiment of a process that is used in the fabrication of semiconductor devices such as the device partially illustrated in <figref idref="f0001">Figure 1</figref>. Although specific steps are disclosed in the flowchart 700, such steps are exemplary. That is, embodiments according to the present invention are well suited to performing various other steps or variations of the steps recited in the flowchart 700. The flowchart 700 is discussed in conjunction with <figref idref="f0006 f0007 f0008 f0009 f0010">Figures 8-17</figref>, which are cross-sectional views showing selected stages in the fabrication of a semiconductor device according to an embodiment of the present invention. Certain well-known stages are left out of the following discussion. For example, operations associated with the formation and removal of masks are not described.</p>
<p id="p0040" num="0040">In block 702 of <figref idref="f0004 f0005">Figure 7</figref>, with reference also to <figref idref="f0006">Figure 8</figref>, trenches 802 are formed in a substrate/laminate that includes n+ region 210 and epitaxial region 220. An etching process may be used to form the trenches 802. The trenches 802 are used as source trenches.<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></p>
<p id="p0041" num="0041">In block 704, with reference also to <figref idref="f0006">Figure 9</figref>, an oxide layer 904 is deposited along the sidewalls and bottoms of the trenches 802, and also over the mesas 906 between those trenches.</p>
<p id="p0042" num="0042">In block 706, with reference also to <figref idref="f0007">Figure 10</figref>, polysilicon 1008 (poly-1) is deposited into the trenches 802. Each trench may be overfilled with poly-1. In one embodiment, a first polysilicon polishing process (e.g., CMP) is used to polish the poly-1 to form a flat surface. The poly-1 can then be etched back (e.g., in plasma) so that it is recessed relative to the adjacent oxide layer 904.</p>
<p id="p0043" num="0043">In block 708, with reference also to <figref idref="f0007">Figure 11</figref>, an oxide polishing process (e.g., CMP) is used to form an even (flat and smooth) surface 1110. Specifically, the oxide layer 904 over the mesas is removed, so that exposed surfaces of the oxide layer (the ends of the remainder of the oxide layer 904, along the sidewalls of the trenches 802) are flush with the adjacent surfaces/mesas. Also, any portions of the poly-1 protruding from the trenches 802 are removed, so that the exposed surfaces of the poly-1 are also flush with the adjacent surfaces/mesas.</p>
<p id="p0044" num="0044">During the oxide polishing (e.g., CMP) process, additional oxide may be added by deposition and removed during the oxide CMP process to achieve a surface 1110 that is both flat and smooth. It is beneficial for the surface 1110 to be free from imperfections (e.g., dips, pits, and scratches) to the extent practical. In a later process stage (block 712), polysilicon (poly-2) is deposited into the trenches used as gate trenches; that poly-2 may be captured in an imperfection, potentially forming stringers, if the surface 1110 is not as flat and smooth as practical.<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --></p>
<p id="p0045" num="0045">In block 710, with reference to <figref idref="f0008">Figure 12</figref>, trenches 1202 are formed in the substrate. An etching process may be used to form the trenches 1202. The trenches 1202 are used as gate trenches and are shallower than the source trenches (trenches 802). At one end of the trenches 1202 - at the end of the trenches at which the gate metal contacts are formed - the trenches 1202 are widened, as shown in <figref idref="f0001">Figure 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0046" num="0046">In block 712, with reference also to <figref idref="f0008">Figure 12</figref>, a thin gate oxide layer 1204 is grown along the sidewalls and bottoms of the trenches 1202, and also over the mesas 1206 between the trenches 1202 and the trenches 802.</p>
<p id="p0047" num="0047">In block 714, with reference to <figref idref="f0008">Figure 13</figref>, polysilicon 1308 (poly-2) is deposited into the trenches 1202. Each trench may be overfilled with poly-2, in which case a second polysilicon polishing process (e.g., CMP) is used to again generate a flat surface. The poly-2 can then be etched back (e.g., in plasma) so that it is recessed relative to the adjacent oxide layer.</p>
<p id="p0048" num="0048">With reference still to <figref idref="f0008">Figure 13</figref>, in one embodiment, p-body regions 240 can be formed in the regions between the trenches 802 and 1202.</p>
<p id="p0049" num="0049">In block 716, with reference also to <figref idref="f0009">Figure 14</figref>, regions 1450 are formed in the regions between the trenches 802 and 1202. As described above in conjunction with <figref idref="f0002">Figure 3</figref>, the regions 1450 include alternating n+ source regions 250 and p+ regions 350. That is, the n+ source regions 250 and the p+ regions 350 alternate with one another as shown in <figref idref="f0002">Figure 3</figref>.<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></p>
<p id="p0050" num="0050">In block 718, with reference also to <figref idref="f0009">Figure 15</figref>, oxide 570 is deposited in selected locations in the source metal region. Specifically, an oxide layer is deposited, then selectively removed so that, in the source metal region, the oxide 570 remains in the termination regions and over the gate trenches 1202, leaving the regions 1450 (e.g., the alternating n+ source regions 250 and p+ regions 350) exposed in the active region and the source trenches 802 exposed in the termination and active regions.</p>
<p id="p0051" num="0051">Consequently, when the source metal layer 121 is subsequently deposited, physical and electrical contact to the source trenches 111 and 112 and to the n+ source regions 250 is made, as shown in <figref idref="f0003">Figure 5</figref>. Also, when the source metal layer 121 is subsequently deposited, electrical and physical contact to the p+ regions 350, and hence electrical contact to the p-body regions 240, is made, as shown in <figref idref="f0010">Figure 16</figref>. Thus, the same source metal layer makes electrical contact to both the n+ source regions 250 and the p-body regions 240.</p>
<p id="p0052" num="0052">Also, with reference to <figref idref="f0010">Figure 17</figref>, oxide 270 is deposited in selected locations in the gate metal region. Specifically, an oxide layer is deposited, then selectively removed so that, in the gate metal region, the oxide 270 remains over the source trenches 802 and over the regions 1450 (n+ source regions 250 and p+ regions 350), leaving the gate trenches 1202 exposed. Consequently, when the gate metal layer 122 is subsequently deposited, physical and electrical contact to the gate trenches is made, as shown in <figref idref="f0002">Figure 2</figref>. The width of the gate trench (measured in the direction 'W') is less than the width of the contact of the gate trench with the gate metal layer 122.<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></p>
<p id="p0053" num="0053">In summary, embodiments in accordance with the present invention pertain to structures of, and methods of fabricating, trench-gated devices (e.g., MIS devices) incorporating dual gate structures that have separated polysilicon layers inside independent gate and source trenches that are respectively coupled. The dual gate structures are implemented with a gate contact connecting the gate polysilicon (poly-2) layer in the gate trench to a gate electrode, and a source contact connecting the source polysilicon (poly-1) layer in the source trench to a source electrode. The source contact and the gate contact are at the same surface plane.</p>
<p id="p0054" num="0054">CMP is used to facilitate the manufacture of such devices. The use of CMP allows for planarization of the polysilicon inside the source and gate trenches and the oxide at the top of each source trench, which results in better control over the structure and improved process margins, thereby improving performance. For example, planarization improves the depth of focus during photolithography. As a result, material can be deposited more accurately and uniformly, and shallower trenches can be formed. Consequently, device features can be scaled to smaller dimensions.</p>
<p id="p0055" num="0055">Embodiments in accordance with the invention can be used with medium voltage rating (60-150 volts) trench power MOS devices and high voltage rating (150-300 volts) trench power MOS devices.</p>
<p id="p0056" num="0056">In summary, embodiments of semiconductor devices, and embodiments of methods for fabricating such devices, are described. The foregoing descriptions of specific embodiments of the present invention have been presented for purposes of illustration and description. They are not intended to<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> be exhaustive or to limit the invention to the precise forms disclosed, and many modifications and variations are possible in light of the above teaching. The embodiments were chosen and described in order to best explain the principles of the invention and its practical application, to thereby enable others skilled in the art to best utilize the invention and various embodiments with various modifications as are suited to the particular use contemplated. It is intended that the scope of the invention be defined by the claims appended hereto.</p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> -->
<claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>A method (700) of fabricating a dual trench semiconductor device (100), said method comprising:
<claim-text>forming an epi region (220) over a substrate (210);</claim-text>
<claim-text>(702) forming a first source trench (802) through said epi region and into said substrate, and forming a second source trench (802) parallel to said first source trench and through said epi region into said substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(704) depositing oxide along the sidewalls and bottom of said first source trench and along the sidewalls and bottom of said second source trench, such that the walls of said first and second source trenches are lined with said oxide, said oxide also deposited over an upper surface of a first mesa (906) that is between said first source trench and said second source trench to form a first oxide layer (904) with an upper surface over said upper surface of said first mesa;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(706) after said oxide depositing, depositing first polysilicon (1008) into said first source trench and into said second source trench, wherein upper surfaces of said first polysilicon in said first and second source trenches are exposed;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(706) performing a first polysilicon polishing process to polish said upper surfaces of said first polysilicon so that, after completing said first polysilicon polishing process, said upper surfaces of said first polysilicon are flat;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(708) after completing said first polysilicon polishing process, performing an oxide polishing process to remove said first oxide layer (904) from over said first mesa and to also remove first polysilicon from said upper surfaces of said first polysilicon so that, after completing said oxide polishing process, exposed surfaces of said oxide are flush with said upper surface of said first mesa and also exposed surfaces of said first polysilicon are flush with said upper surface of said first mesa;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(710) after said oxide polishing process, forming a gate trench (1202) into but not through said epi region in said first mesa between said first and second source<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> trenches, wherein said gate trench is shallower than said first and second source trenches and wherein said gate trench is parallel to said first source trench and said second source trench;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(712) growing a second oxide layer along the sidewalls and bottom of said gate trench and over mesas between said gate trench and said first and second source trenches;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(714) after said oxide growing, depositing second polysilicon (1308) into said gate trench, wherein an upper surface of said second polysilicon in said gate trench is exposed;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(714) performing a second polysilicon polishing process to polish said upper surface of said second polysilicon so that, after completing said second polysilicon polishing process, said upper surface of said second polysilicon is flat; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a source contact of a source metal layer (121), wherein said source metal layer is physically and electrically in contact with said upper surfaces of said first polysilicon in said first and second source trenches and also with source regions adjacent to said first and second source trenches, wherein said source metal layer extends over said upper surfaces of said first polysilicon and said second polysilicon and said first mesa; and forming a gate contact of a gate metal layer (122), wherein said gate metal layer is physically and electrically in contact with said upper surface of said second polysilicon, wherein said gate metal layer is formed on said substrate to extend over said upper surfaces of said first polysilicon and said second polysilicon and said first mesa.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>The method of Claim 1, wherein said source and gate metal layers are in the same surface plane but are physically isolated from one another.<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>The method of Claim 1 wherein said gate trench is wider than said gate contact.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>The method of claim 1 or 2, further comprising:<br/>
after said first polysilicon polishing process is performed, etching back said upper surfaces of said first polysilicon so that said upper surfaces of said first polysilicon are recessed relative to said upper surface of said first oxide layer.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>The method of Claim 1, wherein said first and second polysilicon polishing processes and said oxide polishing process comprise chemical mechanical polishing processes.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>The method of claim 1 or 2, further comprising:<br/>
after said second polysilicon polishing process is performed, etching back said upper surfaces of said second polysilicon so that said upper surfaces of said second polysilicon are recessed relative to said upper surface of said second oxide layer.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>A semiconductor device (100) comprising:
<claim-text>a substrate (210);</claim-text>
<claim-text>an epi region (220) over said substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first source trench (802) that extends through said epi region and into said substrate, the walls of said first source trench being lined with oxide;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second source trench (802) parallel to said first source trench that extends through said epi region and into said substrate, the walls of said second source trench being lined with oxide;<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>a gate trench (1202) that extends into but not through said epi region, wherein said gate trench is shallower than said first and second source trenches, wherein said gate trench is parallel to said first source trench and to said second source trench, and wherein said gate trench is formed in a mesa (1206) between said first source trench and said second source trench, said mesa having an upper surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a source contact of a source metal layer (121) physically and electrically in contact with a surface of first polysilicon (1008) in said first source trench and with a surface of first polysilicon in said second source trench, and also with source regions adjacent to said first and second source trenches, wherein said surfaces of first polysilicon in the first and second source trenches are flat upper surfaces of said first polysilicon, and wherein said source metal layer is formed on said substrate to extend over said first source trench, said second source trench, said mesa, and said gate trench; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a gate contact of a gate metal layer (122) physically and electrically in contact with a surface of second polysilicon (1308) in said gate trench, wherein said gate metal layer formed on said substrate extends over said first source trench and said second source trench, said mesa, and said gate trench, and wherein said surface of said first polysilicon is flush with said upper surface of said mesa.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>The semiconductor device of Claim 7, wherein said source contact is part of a first metal layer and said gate contact is part of a second metal layer, wherein said first and second metal layers are physically isolated from one another and in the same surface plane.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>The semiconductor device of Claim 7, wherein said gate trench is wider than said gate contact.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims02" lang="de"><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> -->
<claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Verfahren (700) zur Herstellung einer Dual-Trench-Halbleitervorrichtung (100), wobei das Verfahren folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>Ausbilden einer Epi-Region (220) über einem Substrat (210);</claim-text>
<claim-text>(702) Ausbilden eines ersten Source-Trench (802) durch die Epi-Region und in das Substrat, und Ausbilden eines zweiten Source-Trench (802) parallel zu dem ersten Source-Trench und durch die Epi-Region in das Substrat;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(704) Abscheiden von Oxid entlang der Seitenwände und des Bodens des ersten Source-Trench und entlang der Seitenwände und des Bodens des zweiten Source-Trench, so dass die Wände des ersten und des zweiten Source-Trench mit dem Oxid ausgekleidet sind, wobei das Oxid ferner über einer oberen Oberfläche einer ersten Mesa (906) abgeschieden wird, die sich zwischen dem ersten Source-Trench und dem zweiten Source-Trench befindet, so dass eine erste Oxidschicht (904) mit einer oberen Oberfläche über der oberen Oberfläche der ersten Mesa gebildet wird;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(706) nach dem Abscheiden des Oxids, Abscheiden eines ersten Polysiliziums (1008) in den ersten Source-Trench und in den zweiten Source-Trench, wobei die oberen Oberflächen des ersten Polysiliziums in dem ersten und dem zweiten Source-Trench frei liegen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(706) Ausführen eines Polierprozesses des ersten Polysiliziums, um die oberen Oberflächen des ersten Polysiliziums zu polieren, so dass die oberen Oberflächen des ersten Polysiliziums nach Abschluss des Polierprozesses des ersten Polysiliziums flach sind;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(708) nach Abschluss des Polierprozesses des ersten Polysiliziums, Ausführen eines Oxidpolierprozesses zur Entfernung der ersten Oxidschicht (904) von über der ersten Mesa und ferner zur Entfernung des ersten Polysiliziums von den oberen Oberflächen des ersten Polysiliziums, so dass nach dem Abschluss des Oxidpolierprozesses die frei liegenden Oberflächen des Oxids mit der oberen Oberfläche der ersten Mesa bündig sind, und so dass auch die frei liegenden Oberflächen des ersten Polysiliziums mit den oberen Oberflächen der ersten Mesa bündig sind;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(710) nach dem Oxidpolierprozess, Ausbilden eines Gate-Trench (1202) in die Epi-Region in der ersten Mesa zwischen dem ersten und dem zweiten Source-Trench,<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> jedoch nicht durch die Region hindurch, wobei der Gate-Trench flacher ist als der erste und der zweite Source-Trench, und wobei der Gate-Trench parallel zu dem ersten Source-Trench und dem zweiten Source-Trench ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(712) Züchten einer zweiten Oxidschicht entlang der Seitenwände und des Bodens des Gate-Trench und über Mesas zwischen dem Gate-Trench und dem ersten und dem zweiten Source-Trench;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(714) nach dem Züchten des Oxids, Abscheiden eines zweiten Polysiliziums (1308) in den Gate-Trench, wobei eine obere Oberfläche des zweiten Polysiliziums in dem Gate-Trench frei liegt;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(714) Ausführen eines Polierprozesses des zweiten Polysiliziums, um die obere Oberfläche des zweiten Polysiliziums zu polieren, so dass die obere Oberfläche des zweiten Polysiliziums nach Abschluss des Polierprozesses des zweiten Polysiliziums flach ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Ausbilden eines Source-Kontaktes aus einer Source-Metallschicht (121), wobei sich die Source-Metallschicht physisch und elektrisch in Kontakt mit den oberen Oberflächen des ersten Polysiliziums in dem ersten und dem zweiten Source-Trench befindet sowie mit Source-Regionen angrenzend an den ersten und den zweiten Source-Trench, wobei sich die Source-Metallschicht über die oberen Oberflächen des ersten Polysiliziums und des zweiten Polysiliziums und der ersten Mesa erstreckt; und Ausbilden eines Gate-Kontaktes aus einer Gate-Metallschicht (122), wobei sich die Gate-Metallschicht physisch und elektrisch in Kontakt mit der oberen Oberfläche des zweiten Polysiliziums befindet, wobei die Gate-Metallschicht so auf dem Substrat ausgebildet wird, dass sie sich über die oberen Oberflächen des ersten Polysiliziums und des zweiten Polysiliziums und der ersten Mesa erstreckt.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, wobei sich die Source- und Gate-Metallschichten in der gleichen Oberflächenebene befinden, jedoch physisch voneinander isoliert sind.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, wobei der Gate-Trench breiter ist als der Gate-Kontakt.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1 oder 2, wobei das Verfahren ferner folgendes umfasst:<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> -->
<claim-text>nach dem Ausführen des Polierprozesses des ersten Polysiliziums, Rückätzen der oberen Oberflächen des ersten Polysiliziums, so dass die oberen Oberflächen des ersten Polysiliziums im Verhältnis zu der oberen Oberfläche der ersten Oxidschicht vertieft sind.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Polierprozesse des ersten und des zweiten Polysiliziums und der Oxidpolierprozess chemische mechanische Polierprozesse umfassen.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1 oder 2, wobei das Verfahren ferner folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>nach dem Ausführen des Polierprozesses des zweiten Polysiliziums, Rückätzen der oberen Oberflächen des zweiten Polysiliziums, so dass die oberen Oberflächen des zweiten Polysiliziums im Verhältnis zu der oberen Oberfläche der zweiten Oxidschicht vertieft sind.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Halbleitervorrichtung (100), die folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>ein Substrat (210);</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Epi-Region (220) über dem Substrat;</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen ersten Source-Trench (802), der sich durch die Epi-Region und in das Substrat erstreckt, wobei die Wände des ersten Source-Trench mit Oxid ausgekleidet sind;</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen zweiten Source-Trench (802), der zu dem ersten Source-Trench parallel ist und sich durch die Epi-Region und in das Substrat erstreckt, wobei die Wände des zweiten Source-Trench mit Oxid ausgekleidet sind;</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Gate-Trench (1202), der sich in die Epi-Region erstreckt, nicht jedoch durch diese hindurch, wobei der Gate-Trench flacher ist als der erste und der zweite Source-Trench, wobei der Gate-Trench zu dem ersten Source-Trench und zu dem zweiten Source-Trench parallel ist, und wobei der Gate-Trench in einer Mesa (1206) zwischen dem ersten Source-Trench und dem zweiten Source-Trench ausgebildet ist, wobei das Mesa eine obere Oberfläche aufweist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Source-Kontakt aus einer Source-Metallschicht (121), der sich physisch und elektrisch in Kontakt mit einer Oberfläche eines ersten Polysiliziums (1008) in dem ersten Source-Trench befindet sowie mit einer Oberfläche des ersten Polysiliziums in<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> dem zweiten Source-Trench und ferner mit Source-Regionen angrenzend an den ersten und den zweiten Source-Trench, wobei die Oberflächen des ersten Polysiliziums in dem ersten und in dem zweiten Source-Trench flache obere Oberflächen des ersten Polysiliziums sind, und wobei die Source-Metallschicht so auf dem Substrat ausgebildet ist, dass sie sich über den ersten Source-Trench, den zweiten Source-Trench, das Mesa und den Gate-Trench erstreckt; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Gate-Kontakt aus einer Gate-Metallschicht (122), der sich physisch und elektrisch in Kontakt mit einer Oberfläche eines zweiten Polysiliziums (1308) in dem Gate-Trench befindet, wobei sich die auf dem Substrat ausgebildete Gate-Metallschicht über den ersten Source-Trench, den zweiten Source-Trench, das Mesa und den Gate-Trench erstreckt, und wobei die Oberfläche des ersten Polysiliziums mit der Oberfläche des Mesa bündig ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>Halbleitervorrichtung nach Anspruch 7, wobei der Source-Kontakt Teil einer ersten Metallschicht ist, und wobei der Gate-Kontakt Teil einer zweiten Metallschicht ist, wobei die erste und die zweite Metallschicht physisch voneinander isoliert sind und sich in der gleichen Oberflächenebene befinden.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>Halbleitervorrichtung nach Anspruch 7, wobei der Gate-Trench breiter ist als der Gate-Kontakt.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims03" lang="fr"><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> -->
<claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Procédé (700) de fabrication d'un dispositif semi-conducteur à double tranchée (100), ledit procédé comprenant les étapes consistant à :
<claim-text>former une région épi (220) sur un substrat (210) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(702) former une première tranchée de source (802) à travers ladite région épi et dans ledit substrat, et former une seconde tranchée de source (802) parallèle à ladite première tranchée de source et à travers ladite région épi dans ledit substrat ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(704) déposer de l'oxyde le long des parois latérales et du fond de ladite première tranchée de source et le long des parois latérales et du fond de ladite seconde tranchée de source, de sorte que les parois desdites première et seconde tranchées de source sont revêtues dudit oxyde, ledit oxyde étant également déposé sur une surface supérieure d'une première mesa (906) qui est entre ladite première tranchée de source et ladite seconde tranchée de source pour former une première couche d'oxyde (904) avec une surface supérieure sur ladite surface supérieure de ladite première mesa ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(706) après ledit dépôt d'oxyde, déposer un premier polysilicium (1008) dans ladite première tranchée de source et dans ladite seconde tranchée de source, les surfaces supérieures dudit premier polysilicium dans lesdites première et seconde tranchées de source étant exposées ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(706) effectuer un premier processus de polissage de polysilicium pour polir lesdites surfaces supérieures dudit premier polysilicium de sorte que, après avoir terminé ledit premier processus de polissage de polysilicium, lesdites surfaces supérieures dudit premier polysilicium étant plates ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(708) après avoir terminé ledit processus de polissage du premier polysilicium, effectuer un processus de polissage d'oxyde pour éliminer ladite première couche d'oxyde (904) de ladite première mesa et pour éliminer également le premier polysilicium desdites surfaces supérieures dudit premier polysilicium de sorte que, après avoir terminé ledit processus de polissage d'oxyde, les surfaces exposées dudit oxyde soient à fleur de ladite surface supérieure de ladite première mesa et également de sorte que les surfaces exposées dudit premier polysilicium soient à fleur de ladite surface supérieure de ladite première mesa ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(710) après ledit processus de polissage d'oxyde, former une tranchée de grille (1202) dans mais pas à travers ladite région épi dans ladite première mesa entre lesdites première et seconde tranchées de source, ladite tranchée de grille étant moins profonde que<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --> lesdites première et seconde tranchées de source et ladite tranchée de grille étant parallèle à ladite première tranchée de source et à ladite seconde tranchée de source ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(712) faire croître une seconde couche d'oxyde le long des parois latérales et du fond de ladite tranchée de grille et sur les mesas entre ladite tranchée de grille et lesdites première et seconde tranchées de source ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(714) après ladite croissance d'oxyde, déposer un second polysilicium (1308) dans ladite tranchée de grille, une surface supérieure dudit second polysilicium dans ladite tranchée de grille étant exposée ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(714) effectuer un second processus de polissage de polysilicium pour polir ladite surface supérieure dudit second polysilicium de sorte que, après avoir terminé ledit second processus de polissage de polysilicium, ladite surface supérieure dudit second polysilicium soit plate ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>former un contact de source d'une couche métallique de source (121), ladite couche métallique de source étant physiquement et électriquement en contact avec lesdites surfaces supérieures dudit premier polysilicium dans lesdites première et seconde tranchées de source et également avec des régions de source adjacentes auxdites première et seconde tranchées de source, ladite couche métallique de source s'étendant sur lesdites surfaces supérieures dudit premier polysilicium et dudit second polysilicium et de ladite première mesa ; et former un contact de grille d'une couche métallique de grille (122), ladite couche métallique de grille étant physiquement et électriquement en contact avec ladite surface supérieure dudit second polysilicium, ladite couche métallique de grille étant formée sur ledit substrat pour s'étendre sur lesdites surfaces supérieures dudit premier polysilicium et dudit second polysilicium et de ladite première mesa.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, lesdites couches métalliques de source et de grille étant dans le même plan de surface mais étant physiquement isolées l'une de l'autre.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, ladite tranchée de grille étant plus large que ledit contact de grille.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1 ou 2, comprenant en outre l'étape consistant à :<br/>
après que ledit premier processus de polissage de polysilicium a été effectué, graver lesdites surfaces supérieures dudit premier polysilicium de sorte que lesdites surfaces<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --> supérieures dudit premier polysilicium soient en retrait par rapport à ladite surface supérieure de ladite première couche d'oxyde.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, lesdits premier et second procédés de polissage de polysilicium et ledit procédé de polissage d'oxyde comprenant des procédés de polissage chimico-mécaniques.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1 ou 2, comprenant en outre l'étape consistant à :<br/>
après que ledit second processus de polissage de polysilicium a été effectué, graver lesdites surfaces supérieures dudit second polysilicium de sorte que lesdites surfaces supérieures dudit second polysilicium soient en retrait par rapport à ladite surface supérieure de ladite seconde couche d'oxyde.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Dispositif semi-conducteur (100) comprenant :
<claim-text>un substrat (210) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une région épi (220) sur ledit substrat ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une première tranchée de source (802) qui s'étend à travers ladite région épi et dans ledit substrat, les parois de ladite première tranchée de source étant revêtues d'oxyde ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une seconde tranchée de source (802) parallèle à ladite première tranchée de source qui s'étend à travers ladite région épi et dans ledit substrat, les parois de ladite seconde tranchée de source étant revêtues d'oxyde ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une tranchée de grille (1202) qui s'étend dans mais pas à travers ladite région épi, ladite tranchée de grille étant moins profonde que lesdites première et seconde tranchées de source, ladite tranchée de grille étant parallèle à ladite première tranchée de source et à ladite seconde tranchée de source, et ladite tranchée de grille étant formée dans une mesa (1206) entre ladite première tranchée de source et ladite seconde tranchée de source, ladite mesa ayant une surface supérieure ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un contact de source d'une couche métallique de source (121) physiquement et électriquement en contact avec une surface de premier polysilicium (1008) dans ladite première tranchée de source et avec une surface de premier polysilicium dans ladite seconde tranchée de source, et également avec des régions de source adjacentes auxdites première et seconde tranchées de source, lesdites surfaces de premier polysilicium dans les première et seconde tranchées de source étant des surfaces supérieures plates dudit premier polysilicium, et ladite couche métallique de source étant formée sur ledit substrat pour s'étendre sur ladite<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --> première tranchée de source, ladite seconde tranchée de source, ladite mesa, et ladite tranchée de grille ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un contact de grille d'une couche métallique de grille (122) physiquement et électriquement en contact avec une surface de second polysilicium (1308) dans ladite tranchée de grille, ladite couche métallique de grille formée sur ledit substrat s'étendant sur ladite première tranchée de source et ladite seconde tranchée de source, ladite mesa, et ladite tranchée de grille, et ladite surface dudit premier polysilicium étant à fleur de ladite surface supérieure de ladite mesa.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>Dispositif semi-conducteur selon la revendication 7, ledit contact de source faisant partie d'une première couche métallique et ledit contact de grille faisant partie d'une seconde couche métallique, lesdites première et seconde couches métalliques étant physiquement isolées l'une de l'autre et dans le même plan de surface.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>Dispositif semi-conducteur selon la revendication 7, ladite tranchée de grille étant plus large que ledit contact de grille.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="146" he="134" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="2,3"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="136" he="196" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="33"> -->
<figure id="f0003" num="4,5"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="125" he="198" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="34"> -->
<figure id="f0004" num="6,7A"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="122" he="198" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="35"> -->
<figure id="f0005" num="7B"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="69" he="192" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="36"> -->
<figure id="f0006" num="8,9"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="107" he="183" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="37"> -->
<figure id="f0007" num="10,11"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="115" he="192" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="38"> -->
<figure id="f0008" num="12,13"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="110" he="190" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="39"> -->
<figure id="f0009" num="14,15"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="110" he="190" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="40"> -->
<figure id="f0010" num="16,17"><img id="if0010" file="imgf0010.tif" wi="116" he="201" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<ep-reference-list id="ref-list">
<heading id="ref-h0001"><b>REFERENCES CITED IN THE DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0001" num=""><i>This list of references cited by the applicant is for the reader's convenience only. It does not form part of the European patent document. Even though great care has been taken in compiling the references, errors or omissions cannot be excluded and the EPO disclaims all liability in this regard.</i></p>
<heading id="ref-h0002"><b>Patent documents cited in the description</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0002" num="">
<ul id="ref-ul0001" list-style="bullet">
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0001" dnum="US6653691B"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>6653691</doc-number><kind>B</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0001">[0003]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0002" dnum="US2009200578A"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2009200578</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0002">[0004]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0003" dnum="US2009140327A"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2009140327</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0003">[0005]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0004" dnum="US7009247B"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>7009247</doc-number><kind>B</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0004">[0006]</crossref></li>
</ul></p>
</ep-reference-list>
</ep-patent-document>
