<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP17793256B1" file="EP17793256NWB1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3453223" kind="B1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSK..HRIS..MTNORS..SM..................</B001EP><B003EP>*</B003EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  2100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3453223</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT SPECIFICATION</B121></B120><B130>B1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>17793256.3</B210><B220><date>20170503</date></B220><B240><B241><date>20181129</date></B241><B242><date>20200928</date></B242></B240><B250>en</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B300><B310>201662331245 P</B310><B320><date>20160503</date></B320><B330><ctry>US</ctry></B330></B300><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20190313</date><bnum>201911</bnum></B430><B450><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B450><B452EP><date>20210430</date></B452EP></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>H04B   7/185       20060101AFI20191113BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="2"><text>H04B   7/19        20060101ALI20191113BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="3"><text>H04W  84/06        20090101ALI20191113BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="4"><text>H04B   7/14        20060101ALI20191113BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="5"><text>B64G   1/10        20060101ALI20191113BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="6"><text>H04B   7/195       20060101ALI20191113BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>H04B   7/19        20130101 LI20171205BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>H04B   7/18513     20130101 LI20191111BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="3"><text>B64G   1/242       20130101 LI20191105BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="4"><text>H04B   7/195       20130101 FI20181129BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="5"><text>B64G   1/66        20130101 LI20191105BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="6"><text>B64G   1/1085      20130101 LI20191105BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="7"><text>H04W  84/06        20130101 LI20171205BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="8"><text>H04B   7/18523     20130101 LI20181129BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="9"><text>B64G   1/1007      20130101 LI20191105BHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>SATELLITENKONSTELLATIONSSYSTEM MIT NIEDRIGER UMLAUFBAHN ZUR KOMMUNIKATION MIT WIEDERVERWENDUNG EINES GEOSTATIONÄREN SATELLITENSPEKTRUMS</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>LOW EARTH ORBIT SATELLITE CONSTELLATION SYSTEM FOR COMMUNICATIONS WITH RE-USE OF GEOSTATIONARY SATELLITE SPECTRUM</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>SYSTÈME DE CONSTELLATION DE SATELLITES D'ORBITE TERRESTRE BASSE DESTINÉ AUX COMMUNICATIONS AVEC RÉUTILISATION D'UN SPECTRE SATELLITE GÉOSTATIONNAIRE</B542></B540><B560><B561><text>EP-A1- 3 272 031</text></B561><B561><text>WO-A1-00/41340</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2002 041 328</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2002 150 060</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2005 143 005</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2011 169 688</text></B561><B561><text>US-B1- 6 175 340</text></B561><B561><text>US-B1- 6 236 834</text></B561><B561><text>US-B1- 6 556 828</text></B561><B561><text>US-B2- 6 940 452</text></B561><B565EP><date>20191119</date></B565EP></B560></B500><B700><B720><B721><snm>OLSON, Erlend</snm><adr><str>P.O. Box 10939</str><city>Newport Beach, CA 92658</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B730><B731><snm>Theia Group, Incorporated</snm><iid>101706657</iid><irf>P16.552EP</irf><adr><str>1600 Market Street 
Suite 1320</str><city>Philadelphia, PA 19103</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B731></B730><B740><B741><snm>Zucker, Volker</snm><iid>100042324</iid><adr><str>Patentanwälte Bressel und Partner mbB 
Potsdamer Platz 10</str><city>10785 Berlin</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840><B860><B861><dnum><anum>US2017030847</anum></dnum><date>20170503</date></B861><B862>en</B862></B860><B870><B871><dnum><pnum>WO2017192727</pnum></dnum><date>20171109</date><bnum>201745</bnum></B871></B870></B800></SDOBI>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<heading id="h0001">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<heading id="h0002">1. Field of the Invention</heading>
<p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a low earth orbit satellite constellation system for communications, a method for implementing communications through a low earth orbiting satellite communication system and a low earth orbiting satellite.</p>
<heading id="h0003">2. Brief Description of the Related Art</heading>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">A large amount of microwave spectrum suitable for communications between earth stations and satellites is allocated by various national and international regulatory agencies to communications services involving geo-stationary earth orbit (GEO) satellites. In the present situation, there is very little unallocated microwave spectrum left for allocation to new communications services employing satellite based communications systems as they are traditionally conceived, constructed and operated. In addition, much of the existing spectrum allocated to GEO satellite communication services is already consumed with existing applications, primarily for television distribution, existing telephony backhaul and government data movement. As such, it is unlikely that existing GEO satellite communications system operators will be either able to repurpose any of their existing allocated spectrum to new applications as rapidly as such applications are growing.</p>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">New industries with requirements for high volumes and high rates of data are emerging rapidly, and many applications within these industries require high data volume or high data rate global communications capabilities, and communications coverage outside of the service areas of terrestrial based networks. Some examples include remote sensing, remote control of unmanned aerial vehicles, video and image-based communications (as contrasted to audio communications), video and image based machine-to-machine communications and control, and ultra-high security data transfers between two earth stations without transiting through a terrestrial network. These applications are well suited for service by purpose-built satellite communications systems. However deployment of new satellite based communications systems are largely constrained by lack of available spectrum for allocation.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">Satellite communications systems today are well known and are responsible for many modern conveniences, including the distribution of direct broadcast television throughout many parts of the world. While there are presently a few low-earth-orbit (LEO) and middle-earth-orbit (MEO) satellites and satellite constellations dedicated to communications functions, most of the communications satellites and systems today are of the geo-stationary earth orbit (GEO) type.</p>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">The International Telecommunications Union (ITU) as well as other governing and regulatory bodies have recognized and allocated large swaths of the radio frequency spectrum to GEO satellite usage for bi-directional communications between the earth and the satellite for a wide variety of purposes. The large number of GEO satellites in operation today has led to a situation in which there is very little spectrum available for new satellite communications links. Most mobile earth station-to-satellite communications can only be practically met by employing microwave frequencies, so that the antennas employed on the earth stations can be small and/or portable, and so that the data rates that can be transceived with known data communications methods can be high. This imposes a practical lower limit to the usable earth station-to-satellite communications frequencies, irrespective of regulatory or assignment issues. Because of atmospheric absorption and rain-fade issues, there is a practical upper limit to the usable earth station-to-satellite communications frequencies as well, irrespective of regulatory or assignment issues. Between these practical limits, there is little unused spectrum available for new assignments, as most of it is already allocated to earth-space communications with GEO satellite systems, for fixed satellite services.</p>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">Much of the spectrum in the so-called Ka and Ku bands is assigned to fixed satellite service uses, employing a GEO satellite for the space segment, which, because of the fact that GEO satellites appear to an earth station at a fixed point in the sky, are necessarily directional, instead of omni-directional. For example, the most popular use of GEO associated spectrum presently is for direct broadcast of television programs, which are received by small directional dishes at earth stations, with fixed pointing, typically mounted on customer's homes or buildings. The 3dB beam width of popular consumer grade direct broadcast satellite antennas is on the order of 2 to 3 degrees, and they are highly directional.</p>
<p id="p0007" num="0007"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US6236834B1"><text>US 6,236,834 B1</text></patcit> teaches a low earth orbiting satellite constellation system for communications, which comprises a plurality of satellites in a polar orbit about the earth, wherein each satellite has an antenna for receiving and transmitting signals to earth stations. The satellite antenna is controlled with a control mechanism. The potential for interference<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> between these satellites and a geostationary satellite arises when a non-geostationary satellite becomes located proximate a feeder link path between the geostationary satellite and a ground station. Signals transmitted by the non-geostationary satellite are prevented from interfering, beyond a predefined extend, with signal transmission between the geostationary satellite and ground station by modifying the antenna beam pattern radiated by the non-geostationary satellite. This modification involves nulling the portion of the beam pattern incident on a forbidden band of latitudes on the surface of the earth.</p>
<heading id="h0004">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">The invention is defined by a system with the features of claim 1, a method with the features of claim 77 and a low earth satellite with the features of claim 82.</p>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">Further aspects of the invention are disclosed in the dependent claims.</p>
<heading id="h0005">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWING FIGURES</heading>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li><figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> presents the nomenclature used throughout this disclosure.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> is a diagram of the earth illustrating satellites and an orbit throughout the four quadrants.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> is a diagram representing the earth and showing an actual elevation pointing angle between a directional antenna and a geostationary satellite.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0004">FIG. 4</figref> is a diagram representing the earth and showing the geometry of two satellites in a LEO orbital plane.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0005">FIG. 5</figref> is a diagram representing the earth and showing two sets of geometries overlaid, and indicating direction vectors to LEO satellite locations as an LEO satellite constellation orbits.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0006">FIG. 6A</figref> is a diagram representing the earth and showing an end-case situation near maximum latitude where any earth station may be practically anticipated to communicate with a GEO satellite.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></li>
<li><figref idref="f0007">FIG. 6B</figref> is an enlarged partial view of the diagram of <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 6A</figref>, showing the top portion thereof.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0008">FIG. 7A</figref> is a diagram representing the earth and showing an end-case situation at the equator where any earth station may be practically anticipated to communicate with a GEO satellite.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0009">FIG. 7B</figref> is an enlarged partial view of the diagram of <figref idref="f0008">FIG. 7A</figref>, showing the top portion thereof.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0010">FIG. 8</figref> is a diagram representing the earth showing a portion of one plane to illustrate the invention, and depicts a LEO-based constellation for communications with earth stations anywhere in the world.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0011">FIG. 9</figref> is a diagram representing the earth and illustrating communications beams associated with two satellites according to the invention which are depicted transitioning across the sky over the equator from North to South.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0012">FIG. 10A</figref> is a diagram representing the earth and illustrating the latitude of a satellite at any particular point in its orbit, <b><i>σ</i></b>.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0013">FIG. 10B</figref> is an enlarged view of the diagram of <figref idref="f0012">FIG. 10A</figref>.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0014">FIG. 11</figref> is an illustration representing the earth and showing a satellite constellation (not to scale) according to the invention, which complies with the specifications of Table 1 (<figref idref="f0017 f0018">FIG. 14</figref>).</li>
<li><figref idref="f0015">FIG. 12</figref> is a diagram depicting an in-plane antenna pattern of a simple loop antenna.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0016">FIG. 13</figref> is an illustration representing the earth and showing an exemplary arrangement of satellites which comprise part of a constellation of satellites according to the invention, and showing antennas provided on the surface of the earth with maximum gain indications depicts.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0017 f0018">FIG. 14</figref> is a table, referenced as Table 1, showing tabulations of the various parameters for the input parameters of <b><i>α</i></b>=5 degrees, <b>β</b>=5 degrees and h=1,800km.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0019 f0020">FIG. 15</figref> is a table, referenced as Table 2, which is similar to Table 1, but for the limiting case where <b>β</b>=0, the back angle never goes negative and the back beam angle <b>λ</b> at the equator is 0.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0021 f0022">FIG. 16</figref> is a table, referenced as Table 3, which is similar to Table 1, but for input parameters of <b><i>α</i></b>=10 degrees, <b>β</b>=10 degrees and h=800km.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></li>
<li><figref idref="f0023">FIG. 17</figref> is a table, referenced as Table 4, showing free space path loss (FSPL) in-plane calculated for various angles from a LEO satellite in a constellation orbiting at an altitude to an earth station, compared to the FSPL to a GEO satellite, at the same communications frequency.</li>
</ul></p>
<heading id="h0006">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">Referring to <figref idref="f0001">Figure 1</figref>, nomenclature used throughout this disclosure and the Figures and Equations is presented. In addition, in order to effectively illustrate and explain the invention, the diagrams and equations presented are for a 2 dimensional view of the system, with diagrams being illustrated in <figref idref="f0002 f0003 f0004 f0005 f0006 f0007 f0008 f0009 f0010 f0011 f0012 f0013 f0014 f0015 f0016">Figures 2 through 13</figref>, and with equations (1 through 19) being presented herein and in a listing at the end of this section. One feature of the invention is that the LEO communications satellites in the constellation be in polar orbits. Because the plane containing geosynchronous satellites for which the frequencies are to be re-used are in an orbit which is orthogonal to any plane of the polar orbiting LEO communications satellite constellation disclosed, the 2D configuration disclosed in the diagrams and equations is the simple projection from any LEO orbital plane of a 3D configuration. Therefore, 3D diagrams and equations are projected extensions of the 2D depictions which are well understood and simple to produce by those practiced in the art of orbital mechanics and analysis.</p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">Furthermore, more complex equations than those presented herein, which accommodate the slight ellipsoid shape of the earth and other higher order factors, are well known to those practiced in the art of orbital mechanics. The assumption of the earth as being perfectly spherical is used throughout this disclosure to illustrate the principles involved and the mechanics of the invention, but is not meant to form a limitation on any matter disclosed herein. The principles disclosed herein and the invention may be extended to accommodate a non-spherical earth and higher order orbital elements without departure from the scope of the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013"><figref idref="f0002">Figure 2</figref> illustrates the situation and provides foundation for the subsequent Figures. In <figref idref="f0002">Figure 2</figref>, a single plane of multiple LEO satellite planes of a LEO satellite constellation in a polar orbit is represented, with two of many satellites which would be in the orbital plane OP shown, indicated at LEO1 and LEO2. As would be typical for a LEO communications constellation, and as indicated in the figure as LEO1 BEAM and LEO2 BEAM, LEO satellites typically create overlapping beams of coverage, for both transmission<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> to, and reception of, signals from ground stations. Within each beam of coverage of a single LEO satellite, there may be multiple sub-beams, enabling frequency and polarization re-use within a beam, in the communications functions with the earth stations. Furthermore, as is well understood by those practiced in the art, the beams and/or sub-beams may be directed in real-time in order to accommodate various orbital elements and earth station practicalities. By fully populating an orbital plane, and by positioning multiple orbital planes at regular angular longitudinal spacing, the entire earth can be covered at all times with beams of at least one satellite in the LEO communications constellation. The Iridium communications satellite constellation is an example of such a constellation, owned and operated by Iridium Satellite LLC. However, the Iridium system, as well as other systems, employ spectrum which is not the same as that employed by GEO satellite communications systems, and no more of such spectrum is available. Examples of satellites and their operations are disclosed in <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="US5410728A"><text>US Patents 5,410,728</text></patcit> and <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="US5604920A"><text>5,604,920</text></patcit>.</p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">Still referring to <figref idref="f0002">Figure 2</figref>, points on the surface of the earth in the northern hemisphere are indicated as <b>P1NE</b> at 70 degrees north latitude, through <b>P8NE,</b> which lies on the equator. For each point <b>P,</b> a vector is drawn indicating the bore sight of a directional antenna which would point at a geostationary satellite if located at that point. In addition, the LEO satellite orbit track OP shown orbits in a clockwise fashion, however this is simply for convention in the Figures and nomenclature in this disclosure and does not limit the generality of this disclosure. Under the convention used herein, for any point <b>P</b> in Quadrant 1 or 2, the LEO satellites in polar orbit ascend from the North and descend toward the South (in the direction of travel indicated).</p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">Still referring to <figref idref="f0002">Figure 2</figref>, as can be seen, anytime a LEO satellite using the same frequencies as a GEO satellite for communications with an earth station passes over a point <b>P,</b> there is a spot in the orbit track where the LEO satellite is directly in line between the GEO satellite and the earth station. Therefore, at that point, if the LEO satellite were transmitting on the same frequency that the earth station is set to receive from the GEO satellite, then interference would result, and the GEO satellite's signal could be interfered with by the LEO satellite's signal, as both signals on the same frequency would be simultaneously received by the earth station's antenna and RF front end, even with a highly directional earth station antenna pointed specifically at the GEO satellite.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">Referring now to <figref idref="f0003">Figure 3</figref>, the actual elevation pointing angle between a directional antenna at any point <b>P</b> on the surface of the earth, pointing to any geostationary satellite, is indicated. The azimuth pointing angle is not shown and not relevant to illustrating the operative principles since any azimuth angle in 3D would have the same projection into the orthogonal polar plane shown in <figref idref="f0003">Figure 3</figref>. The governing Equations 1 and 2 provide the solutions to computation of <b><i>γ</i></b> for any latitude Φ. Equations 1 and 2 are set forth in the Equations Table and below (the equation number appearing next to the equation, in parentheses): <maths id="math0001" num="(1)"><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">g</mi><mo>=</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">r</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">G</mi></msub><msup><mfenced open="[" close="]" separators=""><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><msup><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">r</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">E</mi></msub><mo>/</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">r</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">G</mi></msub></mfenced><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>2</mn><mspace width="1ex"/><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">r</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">E</mi></msub><mo>/</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">r</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">G</mi></msub></mfenced><mi mathvariant="italic">COS</mi><mfenced><mi mathvariant="normal">Φ</mi></mfenced></mfenced><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>/</mo><mn>2</mn></mrow></msup></math><img id="ib0001" file="imgb0001.tif" wi="95" he="8" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> <maths id="math0002" num="(2)"><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">γ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi mathvariant="italic">COS</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced open="[" close="]" separators=""><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">r</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">G</mi></msub><mo>/</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">g</mi></mfenced><mspace width="1ex"/><mi mathvariant="italic">SIN</mi><mfenced><mi mathvariant="normal">Φ</mi></mfenced></mfenced></math><img id="ib0002" file="imgb0002.tif" wi="95" he="8" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">By way of example, and without limitation, the table in <figref idref="f0003">Figure 3</figref> computes the approximate elevation angle for a directional antenna at increments of 10 degrees of latitude, starting 80 degrees of latitude, which is approximately the highest latitude under which GEO-to-earth station line-of-sight communication links could be sustained, to 0 degrees of latitude, which is the equator.</p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">Next, referring to <figref idref="f0004">Figure 4</figref>, the geometry of two satellites in a LEO orbital plane is presented. In this <figref idref="f0004">Figure 4</figref> and including Equations 3 and 4, the relationship between the spacing, <b>s,</b> of the LEO satellites in-plane and the subtended angle <b>θ</b> as measured from a vertex at the earth's geometric center, <b>C,</b> is indicated. In this <figref idref="f0004">Figure 4</figref>, <b>P</b> is indicated at the equator. Equations 3 and 4 are set forth below (the equation number appearing next to the equation, in parentheses). <maths id="math0003" num="(3)"><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="italic">SIN</mi><mfenced><mi mathvariant="normal">θ</mi></mfenced><mo>/</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">a</mi><mo>=</mo><mi mathvariant="italic">SIN</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">α</mi></mfenced><mo>/</mo><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">r</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">E</mi></msub><mo>+</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">h</mi></mfenced><mo>=</mo><mi mathvariant="italic">SIN</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>−</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">α</mi></mfenced><mo>/</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">r</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">E</mi></msub></math><img id="ib0003" file="imgb0003.tif" wi="77" he="8" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> <maths id="math0004" num="(4)"><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">s</mi><mo>=</mo><mn>2</mn><mspace width="1ex"/><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">r</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">L</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi mathvariant="italic">SIN</mi><mfenced separators=""><mi mathvariant="normal">θ</mi><mo>/</mo><mn>2</mn></mfenced></math><img id="ib0004" file="imgb0004.tif" wi="76" he="7" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> Expressed in terms of <b>Θ</b>, Equation 5 provides a solution for determining the angle <b>Θ</b>. <maths id="math0005" num="(5)"><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">Θ</mi><mo>=</mo><mn>2</mn><mspace width="1ex"/><mi mathvariant="italic">ARCSIN</mi><mfenced separators=""><mi mathvariant="normal">S</mi><mo>/</mo><mn>2</mn><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">r</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">L</mi></msub></mfenced></math><img id="ib0005" file="imgb0005.tif" wi="72" he="8" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">Next, referring to <figref idref="f0005">Figure 5</figref>, the two sets of geometries are overlaid, with the heavy blue lines indicating direction vectors to LEO satellite locations as the LEO satellite constellation orbits, as seen from <b>P1NE</b> and <b>P8NE.</b> In the <figref idref="f0005">Figure 5</figref> overlay it can be seen that<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> as a LEO satellite approaches any point <b>P</b> on the earth from the north, a directional antenna at <b>P</b> pointing toward the GEO satellite is pointing south.</p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">However, as any specific LEO satellite passes over and then goes beyond any point <b>P,</b> if it continues transmitting backwards toward the earth station at <b>P,</b> at some point it would transmit down the boresight of any antenna pointing toward a GEO satellite.</p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">In order for a LEO satellite constellation to provide continuous coverage to anywhere on earth, at least one satellite must be in view at all times from any point <b>P</b> on the earth, and the pointing direction from that satellite to the point <b>P</b> must not be the along the same vector as the pointing direction between point <b>P</b> and a GEO satellite. Therefore, during the period when a first satellite in LEO orbit must cease transmitting to point <b>P</b> in order to avoid interfering with GEO signals arriving at the same time and place on the same frequency, another second satellite in LEO orbit must be available in view of the point <b>P</b> in order to carry on whatever communications may be taking place between the LEO communications satellite constellation and the earth station at point <b>P.</b> <figref idref="f0006 f0007">Figures 6</figref> and <figref idref="f0008 f0009">7</figref>, including the 'zoom-in' views of those diagrams, will be used to demonstrate two end-case situations, first in <figref idref="f0006">Figures 6A</figref>, <figref idref="f0007">6B</figref> at the near maximum latitude where any earth station may be practically anticipated to communicate with a GEO satellite (approximately 70 degrees latitude) and secondly in <figref idref="f0008">Figures 7A</figref>, <figref idref="f0009">7B</figref> at the equator.</p>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">Referring now to <figref idref="f0006">Figures 6A</figref>, <figref idref="f0007">6B</figref>, the computation is shown to compute the maximum spacing of two satellites in a polar LEO orbit which are, or could be, in communication with point <b>P1NE</b> at 70 degrees latitude, such that both (a) the earth station is never without line-of-sight to an orbiting LEO satellite suitably far enough above the local horizon to be available for reliable communications, and (b) during the period when any orbiting LEO satellite is within a guard band around the vector between the earth station and a GEO satellite, another LEO satellite is within view (and far enough above the local horizon), to take over any communications function with the earth station from the first LEO satellite (since the first LEO cannot transmit to the earth station when it is within the guard band, so that it does not interfere with the GEO satellite communications to the earth station).</p>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">In <figref idref="f0006">Figures 6A</figref>, <figref idref="f0007">6B</figref>, s must be found (see Equations 3 and 4), which is used to compute <b>θ</b> (see Equation 5) and thus the number of satellites in the LEO orbital plane required, subject to the constraints that the satellite orbiting at altitude <b>h</b> must be at least an angle <b><i>α</i></b> above the local horizon and maintain a guard band angle of <b>β</b> around the vector between the earth station and a GEO at angle <b><i>γ</i></b>. The cosine formula is employed, first with<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> respect to triangle <b>C-P1NE-D</b> to compute d, then with respect to triangle <b>C-P1NE-A</b> to compute <b>a,</b> then finally with respect to triangle <b>A-P1NE-D</b> to compute s, given the previously computed <b>d,</b> previously computed <b>a</b> and known angle <b>ω1.</b> (Although Equation 8 may provide two solutions, the meaningful solution is utilized for the distance d.) The relevant equations are indicated as Equations 5 through 8, 9 through 12, and 11 through 13, which are set forth below (the equation number appearing next to the equation, in parentheses). <maths id="math0006" num="(5)"><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">Θ</mi><mo>=</mo><mn>2</mn><mspace width="1ex"/><mi mathvariant="italic">ARCSIN</mi><mfenced separators=""><mi mathvariant="normal">S</mi><mo>/</mo><mn>2</mn><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">r</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">L</mi></msub></mfenced></math><img id="ib0006" file="imgb0006.tif" wi="103" he="8" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> <maths id="math0007" num="(6)"><math display="block"><msubsup><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>d</mi><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>+</mo><msubsup><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup><mo>−</mo><mn>2</mn><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>d</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>cos</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><msub><mi>ω</mi><mn>1</mn></msub></math><img id="ib0007" file="imgb0007.tif" wi="103" he="10" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> <maths id="math0008" num="(7)"><math display="block"><msup><mi>d</mi><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>2</mn><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>d</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>cos</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><msub><mi>ω</mi><mn>1</mn></msub><mo>+</mo><mfenced separators=""><msubsup><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup><mo>−</mo><msubsup><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup></mfenced><mo>=</mo><mn>0</mn></math><img id="ib0008" file="imgb0008.tif" wi="103" he="8" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> <maths id="math0009" num="(8)"><math display="block"><mi>d</mi><mo>=</mo><mfrac><mrow><mn>2</mn><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>cos</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><msub><mi>ω</mi><mn>1</mn></msub><mo>±</mo><msqrt><mrow><msup><mfenced open="[" close="]" separators=""><mn>2</mn><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>cos</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><msub><mi>ω</mi><mn>1</mn></msub></mfenced><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>4</mn><mfenced separators=""><msubsup><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup><mo>−</mo><msubsup><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup></mfenced></mrow></msqrt></mrow><mn>2</mn></mfrac></math><img id="ib0009" file="imgb0009.tif" wi="97" he="18" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> <maths id="math0010" num="(9)"><math display="block"><msub><mi>ω</mi><mn>3</mn></msub><mo>=</mo><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></math><img id="ib0010" file="imgb0010.tif" wi="103" he="7" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> <maths id="math0011" num="(10)"><math display="block"><msubsup><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>a</mi><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>+</mo><msubsup><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup><mo>−</mo><mn>2</mn><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>a</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>cos</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><msub><mi>ω</mi><mn>3</mn></msub></math><img id="ib0011" file="imgb0011.tif" wi="105" he="8" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> <maths id="math0012" num="(11)"><math display="block"><msup><mi>a</mi><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>2</mn><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>a</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>cos</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><msub><mi>ω</mi><mn>3</mn></msub><mo>+</mo><mfenced separators=""><msubsup><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup><mo>−</mo><msubsup><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup></mfenced><mo>=</mo><mn>0</mn></math><img id="ib0012" file="imgb0012.tif" wi="105" he="9" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> <maths id="math0013" num="(12)"><math display="block"><mi>a</mi><mo>=</mo><mfrac><mrow><mn>2</mn><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>cos</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><msub><mi>ω</mi><mn>3</mn></msub><mo>±</mo><msqrt><mrow><msup><mfenced open="[" close="]" separators=""><mn>2</mn><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>cos</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><msub><mi>ω</mi><mn>3</mn></msub></mfenced><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>4</mn><mfenced separators=""><msubsup><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup><mo>−</mo><msubsup><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup></mfenced></mrow></msqrt></mrow><mn>2</mn></mfrac></math><img id="ib0013" file="imgb0013.tif" wi="106" he="13" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> <maths id="math0014" num="(13)"><math display="block"><msub><mi>ω</mi><mn>2</mn></msub><mo>=</mo><mfenced separators=""><mn>180</mn><mo>−</mo><mi>α</mi><mo>−</mo><mi>γ</mi><mo>−</mo><mi>β</mi></mfenced></math><img id="ib0014" file="imgb0014.tif" wi="106" he="7" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">As can be seen by comparing <figref idref="f0006">Figures 6A</figref>, <figref idref="f0007">6B</figref> and <figref idref="f0008">Figures 7A</figref>, <figref idref="f0009">7B</figref>, as a satellite in the LEO constellation approaches the equator and covers a point <b>P</b> with its communications beam, the distance between when the satellite ascends above the horizon and when it must stop transmitting to the point <b>P,</b> as <b>P</b> also approaches the equator, is reduced. Unlike the more northerly positions of the satellite and points <b>P,</b> however, point <b>P</b> at the equator can also be communicated with by a LEO satellite which is departing the equator, or descending in the sky to the South.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025"><figref idref="f0010">Figure 8</figref> shows one portion of one plane of the invention, which comprises a LEO-based constellation for communications with earth stations anywhere in the world, and which can operate simultaneously in spectrum allocated for GEO-to-earth station use, including to an earth station at the same time and place, which operates as will be further described below. <figref idref="f0010">Figure 8</figref> shows three satellites (represented by the circles designated 1, 2 and 3) in one orbital plane at two different conceptual times, called T=1 and T=2, operating near the equator to service a ground station at the equator. The satellites 1, 2 and 3 at time T=1 are represented by solid line circles and at time T=2 are represented by broken line circles. Operations near the equator are the limiting case for the invention, and so are shown in detail and the focus of much of the disclosure. In <figref idref="f0010">Figure 8</figref>, one of the satellites labeled "2" approaches the equator at T=1, and then crosses the equator, with point <b>P8NE</b> below it. In this Figure, the point <b>P8SE</b> is introduced, being the nearly identical point to <b>P8NE,</b> except just south of the equator whilst <b>P8NE</b> is just north of the equator. The northern horizon is indicated as <b>NH</b> and the southern horizon as <b>SH.</b></p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">In the disclosed invention, as satellite 3 rises above the northern horizon <b>NH</b> by a chosen angle <b><i>α</i></b> with respect to an earth station at <b>P8NE</b> at the equator, satellite 3 is able to create a communications link with <b>P8NE.</b> At the same time T=1, excepting a necessary time for hand-off, satellite 2, which was previously serving communications with <b>P8NE,</b> ceases its communications with P8NE as it enters <b>P8NE's</b> GEO satellite guard band. As satellite 3 continues ascending across <b>P8NE's</b> northern sky, it continues serving any communications needs of <b>P8NE,</b> which can be on the same frequency as that used with any GEO satellite, without interfering with any communications which may be ongoing with said GEO satellite, until it arrives at the position indicated of satellite 2 at T=1. At that time a satellite 4 (not shown) will begin rising above the northern horizon with respect to <b>P8NE,</b> so that satellite 3 can turn off its communications link with <b>P8NE</b> while it transitions across <b>P8NE</b>'s GEO guard band.</p>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">Meanwhile, as satellite 2 comes out of the guard band of <b>P8NE</b> at T=2, it can begin serving <b>P8SE,</b> which is assumed at the same place on the equator as <b>P8NE,</b> except south of the equator. Prior to satellite 2 beginning service of <b>P8SE, P8SE</b> was served by satellite 3, which is setting to the south, with respect to <b>P8SE.</b> In the same way, every point around the globe is covered by a satellite in the constellation.</p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">Referring now to <figref idref="f0011">Figure 9</figref>, the communications beams associated with two satellites in the disclosed invention are described as they transition across the sky over the<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> equator from North to South. As stated previously, the beams described are the antenna patterns created by real-time adjustable beam antennas on the LEO satellites, such as can be created with phased array antennas, which are well known and understood to those practiced in the art. As also previously stated, the beam envelopes may have within each of them various sub-beams for specific frequency-reuse, polarization re-use or accommodation of other orbital elements or earth station elements which are nevertheless within the scope of the invention.</p>
<p id="p0029" num="0029">Referring still to <figref idref="f0011">Figure 9</figref>, the forward beam angle with respect to the satellite is indicated as angle <b>ψ</b> and the backward angle of the beam is indicated as angle <b>λ</b>.</p>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">As indicated in <figref idref="f0011">Figure 9</figref>, around the descending semi-circle of the polar orbit of the LEO communications satellite, for that portion during which a satellite is in quadrant 1, the LEO projects its communications beam forward in the direction it is travelling, continuously, at an angle of <b>ψ</b>, which can be as large an angle as reasonable or feasible for communications with earth stations until the satellite's latitude, <b><i>σ</i></b>, reaches a so-called latitude limit, as it approaches the equator. With respect to the forward portion of the beam, as it approaches the equator, the control means of the LEO satellite's directional antenna begins to reduce the forward angle of its forward beam as indicated as the satellite labeled SAT2 progresses from T=1 to T=6 toward the equator.</p>
<p id="p0031" num="0031">Also in <figref idref="f0011">Figure 9</figref>, now noting the satellite labeled SAT1, as it progresses from T=1 to T=6, its beam is extinguished over the equator and no communications occur with that satellite from any ground station while it transits across the GEO guard band at the equator. After crossing the equatorial guard band into quadrant 2, the SAT1 then expands what is now the backward pointing portion of its communications beam as indicated, such that when the satellite has reached the latitude limit angle away from the equator, the backward beam cover a maximum region behind it, as a mirror image to the forward beam communications coverage area produced in quadrant 1.</p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032">Each satellite also controls the angle, <b>λ</b>, of a so-called backward beam as shown in <figref idref="f0012">Figures 10A</figref>, <figref idref="f0013">10B</figref>. <figref idref="f0012">Figures 10A</figref>, <figref idref="f0013">10B</figref> also indicate the latitude of the satellite at any particular point in its orbit, <b><i>σ</i></b>. The parameters and labels <b>α</b>, <b>β</b>, <b><i>γ</i></b>, <b>A, P, C, a,</b> and d are as previously discussed with respect to <figref idref="f0006 f0007">Figures 6</figref> and <figref idref="f0008 f0009">7</figref>, and Equations 5 through 15 are operative as previously described with respect to <figref idref="f0006 f0007">Figures 6</figref> and <figref idref="f0008 f0009">7</figref> to compute the relevant geometric angles and lengths of the triangles. Once the lengths <b>a</b> and <b>d</b> are found, the Equations 17, 18 and 19 are employed to calculate <b>ψ</b> at the latitude limit and <b>λ</b> as a function<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> of <b><i>σ</i></b>, for a given <b>β</b> and <b><i>γ</i></b>. Equations 14 through 19 are set forth below (the equation number appearing next to the equation, in parentheses). <maths id="math0015" num="(14)"><math display="block"><msup><mi>s</mi><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>a</mi><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>+</mo><msup><mi>d</mi><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>2</mn><mi mathvariant="italic">ad</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>cos</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><msub><mi>ω</mi><mn>2</mn></msub></math><img id="ib0015" file="imgb0015.tif" wi="72" he="9" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> <maths id="math0016" num="(15)"><math display="block"><mi>s</mi><mo>=</mo><msqrt><mrow><msup><mi>a</mi><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>+</mo><msup><mi>d</mi><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>2</mn><mi mathvariant="italic">ad</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>cos</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><msub><mi>ω</mi><mn>2</mn></msub></mrow></msqrt></math><img id="ib0016" file="imgb0016.tif" wi="72" he="9" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> <maths id="math0017" num="(16)"><math display="block"><mfrac><mrow><mi>sin</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>ψ</mi></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub></mfrac><mo>=</mo><mfrac><mrow><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac><mo>=</mo><mfrac><mrow><mi>sin</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>σ</mi></mrow><mi>a</mi></mfrac></math><img id="ib0017" file="imgb0017.tif" wi="71" he="15" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> <maths id="math0018" num="(17)"><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">σ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mspace width="1ex"/><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><mi>a</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0018" file="imgb0018.tif" wi="71" he="15" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> <maths id="math0019" num="(18)"><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">ψ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mspace width="1ex"/><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0019" file="imgb0019.tif" wi="71" he="14" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> <maths id="math0020" num="(19)"><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">λ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mspace width="1ex"/><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>γ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>β</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0020" file="imgb0020.tif" wi="71" he="10" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p>
<p id="p0033" num="0033">Tabulations of the various parameters appear in Table 1 (<figref idref="f0017 f0018">Figure 14</figref>) for the input parameters of <b><i>α</i></b>=5 degrees, <b>β</b>=5 degrees and <b>h=</b>1,800km<b>.</b> For those parameters, the computations outlined in red define the primary elements of the disclosed invention, and the implementation of the satellite antenna control mechanism which regulates the beam and/or sub beam projection, showing: that 11 satellites are required in each polar orbital plane, that the maximum forward beam angle required is 50.96 degrees, that the forward beam should begin limiting at a satellite latitude of 34.04 degrees (maintaining pointing to just past the equator as it approaches the equator), and that the angle of the back beam <b>λ</b> should track the values indicated in the columns titled with <b>λ</b> and <b><i>σ</i></b>, where <b>σ</b> to the left of the long black line is treated as a dependent variable based on the LEO sat communicating with an earth station <b>P</b> as indicated in the first column. Notice that as the equator is approached, the back beam angle becomes negative, indicating that the back beam must begin pointing somewhat ahead of the satellite, rather than behind it, as the satellite nears the equator, in order to avoid<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> transmitting down the bore sight of an antenna pointed at a GEO satellite. In the limiting case where <b>β</b>=0, the back angle never goes negative and the back beam angle <b>λ</b> at the equator is 0 (this situation is shown in Table 2, <figref idref="f0019 f0020">Figure 15</figref>). The columns under <b><i>σ</i></b> and <b>ψ</b> to the right of the long black line in Table 1 (<figref idref="f0017 f0018">Figure 14</figref>) compute the forward beam angle as a function of the latitude of the satellite, where now the latitude of the satellite is treated as an independent variable.</p>
<p id="p0034" num="0034">To show how the disclosed invention is applicable to other parameters, Table 3 (<figref idref="f0021 f0022">Figure 16</figref>) shows the computations for input parameters of <b><i>α</i></b>= 10 degrees, <b>β</b>=10 degrees and <b>h</b>=800km. For those parameters the computations show: that 21 satellites are required in each polar orbital plane to implement the method, that the maximum forward beam angle required is 61.04 degrees, and that the forward beam should begin limiting at a satellite latitude of 18.96 degrees (maintaining pointing to just past the equator as it approaches the equator). For example, still referring to Table 3 (<figref idref="f0021 f0022">Figure 16</figref>), when one of the satellites in the constellation approaches the equator in quadrant 1, when its latitude references to the center of the earth is at 8.06 degrees North, its back beam must be -0.05 degrees or less, therefore actually then the back beam is pointing forward.</p>
<p id="p0035" num="0035">As can be seen in <figref idref="f0011">Figure 9</figref> and <figref idref="f0012 f0013">10</figref>, as one of the satellites in the constellation approaches the equator, its overall beam width declines by the governing equations to zero. However, as the beam width approaches zero, there is some practical limit for realizable satellite antennas. This practical limit can change based on implementation methods for the antenna and its associated control function, and at that limit the beam can simply be turned off (no longer transmitting). Any additional margin associated with such minimum beam width can be accommodated by adjusting the guard band, <b>β</b>.</p>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">The satellites may be configured with a satellite control mechanism that controls the satellite operations. For example, the control mechanism may determine the position of the satellite, including its latitude, and may use the latitude position to regulate the beam projected form the satellite. According to some embodiments, the satellite control mechanism preferably includes computing components that are carried by the satellite. The computing components preferably include a computer that is provided with software that includes instructions for monitoring the positions of the satellite along its orbit and regulating beams projected by antennas of the satellite. Any suitable mechanism for directing the beam of the antenna may be employed, including mechanical or electronic controls that limit, expand, direct, or combine these methods to regulate the beam angle. The beam also may be<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> formed from sub-beams. The satellite may be provided with one or more real-time adjustable beam antennas, such as, for example, a phased array antenna, or other antennas that are known in the art. The satellite antennas may generate beam envelopes that may comprise various sub-beams for specific frequency-reuse and/or polarization re-use. According to some embodiment, the beam envelope sub-beams may be configured to accommodate other orbital elements and/or earth station elements. According to preferred embodiments, the satellite is configured to produce one or more beams, and preferably, a beam may be provided with one or more forward portions, and one or more rearward portions (for example, where a beam forward portion may comprise a first beam, and a beam rearward portion may comprise a second beam). The beam portion may be regulated (e.g., by turning it on or off) to limit the beam field or projection. According to some embodiments, the satellite control mechanism may be powered using the power source of the satellite. According to some embodiments, the system components may be powered with solar panels that may be deployed on the satellite for this and other purposes. The satellite beam control mechanism preferably includes computing components configured to process the satellite location information, and determine the beam angle to be provided by an antenna, such as, for example, a transmitting antenna of the satellite. The control mechanism preferably manipulates the beam angle in accordance with determinations from the satellite location information and the application of the positioning as set forth herein, and, in particular, according to the embodiments provided represented by the equations herein (see <i>e.g.,</i> Equations 5 through 13). Satellites may be provided with suitable antennas for communications with earth stations. For example, phased array antennas, helical antennas, or other suitable antennas may be provided. In addition, the satellites may be configured to communicate with other satellites. Suitable antennas, such as lenses for satellite cross-link communications may be provided. For example, adjacent satellites may communicate with each other. The satellites also may be provided with devices for routing signals, such as, communications and data. For example, the satellite may be configured with one or more switching units that process information as to the communication destination, and route the communication through an appropriate satellite. According to some embodiments, the satellites are configured to route communications to an earth station within the beam range of the satellite, and the earth station may be connected to a network that routes the communication to a designated destination. Similarly, transmissions from an earth station may be received by a satellite, and the satellite may route that communication to a destination, such as, a device. For example, according to some embodiments, the satellites<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> and the satellite system preferably may transport of datagrams between any satellite and a ground terrestrial network. Earth stations, which may be configured as or in association with a gateway station may receive and transmit signals, such as datagrams, between a satellite. This may be carried via immediate re-transception of the datagram to a gateway station in view of the same satellite (<i>i.e.,</i> bent pipe), where the data is transmitted to the satellite from an earth station or gateway, and the satellite sends it right back down again. In some embodiments, the signal or data may be sent without modification, other than processing to retransmit the signal back (which may involve one or more of signal amplification, shifting the uplink/downlink frequency for the re-transmission. According to other embodiments, the satellite may be configured with equipment that may be used to carry out on-board processing of the signal, such as for example, to demodulate, decode, re-encode and/or modulate the signal (e.g., through a regenerative transponder). According to some preferred embodiments, transport of datagrams between any satellite and a ground terrestrial network may be carried out via a crosslink to one or more other satellites in the satellite constellation, and then from these other satellites to a gateway. For example, the intended gateway may not be in view of the first satellite at any particular time, but may be in view of one of the other satellites of the satellite constellation. A satellite in view of the gateway may receive a datagram routed from another satellite (<i>e.g.,</i> the first satellite). The satellites of the constellation preferably may be configured to crosslink, and route transmissions through their respective cross-links.</p>
<p id="p0037" num="0037">The equations and tables may be re-arranged with straightforward mathematical manipulations well known to those practiced in mathematical arts, to enable any particular parameter shown to be a free variable, allowing the rest of the satellite constellation orbital elements and satellite antenna pointing arrangements to be computed thereafter, without going outside of the scope of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p0038" num="0038">It is readily understood from the symmetry of the disclosed invention that the satellites operate in mirror image of each other in each quadrant. That is, the geometry, antenna patterns and operation of the satellites in a plane in quadrant 1 are mirrored around the equator to generate quadrant 2, which is then mirrored around the North-South axis of the earth to generate quadrant 3, and then mirrored up around the equator to generate quadrant 4. The details of a satellite crossing the equator have been presented in detail as this is the place of highest potential for interference, and this when crossing the equator, the most effective interference avoidance technique is to simply have the equator-overpassing satellite cease transmitting to the earth stations when within the guard band around the GEO pointing<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> vector. This also permits the satellite sufficient time to re-orient the antenna system to the subsequent quadrant. When a satellite is over the poles, it must also re-orient its antenna pointing system however the mechanics of that can be performed in an unconstrained way in any manner suitably designed by those practiced in the art, because there are no geostationary communications possible at the poles, since no geostationary satellite can be in view from the poles.</p>
<p id="p0039" num="0039">It should be noted that the drawings in <figref idref="f0010">Figures 8</figref>, <figref idref="f0011">9</figref> and <figref idref="f0012 f0013">10</figref> imply that the LEO communications beam intersects the ground at exactly the equator. In practical implementation, the beam would extend forward beyond the equator as the satellite approaches the equator, by an extent necessary to accommodate various uncertainties in orbit and antenna patterns, as well to accommodate the time necessary to handoff from the other LEO satellite as it enters the guard zone over the equator. This practical matter is easily accommodated without going outside of the scope of the invention.</p>
<p id="p0040" num="0040">An option that complicates the design of the satellite antenna and antenna control system is as follows, but remains within the scope of this invention. The beam envelope which has been disclosed above is typically composed of many sub-beams. Certain sub-beams may be turned off or re-directed as the satellite passes over or near the equator, enabling additional communications support for areas above and below the equator, without causing the satellite to cease all transmission to earth stations. This option however requires careful control of side lobes of the satellite antenna pattern, which can add expense and may not be technically possible for certain antenna implementation methods.</p>
<p id="p0041" num="0041">Because the orbit of the disclosed satellite constellation is polar, the azimuth plane of the LEO satellite constellation can be operated independently of the elevation plane which has been thoroughly described herein. As such, the number of planes for complete global coverage can be designed as an independent variable with respect to the operation of the satellites and their antenna patterns in a plane. For example, the LEO-based communications system can be designed to cover 30 degrees of longitude to the right or left of the plane of orbit, while simultaneously operating as provided for in this disclosure, and as above with respect to Table 1 (<figref idref="f0017 f0018">Figure 14</figref>) for example, within the plane of orbit.</p>
<p id="p0042" num="0042"><figref idref="f0014">Figure 11</figref> shows a complete satellite constellation (not to scale) which complies with the specifications of Table 1 (<figref idref="f0017 f0018">Figure 14</figref>), with 11 satellites per plane and 6 planes (only three being depicted in the Figure), at an orbit height of 1800km, in the required polar orbit. As seen in <figref idref="f0014">Figure 11</figref>, each plane may be populated such that the satellite within<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> the plane have the equator crossing time of each satellite slightly offset from the neighboring plane, which, depending on plane spacing selected, may provide further assistance to cover earth stations near the equator which are closer to a neighboring orbital plane.</p>
<p id="p0043" num="0043">The method of onward communications between the class of LEO communications constellations disclosed herein and a further earth terminal or earth gateway is flexible and may be either via an earth gateway within view of each satellite in a so-called bent pipe architecture, or may be via a cross-linked architecture, such as that employed by the Iridium satellite constellation. Both implementations are possible with the disclosed invention, and either may be employed to complete a communications link between an earth station, a satellite operated within a satellite constellation as disclosed herein, and another earth station, or other terrestrial data or communications network.</p>
<p id="p0044" num="0044">In addition to the isolation provided between the GEO communications satellites, GEO-involved earth stations and the LEO-based communications system disclosed herein that is provided by the geometry of the operations and the antenna system, there are additional features of the disclosed system related to the earth stations which communicate with the LEO satellites which can now be described. When an earth station transmits up to a LEO satellite in the disclosed system, the transmission must only overcome the distance to the LEO satellite, which requires considerably less signal power than that required to overcome the distance to a GEO satellite at the same frequency. This situation is shown in Table 4 of <figref idref="f0023">Figure 17</figref>, which shows the free space path loss (FSPL) in-plane calculated for various angles from a LEO satellite in a constellation orbiting at an 800km altitude to an earth station, compared to the FSPL to a GEO satellite, at the same communications frequency of 12 GHz (Ku Band). The calculations show a minimum difference in path loss of 33dB. The difference in path loss provides a significant link margin to further reduce the possibility that a signal transmitted by an earth station with an omnidirectional antenna which is intending to transmit only to a LEO satellite is nevertheless recognized by a GEO satellite listening on the same frequency, thereby causing an interference with the GEO satellite communications system.</p>
<p id="p0045" num="0045">Referring still to Table 4 shown in <figref idref="f0023">Figure 17</figref>, the same path loss data provides the basis for the ability of an earth station associated with the LEO satellite communications constellation which has an omnidirectional antenna to avoid interference to it from a GEO-based communications signal. Because the LEO satellite is isolated from GEO-based receiving stations by geometry, the LEO satellite may transmit at powers such that the signal<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> power received on-ground by the earth stations associated with the LEO system may be much higher than the same power received by an omnidirectional antenna at the same frequency from a GEO system, thus providing the ability for the LEO-associated earth station to reject the much weaker signal from the GEO satellite, by means commonly known to those practiced in the art of receiver design.</p>
<p id="p0046" num="0046">Notwithstanding the previous paragraph, additional link margin may be desired to accommodate wider operating envelopes in a given system design. Therefore, the LEO system disclosed may be paired with earth stations which are designed to communicate solely with the LEO satellites, even though they are communicating on the same frequency as an earth station communicating with a GEO satellite right next to it. One additional optional element of the LEO satellite based communications system disclosed is to add a directional antenna to the earth station. While a fully azimuth and elevation directional antenna with a small beam width is an option, such an antenna is often prohibitive in cost, size, weight or power for certain applications. However, with the LEO satellite operating as described above provides for a communications direction that is always pointing towards the North in the Northern hemisphere, and pointing South in the Southern hemisphere. This fact enables a dramatically simpler directional antenna to be employed by the earth station. The in-plane antenna pattern of a simple loop antenna, which is oriented perpendicular to the ground, is shown in <figref idref="f0015">Figure 12</figref>. Even this simple antenna provides as much as 12 dB of additional link margin at a point P on the equator, and even more for higher latitudes. The only requirement on the earth station is that the direction of the antenna's highest gain be pointed generally South, if the earth station is in the Southern hemisphere, or generally North, if the earth station is in the Northern hemisphere.</p>
<p id="p0047" num="0047">Referring now to <figref idref="f0016">Figure 13</figref>, it is shown that by pointing the maximum antenna gain away from the direction of the GEO satellite, and towards the direction of the LEO satellite, additional margin is obtained to assist in minimizing the possibility that the LEO earth station's transmissions is received with sufficient power by a GEO satellite system to be recognized. The requirement to be generally pointing North or South, depending only on which hemisphere the earth station is in, is a much simpler requirement on an earth station directional antenna than the requirement to be fully azimuth and elevation directional capable, thus making the LEO-based system disclosed more economical for mass deployment. Other similar patterns from other types of antennas can be created which are well known to those practiced in the art of directional antennas which can provide for the<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> same or greater additional margins with economical implementations, without departing from the scope of this disclosure.</p>
<p id="p0048" num="0048">References are made to an earth station that receives and transmits communications between it and LEO satellites. The earth station may include antennas that are located on earth to receive transmissions from and/or send transmissions to LEO satellites. The antennas of the earth station may be any suitable antennas for receiving and/or transmitting suitable frequencies, and in particular RF frequencies to and from LEO satellites. Each LEO satellite may be configured with one and preferably a plurality of antennas. For example, an LEO satellite may have a first antenna that transmits a forward beam in a forward direction and a second antenna that transmits a rearward beam in a rearward direction (e.g., relative to the satellite orbit direction), where the antennas may be independently controlled, and may restrict or expand their respective beams or extinguish them. Satellite antennas may comprise one or more phased array antennas. For example, the phased array antenna may be configured with a number of individual radiating elements that are controllable to control the beam coverage, and in particular the beam configuration and angle. A computer on the satellite, which, according to some embodiments, may comprise a dedicated computer programmed with instructions for manipulating the beam angle (which, for example, may include software stored on a chip or other circuitry component that contains the instructions), may be used to control the antenna array to generate a beam projection that may be increased or decreased in accordance with the satellite orbit, and which may be carried out to maximize the coverage for an antenna. The computer preferably is configured with software containing instructions to regulate the operation of the antenna to eliminate transmissions that may otherwise interfere with GEO satellite communications (including where the LEO satellite and GEO satellite transmissions use the same spectrum). This may be carried out by controlling the beam angles of the projections from the antennas as well as turning off the antennas as needed (e.g., when within the guard band range of a GEO earth station antenna). According to some preferred embodiments, the computer may be configured to manipulate the beam projections in accordance with the determinations set forth herein. The satellite beams preferably are manipulated mechanically, electronically, or by both ways, to generate a desired beam of coverage and avoid transmissions within the guard band of a GEO satellite antenna (<i>e.g.,</i> of a GEO earth station).</p>
<p id="p0049" num="0049">These and other advantages may be realized with the present invention. While the invention has been described with reference to specific embodiments, the description is illustrative and is not to be construed as limiting the scope of the invention. Various<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> modifications and changes may occur to those skilled in the art without departing from the scope of the invention described herein and as defined by the appended claims.</p>
<heading id="h0007">LIST OF EQUATIONS REFERENCED</heading>
<p id="p0050" num="0050">
<tables id="tabl0001" num="0001">
<table frame="all">
<tgroup cols="3">
<colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="64mm"/>
<colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="84mm"/>
<colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="18mm"/>
<tbody>
<row rowsep="0">
<entry morerows="1" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="middle">Equations for <figref idref="f0003">Figure 3</figref>, to compute γ as a function of latitude Φ</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle"><maths id="math0021" num=""><math display="block"><mi>g</mi><mo>=</mo><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>G</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><msup><mfenced open="[" close="]" separators=""><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><msup><mfenced><mfrac><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>G</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>2</mn><mfenced><mfrac><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>G</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>cos</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>ϕ</mi></mfenced><mfrac><mn>1</mn><mn>2</mn></mfrac></msup></math><img id="ib0021" file="imgb0021.tif" wi="58" he="10" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Equation 1</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center" valign="middle"><maths id="math0022" num=""><math display="block"><mi>γ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>cos</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mspace width="1ex"/><mfenced open="[" close="]"><mfrac><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>G</mi></msub><mi>g</mi></mfrac></mfenced><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>sin</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>ϕ</mi></math><img id="ib0022" file="imgb0022.tif" wi="37" he="10" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Equation 2</entry></row>
<row rowsep="0">
<entry morerows="1" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="middle">Equations for <figref idref="f0004">Figure 4</figref>, to compute the angle θ between two LEO satellites as a function of S, the line-of-sight distance between them while in orbit</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle"><maths id="math0023" num=""><math display="block"><mi>s</mi><mo>=</mo><mn>2</mn><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>sin</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><mfenced><mfrac><mi>θ</mi><mn>2</mn></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0023" file="imgb0023.tif" wi="23" he="10" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Equation 3</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center" valign="middle"><maths id="math0024" num=""><math display="block"><mi>θ</mi><mo>=</mo><mn>2</mn><mspace width="1ex"/><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mspace width="1ex"/><mfenced><mfrac><mi>s</mi><mrow><mn>2</mn><mspace width="1ex"/><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mrow></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0024" file="imgb0024.tif" wi="31" he="10" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Equation 4</entry></row>
<row rowsep="0">
<entry align="center" valign="middle"/>
<entry align="center" valign="middle"><maths id="math0025" num=""><math display="block"><msub><mi>ω</mi><mn>1</mn></msub><mo>=</mo><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>γ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>β</mi></mfenced></math><img id="ib0025" file="imgb0025.tif" wi="33" he="5" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Equation 5</entry></row>
<row rowsep="0">
<entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">Equations for <figref idref="f0006">Figures 6A</figref>, <figref idref="f0007">6B</figref> to find <i>d</i> using cosine law on triangle C-P<sub>1</sub>-D</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle"><maths id="math0026" num=""><math display="block"><msubsup><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>d</mi><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>+</mo><msubsup><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup><mo>−</mo><mn>2</mn><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>d</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>cos</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><msub><mi>ω</mi><mn>1</mn></msub></math><img id="ib0026" file="imgb0026.tif" wi="47" he="6" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Equation 6</entry></row>
<row rowsep="0">
<entry align="center" valign="middle"><maths id="math0027" num=""><math display="block"><msup><mi>d</mi><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>2</mn><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>d</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>cos</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><msub><mi>ω</mi><mn>1</mn></msub><mo>+</mo><mfenced separators=""><msubsup><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup><mo>−</mo><msubsup><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup></mfenced><mo>=</mo><mn>0</mn></math><img id="ib0027" file="imgb0027.tif" wi="57" he="6" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Equation 7</entry></row>
<row rowsep="0">
<entry morerows="1" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="middle">Equations for <figref idref="f0008">Figures 7A</figref>, <figref idref="f0009">7B</figref> to find <i>d</i> using cosine law on triangle C-P<sub>8</sub>-D</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle"><maths id="math0028" num=""><math display="block"><mi>d</mi><mo>=</mo><mfrac><mrow><mn>2</mn><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>cos</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><msub><mi>ω</mi><mn>1</mn></msub><mo>±</mo><msqrt><mrow><msup><mfenced open="[" close="]" separators=""><mn>2</mn><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>cos</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><msub><mi>ω</mi><mn>1</mn></msub></mfenced><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>4</mn><mfenced separators=""><msubsup><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup><mo>−</mo><msubsup><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup></mfenced></mrow></msqrt></mrow><mn>2</mn></mfrac></math><img id="ib0028" file="imgb0028.tif" wi="78" he="11" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Equation 8</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">For <figref idref="f0008">Figures 7A</figref>, <figref idref="f0009">7B</figref> for the same result, one may substitute <i>ω</i><sub>1</sub> = (180 - <i>β</i>)</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle"/></row><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> -->
<row rowsep="0">
<entry morerows="2" align="center">Equations for <figref idref="f0006">Figures 6A</figref>, <figref idref="f0007">6B</figref> to find <i>α</i> using cosine law on triangle C-P<sub>1</sub>-A</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle"><i>ω</i><sub>3</sub> = (90 + <i>α</i>)</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Equation 9</entry></row>
<row rowsep="0">
<entry align="center" valign="middle"><maths id="math0029" num=""><math display="block"><msubsup><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>a</mi><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>+</mo><msubsup><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup><mo>−</mo><mn>2</mn><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>a</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>cos</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><msub><mi>ω</mi><mn>3</mn></msub></math><img id="ib0029" file="imgb0029.tif" wi="47" he="6" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Equation 10</entry></row>
<row rowsep="0">
<entry align="center" valign="middle"><maths id="math0030" num=""><math display="block"><msup><mi>a</mi><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>2</mn><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>a</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>cos</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><msub><mi>ω</mi><mn>3</mn></msub><mo>+</mo><mfenced separators=""><msubsup><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup><mo>−</mo><msubsup><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup></mfenced><mo>=</mo><mn>0</mn></math><img id="ib0030" file="imgb0030.tif" wi="57" he="6" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Equation 11</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Equations for <figref idref="f0008">Figures 7A</figref>, <figref idref="f0009">7B</figref> to find <i>α</i> using cosine law on triangle C-P<sub>8</sub>-A</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle"><maths id="math0031" num=""><math display="block"><mi>a</mi><mo>=</mo><mfrac><mrow><mn>2</mn><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>cos</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><msub><mi>ω</mi><mn>3</mn></msub><mo>±</mo><msqrt><mrow><msup><mfenced open="[" close="]" separators=""><mn>2</mn><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>cos</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><msub><mi>ω</mi><mn>3</mn></msub></mfenced><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>4</mn><mfenced separators=""><msubsup><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup><mo>−</mo><msubsup><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup></mfenced></mrow></msqrt></mrow><mn>2</mn></mfrac></math><img id="ib0031" file="imgb0031.tif" wi="77" he="11" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Equation 12</entry></row>
<row rowsep="0">
<entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">Equations for <figref idref="f0006">Figures 6A</figref>, <figref idref="f0007">6B</figref> to find <i>S</i> using cosine law on triangle A-P<sub>1</sub>-D</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle"><i>ω</i><sub>2</sub> = (180 - <i>α</i> - <i>γ</i> - <i>β</i>)</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Equation 13</entry></row>
<row rowsep="0">
<entry align="center" valign="middle">s<sup>2</sup> = <i>a</i><sup>2</sup> + <i>d</i><sup>2</sup> - 2<i>ad</i> cos <i>ω</i><sub>2</sub></entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Equation 14</entry></row>
<row rowsep="0">
<entry morerows="1" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="middle">Equations for <figref idref="f0008">Figures 7A</figref>, <figref idref="f0009">7B</figref> to find <i>S</i> using cosine law on triangle A-P<sub>8</sub>-D</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle"><maths id="math0032" num=""><math display="block"><mi>s</mi><mo>=</mo><msqrt><mrow><msup><mi>a</mi><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>+</mo><msup><mi>d</mi><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>2</mn><mi mathvariant="italic">ad</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>cos</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><msub><mi>ω</mi><mn>2</mn></msub></mrow></msqrt></math><img id="ib0032" file="imgb0032.tif" wi="48" he="6" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Equation 15</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">For <figref idref="f0008">Figures 7A</figref>, <figref idref="f0009">7B</figref>, for the same result one may substitute <i>ω</i><sub>2</sub> = (90 + <i>α</i> + <i>β</i>)</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle"/></row>
<row rowsep="0">
<entry morerows="3" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="middle">Equations for <figref idref="f0012">Figures 10A</figref>, <figref idref="f0013">10B</figref> to find λ, σ and ψ for LEO at position A</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle"><maths id="math0033" num=""><math display="block"><mfrac><mrow><mi>sin</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>ψ</mi></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub></mfrac><mo>=</mo><mfrac><mrow><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac><mo>=</mo><mfrac><mrow><mi>sin</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>σ</mi></mrow><mi>a</mi></mfrac></math><img id="ib0033" file="imgb0033.tif" wi="48" he="11" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Equation 16</entry></row>
<row rowsep="0">
<entry align="center" valign="middle"><maths id="math0034" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">σ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mspace width="1ex"/><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><mi>a</mi><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0034" file="imgb0034.tif" wi="45" he="11" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Equation 17</entry></row>
<row rowsep="0">
<entry align="center" valign="middle"><maths id="math0035" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">ψ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mspace width="1ex"/><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0035" file="imgb0035.tif" wi="47" he="11" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></entry>
<entry align="center" valign="middle">Equation 18</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center" valign="middle"><maths id="math0036" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">λ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mspace width="1ex"/><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>γ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>β</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0036" file="imgb0036.tif" wi="53" he="11" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></entry>
<entry align="center" valign="bottom">Equation 19</entry></row></tbody></tgroup>
</table>
</tables></p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> -->
<claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>A low earth orbiting, LEO, satellite constellation system for communications, which comprises
<claim-text>a) a plurality of satellites in a polar orbit about the earth;</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) the satellites being arranged in orbital planes around the earth to provide coverage for points on earth for communications and at all times, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) wherein the number of satellites in each orbital plane provides communications over the range of the orbital plane;</claim-text>
<claim-text>d) wherein each satellite has an antenna for receiving and transmitting signals to earth stations, and wherein the satellite antenna is controlled with a control mechanism to avoid transmitting down the bore sight of a GEO-pointing antenna at any point on earth;</claim-text>
<claim-text>e) wherein the satellite orbital plane defines a polar orbit about the four quadrants of the earth, wherein the satellite has a pointing control, and wherein the pointing control in the first quadrant is programmed with an algorithm to direct satellite transmissions to maximize the coverage and avoid transmitting down the boresight of a GEO-pointing antenna;</claim-text>
<claim-text>f) wherein the satellite pointing control directs the satellite transmission coverage in each quadrant of the plane of orbit to mirror the satellite transmission coverage of the rearward directed beam projected in the prior quadrant of the satellite orbit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>g) wherein the transition between quadrants at the equator includes the satellite turning off its transmitter towards the earth so as to avoid transmitting down the bore sight of an antenna pointing towards a geo-stationary earth orbiting, GEO, satellite; and<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>h) wherein the transmission between satellites and an earth station is carried out using spectrum also employed by GEO communications satellites communicating in the same region.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>The system of claim 1, wherein the means of transport of datagrams between any satellite and a ground terrestrial network is via immediate re-transception of the datagram to a gateway station that is located in view of the same satellite.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>The system of claim 1, wherein the means of transport of datagrams between any satellite of the LEO satellite constellation and a ground terrestrial network is via a crosslink to one or more other satellites in said constellation and then from said other satellites to a gateway, wherein the gateway is not in view of the first satellite at any particular time.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>The system of claim 3, wherein said satellites comprise switching means for switching transport of datagrams between satellites, wherein the switching means associated with a satellite is configured to hand-off transmission of datagrams to switching means associated with another satellite.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>The system of claim 1, wherein the associated earth station associated to transmit datagrams between the earth station and a satellite employs an omnidirectional antenna.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>The system of claim 1, wherein the associated earth station associated to transmit datagrams between the earth station and a satellite employs a directional antenna that is directional northerly or southerly with respect to the orbital plane of the constellation of satellites.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>The system of claim 5, wherein the antenna is directional in both elevation and azimuth.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>The system of claim 1, wherein the satellites are arranged in a orbital planes around the earth to provide coverage for every point on earth.<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>The system of claim 1, wherein the number of satellites in each orbital plane is selected according to the maximum transmission and reception coverage for the satellite altitude and horizon elevation angle.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>The system of claim 1, wherein said satellite pointing control comprises a control mechanism, and wherein the control mechanism controls the beam from one or more antennas of the satellite to direct satellite transmissions:
<claim-text>a) in accordance with a beam projection in the rearward direction being projected at a rearward beam angle of angle <b>λ</b>, which for an acute angle <b><i>γ</i></b> between the horizon and the vector at a location of a point on earth where a GEO earth station is pointing to a geostationary satellite, and for a GEO protection guard band angle <b>β</b> around the vector between the GEO earth station and the GEO satellite to which it points, which is at angle <b>γ</b> to the horizon, is determined by the expression: <maths id="math0037" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">λ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>γ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>β</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0037" file="imgb0037.tif" wi="52" he="10" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> where <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> represents the radius of the earth, where <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> represents the radius of the satellite's orbit, where <b><i>γ</i></b> represents an acute angle between the horizon and the vector at a location of a point on earth where a GEO earth station is pointing to a geostationary satellite, and where <b>β</b> represents a GEO protection guard band angle around the vector between the GEO earth station and the GEO satellite to which it points, which is at angle <b><i>γ</i></b> to the horizon; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) in accordance with a beam projection in the forward direction being projected at a forward beam angle of <b>ψ</b>, which for a given latitude position in the satellite's orbit, is determined by the expression: <maths id="math0038" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">ψ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mspace width="1ex"/><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0038" file="imgb0038.tif" wi="53" he="12" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> where <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> represents the radius of the earth, where <b><i>α</i></b> represents the horizon elevation angle, and where <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> represents the radius of the satellite's orbit.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>The system of claim 10, wherein the projections from the satellite are controlled with the control mechanism to maximize the coverage, and wherein the projections from the satellite are controlled to avoid transmitting down the boresight of a GEO-pointing antenna.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>The system of claim 1, wherein the satellite has a control mechanism that controls the satellite transmitter, and wherein the satellite antenna is controlled to turn off its communications link to avoid transmitting down the bore sight of a GEO-pointing antenna with said control mechanism at any point on earth by the control mechanism, said control mechanism being configured to turn off the transmitter at locations where transmissions from the transmitter would coincide with the boresight of a GEO earth station antenna pointing towards a GEO satellite.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>The system of claim 12, wherein each satellite is configured to turn off its transmitter that transmits toward the earth at the transition between quadrants at the equator, so as to avoid transmitting down the bore sight of an antenna pointing towards a GEO satellite.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>The system of claim 1, wherein the LEO satellites provide communications links, and wherein a satellite of the constellation of LEO satellites approaching a boresight of an antenna of a GEO satellite earth station or a GEO satellite guard band that is within the orbital plane of the approaching satellite is configured to hand-off communications to another of the LEO satellites that is not within the boresight of an antenna of a GEO satellite.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0015" num="0015">
<claim-text>The system of claim 1, wherein said LEO satellite antenna for receiving and transmitting signals to earth stations comprises a real-time adjustable beam antenna.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0016" num="0016">
<claim-text>The system of claim 1, wherein the satellite transmits a beam that is projected from the antenna, said beam having a forward direction and a rearward direction relative to the satellite movement within the orbit.<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0017" num="0017">
<claim-text>The system of claim 1, wherein the satellite transmits a beam that is projected from the antenna, and wherein said beam has a forward pointing portion and a rearward pointing portion.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0018" num="0018">
<claim-text>The system of claim 16, wherein the satellite antenna comprises a directional antenna; wherein the satellite beam in the forward direction is projected at a forward beam angle of <b>ψ</b>, and wherein the satellite beam in the rearward direction is projected at a rearward beam angle of <b>λ</b>; wherein said satellite directional antenna is directed with the control mechanism to reduce the forward beam angle of <b>ψ</b> as the LEO satellite moves toward a latitude limit.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0019" num="0019">
<claim-text>The system of claim 18, wherein the satellite directional antenna is directed with the control mechanism to decrease the forward beam angle of <b>ψ</b> as the LEO satellite moves as the satellite moves toward a latitude limit angle away from the equator.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0020" num="0020">
<claim-text>The system of claim 18, wherein the satellite directional antenna is manipulated to increase the rearward pointing beam angle of <b>λ</b> as the satellite moves away from the equator.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0021" num="0021">
<claim-text>The system of claim 18, wherein the satellite directional antenna is directed with the control mechanism to increase the rearward pointing beam angle of <b>λ</b> as the satellite moves away from a GEO earth station guard band.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0022" num="0022">
<claim-text>The system of claim 18, wherein the satellite directional antenna is directed with the control mechanism to increase the rearward pointing beam angle of <b>λ</b> as the satellite moves away from the boresight of a GEO earth station.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0023" num="0023">
<claim-text>The system of claim 17, wherein the satellite communication beam forward portion of a satellite beam has a forward beam angle that is adjusted as a function of the latitude of the satellite.<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0024" num="0024">
<claim-text>The system of claim 1 , wherein the control mechanism controls one or more antennas of a satellite to produce a beam in the forward direction projected at a forward beam angle and to produce a beam in the rearward direction projected at a rearward beam angle.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0025" num="0025">
<claim-text>The system of claim 24, wherein the satellite beam in the rearward direction is projected at a rearward beam angle that decreases as the satellite moves forward in its directional orbit.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0026" num="0026">
<claim-text>The system of claim 24, wherein the satellite beam in the forward direction is projected at a forward beam angle that increases as the satellite moves forward in its directional orbit.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0027" num="0027">
<claim-text>The system of claim 25, wherein the satellite beam in the forward direction is projected at a forward beam angle that increases as the satellite moves forward in its directional orbit.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0028" num="0028">
<claim-text>The system of claim 25, wherein the satellite beam in the rearward direction is projected at a rearward beam angle of <b>λ</b>, which for an acute angle <b><i>γ</i></b> between the horizon and the vector at a location of a point on earth where a GEO earth station is pointing to a geostationary satellite, and for a GEO protection guard band angle <b>β</b> around the vector between the GEO earth station and the GEO satellite to which it points, which is at angle γ to the horizon, is determined by the expression: <maths id="math0039" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">λ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mspace width="1ex"/><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>γ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>β</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0039" file="imgb0039.tif" wi="52" he="10" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> where <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> represents the radius of the earth, where <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> represents the radius of the satellite's orbit, where <b><i>γ</i></b> represents an acute angle between the horizon and the vector at a location of a point on earth where a GEO earth station is pointing to a geostationary satellite, and where <b>β</b> represents a GEO protection guard band angle around the vector between the GEO earth station and the GEO satellite to which it points, which is at angle <b><i>γ</i></b> to the horizon.<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0029" num="0029">
<claim-text>The system of claim 26, wherein the satellite beam in the forward direction is projected at a forward beam angle of <b>ψ</b>, and wherein for a given latitude position in the satellite's orbit, the forward beam angle <b>ψ</b> projected is determined by the expression: <maths id="math0040" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">ψ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mspace width="1ex"/><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0040" file="imgb0040.tif" wi="53" he="12" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> where <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> represents the radius of the earth, where <b><i>α</i></b> represents the horizon elevation angle, and where <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> represents the radius of the satellite's orbit.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0030" num="0030">
<claim-text>The system of claim 29, wherein the horizon elevation angle consists of the minimum angle between (1) the horizon and (2) the satellite at which the satellite and an earth station to which the satellite may communicate, as viewed from the earth station location.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0031" num="0031">
<claim-text>The system of claim 27, wherein the satellite beam in the rearward direction is projected at a rearward beam angle of angle <b>λ</b>, wherein for a given latitude position in the satellite's orbit the rearward beam angle <b>λ</b> projected is determined by the expression: <maths id="math0041" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">λ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mspace width="1ex"/><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>γ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>β</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0041" file="imgb0041.tif" wi="52" he="10" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> where <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> represents the radius of the earth, where <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> represents the radius of the satellite's orbit where <b><i>γ</i></b> represents an acute angle between the horizon and the vector at a location of a point on earth where a GEO earth station is pointing to a geostationary satellite, and where <b>β</b> represents a GEO protection guard band angle around the vector between the GEO earth station and the GEO satellite to which it points, which is at angle <b><i>γ</i></b> to the horizon, and where <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> represents the radius of the satellite's orbit, wherein the satellite beam in the forward direction is projected at a forward beam angle of <b>ψ</b>, and wherein for a given latitude position in the satellite's orbit the forward beam angle <b>ψ</b> projected is determined by the expression:<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --> <maths id="math0042" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">ψ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mspace width="1ex"/><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0042" file="imgb0042.tif" wi="53" he="12" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> where <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> represents the radius of the earth, where <b><i>α</i></b> represents the horizon elevation angle, and where <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> represents the radius of the satellite's orbit.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0032" num="0032">
<claim-text>The system of claim 24, wherein the beam produced in the forward direction is comprised of a plurality of sub-beams.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0033" num="0033">
<claim-text>The system of claim 24, wherein the beam produced in the rearward direction is comprised of a plurality of sub-beams.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0034" num="0034">
<claim-text>The system of claim 24, wherein at least one of the beam produced in the forward direction and the beam produced in the rearward direction is comprised of a plurality of sub-beams, and wherein said sub-beams are controllable to control the projection of the communication beam from said satellite antenna.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0035" num="0035">
<claim-text>The system of claim 24, wherein the beam produced in the forward direction is comprised of a plurality of sub-beams, wherein the beam produced in the rearward direction is comprised of a plurality of sub-beams, and wherein said sub-beams are controllable to control the projection of the communication beam from said satellite antenna.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0036" num="0036">
<claim-text>The system of claim 34, wherein a sub-beam is controllable by positioning said antenna that provides the sub-beam.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0037" num="0037">
<claim-text>The system of claim 34, wherein at least one of said forward beam and said rearward beam is controllable by activating or deactivating a sub-beam comprising the respective forward beam or rearward beam.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0038" num="0038">
<claim-text>The system of claim 34, wherein said forward beam is controllable by activating or deactivating a sub-beam comprising the forward beam, and wherein said rearward beam is controllable by activating or deactivating a sub-beam comprising the rearward beam.<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0039" num="0039">
<claim-text>The system of claim 24 , wherein the satellite antenna comprises a real-time adjustable beam antenna.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0040" num="0040">
<claim-text>The system of claim 39, wherein the real-time adjustable beam antenna comprises a phased array antenna.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0041" num="0041">
<claim-text>The system of claim 39, wherein the antenna provides a beam envelope that is comprised of sub-beams configured for specific frequency-reuse, polarization re-use, or accommodation of other orbital elements or earth station elements.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0042" num="0042">
<claim-text>The system of claim 40, wherein the antenna provides a beam envelope that is comprised of sub-beams configured for specific frequency-reuse, polarization re-use, or accommodation of other orbital elements or earth station elements.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0043" num="0043">
<claim-text>The system of claim 24 , wherein said satellite constellation is provided so that at least one satellite of the satellite constellation is in view at all times from any earth station on the earth.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0044" num="0044">
<claim-text>The system of claim 24 , wherein the satellite beam in the forward direction is projected at a forward beam angle <b>ψ</b>; wherein the satellite beam in the rearward direction is projected at a rearward beam angle of <b>λ</b>; wherein at least one satellite antenna comprises a directional antenna that projects the forward beam, and wherein the at least one directional antenna projecting the forward beam is directed with the control mechanism to reduce the forward beam angle <b>ψ</b> as the LEO satellite moves toward a latitude limit, wherein at least one satellite antenna comprises a directional antenna that projects the rearward beam, wherein the at least one satellite directional antenna projecting the rearward beam is directed with the control mechanism to increase the rearward beam angle <b>λ</b> as the LEO satellite moves toward a latitude limit.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0045" num="0045">
<claim-text>The system of claim 44, wherein each directional antenna has an associated transmitter that provides a signal to the antenna, and wherein each satellite is configured to turn off an<!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --> associated transmitter at locations where transmission from its transmitter would coincide with the boresight of an antenna pointing towards a GEO satellite.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0046" num="0046">
<claim-text>The system of claim 24 , wherein said at least one antenna for receiving and transmitting to earth stations comprises a directional antenna and wherein there is at least one transmitter associated with the directional antenna that provides a signal to the antenna, and wherein each satellite is configured to turn off the associated transmitter at locations where transmission from its transmitter would coincide with the boresight of an antenna pointing towards a GEO satellite.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0047" num="0047">
<claim-text>The system of claim 46, wherein the equator defines a transition between quadrants of the plane of orbit.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0048" num="0048">
<claim-text>The system of claim 47, wherein each satellite is configured to turn off its transmitter that transmits toward the earth at the transition between quadrants at the equator, so as to avoid transmitting down the bore sight of an antenna pointing towards a GEO satellite.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0049" num="0049">
<claim-text>The system of claim 48, wherein each second, third and fourth quadrant of the plane of orbit is a mirror in operation of the first quadrant, wherein a satellite of the constellation of satellites in an orbit mirrors the angular beam projections for each successive quadrant.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0050" num="0050">
<claim-text>The system of claim 44, wherein the forward beam angle <b>ψ</b> and the rearward beam angle <b>λ</b> are determined at the latitude limit as a function of the latitude limit <b><i>σ</i></b> for a given guard band angle <b>β</b> around the vector between a GEO earth station and a GEO satellite at an angle <b><i>γ</i></b>, and wherein the satellite is in orbit at an altitude <b>h</b> that is at least an angle <b><i>α</i></b> above the local horizon.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0051" num="0051">
<claim-text>The system of claim 27, wherein each satellite includes a computer having a hardware processor, and wherein the computer is programmed with software containing instructions for instructing the computer to manipulate the beam from the satellite in the forward and rearward directions, said instructions comprising instructing the computer to:<!-- EPO <DP n="32"> -->
<claim-text>determine the forward beam angle <b>ψ</b> by monitoring the satellite altitude and location coordinates for a satellite, wherein the forward beam angle <b>ψ</b> is the beam angle relative to a vector defined by the center of the earth and the satellite location that projects forward from the satellite in the direction of the satellite orbit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determine the rearward beam angle <b>λ</b> by monitoring the satellite altitude and location coordinates for a satellite, wherein the rearward beam angle <b>λ</b> is the beam angle relative to a vector defined by the center of the earth and the satellite location that projects rearward from the satellite in the direction opposite to that of the satellite orbit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>identify locations of GEO earth stations that are in the line of sight of the satellite orbit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>control the forward beam angle <b>ψ</b> and rearward beam angle <b>λ</b> to maximize coverage and to avoid transmitting down the bore sight of a GEO earth station antenna.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0052" num="0052">
<claim-text>The system of claim 24, wherein the LEO satellites of the satellite constellation are distributed in orbital planes above the earth surface; wherein an LEO satellite of the constellation of satellites is distributed in the orbit relative to an adjacent LEO satellite of the constellation of satellites so that the LEO satellite and the satellite adjacent to it are within a line of sight distance between them.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0053" num="0053">
<claim-text>The system of claim 24, wherein the satellites are spaced within their orbital plane at a line of sight distance, s, spacing adjacent satellites, wherein the line of sight distance "s" is the line-of-sight distance between two LEO satellites in orbit.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0054" num="0054">
<claim-text>The system of claim 52, wherein the maximum line-of-sight distance spacing between satellites of the constellation of satellites is determined by the minimum angle between the horizon and a satellite at which that satellite may communicate with an earth station located at a point on the earth.<!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0055" num="0055">
<claim-text>The system of claim 54, wherein the maximum spacing distance between adjacent satellites is determined by an angle <b>Θ</b> of a vector defined by the respective latitude positions of each respective adjacent satellite in a respective orbital plane, where the angle vertex is the center of the earth.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0056" num="0056">
<claim-text>The system of claim 55, wherein said angle <b>Θ</b> is determined by the expression Θ = 2 <i>ARCSIN</i>(S/2r<sub>L</sub>), wherein <b>S</b> is the spacing distance between adjacent satellites and is represented by the expression S = 2 <i>r<sub>L</sub> SIN</i>(θ/2), where <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> represents the radius of the satellite's orbit.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0057" num="0057">
<claim-text>The system of claim 52, wherein at least one first orbiting LEO satellite of the constellation of satellites is far enough above the local horizon to be within the line-of-sight of an LEO earth station that receives transmissions from the satellite constellation to be available for reliable communications; wherein during the period when the at least one first orbiting LEO satellite of the constellation of satellites is within a guard band around the vector between the GEO earth station and a GEO satellite, at least one second LEO satellite is within view and far enough above the local horizon, and takes over any communications function with the earth station from the first LEO satellite within the guard band vector.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0058" num="0058">
<claim-text>The system of claim 55, wherein the at least one second LEO satellite taking over the communications function takes over the communications functions from the at least one first satellite prior to the first satellite turning off its transmission function at the guard band vector.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0059" num="0059">
<claim-text>The system of claim 58, wherein said at least one first satellite ceases transmission when it is within the guard band vector by turning off one or more sub-beams of its transmission beam.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0060" num="0060">
<claim-text>The system of claim 57, wherein the rearward beam projection of the first satellite may communicate with the earth station after the forward beam has passed the bore sight vector.<!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0061" num="0061">
<claim-text>The system of claim 24, wherein a satellite controls the forward beam angle of the forward projected beam by changing the angle of the projection as the satellite moves through its orbit in a quadrant; wherein the rearward beam of the satellite of the constellation of satellites in the next quadrant of its orbit is projected to mirror the forward beam projected by the satellite in the previous quadrant.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0062" num="0062">
<claim-text>The system of claim 61, wherein said rearward projection mirroring provides a maximum region of coverage behind the satellite as the satellite travels through the quadrant.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0063" num="0063">
<claim-text>The system of claim 24, wherein the beam transmitted by an LEO satellite of the constellation of satellites is in a direction opposing the direction that a GEO satellite would be transmitting to the same earth station.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0064" num="0064">
<claim-text>The system of claim 24, wherein when a transmitting satellite must cease transmission to an earth station located at a point on the earth to avoid the boresight vector of an earth station GEO antenna, another satellite of the LEO satellite constellation takes over the transmission of the transmitting satellite.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0065" num="0065">
<claim-text>The system of claim 24, including a plurality of earth stations configured to receive transmissions from LEO satellites and send transmissions to LEO satellites, wherein at least some of the plurality of the earth stations have omnidirectional antennas.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0066" num="0066">
<claim-text>The system of claim 27, including a plurality of earth stations configured to receive transmissions from LEO satellites and send transmissions to LEO satellites, wherein at least some of the plurality of the earth stations have directional antennas.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0067" num="0067">
<claim-text>The system of claim 66, wherein said directional antennas are directional northerly or southerly with respect to the orbital plane of the constellation of satellites.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0068" num="0068">
<claim-text>The system of claim 67, wherein said northerly or southerly directed antennas are directable in elevation and azimuth.<!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0069" num="0069">
<claim-text>The system of claim 1, wherein the satellites of the satellite constellation are positioned in multiple orbital planes at regular angular longitudinal spacing.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0070" num="0070">
<claim-text>The system of claim 56, wherein the number of satellites provided in an orbital plane is determined by the distance between satellites in the orbit which are at an altitude <b>h</b> and at least and angle <b><i>α</i></b> above the horizon, and maintain a guard band angle of <b>β</b> around the vector between a GEO earth station and a GEO at an angle <b><i>γ</i></b>.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0071" num="0071">
<claim-text>The system of claim 1, wherein each satellite has a plurality of antennas.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0072" num="0072">
<claim-text>The system of claim 71, wherein each satellite plurality of antennas includes antennas for up/down links with earth stations and antennas for cross-links with other satellites.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0073" num="0073">
<claim-text>The system of claim 72, wherein said up/down links comprise helical antennas, and wherein said cross-link antennas comprise lenses.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0074" num="0074">
<claim-text>The system of claim 24, wherein the number of satellites is the minimum number of satellites and wherein the distance between satellites is the maximum distance between satellites.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0075" num="0075">
<claim-text>The system of claim 24, further including a plurality of earth stations having at least one directional antenna, wherein the directional antenna's highest gain is directed to point South or in a southern direction for an earth station located in the southern hemisphere, and wherein the directional antenna's highest gain is directed to point North or in a Northern direction for an earth station located in the northern hemisphere.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0076" num="0076">
<claim-text>The system of claim 75, wherein the directional earth station antenna is directed to point its maximum antenna gain away from the direction of a geo-stationary earth orbiting, GEO, satellite and toward the direction of an LEO satellite.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0077" num="0077">
<claim-text>A method for implementing communications through a low earth orbiting, LEO, satellite communication system with LEO satellites that provide re-use of geostationary<!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --> earth orbiting, GEO, communication satellite frequencies, the method comprising:
<claim-text>a) arranging a plurality of LEO satellites in a plurality of orbital planes about the earth; wherein each satellite includes equipment for transmitting radio frequency, RF, transmissions having frequencies for receipt by an earth station located on the earth, and wherein each satellite orbital plane defines a polar orbit about the four quadrantes of the earth;</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) providing a control mechanism that controls the satellite RF transmissions;</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) transmitting from an LEO satellite a transmission to an earth station;</claim-text>
<claim-text>d) controlling the satellite RF transmission to avoid transmitting down the bore sight of an antenna pointing towards a GEO satellite, including processing the satellite's location information with computing components of the satellite beam control mechanism, and controlling the satellite antenna with a control mechanism to avoid transmitting down the bore sight of a GEO-pointing antenna at any point on earth;</claim-text>
<claim-text>e) wherein controlling the satellite RF transmission includes controlling coverage of the beam with the satellite control mechanism to direct the satellite transmission coverage in each quadrant of the plane of orbit to mirror the satellite transmission coverage of the rearward directed beam projected in the prior quadrant of the satellite;</claim-text>
<claim-text>f) wherein controlling the satellite RF transmission further includes turning of the satellite's transmissions towards the earth at the transition between quadrants at the equator so as to avoid transmitting down the bore sight of an antenna pointing towards a GEO satellite; and<!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>g) wherein transmitting from an LEO satellite a transmission to an earth station is carried out using spectrum also employed by GEO communications satellites communicating in the same region.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0078" num="0078">
<claim-text>The method of claim 77, wherein controlling the satellite transmission includes controlling with a control mechanism the operation of one or more antennas of the satellite to produce a transmission beam in the forward direction projected at a forward beam angle and to produce a transmission beam in the rearward direction projected at a rearward beam angle.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0079" num="0079">
<claim-text>The method of claim 78, wherein controlling the beam angle comprises projecting a transmission beam in the forward direction at a forward beam angle of <b>ψ</b>, and wherein for a given latitude position in the satellite's orbit, the forward beam angle ψ at which the beam is projected is determined by the expression: <maths id="math0043" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">ψ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mspace width="1ex"/><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0043" file="imgb0043.tif" wi="53" he="12" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> where <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> represents the radius of the earth, where <b><i>α</i></b> represents the horizon elevation angle, and where <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> represents the radius of the satellite's orbit.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0080" num="0080">
<claim-text>The method of claim 78, wherein controlling the beam angle comprises projecting a transmission beam in the rearward direction at a rearward beam angle of angle <b>λ</b>, wherein for a given latitude position in the satellite's orbit the rearward beam angle <b>λ</b> at which the beam is projected is determined by the expression: <maths id="math0044" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">λ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mspace width="1ex"/><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>γ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>β</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0044" file="imgb0044.tif" wi="52" he="10" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> where <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> represents the radius of the earth, where <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> represents the radius of the satellite's orbit where <b><i>γ</i></b> represents an acute angle between the horizon and the vector at a location of a point on earth where a GEO earth station is pointing to a geostationary satellite, and where <b>β</b> represents a<!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --> GEO protection guard band angle around the vector between the GEO earth station and the GEO satellite to which it points, which is at angle <b><i>γ</i></b> to the horizon, and where <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> represents the radius of the satellite's orbit.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0081" num="0081">
<claim-text>The method of claim 78, wherein controlling the beam angle comprises projecting a transmission beam in the forward direction at a forward beam angle of <b>ψ</b>, and wherein for a given latitude position in the satellite's orbit, the forward beam angle <b>ψ</b> at which the beam is projected is determined by the expression: <maths id="math0045" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">ψ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mspace width="1ex"/><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0045" file="imgb0045.tif" wi="53" he="12" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> where <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> represents the radius of the earth, where <b><i>α</i></b> represents the horizon elevation angle, and where <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> represents the radius of the satellite's orbit; and<br/>
wherein controlling the beam angle comprises projecting a transmission beam in the rearward direction at a rearward beam angle of angle <b>λ</b>, wherein for a given latitude position in the satellite's orbit the rearward beam angle <b>λ</b> at which the beam is projected is determined by the expression: <maths id="math0046" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">λ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mspace width="1ex"/><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>γ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>β</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0046" file="imgb0046.tif" wi="52" he="10" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> where <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> represents the radius of the earth, where <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> represents the radius of the satellite's orbit where <b><i>γ</i></b> represents an acute angle between the horizon and the vector at a location of a point on earth where a GEO earth station is pointing to a geostationary satellite, and where <b>β</b> represents a GEO protection guard band angle around the vector between the GEO earth station and the GEO satellite to which it points, which is at angle <b><i>γ</i></b> to the horizon, and where <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> represents the radius of the satellite's orbit.<!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0082" num="0082">
<claim-text>A low earth orbiting, LEO, satellite configured to operate in an orbital plane defined by a polar orbit about the four quadrants of the earth comprising:
<claim-text>a) communications equipment, said communications equipment comprising equipment for transmitting RF transmissions having frequencies for receipt by an earth station located on the earth, and communications equipment for communicating with other satellites;</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) a control mechanism including a processing component and software with instructions for controlling RF transmissions from the LEO satellite to an earth station;</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) a transmitter for transmitting RF transmissions;</claim-text>
<claim-text>d) at least one antenna for projecting the RF transmissions from the LEO satellite, including a forward directed beam and a rearward directed beam;</claim-text>
<claim-text>e) wherein said control mechanism controls the satellite transmissions to avoid transmitting down the bore sight of an antenna pointing towards a GEO satellite; wherein the control mechanism processing component and software is configured to process the satellite's location information and determine the beam angle to be provided by the satellite's antenna,</claim-text>
<claim-text>f) wherein the control mechanism directs the satellite transmission coverage in each quadrant of the plane of orbit to mirror the satellite transmission coverage of the rearward directed beam projected in the prior quadrant of the satellite orbit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>g) wherein the control mechanism turns off the satellite's transmissions towards the earth at the transition between quadrants at the equator so as to avoid transmitting down the bore sight of an antenna pointing towards a geo-stationary earth orbiting, GEO, satellite; and<!-- EPO <DP n="40"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>h) wherein the RF transmissions from the LEO satellite to an earth station are carried out using spectrum also employed by GEO communications satellites communicating in the same region.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0083" num="0083">
<claim-text>The satellite of claim 82, wherein the control mechanism controls the operation of one or more antennas of the satellite to produce a transmission beam in the forward direction projected at a forward beam angle and to produce a transmission beam in the rearward direction projected at a rearward beam angle.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0084" num="0084">
<claim-text>The satellite of claim 83, wherein the control mechanism controls the beam angle to project a transmission beam in the forward direction at a forward beam angle of <b>ψ</b>, and wherein for a given latitude position in the satellite's orbit, the forward beam angle <b>ψ</b> is determined by the expression: <maths id="math0047" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">ψ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mspace width="1ex"/><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0047" file="imgb0047.tif" wi="53" he="12" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> where <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> represents the radius of the earth, where <b><i>α</i></b> represents the horizon elevation angle, and where <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> represents the radius of the satellite's orbit.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0085" num="0085">
<claim-text>The satellite of claim 83, wherein the control mechanism controls the beam angle to project a transmission beam in the rearward direction at a rearward beam angle of angle <b>λ</b>, wherein for a given latitude position in the satellite's orbit the rearward beam angle <b>λ</b> is determined by the expression: <maths id="math0048" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">λ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mspace width="1ex"/><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>γ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>β</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0048" file="imgb0048.tif" wi="52" he="10" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> where <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> represents the radius of the earth, where <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> represents the radius of the satellite's orbit where <b><i>γ</i></b> represents an acute angle between the horizon and the vector at a location of a point on earth where a GEO earth station is pointing to a geostationary satellite, and where <b>β</b> represents a<!-- EPO <DP n="41"> --> GEO protection guard band angle around the vector between the GEO earth station and the GEO satellite to which it points, which is at angle <b><i>γ</i></b> to the horizon, and where <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> represents the radius of the satellite's orbit.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0086" num="0086">
<claim-text>The satellite of claim 83, wherein the control mechanism controls the beam angle to project a transmission beam in the forward direction at a forward beam angle of <b>ψ</b>, and wherein for a given latitude position in the satellite's orbit, the forward beam angle <b>ψ</b> is determined by the expression: <maths id="math0049" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">ψ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mspace width="1ex"/><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0049" file="imgb0049.tif" wi="53" he="12" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> where <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> represents the radius of the earth, where <b><i>α</i></b> represents the horizon elevation angle, and where <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> represents the radius of the satellite's orbit; and<br/>
wherein the control mechanism controls the beam angle to project a transmission beam in the rearward direction at a rearward beam angle of angle <b>λ</b>, wherein for a given latitude position in the satellite's orbit the rearward beam angle <b>λ</b> is determined by the expression: <maths id="math0050" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">λ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mspace width="1ex"/><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mspace width="1ex"/><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>γ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>β</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0050" file="imgb0050.tif" wi="52" he="10" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> where <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> represents the radius of the earth, where <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> represents the radius of the satellite's orbit where <b><i>γ</i></b> represents an acute angle between the horizon and the vector at a location of a point on earth where a GEO earth station is pointing to a geostationary satellite, and where <b>β</b> represents a GEO protection guard band angle around the vector between the GEO earth station and the GEO satellite to which it points, which is at angle <b><i>γ</i></b> to the horizon, and where <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> represents the radius of the satellite's orbit.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims02" lang="de"><!-- EPO <DP n="42"> -->
<claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Satellitenkonstellationssystem mit niedriger Erdumlaufbahn, LEO, zur Kommunikation, das umfasst:
<claim-text>a) eine Mehrzahl von Satelliten in einer polaren Umlaufbahn um die Erde;</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) wobei die Satelliten in Umlaufbahnebenen um die Erde angeordnet sind, um Abdeckung für Punkte auf der Erde zur Kommunikation und zu jeder Zeit bereitzustellen, und</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) wobei die Anzahl von Satelliten in jeder Umlaufebene Kommunikation über den Bereich der Umlaufebene bereitstellt;</claim-text>
<claim-text>d) wobei jeder Satellit eine Antenne zum Empfangen und Senden von Signalen von/an Erdstationen aufweist, und wobei die Satellitenantenne mit einem Steuermechanismus zum Vermeiden von Senden entlang der Hauptstrahlrichtung einer Antenne mit GEO-Ausrichtung an einem beliebigen Punkt auf der Erde gesteuert wird;</claim-text>
<claim-text>e) wobei die Satellitenbahnebene eine polare Umlaufbahn um die vier Quadranten der Erde definiert, wobei der Satellit eine Ausrichtungssteuerung aufweist, und wobei die Ausrichtungssteuerung im ersten Quadranten mit einem Algorithmus programmiert ist, um Satellitenübertragungen zum Maximieren der Reichweite und Vermeiden von Senden entlang der Hauptstrahlrichtung einer Antenne mit GEO-Ausrichtung zu lenken;</claim-text>
<claim-text>f) wobei die Satellitenausrichtungssteuerung die Satellitenübertragungsabdeckung in jedem Quadranten der Umlaufbahnebene lenkt, um die<!-- EPO <DP n="43"> --> Satellitenübertragungsabdeckung des im vorherigen Quadranten der Satellitenbahn projizierten rückwärtsgerichteten Strahls zu spiegeln;</claim-text>
<claim-text>g) wobei der Übergang zwischen Quadranten am Äquator umfasst, dass der Satellit seinen Sender in Richtung Erde abschaltet, um Senden entlang der Hauptstrahlrichtung einer Antenne zu vermeiden, die auf einen Satelliten mit geostationärer Erdumlaufbahn, GEO, ausgerichtet ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>h) wobei die Übertragung zwischen Satelliten und einer Erdstation unter Verwendung eines Spektrums durchgeführt wird, das auch von GEO-Kommunikationssatelliten eingesetzt wird, die in derselben Region kommunizieren.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 1, wobei das Mittel zum Transport von Datagrammen zwischen jedem Satelliten und einem terrestrischen Bodennetzwerk mittels Sofort-Neusendung/-empfang des Datagramms zu/von einer Gateway-Station ist, die sich in Sichtweite desselben Satelliten befindet.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 1, wobei das Mittel zum Transport von Datagrammen zwischen jedem Satelliten der LEO-Satellitenkonstellation und einem terrestrischen Bodennetzwerk mittels Kreuzverbindung zu einem oder mehreren anderen Satelliten in der Konstellation und dann von den anderen Satelliten zu einem Gateway ist, wobei das Gateway zu keinem bestimmten Zeitpunkt in Sichtweite des ersten Satelliten ist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 3, wobei die Satelliten Schaltmittel zum Umschalten des Transports von Datagrammen zwischen Satelliten umfassen, wobei das Schaltmittel, das mit einem Satelliten assoziiert ist, zum Weiterreichen von Übertragung von Datagrammen an ein Schaltmittel konfiguriert ist, das mit einem anderen Satelliten assoziiert ist.<!-- EPO <DP n="44"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 1, wobei die assoziierte Erdstation, die zum Senden von Datagrammen zwischen der Erdstation und einem Satelliten assoziiert ist, eine Rundstrahlantenne einsetzt.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 1, wobei die assoziierte Erdstation, die zum Senden von Datagrammen zwischen der Erdstation und einem Satelliten assoziiert ist, eine Richtantenne einsetzt, die in Bezug auf die Umlaufbahnebene der Konstellation von Satelliten nördlich oder südlich gerichtet ist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 5, wobei die Antennen sowohl in Elevation als auch Azimut gerichtet sind.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Satelliten in Umlaufbahnebenen um die Erde angeordnet sind, um Abdeckung für jeden Punkt auf der Erde bereitzustellen.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Anzahl von Satelliten in jeder Umlaufbahnebene gemäß der maximalen Sende- und Empfangsreichweite für den Höhen- und Horizontelevationswinkel des Satelliten ausgewählt ist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Satellitenausrichtungssteuerung einen Steuermechanismus umfasst, und wobei der Steuermechanismus den Strahl von einer oder mehreren Antennen des Satelliten steuert, um Satellitenübertragungen zu lenken:
<claim-text>a) gemäß einer Strahlprojektion in der Rückwärtsrichtung, die in einem Rückwärtsstrahlwinkel von Winkel λ projiziert wird, der für einen spitzen Winkel γ zwischen dem Horizont und dem Vektor in einer Position eines Punkts auf der Erde, wo eine GEO-Erdstation auf einen geostationären Satelliten ausgerichtet ist, und für einen GEO-Schutzbandwinkel β um den Vektor zwischen der GEO-Erdstation und dem GEO-Satelliten, auf den sie ausgerichtet ist und der im<!-- EPO <DP n="45"> --> Winkel γ zum Horizont ist, durch den folgenden Ausdruck bestimmt wird: <maths id="math0051" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">λ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>γ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>β</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0051" file="imgb0051.tif" wi="44" he="9" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> wobei <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> den Radius der Erde darstellt, wobei <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> den Radius der Satellitenumlaufbahn darstellt, wobei γ einen spitzen Winkel zwischen dem Horizont und dem Vektor in einer Position eines Punkts auf der Erde darstellt, wo eine GEO-Erdstation auf einen geostationären Satelliten ausgerichtet ist, und wobei β einen GEO-Schutzbandwinkel um den Vektor zwischen der GEO-Erdstation und dem GEO-Satelliten darstellt, auf den sie ausgerichtet ist und der im Winkel γ zum Horizont ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) gemäß einer Strahlprojektion in der Vorwärtsrichtung, die in einem Vorwärtsstrahlwinkel von ψ projiziert wird, der für eine gegebene Breitengradposition in der Satellitenumlaufbahn durch den folgenden Ausdruck bestimmt wird: <maths id="math0052" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">ψ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0052" file="imgb0052.tif" wi="44" he="11" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> wobei <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> den Radius der Erde darstellt, wobei α einen Horizontelevationswinkel darstellt, und wobei <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> den Radius der Satellitenumlaufbahn darstellt.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 10, wobei die Projektionen vom Satelliten mit dem Steuermechanismus gesteuert werden, um die Reichweite zu maximieren, und wobei die Projektionen vom Satelliten gesteuert werden, um Senden entlang der Hauptstrahlrichtung einer Antenne mit GEO-Ausrichtung zu vermeiden.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 1, wobei der Satellit einen Steuermechanismus aufweist, der den Satellitensender steuert, und wobei die Satellitenantenne zum Abschalten<!-- EPO <DP n="46"> --> ihrer Kommunikationsverbindung zum Vermeiden von Senden entlang der Hauptstrahlrichtung einer Antenne mit GEO-Ausrichtung mit dem Steuermechanismus an jedem Punkt auf der Erde durch den Steuermechanismus gesteuert wird, wobei der Steuermechanismus zum Abschalten des Senders in Positionen konfiguriert ist, wo Übertragungen vom Sender mit der Hauptstrahlrichtung einer GEO-Erdstationsantenne, die auf einen GEO-Satelliten ausgerichtet ist, zusammenfallen würden.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 12, wobei jeder Satellit so konfiguriert ist, dass er seinen Sender, der zur Erde sendet, beim Übergang zwischen Quadranten am Äquator abschaltet, um Senden entlang der Hauptstrahlrichtung einer auf einen GEO-Satelliten ausgerichteten Antenne zu vermeiden.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 1, wobei die LEO-Satelliten Kommunikationsverbindungen bereitstellen, und wobei ein Satellit der Konstellation von LEO-Satelliten, der sich einer Hauptstrahlrichtung einer Antenne einer GEO-Satellitenerdstation oder einem GEO-Satellitenschutzband nähert, das innerhalb der Umlaufbahnebene des sich nähernden Satelliten ist, zum Weiterreichen von Kommunikation an einen anderen der LEO-Satelliten konfiguriert ist, der nicht innerhalb der Hauptstrahlrichtung einer Antenne eines GEO-Satelliten ist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0015" num="0015">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 1, wobei die LEO-Satellitenantenne zum Empfangen und Senden von Signalen von/an Erdstationen eine in Echtzeit anpassbare Strahlantenne umfasst.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0016" num="0016">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 1, wobei der Satellit einen Strahl sendet, der von der Antenne projiziert wird, wobei der Strahl eine Vorwärtsrichtung und eine Rückwärtsrichtung in Bezug auf die Satellitenbewegung innerhalb der Umlaufbahn aufweist.<!-- EPO <DP n="47"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0017" num="0017">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 1, wobei der Satellit einen Strahl sendet, der von der Antenne projiziert wird, und wobei der Strahl einen vorwärtsgerichteten Teil und einen rückwärtsgerichteten Teil aufweist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0018" num="0018">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 16, wobei die Satellitenantenne eine Richtantenne umfasst; wobei der Satellitenstrahl in der Vorwärtsrichtung in einem Vorwärtsstrahlwinkel von ψ projiziert wird, und wobei der Satellitenstrahl in der Rückwärtsrichtung in einem Rückwärtsstrahlwinkel von λ projiziert wird; wobei die Satelliten-Richtantenne mit dem Steuermechanismus zum Reduzieren des Vorwärtsstrahlwinkels von ψ gelenkt wird, wenn der LEO-Satellit sich zu einer Breitengradgrenze bewegt.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0019" num="0019">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 18, wobei die Satelliten-Richtantenne mit dem Steuermechanismus zum Verkleinern des Vorwärtsstrahlwinkels von ψ gelenkt wird, wenn der LEO-Satellit sich bewegt, wenn der Satellit sich zu einem Breitengradgrenzwinkel vom Äquator wegbewegt.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0020" num="0020">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 18, wobei die Satelliten-Richtantenne manipuliert wird, um den Winkel von λ des rückwärtsgerichteten Strahls zu vergrößern, wenn der Satellit sich vom Äquator wegbewegt.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0021" num="0021">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 18, wobei die Satelliten-Richtantenne mit dem Steuermechanismus zum Vergrößern des Winkels von λ des rückwärtsgerichteten Strahls gelenkt wird, wenn der Satellit sich von einem GEO-Erdstationsschutzband wegbewegt.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0022" num="0022">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 18, wobei die Satelliten-Richtantenne mit dem Steuermechanismus zum Vergrößern des Winkels von λ des rückwärtsgerichteten Strahls gelenkt wird, wenn der Satellit sich von der Hauptstrahlrichtung einer GEO-Erdstation wegbewegt.<!-- EPO <DP n="48"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0023" num="0023">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 17, wobei der Satellitenkommunikationsstrahlvorwärtsteil eines Satellitenstrahls einen Vorwärtsstrahlwinkel aufweist, der in Abhängigkeit vom Breitengrad des Satelliten angepasst wird.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0024" num="0024">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 1, wobei der Steuermechanismus eine oder mehrere Antennen eines Satelliten zum Erzeugen eines Strahls in der Vorwärtsrichtung, der in einem Vorwärtsstrahlwinkel projiziert wird, und zum Erzeugen eines Strahls in der Rückwärtsrichtung steuert, der in einem Rückwärtsstrahlwinkel projiziert wird.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0025" num="0025">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 24, wobei der Satellitenstrahl in der Rückwärtsrichtung in einem Rückwärtsstrahlwinkel projiziert wird, der kleiner wird, wenn der Satellit sich in seiner Umlaufbahnrichtung vorwärtsbewegt.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0026" num="0026">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 24, wobei der Satellitenstrahl in der Vorwärtsrichtung in einem Vorwärtsstrahlwinkel projiziert wird, der größer wird, wenn der Satellit sich in seiner Umlaufbahnrichtung vorwärtsbewegt.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0027" num="0027">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 25, wobei der Satellitenstrahl in der Vorwärtsrichtung in einem Vorwärtsstrahlwinkel projiziert wird, der größer wird, wenn der Satellit sich in seiner Umlaufbahnrichtung vorwärtsbewegt.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0028" num="0028">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 25, wobei der Satellitenstrahl in der Rückwärtsrichtung in einem Rückwärtsstrahlwinkel von λ projiziert wird, der für einen spitzen Winkel γ zwischen dem Horizont und dem Vektor in einer Position eines Punkts auf der Erde, wo eine GEO-Erdstation auf einen geostationären Satelliten ausgerichtet ist, und für einen GEO-Schutzbandwinkel β um den Vektor zwischen der GEO-Erdstation und dem GEO-Satelliten, auf den sie ausgerichtet ist und der im Winkel γ zum Horizont ist, durch den folgenden Ausdruck bestimmt wird:<!-- EPO <DP n="49"> --> <maths id="math0053" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">λ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>γ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>β</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0053" file="imgb0053.tif" wi="44" he="9" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> wobei <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> den Radius der Erde darstellt, wobei <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> den Radius der Satellitenumlaufbahn darstellt, wobei γ einen spitzen Winkel zwischen dem Horizont und dem Vektor in einer Position eines Punkts auf der Erde darstellt, wo eine GEO-Erdstation auf einen geostationären Satelliten ausgerichtet ist, und wobei β einen GEO-Schutzbandwinkel um den Vektor zwischen der GEO-Erdstation und dem GEO-Satelliten darstellt, auf den sie ausgerichtet ist und der im Winkel γ zum Horizont ist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0029" num="0029">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 26, wobei der Satellitenstrahl in der Vorwärtsrichtung in einem Vorwärtsstrahlwinkel von ψ projiziert wird, und wobei für eine gegebene Breitengradposition in der Satellitenumlaufbahn der Vorwärtsstrahlwinkel ψ, in welchem projiziert wird, durch den folgenden Ausdruck bestimmt wird: <maths id="math0054" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">ψ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0054" file="imgb0054.tif" wi="44" he="11" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> wobei <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> den Radius der Erde darstellt, wobei α einen Horizontelevationswinkel darstellt, und wobei <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> den Radius der Satellitenumlaufbahn darstellt.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0030" num="0030">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 29, wobei der Horizontelevationswinkel aus dem kleinsten Winkel zwischen (1) dem Horizont und (2) dem Satelliten besteht, in welchem der Satellit und eine Erdstation, mit welcher der Satellit kommunizieren kann, wie von der Erdstationsposition betrachtet.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0031" num="0031">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 27, wobei der Satellitenstrahl in der Rückwärtsrichtung in einem Rückwärtsstrahlwinkel von Winkel λ projiziert wird, wobei für eine gegebene Breitengradposition in der Satellitenumlaufbahn der<!-- EPO <DP n="50"> --> Rückwärtsstrahlwinkel λ, in welchem projiziert wird, durch den folgenden Ausdruck bestimmt wird: <maths id="math0055" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">λ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>γ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>β</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0055" file="imgb0055.tif" wi="44" he="9" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths>
<claim-text>wobei <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> den Radius der Erde darstellt, wobei <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> den Radius der Satellitenumlaufbahn darstellt, wobei γ einen spitzen Winkel zwischen dem Horizont und dem Vektor in einer Position eines Punkts auf der Erde darstellt, wo eine GEO-Erdstation auf einen geostationären Satelliten ausgerichtet ist, und wobei β einen GEO-Schutzbandwinkel um den Vektor zwischen der GEO-Erdstation und dem GEO-Satelliten darstellt, auf den sie ausgerichtet ist und der im Winkel γ zum Horizont ist, und wobei <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> den Radius der Satellitenumlaufbahn darstellt, wobei der Satellitenstrahl in der Vorwärtsrichtung in einem Vorwärtsstrahlwinkel von ψ projiziert wird, und wobei für eine gegebene Breitengradposition in der Satellitenumlaufbahn der Vorwärtsstrahlwinkel ψ, in welchem projiziert wird, durch den folgenden Ausdruck bestimmt wird: <maths id="math0056" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">ψ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0056" file="imgb0056.tif" wi="44" he="11" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> den Radius der Erde darstellt, wobei α den Horizontelevationswinkel darstellt, und wobei <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> den Radius der Satellitenumlaufbahn darstellt.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0032" num="0032">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 24, wobei der Strahl, der in der Vorwärtsrichtung erzeugt wird, eine Mehrzahl von Teilstrahlen umfasst.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0033" num="0033">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 24, wobei der Strahl, der in der Rückwärtsrichtung erzeugt wird, eine Mehrzahl von Teilstrahlen umfasst.<!-- EPO <DP n="51"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0034" num="0034">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 24, wobei mindestens einer des Strahls, der in der Vorwärtsrichtung erzeugt wird, und des Strahls, der in der Rückwärtsrichtung erzeugt wird, eine Mehrzahl von Teilstrahlen umfasst, und wobei die Teilstrahlen gesteuert werden können, um die Projektion des Kommunikationsstrahls von der Satellitenantenne zu steuern.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0035" num="0035">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 24, wobei der Strahl, der in der Vorwärtsrichtung erzeugt wird, eine Mehrzahl von Teilstrahlen umfasst, wobei der Strahl, der in der Rückwärtsrichtung erzeugt wird, eine Mehrzahl von Teilstrahlen umfasst, und wobei die Teilstrahlen gesteuert werden können, um die Projektion des Kommunikationsstrahls von der Satellitenantenne zu steuern.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0036" num="0036">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 34, wobei ein Teilstrahl durch Positionieren der Antenne, die den Teilstrahl bereitstellt, gesteuert werden kann.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0037" num="0037">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 34, wobei mindestens einer des Vorwärtsstahls und des Rückwärtsstrahls durch Aktivieren oder Deaktivieren eines Teilstrahls, der den jeweiligen Vorwärtsstrahl oder Rückwärtsstrahl umfasst, gesteuert werden kann.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0038" num="0038">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 34, wobei der Vorwärtsstahl durch Aktivieren oder Deaktivieren eines Teilstrahls, der den Vorwärtsstrahl umfasst, gesteuert werden kann, und der Rückwärtsstrahl durch Aktivieren oder Deaktivieren eines Teilstrahls, der den Rückwärtsstrahl umfasst, gesteuert werden kann.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0039" num="0039">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 24, wobei die Satellitenantenne eine in Echtzeit anpassbare Strahlantenne umfasst.<!-- EPO <DP n="52"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0040" num="0040">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 39, wobei die in Echtzeit anpassbare Strahlantenne eine phasengesteuerte Gruppenantenne umfasst.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0041" num="0041">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 39, wobei die Antenne eine Strahleinhüllende bereitstellt, die Teilstrahlen umfasst, die für spezifische Frequenzwiederverwendung, Polarisationswiederverwendung oder Akkommodation anderer Umlaufbahnelemente oder Erdstationselemente konfiguriert sind.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0042" num="0042">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 40, wobei die Antenne eine Strahleinhüllende bereitstellt, die Teilstrahlen umfasst, die für spezifische Frequenzwiederverwendung, Polarisationswiederverwendung oder Akkommodation anderer Umlaufbahnelemente oder Erdstationselemente konfiguriert sind.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0043" num="0043">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 24, wobei die Satellitenkonstellation so vorgesehen ist, dass mindestens ein Satellit der Satellitenkonstellation jederzeit in Sichtweite einer Erdstation auf der Erde ist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0044" num="0044">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 24, wobei der Satellitenstrahl in der Vorwärtsrichtung in einem Vorwärtsstrahlwinkel ψ projiziert wird; wobei der Satellitenstrahl in der Rückwärtsrichtung in einem Rückwärtsstrahlwinkel von λ projiziert wird; wobei mindestens eine Satellitenantenne eine Richtantenne umfasst, die den Vorwärtsstrahl projiziert, und wobei die mindestens eine Richtantenne, die den Vorwärtsstrahl projiziert, mit dem Steuermechanismus zum Reduzieren des Vorwärtsstrahlwinkels ψ gelenkt wird, wenn der LEO-Satellit sich zu einer Breitengradgrenze bewegt, wobei mindestens eine Satellitenantenne eine Richtantenne umfasst, die einen Rückstrahl projiziert, wobei die mindestens eine Satelliten-Richtantenne, die den Rückwärtsstrahl projiziert, mit dem Steuermechanismus zum Vergrößern des Rückwärtsstrahlwinkels λ gelenkt wird,<!-- EPO <DP n="53"> --> wenn der LEO-Satellit sich zu einer Breitengradgrenze bewegt.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0045" num="0045">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 44, wobei jede Richtantenne einen assoziierten Sender aufweist, der ein Signal für die Antenne bereitstellt, und wobei jeder Satellit so konfiguriert ist, dass er einen assoziierten Sender in Positionen abschaltet, in welchen Übertragung von seinem Sender mit der Hauptstrahlrichtung einer Antenne zusammenfallen würde, die auf einen GEO-Satelliten ausgerichtet ist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0046" num="0046">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 24, wobei die mindestens eine Antenne zum Empfangen und Senden von/an Erdstationen eine Richtantenne umfasst, und wobei es mindestens einen Sender gibt, der mit der Richtantenne assoziiert ist und der ein Signal für die Antenne bereitstellt, und wobei jeder Satellit so konfiguriert ist, dass er den assoziierten Sender in Positionen abschaltet, in welchen Übertragung von seinem Sender mit der Hauptstrahlrichtung einer Antenne zusammenfallen würde, die auf einen GEO-Satelliten ausgerichtet ist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0047" num="0047">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 46, wobei der Äquator einen Übergang zwischen Quadranten der Umlaufbahnebene definiert.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0048" num="0048">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 47, wobei jeder Satellit so konfiguriert ist, dass er seinen Sender, der zur Erde sendet, beim Übergang zwischen Quadranten am Äquator abschaltet, um Senden entlang der Hauptstrahlrichtung einer auf einen GEO-Satelliten ausgerichteten Antenne zu vermeiden.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0049" num="0049">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 48, wobei jeder zweite, dritte und vierte Quadrant der Umlaufbahnebene ein Spiegel bei Betrieb des ersten Quadranten ist, wobei ein Satellit der Konstellation von Satelliten in einer Umlaufbahn die<!-- EPO <DP n="54"> --> Winkelstrahlprojektionen für jeden nachfolgenden Quadranten spiegelt.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0050" num="0050">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 44, wobei der Vorwärtsstrahlwinkel ψ und der Rückwärtsstrahlwinkel λ an der Breitengradgrenze in Abhängigkeit von der Breitengradgrenze σ für einen gegebenen Schutzbandwinkel β um den Vektor zwischen einer GEO-Erdstation und einem GEO-Satelliten in einem Winkel γ bestimmt werden, und wobei der Satellit in einer Umlaufbahn in einer Höhe h ist, die mindestens einen Winkel α über dem lokalen Horizont ist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0051" num="0051">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 27, wobei jeder Satellit einen Computer mit einem Hardwareprozessor umfasst, und wobei der Computer mit Software programmiert ist, die Anweisungen zum Anweisen des Computers zum Manipulieren des Strahls vom Satelliten in der Vorwärts- und der Rückwärtsrichtung enthält, wobei die Anweisungen umfassen, dass sie den Computer anweisen zum:
<claim-text>Bestimmen des Vorwärtsstrahlwinkels ψ durch Überwachen der Satellitenhöhe und von Positionskoordinaten für einen Satelliten, wobei der Vorwärtsstrahlwinkel ψ der Strahlwinkel in Bezug auf einen Vektor ist, der durch den Mittelpunkt der Erde und der Satellitenposition definiert wird und der vom Satelliten in die Richtung der Satellitenumlaufbahn vorwärts projiziert wird;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Bestimmen des Rückwärtsstrahlwinkels λ durch Überwachen der Satellitenhöhe und von Positionskoordinaten für einen Satelliten, wobei der Rückwärtsstrahlwinkel λ der Strahlwinkel in Bezug auf einen Vektor ist, der durch den Mittelpunkt der Erde und der Satellitenposition definiert wird und der vom Satelliten in die Richtung entgegengesetzt zu jener der Satellitenumlaufbahn rückwärts projiziert wird;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Identifizieren von Positionen von GEO-Erdstationen, die in Sichtlinie der Satellitenumlaufbahn sind; und<!-- EPO <DP n="55"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>Steuern des Vorwärtsstrahlwinkels ψ und des Rückwärtsstrahlwinkels λ zum Maximieren der Reichweite und Vermeiden von Senden entlang der Hauptstrahlrichtung einer GEO-Erdstationsantenne.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0052" num="0052">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 24, wobei die LEO-Satelliten der Satellitenkonstellation in Umlaufbahnebenen über der Erdoberfläche verteilt sind; wobei ein LEO-Satellit der Konstellation von Satelliten in der Umlaufbahn in Bezug auf einen benachbarten LEO-Satelliten der Konstellation von Satelliten so verteilt ist, dass der LEO-Satellit und der zu ihm benachbarte Satellit innerhalb einer Sichtlinienentfernung zwischen ihnen sind.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0053" num="0053">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 24, wobei die Satelliten innerhalb ihrer Umlaufbahnebene in einer Sichtlinienentfernung s beabstandet sind, die benachbarte Satelliten beabstandet, wobei die Sichtlinienentfernung <i>"s"</i> die Sichtlinienentfernung zwischen zwei LEO-Satelliten in der Umlaufbahn ist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0054" num="0054">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 52, wobei der maximale Sichtlinienentfernungsabstand zwischen Satelliten der Konstellation von Satelliten durch den kleinsten Winkel zwischen dem Horizont und einem Satelliten bestimmt wird, in welchem dieser Satellit mit einer Erdstation kommunizieren kann, die sich an einem Punkt auf der Erde befindet.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0055" num="0055">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 54, wobei die maximale Abstandsentfernung zwischen benachbarten Satelliten durch einen Winkel Θ eines Vektors bestimmt wird, der durch die jeweiligen Breitengradpositionen jedes jeweiligen benachbarten Satelliten in einer jeweiligen Umlaufbahnebene definiert wird, wobei der Scheitelpunkt des Winkels der Mittelpunkt der Erde ist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0056" num="0056">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 55, wobei der Winkel Θ durch den Ausdruck Θ = 2 ARCSIN(S/2r<sub>L</sub>) bestimmt wird, wobei S<!-- EPO <DP n="56"> --> die Abstandsentfernung zwischen benachbarten Satelliten ist und durch den Ausdruck s = 2 r<sub>L</sub> SIN(9/2) dargestellt wird, wobei <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> den Radius der Satellitenumlaufbahn darstellt.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0057" num="0057">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 52, wobei mindestens ein erster umlaufender LEO-Satellit der Konstellation von Satelliten weit genug über dem lokalen Horizont ist, um innerhalb der Sichtlinie einer LEO-Erdstation zu sein, die Übertragungen von der Satellitenkonstellation empfängt, die für zuverlässige Kommunikation verfügbar ist; wobei während des Zeitraums, in welchem der mindestens eine erste umlaufende LEO-Satellit der Konstellation von Satelliten innerhalb eines Schutzbandes um den Vektor zwischen der GEO-Erdstation und einem GEO-Satelliten ist, mindestens ein zweiter LEO-Satellit in Sichtweite und weit genug über dem lokalen Horizont ist und jegliche Kommunikationsfunktion mit der Erdstation vom ersten LEO-Satelliten innerhalb des Schutzbandvektors übernimmt.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0058" num="0058">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 55, wobei der mindestens eine zweite LEO-Satellit, der die Kommunikationsfunktion übernimmt, Kommunikationsfunktionen von dem mindestens einen ersten Satelliten übernimmt, bevor der erste Satellit seine Übertragungsfunktion am Schutzbandvektor abschaltet.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0059" num="0059">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 58, wobei der mindestens eine erste Satellit durch Abschalten eines oder mehrerer Teilstrahlen seines Übertragungsstrahls Übertragung beendet, wenn er innerhalb des Schutzbandvektors ist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0060" num="0060">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 57, wobei die Rückwärtsstahlprojektion des ersten Satelliten mit der Erdstation kommunizieren kann, nachdem der Vorwärtsstrahl den Hauptstrahlrichtungsvektor passiert hat.<!-- EPO <DP n="57"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0061" num="0061">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 24, wobei ein Satellit den Vorwärtsstrahlwinkel des vorwärts projizierten Strahls durch Ändern des Winkels der Projektion steuert, wenn der Satellit sich durch seine Umlaufbahn in einem Quadranten bewegt; wobei der Rückwärtsstrahl des Satelliten der Konstellation von Satelliten im nächsten Quadranten seiner Umlaufbahn projiziert wird, um den vom Satelliten im vorherigen Quadranten projizierten Vorwärtsstrahl zu spiegeln.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0062" num="0062">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 61, wobei die Rückwärtsprojektionsspiegelung eine maximale Abdeckungsregion hinter dem Satelliten bereitstellt, wenn der Satellit sich durch den Quadranten bewegt.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0063" num="0063">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 24, wobei der Strahl, der von einem LEO-Satelliten der Konstellation von Satelliten gesendet wird, in einer Richtung ist, die entgegengesetzt zu der ist, in der ein GEO-Satellit an dieselbe Erdstation senden würde.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0064" num="0064">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 24, wobei, wenn ein sendender Satellit Übertragung an eine Erdstation, die sich an einem Punkt auf der Erde befindet, beenden muss, um die Hauptstrahlrichtungsvektor einer GEO-Antenne einer Erdstation zu vermeiden, ein anderer Satellit der LEO-Satellitenkonstellation die Übertragung des sendenden Satelliten übernimmt.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0065" num="0065">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 24, umfassend eine Mehrzahl von Erdstationen, die zum Empfangen von Übertragungen von LEO-Satelliten und Senden von Übertragungen an LEO-Satelliten konfiguriert ist, wobei wenigstens einige der Mehrzahl von Erdstationen Rundstrahlantennen aufweisen.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0066" num="0066">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 27, umfassend eine Mehrzahl von Erdstationen, die zum Empfangen von Übertragungen von LEO-Satelliten und Senden von Übertragungen an LEO-Satelliten<!-- EPO <DP n="58"> --> konfiguriert ist, wobei wenigstens einige der Mehrzahl von Erdstationen Richtantennen aufweisen.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0067" num="0067">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 66, wobei die Richtantennen in Bezug auf die Umlaufbahnebene der Konstellation von Satelliten nördlich oder südlich gerichtet sind.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0068" num="0068">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 67, wobei die nördlich oder südlich gerichteten Antennen in Elevation und Azimut gesteuert werden können.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0069" num="0069">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Satelliten der Satellitenkonstellation in mehreren Umlaufbahnebenen in einem regelmäßigen Längswinkelabstand positioniert sind.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0070" num="0070">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 56, wobei die Anzahl von Satelliten, die in einer Umlaufbahn vorgesehen ist, durch die Entfernung zwischen Satelliten in der Umlaufbahn bestimmt wird, die in einer Höhe h und mindestens einem Winkel α über dem Horizont sind und einen Schutzbandwinkel von β um den Vektor zwischen einer GEO-Erdstation und einem GEO in einem Winkel γ aufrechterhalten.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0071" num="0071">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 1, wobei jeder Satellit eine Mehrzahl von Antennen aufweist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0072" num="0072">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 71, wobei die Mehrzahl von Antennen jedes Satelliten Antennen für Up-/Downlink-Verbindungen mit Erdstationen und Antennen für Kreuzverbindungen mit anderen Satelliten umfasst.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0073" num="0073">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 72, wobei die Up-/Downlink-Verbindungen Wendelantennen umfassen, und/oder wobei die Kreuzverbindungsantennen Linsen umfassen.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0074" num="0074">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 24, wobei die Anzahl von Satelliten die Mindestanzahl von Satelliten ist, und<!-- EPO <DP n="59"> --> wobei die Entfernung zwischen Satelliten die größte Entfernung zwischen Satelliten ist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0075" num="0075">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 24, ferner umfassend eine Mehrzahl von Erdstationen mit mindestens einer Richtantenne, wobei der höchste Gewinn der Richtantenne so gerichtet ist, dass er für eine auf der Südhalbkugel angeordnete Erdstation nach Süden oder in eine südlichen Richtung ausgerichtet ist, und wobei der höchste Gewinn der Richtantenne so gerichtet ist, dass er für eine auf der Nordhalbkugel angeordnete Erdstation nach Norden oder in eine nördliche Richtung ausgerichtet ist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0076" num="0076">
<claim-text>System nach Anspruch 75, wobei die Richtantenne der Erdstation so gerichtet ist, dass sie ihren maximalen Antennengewinn von der Richtung eines Satelliten mit geostationärer Erdumlaufbahn, GEO, weg und in die Richtung eines LEO-Satelliten ausrichtet.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0077" num="0077">
<claim-text>Verfahren zur Implementierung von Kommunikation durch ein Satellitenkommunikationssystem mit niedriger Erdumlaufbahn, LEO, mit LEO-Satelliten, die Wiederverwendung von Frequenzen von Kommunikationssatelliten mit geostationärer Erdumlaufbahn, GEO, bereitstellen, wobei das Verfahren umfasst:
<claim-text>a) Anordnen einer Mehrzahl von LEO-Satelliten in einer Mehrzahl von Erdumlaufbahnen um die Erde; wobei jeder Satellit Einrichtungen zum Senden von Hochfrequenz-,HF-,Übertragungen mit Frequenzen zum Empfang durch eine Erdstation umfasst, die sich auf der Erde befindet, und wobei jede Satellitenumlaufbahnebene eine polare Umlaufbahn um die vier Quadranten der Erde definiert;</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) Bereitstellen eines Steuermechanismus, der die HF-Übertragungen des Satelliten steuert;</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) Senden einer Übertragung von einem LEO-Satelliten an eine Erdstation;<!-- EPO <DP n="60"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>d) Steuern der HF-Satellitenübertragung zum Vermeiden von Senden entlang der Hauptstrahlrichtung einer Antenne, die auf einen GEO-Satelliten ausgerichtet ist, umfassend ein Verarbeiten der Positionsinformationen des Satelliten mit Computerkomponenten des Satellitenstrahlsteuermechanismus, und Steuern der Satellitenantenne mit einem Steuermechanismus zum Vermeiden von Senden entlang der Hauptstrahlrichtung einer Antenne mit GEO-Ausrichtung an einem beliebigen Punkt auf der Erde;</claim-text>
<claim-text>e) wobei das Steuern der HF-Übertragung des Satelliten ein Steuern der Reichweite des Strahls mit dem Satellitensteuermechanismus umfasst, um die Satellitenübertragungsabdeckung in jedem Quadranten der Umlaufbahnebene zu lenken, um die Satellitenübertragungsabdeckung des im vorherigen Quadranten des Satelliten projizierten rückwärtsgerichteten Strahls zu spiegeln;</claim-text>
<claim-text>f) wobei das Steuern der HF-Übertragung des Satelliten ein Drehen der Satellitenübertragungen zur Erde beim Übergang zwischen Quadranten am Äquator umfasst, um Senden entlang der Hauptstrahlrichtung einer auf einen GEO-Satelliten ausgerichteten Antenne zu vermeiden; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>g) wobei das Senden von einem LEO-Satelliten eine Übertragung an eine Erdstation unter Verwendung eines Spektrums durchgeführt wird, das auch von GEO-Kommunikationssatelliten eingesetzt wird, die in der gleichen Region kommunizieren.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0078" num="0078">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 77, wobei das Steuern der Satellitenübertragung ein Steuern des Betriebs einer oder mehrerer Antennen des Satelliten mit einem Steuermechanismus zum Erzeugen eines Übertragungsstrahls in der Vorwärtsrichtung, der in einem Vorwärtsstrahlwinkel projiziert wird, und zum Erzeugen eines Übertragungsstrahls in der Rückwärtsrichtung umfasst, der in einem Rückwärtsstrahlwinkel projiziert wird.<!-- EPO <DP n="61"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0079" num="0079">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 78, wobei das Steuern des Strahlwinkels ein Projizieren eines Übertragungsstrahls in der Vorwärtsrichtung in einem Vorwärtsstrahlwinkel von ψ umfasst, und wobei für eine gegebene Breitengradposition in der Satellitenumlaufbahn der Vorwärtsstrahlwinkel ψ, in welchem der Strahl projiziert wird, durch den folgenden Ausdruck bestimmt wird: <maths id="math0057" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">ψ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0057" file="imgb0057.tif" wi="44" he="11" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> wobei <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> den Radius der Erde darstellt, wobei α den Horizontelevationswinkel darstellt, und wobei <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> den Radius der Satellitenumlaufbahn darstellt.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0080" num="0080">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 78, wobei das Steuern des Strahlwinkels ein Projizieren eines Übertragungsstrahls in der Rückwärtsrichtung in einem Rückwärtsstrahlwinkel von Winkel λ umfasst, und wobei für eine gegebene Breitengradposition in der Satellitenumlaufbahn der Rückwärtsstrahlwinkel λ, in welchem der Strahl projiziert wird, durch den folgenden Ausdruck bestimmt wird: <maths id="math0058" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">λ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>γ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>β</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0058" file="imgb0058.tif" wi="44" he="9" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> wobei <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> den Radius der Erde darstellt, wobei <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> den Radius der Satellitenumlaufbahn darstellt, wobei γ einen spitzen Winkel zwischen dem Horizont und dem Vektor in einer Position eines Punkts auf der Erde darstellt, wo eine GEO-Erdstation auf einen geostationären Satelliten ausgerichtet ist, und wobei β einen GEO-Schutzbandwinkel um den Vektor zwischen der GEO-Erdstation und dem GEO-Satelliten darstellt, auf den sie ausgerichtet ist und der im Winkel γ zum Horizont ist, und wobei <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> den Radius der Satellitenumlaufbahn darstellt.<!-- EPO <DP n="62"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0081" num="0081">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 78, wobei das Steuern des Strahlwinkels ein Projizieren eines Übertragungsstrahls in der Vorwärtsrichtung in einem Vorwärtsstrahlwinkel von ψ umfasst, und wobei für eine gegebene Breitengradposition in der Satellitenumlaufbahn der Vorwärtsstrahlwinkel ψ, in welchem der Strahl projiziert wird, durch den folgenden Ausdruck bestimmt wird: <maths id="math0059" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">ψ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0059" file="imgb0059.tif" wi="44" he="11" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths>
<claim-text>wobei <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> den Radius der Erde darstellt, wobei α den Horizontelevationswinkel darstellt, und wobei <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> den Radius der Satellitenumlaufbahn; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei das Steuern des Strahlwinkels ein Projizieren eines Übertragungsstrahls in der Rückwärtsrichtung in einem Rückwärtsstrahlwinkel von Winkel λ umfasst, und wobei für eine gegebene Breitengradposition in der Satellitenumlaufbahn der Rückwärtsstrahlwinkel λ, in welchem der Strahl projiziert wird, durch den folgenden Ausdruck bestimmt wird: <maths id="math0060" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">λ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>γ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>β</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0060" file="imgb0060.tif" wi="44" he="9" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> den Radius der Erde darstellt, wobei <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> den Radius der Satellitenumlaufbahn darstellt, wobei γ einen spitzen Winkel zwischen dem Horizont und dem Vektor in einer Position eines Punkts auf der Erde darstellt, wo eine GEO-Erdstation auf einen geostationären Satelliten ausgerichtet ist, und wobei β einen GEO-Schutzbandwinkel um den Vektor zwischen der GEO-Erdstation und dem GEO-Satelliten darstellt, auf den sie ausgerichtet ist und der im Winkel γ zum Horizont ist, und wobei <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> den Radius der Satellitenumlaufbahn darstellt.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0082" num="0082">
<claim-text>Satellit mit niedriger Erdumlaufbahn, LEO, der so konfiguriert ist, dass er in einer Umlaufbahnebene<!-- EPO <DP n="63"> --> funktioniert, die durch eine polare Umlaufbahn um die vier Quadranten der Erde definiert wird, umfassend:
<claim-text>a) Kommunikationseinrichtungen, wobei die Kommunikationseinrichtungen Einrichtungen zum Senden von HF-Übertragungen mit Frequenzen zum Empfang durch eine Erdstation, die sich auf der Erde befindet, und Kommunikationseinrichtungen zum Kommunizieren mit anderen Satelliten umfassen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) einen Steuermechanismus, der eine Verarbeitungskomponente und Software mit Anweisungen zum Steuern von HF-Übertragungen vom LEO-Satelliten an eine Erdstation umfasst;</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) einen Sender zum Senden von HF-Übertragungen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>d) mindestens eine Antenne zum Projizieren der HF-Übertragungen vom LEO-Satelliten, umfassend einen vorwärtsgerichteten Strahl und einen rückwärtsgerichteten Strahl;</claim-text>
<claim-text>e) wobei der Steuermechanismus die Satellitenübertragungen zum Vermeiden von Senden entlang der Hauptstrahlrichtung einer auf einen GEO-Satelliten ausgerichteten Antenne steuert; wobei die Verarbeitungskomponente und die Software des Steuermechanismus zum Verarbeiten der Positionsinformationen des Satelliten und Bestimmen des Strahlwinkels konfiguriert sind, der durch die Satellitenantenne bereitgestellt werden soll,</claim-text>
<claim-text>f) wobei der Steuermechanismus die Satellitenübertragungsabdeckung in jedem Quadranten der Umlaufbahnebene lenkt, um die Satellitenübertragungsabdeckung des im vorherigen Quadranten der Satellitenumlaufbahn projizierten rückwärtsgerichteten Strahls zu spiegeln;</claim-text>
<claim-text>g) wobei der Steuermechanismus die Satellitenübertragungen zur Erde beim Übergang zwischen Quadranten am Äquator abschaltet, um Senden entlang der Hauptstrahlrichtung einer Antenne zu vermeiden, die auf einen Satelliten mit geostationärer Erdumlaufbahn, GEO, ausgerichtet ist; und<!-- EPO <DP n="64"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>h) wobei die HF-Übertragungen vom LEO-Satelliten an eine Erdstation unter Verwendung eines Spektrums durchgeführt werden, das auch von GEO-Kommunikationssatelliten eingesetzt wird, die in derselben Region kommunizieren.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0083" num="0083">
<claim-text>Satellit nach Anspruch 82, wobei der Steuermechanismus den Betrieb einer oder mehrerer Antennen des Satelliten zum Erzeugen eines Übertragungsstrahls in der Vorwärtsrichtung, der in einem Vorwärtsstrahlwinkel projiziert wird, und zum Erzeugen eines Übertragungsstrahls in der Rückwärtsrichtung steuert, der in einem Rückwärtsstrahlwinkel projiziert wird.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0084" num="0084">
<claim-text>Satellit nach Anspruch 83, wobei der Steuermechanismus den Strahlwinkel zum Projizieren eines Übertragungsstrahls in der Vorwärtsrichtung in einem Vorwärtsstrahlwinkel von ψ steuert, und wobei für eine gegebene Breitengradposition in der Satellitenumlaufbahn der Vorwärtsstrahlwinkel ψ durch den folgenden Ausdruck bestimmt wird: <maths id="math0061" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">ψ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0061" file="imgb0061.tif" wi="44" he="11" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> wobei <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> den Radius der Erde darstellt, wobei α den Horizontelevationswinkel darstellt, und wobei <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> den Radius der Satellitenumlaufbahn darstellt.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0085" num="0085">
<claim-text>Satellit nach Anspruch 83, wobei der Steuermechanismus den Strahlwinkel zum Projizieren eines Übertragungsstrahls in der Rückwärtsrichtung in einem Rückwärtsstrahlwinkel von Winkel λ steuert, und wobei für eine gegebene Breitengradposition in der Satellitenumlaufbahn der Rückwärtsstrahlwinkel λ durch den folgenden Ausdruck bestimmt wird:<!-- EPO <DP n="65"> --> <maths id="math0062" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">λ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>γ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>β</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0062" file="imgb0062.tif" wi="44" he="9" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> wobei <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> den Radius der Erde darstellt, wobei <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> den Radius der Satellitenumlaufbahn darstellt, wobei γ einen spitzen Winkel zwischen dem Horizont und dem Vektor in einer Position eines Punkts auf der Erde darstellt, wo eine GEO-Erdstation auf einen geostationären Satelliten ausgerichtet ist, und wobei β einen GEO-Schutzbandwinkel um den Vektor zwischen der GEO-Erdstation und dem GEO-Satelliten darstellt, auf den sie ausgerichtet ist und der im Winkel γ zum Horizont ist, und wobei <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> den Radius der Satellitenumlaufbahn darstellt.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0086" num="0086">
<claim-text>Satellit nach Anspruch 83, wobei der Steuermechanismus den Strahlwinkel zum Projizieren eines Übertragungsstrahls in der Vorwärtsrichtung in einem Vorwärtsstrahlwinkel von ψ steuert, und wobei für eine gegebene Breitengradposition in der Satellitenumlaufbahn der Vorwärtsstrahlwinkel ψ durch den folgenden Ausdruck bestimmt wird: <maths id="math0063" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">ψ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0063" file="imgb0063.tif" wi="44" he="11" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths>
<claim-text>wobei <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> den Radius der Erde darstellt, wobei α den Horizontelevationswinkel darstellt, und wobei <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> den Radius der Satellitenumlaufbahn; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei der Steuermechanismus den Strahlwinkel zum Projizieren eines Übertragungsstrahls in der Rückwärtsrichtung in einem Rückwärtsstrahlwinkel von Winkel λ steuert, und wobei für eine gegebene Breitengradposition in der Satellitenumlaufbahn der Rückwärtsstrahlwinkel λ durch den folgenden Ausdruck bestimmt wird: <maths id="math0064" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">λ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>γ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>β</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0064" file="imgb0064.tif" wi="44" he="9" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><!-- EPO <DP n="66"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> den Radius der Erde darstellt, wobei <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> den Radius der Satellitenumlaufbahn darstellt, wobei γ einen spitzen Winkel zwischen dem Horizont und dem Vektor in einer Position eines Punkts auf der Erde darstellt, wo eine GEO-Erdstation auf einen geostationären Satelliten ausgerichtet ist, und wobei β einen GEO-Schutzbandwinkel um den Vektor zwischen der GEO-Erdstation und dem GEO-Satelliten darstellt, auf den sie ausgerichtet ist und der im Winkel γ zum Horizont ist, und wobei <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> den Radius der Satellitenumlaufbahn darstellt.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims03" lang="fr"><!-- EPO <DP n="67"> -->
<claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Système de constellation de satellites en orbite terrestre basse, LEO, destiné aux communications, qui comprend
<claim-text>a) une pluralité de satellites en orbite polaire autour de la Terre ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) les satellites étant mis en place dans des plans orbitaux autour de la Terre pour assurer la couverture de points sur la Terre pour les communications et à tout moment, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) dans lequel le nombre de satellites dans chaque plan orbital fournit des communications sur l'étendue du plan orbital ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>d) dans lequel chaque satellite comporte une antenne destinée à recevoir et émettre des signaux vers des stations terrestres, et dans lequel l'antenne satellite est commandée au moyen d'un mécanisme de commande de manière à éviter d'émettre le long de la ligne de visée d'une antenne à pointage GEO en tout point sur la Terre ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>e) dans lequel le plan orbital du satellite définit une orbite polaire passant par les quatre quadrants de la Terre, dans lequel le satellite comporte une commande de pointage, et dans lequel la commande de pointage, dans le premier quadrant, est programmée au moyen d'un algorithme de manière à diriger les émissions du satellite afin de rendre maximale la couverture et d'éviter d'émettre le long de la ligne de visée d'une antenne à pointage GEO ;<!-- EPO <DP n="68"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>f) dans lequel la commande de pointage du satellite dirige la couverture d'émission du satellite dans chaque quadrant du plan de l'orbite de manière à former une image miroir de la couverture d'émission du satellite du faisceau dirigé vers l'arrière projeté dans le quadrant précédent de l'orbite du satellite ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>g) dans lequel la transition entre des quadrants à l'équateur comprend l'extinction de l'émetteur satellite vers la Terre de manière à éviter d'émettre le long de la ligne de visée d'une antenne pointant vers un satellite en orbite terrestre géostationnaire, GEO ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>h) dans lequel l'émission entre des satellites et une station terrestre est effectuée en utilisant le spectre également utilisé par des satellites de communications GEO communiquant dans la même région.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 1, dans lequel le moyen de transport de datagrammes entre un satellite quelconque et un réseau terrestre au sol se fait par réémission-réception immédiate du datagramme vers une station passerelle qui est située en visibilité du même satellite.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 1, dans lequel le moyen de transport de datagrammes entre un satellite quelconque de la constellation de satellites LEO et un réseau terrestre au sol se fait par l'intermédiaire d'une liaison transversale vers un ou plusieurs autres satellites de ladite constellation, puis à partir desdits autres satellites vers une passerelle, dans lequel la passerelle n'est pas en visibilité du premier satellite à un moment donné quelconque.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 3, dans lequel lesdits satellites comprennent un moyen de commutation destiné à commuter le transport des datagrammes entre des satellites, dans lequel le moyen de commutation associé à un satellite est configuré pour transférer l'émission<!-- EPO <DP n="69"> --> de datagrammes à un moyen de commutation associé à un autre satellite.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 1, dans lequel la station terrestre associée pour émettre des datagrammes entre la station terrestre et un satellite utilise une antenne omnidirectionnelle.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 1, dans lequel la station terrestre associée pour émettre des datagrammes entre la station terrestre et un satellite utilise une antenne directionnelle qui est directionnelle vers le Nord ou vers le Sud par rapport au plan orbital de la constellation de satellites.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 5, dans lequel l'antenne est directionnelle à la fois en élévation et en azimut.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 1, dans lequel les satellites sont mis en place dans un plan orbital autour de la Terre pour fournir une couverture en chaque point sur la Terre.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 1, dans lequel le nombre de satellites dans chaque plan orbital est sélectionné en fonction de la couverture maximale d'émission et de réception pour l'altitude du satellite et l'angle d'élévation par rapport à l'horizon.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 1, dans lequel ladite commande de pointage de satellite comprend un mécanisme de commande, et dans lequel le mécanisme de commande commande le faisceau d'une ou plusieurs antennes du satellite de manière à diriger les émissions du satellite :
<claim-text>a) selon une projection de faisceau vers l'arrière qui est projetée sous un angle de faisceau arrière égal à l'angle <b>λ</b> qui, pour un angle aigu <b>y</b> entre l'horizon et le<!-- EPO <DP n="70"> --> vecteur à un emplacement d'un point sur la Terre où une station terrestre GEO pointe vers un satellite géostationnaire, et pour un angle de bande de garde de protection GEO <b>β</b> autour du vecteur défini entre la station terrestre GEO et le satellite GEO vers lequel il pointe, qui forme un angle <b>γ</b> avec l'horizon, est déterminé par l'expression : <maths id="math0065" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">λ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>γ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>β</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0065" file="imgb0065.tif" wi="57" he="12" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> où <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> représente le rayon de la Terre, où <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> représente le rayon de l'orbite du satellite, où <b>γ</b> représente un angle aigu entre l'horizon et le vecteur à un emplacement d'un point sur la Terre où une station terrestre GEO pointe vers un satellite géostationnaire, et où <b>β</b> représente un angle de bande de garde de protection GEO autour du vecteur défini entre la station terrestre GEO et le satellite GEO vers lequel il pointe, qui forme un angle <b>γ</b> par rapport à l'horizon ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) selon une projection de faisceau vers l'avant qui est projetée sous un angle de faisceau avant égal à <b>ψ</b> qui, pour une position de latitude donnée sur l'orbite du satellite, est déterminé par l'expression : <maths id="math0066" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">ψ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0066" file="imgb0066.tif" wi="51" he="12" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> où <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> représente le rayon de la Terre, où <b>α</b> représente l'angle d'élévation par rapport à l'horizon, et où <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> représente le rayon de l'orbite du satellite.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 10, dans lequel les projections à partir du satellite sont commandées au moyen du mécanisme de commande de manière à rendre maximale la couverture, et dans lequel les projections à partir du satellite sont commandées de manière à éviter d'émettre le long de la ligne de visée d'une antenne à pointage GEO.<!-- EPO <DP n="71"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 1, dans lequel le satellite comporte un mécanisme de commande qui commande l'émetteur satellite, et dans lequel l'antenne satellite est commandée de manière à interrompre sa liaison de communications afin d'éviter d'émettre le long de la ligne de visée d'une antenne à pointage GEO au moyen dudit mécanisme de commande en tout point sur la Terre par le mécanisme de commande, ledit mécanisme de commande étant configuré pour éteindre l'émetteur à des emplacements où des émissions de l'émetteur coïncideraient avec la ligne de visée d'une antenne de station terrestre GEO pointant vers un satellite GEO.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 12, dans lequel chaque satellite est configuré pour éteindre son émetteur qui émet vers la Terre au niveau de la transition entre des quadrants à l'équateur, de manière à éviter d'émettre le long de la ligne de visée d'une antenne pointant vers un satellite GEO.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 1, dans lequel les satellites LEO fournissent des liaisons de communications, et dans lequel un satellite de la constellation de satellites LEO s'approchant d'une ligne de visée d'une antenne d'une station terrestre de satellite GEO ou d'une bande de garde de satellite GEO qui se trouve dans le plan orbital du satellite en approche est configuré pour transférer les communications à un autre des satellites LEO qui ne se trouve pas sur la ligne de visée d'une antenne d'un satellite GEO.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0015" num="0015">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 1, dans lequel ladite antenne de satellite LEO destinée à recevoir et émettre des signaux vers des stations terrestres comprend une antenne à faisceau réglable en temps réel.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0016" num="0016">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 1, dans lequel le satellite émet un faisceau qui est projeté à partir de<!-- EPO <DP n="72"> --> l'antenne, ledit faisceau ayant une direction avant et une direction arrière par rapport au mouvement du satellite dans l'orbite.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0017" num="0017">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 1, dans lequel le satellite émet un faisceau qui est projeté à partir de l'antenne, et dans lequel ledit faisceau comporte une partie pointant vers l'avant et une partie pointant vers l'arrière.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0018" num="0018">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 16, dans lequel l'antenne satellite comprend une antenne directionnelle ; dans lequel le faisceau satellite avant est projeté sous un angle de faisceau avant égal à <b>ψ</b>, et dans lequel le faisceau satellite arrière est projeté sous un angle de faisceau arrière égal à <b>λ</b> ;<br/>
dans lequel ladite antenne directionnelle de satellite est dirigée au moyen du mécanisme de commande de manière à réduire l'angle de faisceau avant égal à <b>ψ</b> lorsque le satellite LEO se déplace vers une limite de latitude.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0019" num="0019">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 18, dans lequel l'antenne directionnelle de satellite est dirigée au moyen du mécanisme de commande de manière à réduire l'angle de faisceau avant égal à <b>ψ</b> lorsque le satellite LEO se déplace et à mesure que le satellite se déplace vers un angle limite de latitude en s'éloignant de l'équateur.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0020" num="0020">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 18, dans lequel l'antenne directionnelle de satellite est manipulée de manière à augmenter l'angle de faisceau pointant vers l'arrière égal à <b>λ</b> lorsque le satellite s'éloigne de l'équateur.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0021" num="0021">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 18, dans lequel l'antenne directionnelle de satellite est dirigée au moyen du mécanisme de commande de manière à augmenter l'angle de faisceau pointant vers l'arrière égal à <b>λ</b><!-- EPO <DP n="73"> --> lorsque le satellite s'éloigne d'une bande de garde de station terrestre GEO.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0022" num="0022">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 18, dans lequel l'antenne directionnelle de satellite est dirigée au moyen du mécanisme de commande de manière à augmenter l'angle de faisceau pointant vers l'arrière égal à <b>λ</b> lorsque le satellite s'éloigne de la ligne de visée d'une station terrestre GEO.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0023" num="0023">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 17, dans lequel la partie avant du faisceau de communications par satellite présente un angle de faisceau avant qui est ajusté en fonction de la latitude du satellite.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0024" num="0024">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 1, dans lequel le mécanisme de commande commande une ou plusieurs antennes d'un satellite de manière à produire un faisceau vers l'avant projeté sous un angle de faisceau avant et de manière à produire un faisceau vers l'arrière projeté sous un angle de faisceau arrière.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0025" num="0025">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 24, dans lequel le faisceau satellite vers l'arrière est projeté sous un angle de faisceau arrière qui diminue à mesure que le satellite se déplace vers l'avant dans son orbite directionnelle.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0026" num="0026">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 24, dans lequel le faisceau satellite vers l'avant est projeté sous un angle de faisceau avant qui augmente à mesure que le satellite se déplace vers l'avant sur son orbite directionnelle.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0027" num="0027">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 25, dans lequel le faisceau satellite vers l'avant est projeté sous un angle de faisceau avant qui augmente à mesure que le satellite se déplace vers l'avant sur son orbite directionnelle.<!-- EPO <DP n="74"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0028" num="0028">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 25, dans lequel le faisceau satellite vers l'arrière est projeté sous un angle de faisceau arrière égal à <b>λ</b> qui, pour un angle aigu <b>γ</b> entre l'horizon et le vecteur à un emplacement d'un point sur la Terre où une station terrestre GEO pointe vers un satellite géostationnaire, et pour un angle de bande de garde de protection GEO <b>β</b> autour du vecteur défini entre la station terrestre GEO et le satellite GEO vers lequel il pointe, qui forme un angle <b>γ</b> avec l'horizon, est déterminé par l'expression : <maths id="math0067" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">λ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>γ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>β</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0067" file="imgb0067.tif" wi="57" he="12" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> où <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> représente le rayon de la Terre, où <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> représente le rayon de l'orbite du satellite, où <b>γ</b> représente un angle aigu entre l'horizon et le vecteur à l'emplacement d'un point sur la Terre où une station terrestre GEO pointe vers un satellite géostationnaire, et où <b>β</b> représente un angle de bande de garde de protection GEO autour du vecteur défini entre la station terrestre GEO et le satellite GEO vers lequel il pointe, qui forme un angle <b>γ</b> par rapport à l'horizon.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0029" num="0029">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 26, dans lequel le faisceau satellite vers l'avant est projeté sous un angle de faisceau avant égal à <b>ψ</b>, et dans lequel, pour une position de latitude donnée sur l'orbite du satellite, l'angle de faisceau avant <b>ψ</b> projeté est déterminé par l'expression : <maths id="math0068" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">ψ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0068" file="imgb0068.tif" wi="51" he="12" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> où <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> représente le rayon de la Terre, où <b>α</b> représente l'angle d'élévation par rapport à l'horizon, et où <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> représente le rayon de l'orbite du satellite.<!-- EPO <DP n="75"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0030" num="0030">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 29, dans lequel l'angle d'élévation par rapport à l'horizon consiste en l'angle minimal formé entre (1) l'horizon et (2) le satellite, pour lequel le satellite et une station terrestre peuvent communiquer l'un avec l'autre, tel que vu à partir de l'emplacement de la station terrestre.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0031" num="0031">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 27, dans lequel le faisceau satellite vers l'arrière est projeté sous un angle de faisceau arrière égal à l'angle <b>À,</b> dans lequel, pour une position de latitude donnée sur l'orbite du satellite, l'angle de faisceau arrière <b>λ</b> projeté est déterminé par l'expression : <maths id="math0069" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">λ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>γ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>β</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0069" file="imgb0069.tif" wi="57" he="12" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> où <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> représente le rayon de la Terre, où <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> représente le rayon de l'orbite du satellite, où <b>γ</b> représente un angle aigu entre l'horizon et le vecteur à l'emplacement d'un point sur la Terre où une station terrestre GEO pointe vers un satellite géostationnaire, et où <b>β</b> représente un angle de bande de garde de protection GEO autour du vecteur défini entre la station terrestre GEO et le satellite GEO vers lequel il pointe, qui forme un angle <b>γ</b> par rapport à l'horizon, et où <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> représente le rayon de l'orbite du satellite, dans lequel le faisceau satellite vers l'avant est projeté sous un angle de faisceau avant égal à <b>ψ</b>, et dans lequel, pour une position de latitude donnée sur l'orbite du satellite, l'angle de faisceau avant <b>ψ</b> projeté est déterminé par l'expression : <maths id="math0070" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">ψ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0070" file="imgb0070.tif" wi="51" he="12" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> où <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> représente le rayon de la Terre, où <b>α</b> représente l'angle d'élévation par rapport à l'horizon, et où <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> représente le rayon de l'orbite du satellite.<!-- EPO <DP n="76"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0032" num="0032">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 24, dans lequel le faisceau produit vers l'avant est composé d'une pluralité de sous-faisceaux.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0033" num="0033">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 24, dans lequel le faisceau produit vers l'arrière est composé d'une pluralité de sous-faisceaux.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0034" num="0034">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 24, dans lequel au moins l'un du faisceau produit vers l'avant et du faisceau produit vers l'arrière est composé d'une pluralité de sous-faisceaux, et dans lequel lesdits sous-faisceaux sont commandables de manière à commander la projection du faisceau de communications à partir de ladite antenne satellite.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0035" num="0035">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 24, dans lequel le faisceau produit vers l'avant est composé d'une pluralité de sous-faisceaux, dans lequel le faisceau produit vers l'arrière est composé d'une pluralité de sous-faisceaux, et dans lequel lesdits sous-faisceaux sont commandables de manière à commander la projection du faisceau de communications à partir de ladite antenne satellite.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0036" num="0036">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 34, dans lequel le sous-faisceau est commandable en positionnant ladite antenne qui fournit le sous-faisceau.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0037" num="0037">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 34, dans lequel au moins l'un dudit faisceau avant et dudit faisceau arrière est commandable en activant ou en désactivant le sous-faisceau comprenant le faisceau avant ou le faisceau arrière respectif.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0038" num="0038">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 34, dans lequel ledit faisceau avant est commandable en activant ou en désactivant le sous-faisceau comprenant le faisceau avant, et dans lequel ledit faisceau arrière est commandable en<!-- EPO <DP n="77"> --> activant ou en désactivant le sous-faisceau comprenant le faisceau arrière.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0039" num="0039">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 24, dans lequel l'antenne satellite comprend une antenne à faisceau réglable en temps réel.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0040" num="0040">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 39, dans lequel l'antenne à faisceau réglable en temps réel comprend une antenne réseau à commande de phase.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0041" num="0041">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 39, dans lequel l'antenne fournit une enveloppe de faisceau qui est constituée de sous-faisceaux configurés pour une réutilisation de fréquence spécifique, une réutilisation de polarisation, ou une prise en charge d'autres éléments orbitaux ou éléments de station terrestre.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0042" num="0042">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 40, dans lequel l'antenne fournit une enveloppe de faisceau qui est constituée de sous-faisceaux configurés pour une réutilisation de fréquence spécifique, une réutilisation de polarisation, ou une prise en charge d'autres éléments orbitaux ou éléments de station terrestre.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0043" num="0043">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 24, dans lequel ladite constellation de satellites est prévue pour qu'au moins un satellite de la constellation de satellites soit en visibilité à tout moment à partir d'une station terrestre quelconque sur la Terre.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0044" num="0044">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 24, dans lequel le faisceau satellite vers l'avant est projeté sous un angle de faisceau avant <b>ψ</b> ; dans lequel le faisceau satellite vers l'arrière est projeté sous un angle de faisceau arrière égal à <b>λ</b> ; dans lequel au moins une antenne satellite comprend une antenne directionnelle qui projette le faisceau avant, et dans lequel ladite au moins une antenne directionnelle qui projette le faisceau<!-- EPO <DP n="78"> --> avant est dirigée au moyen du mécanisme de commande de manière à réduire l'angle de faisceau avant <b>ψ</b> lorsque le satellite LEO se déplace vers une limite de latitude, dans lequel au moins une antenne satellite comprend une antenne directionnelle qui projette le faisceau arrière, dans lequel ladite au moins une antenne directionnelle de satellite projetant le faisceau arrière est dirigée au moyen du mécanisme de commande de manière à augmenter l'angle de faisceau arrière <b>λ</b> lorsque le satellite LEO se déplace vers une limite de latitude.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0045" num="0045">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 44, dans lequel chaque antenne directionnelle comporte un émetteur associé qui fournit un signal à l'antenne, et dans lequel chaque satellite est configuré pour éteindre un émetteur associé à des emplacements où l'émission de son émetteur coïnciderait avec la ligne de visée d'une antenne pointant vers un satellite GEO.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0046" num="0046">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 24, dans lequel ladite au moins une antenne destinée à recevoir et émettre vers des stations terrestres comprend une antenne directionnelle et dans lequel il existe au moins un émetteur associé à l'antenne directionnelle qui fournit un signal à l'antenne, et dans lequel chaque satellite est configuré pour éteindre l'émetteur associé à des emplacements où l'émission de son émetteur coïnciderait avec la ligne de visée d'une antenne pointant vers un satellite GEO.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0047" num="0047">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 46, dans lequel l'équateur définit une transition entre des quadrants du plan d'orbite.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0048" num="0048">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 47, dans lequel chaque satellite est configuré pour éteindre son émetteur qui émet vers la Terre au niveau de la transition entre des quadrants à l'équateur, de manière à éviter d'émettre<!-- EPO <DP n="79"> --> le long de la ligne de visée d'une antenne pointant vers un satellite GEO.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0049" num="0049">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 48, dans lequel chaque deuxième, troisième et quatrième quadrant du plan d'orbite est une image miroir, lors du fonctionnement, du premier quadrant, dans lequel un satellite de la constellation de satellites sur une orbite est une image miroir des projections angulaires des faisceaux pour chaque quadrant successif.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0050" num="0050">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 44, dans lequel l'angle de faisceau avant <b>ψ</b> et l'angle de faisceau arrière <b>λ</b> sont déterminés à la limite de latitude en fonction de la limite de latitude <b>σ</b> pour un angle de bande de garde <b>β</b> donné autour du vecteur défini entre une station terrestre GEO et le satellite GEO sous un angle <b>γ</b>, et dans lequel le satellite est en orbite à une altitude <b>h</b> qui forme au moins un angle <b>α</b> au-dessus de l'horizon local.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0051" num="0051">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 27, dans lequel chaque satellite comporte un ordinateur comportant un processeur matériel, et dans lequel l'ordinateur est programmé au moyen d'un logiciel ayant des instructions destinées à ordonner à l'ordinateur de manipuler le faisceau provenant du satellite dans les directions avant et arrière, lesdites instructions comprenant les instructions données à l'ordinateur consistant à :
<claim-text>déterminer l'angle de faisceau avant <b>ψ</b> en surveillant l'altitude du satellite et les coordonnées de localisation d'un satellite, dans lequel l'angle de faisceau avant <b>ψ</b> est l'angle de faisceau par rapport à un vecteur défini par le centre de la Terre et l'emplacement du satellite qui se projette en avant du satellite dans la direction de l'orbite du satellite ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>déterminer l'angle de faisceau arrière <b>λ</b> en surveillant l'altitude du satellite et les coordonnées de localisation d'un satellite, dans lequel l'angle de<!-- EPO <DP n="80"> --> faisceau arrière <b>λ</b> est l'angle de faisceau par rapport à un vecteur défini par le centre de la Terre et l'emplacement du satellite qui se projette vers l'arrière du satellite dans la direction opposée à celle de l'orbite du satellite ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>identifier des emplacements de stations terrestres GEO qui sont dans la ligne de visée de l'orbite du satellite ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>commander l'angle de faisceau avant <b>ψ</b> et l'angle de faisceau arrière <b>λ</b> de manière à rendre maximale la couverture et éviter d'émettre le long de la ligne de visée d'une antenne de station terrestre GEO.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0052" num="0052">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 24, dans lequel les satellites LEO de la constellation de satellites sont répartis dans des plans orbitaux au-dessus de la surface terrestre ; dans lequel un satellite LEO de la constellation de satellites est réparti sur l'orbite par rapport à un satellite LEO adjacent de la constellation de satellites de manière à ce que le satellite LEO et le satellite adjacent soient à une distance de visibilité directe entre eux.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0053" num="0053">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 24, dans lequel les satellites sont espacés dans leur plan orbital à une distance de visibilité directe, <b>s,</b> d'espacement entre des satellites adjacents, dans lequel la distance de visibilité directe "s" est la distance de visibilité directe entre deux satellites LEO en orbite.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0054" num="0054">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 52, dans lequel la distance d'espacement maximale de visibilité directe entre des satellites de la constellation de satellites est déterminé par l'angle minimal formé entre l'horizon et le satellite, pour lequel ce satellite peut communiquer avec une station terrestre située en un point sur la Terre.<!-- EPO <DP n="81"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0055" num="0055">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 54, dans lequel la distance d'espacement maximale entre des satellites adjacents est déterminée par un angle <b>Θ</b> d'un vecteur défini par les positions de latitude respectives de chaque satellite adjacent respectif dans un plan orbital respectif, où l'angle au sommet est le centre de la Terre.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0056" num="0056">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 55, dans lequel ledit angle <b>Θ</b> est déterminé par l'expression <b>Θ</b> = 2 <i>ARCSIN</i>(S/2r<sub>L</sub>), où S est la distance d'espacement entre des satellites adjacents et est représenté par l'expression s = 2 <i>r</i><sub>L</sub><i>SIN</i>(Θ/2), où <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> représente le rayon de l'orbite du satellite.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0057" num="0057">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 52, dans lequel au moins un premier satellite LEO en orbite de la constellation de satellites est suffisamment loin au-dessus de l'horizon local pour être dans la ligne de visée d'une station terrestre LEO qui reçoit des émissions en provenance de la constellation de satellites pour être disponible pour des communications fiables ; dans lequel, pendant la période où ledit au moins un premier satellite LEO en orbite de la constellation de satellites se trouve dans une bande de garde autour du vecteur défini entre la station terrestre GEO et le satellite GEO, au moins un deuxième satellite LEO est en visibilité et suffisamment loin au-dessus de l'horizon local, et prend le relais d'une éventuelle fonction de communications établie avec la station terrestre à partir du premier satellite LEO situé dans le vecteur de bande de garde.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0058" num="0058">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 55, dans lequel ledit au moins un deuxième satellite LEO prenant le relais de la fonction de communications prend le relais des fonctions de communications dudit au moins un premier satellite avant que le premier satellite n'interrompe sa fonction d'émission au niveau du vecteur de bande de garde.<!-- EPO <DP n="82"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0059" num="0059">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 58, dans lequel ledit au moins un premier satellite cesse d'émettre lorsqu'il se trouve à l'intérieur du vecteur de bande de garde en désactivant un ou plusieurs sous-faisceaux de son faisceau d'émission.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0060" num="0060">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 57, dans lequel la projection du faisceau arrière du premier satellite peut communiquer avec la station terrestre après que le faisceau avant a franchi le vecteur de ligne de visée.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0061" num="0061">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 24, dans lequel un satellite commande l'angle de faisceau avant du faisceau projeté vers l'avant en modifiant l'angle de la projection lorsque le satellite se déplace sur son orbite dans un quadrant ; dans lequel le faisceau arrière du satellite de la constellation de satellites dans le quadrant suivant de son orbite est projeté pour former une image miroir du faisceau avant projeté par le satellite dans le quadrant précédent.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0062" num="0062">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 61, dans lequel ladite formation d'une image miroir d'une projection arrière fournit une région de couverture maximale à l'arrière du satellite lorsque le satellite se déplace à travers le quadrant.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0063" num="0063">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 24, dans lequel le faisceau émis par un satellite LEO de la constellation de satellites est dans une direction opposée à la direction dans laquelle un satellite GEO émettrait vers la même station terrestre.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0064" num="0064">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 24, dans lequel, lorsqu'un satellite émetteur doit cesser d'émettre vers une station terrestre située en un point sur la Terre pour éviter le vecteur de visée d'une antenne GEO de station terrestre, un autre satellite de la constellation<!-- EPO <DP n="83"> --> de satellites LEO prend le relais de l'émission du satellite émetteur.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0065" num="0065">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 24, comprenant une pluralité de stations terrestres configurées pour recevoir des émissions en provenance de satellites LEO et envoyer des émissions à des satellites LEO, dans lequel au moins certaines de la pluralité des stations terrestres comportent des antennes omnidirectionnelles.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0066" num="0066">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 27, comprenant une pluralité de stations terrestres configurées pour recevoir des émissions en provenance de satellites LEO et envoyer des émissions à des satellites LEO, dans lequel au moins certaines de la pluralité des stations terrestres comportent des antennes directionnelles.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0067" num="0067">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 66, dans lequel lesdites antennes directionnelles sont directionnelles vers le Nord ou vers le Sud par rapport au plan orbital de la constellation de satellites.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0068" num="0068">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 67, dans lequel lesdites antennes dirigées vers le Nord ou vers le Sud sont orientables en élévation et en azimut.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0069" num="0069">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 1, dans lequel les satellites de la constellation de satellites sont positionnés dans de multiples plans orbitaux selon un espacement longitudinal angulaire régulier.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0070" num="0070">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 56, dans lequel le nombre de satellites prévus dans un plan orbital est déterminé par la distance entre des satellites en orbite qui sont à une altitude <b>h</b> et au moins sous un angle <b>α</b> au-dessus de l'horizon, et maintiennent un angle de bande de garde égal à <b>β</b> autour du vecteur défini entre une station terrestre GEO et un GEO sous un angle <b>γ.</b><!-- EPO <DP n="84"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0071" num="0071">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 1, dans lequel chaque satellite comporte une pluralité d'antennes.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0072" num="0072">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 71, dans lequel chaque pluralité d'antennes de satellite comprend des antennes destinées à des liaisons montantes/descendantes avec des stations terrestres et des antennes destinées à des liaisons transversales avec d'autres satellites.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0073" num="0073">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 72, dans lequel lesdites liaisons montantes/descendantes comprennent des antennes hélicoïdales, et dans lequel lesdites antennes de liaisons transversales comprennent des lentilles.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0074" num="0074">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 24, dans lequel le nombre de satellites est le nombre minimal de satellites et dans lequel la distance entre satellites est la distance maximale entre satellites.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0075" num="0075">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 24, comprenant en outre une pluralité de stations terrestres comportant au moins une antenne directionnelle, dans lequel le gain le plus élevé de l'antenne directionnelle est dirigé de manière à pointer vers le Sud ou dans une direction Sud pour une station terrestre située dans l'hémisphère Sud, et dans lequel le gain le plus élevé de l'antenne directionnelle est dirigé de manière à pointer vers le Nord ou dans une direction Nord pour une station terrestre située dans l'hémisphère Nord.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0076" num="0076">
<claim-text>Système selon la revendication 75, dans lequel l'antenne de station terrestre directionnelle est orientée de manière à pointer son gain d'antenne maximal afin qu'il s'écarte de la direction d'un satellite en orbite terrestre géostationnaire, GEO, et vers la direction d'un satellite LEO.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0077" num="0077">
<claim-text>Procédé pour mettre en œuvre des communications par l'intermédiaire d'un système de communications par<!-- EPO <DP n="85"> --> satellite en orbite terrestre basse, LEO, comportant des satellites LEO qui assurent une réutilisation de fréquences de satellites de communications en orbite terrestre géostationnaire, GEO, le procédé comprenant :
<claim-text>a) la mise en place d'une pluralité de satellites LEO dans une pluralité de plans orbitaux autour de la Terre ; dans lequel chaque satellite comporte un équipement destiné à émettre des émissions radiofréquences, RF, ayant des fréquences destinées à être reçues par une station terrestre située sur la Terre, et dans lequel chaque plan orbital de satellite définit une orbite polaire passant par les quatre quadrants de la Terre ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) fournir un mécanisme de commande qui commande les émissions RF du satellite ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) émettre à partir d'un satellite LEO une émission vers une station terrestre ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>d) commander l'émission RF du satellite de manière à éviter d'émettre le long de la ligne de visée d'une antenne pointant vers un satellite GEO, cela comprenant le traitement des informations de localisation du satellite au moyen de composants informatiques du mécanisme de commande de faisceau satellite, et la commande de l'antenne satellite au moyen d'un mécanisme de commande de manière à éviter d'émettre le long de la ligne de visée d'une antenne à pointage GEO en tout point sur la Terre ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>e) dans lequel la commande de l'émission RF du satellite comprend la commande de la couverture du faisceau au moyen du mécanisme de commande du satellite de manière à diriger la couverture d'émission du satellite dans chaque quadrant du plan d'orbite afin de former une image miroir de la couverture d'émission du satellite pour le faisceau dirigé vers l'arrière projeté dans le quadrant précédent du satellite ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>f) dans lequel la commande de l'émission RF du satellite comprend en outre l'orientation des émissions du satellite vers la Terre au niveau de la transition entre des quadrants à l'équateur de manière à éviter<!-- EPO <DP n="86"> --> d'émettre le long de la ligne de visée d'une antenne pointant vers un satellite GEO ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>g) dans lequel l'émission à partir d'un satellite LEO d'une émission vers une station terrestre est effectuée en utilisant le spectre également utilisé par des satellites de communications GEO communiquant dans la même région.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0078" num="0078">
<claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 77, dans lequel la commande de l'émission du satellite comprend la commande, au moyen d'un mécanisme de commande, du fonctionnement d'une ou plusieurs antennes du satellite de manière à produire un faisceau d'émission vers l'avant projeté sous un angle de faisceau avant et de manière à produire un faisceau d'émission vers l'arrière projeté sous un angle de faisceau arrière.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0079" num="0079">
<claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 78, dans lequel la commande de l'angle de faisceau comprend la projection d'un faisceau d'émission vers l'avant sous un angle de faisceau avant égal à <b>ψ</b>, et dans lequel, pour une position de latitude donnée sur l'orbite du satellite, l'angle de faisceau avant égal à <b>ψ</b> sous lequel le faisceau est projeté est déterminé par l'expression : <maths id="math0071" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">ψ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0071" file="imgb0071.tif" wi="51" he="12" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> où <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> représente le rayon de la Terre, où <b>α</b> représente l'angle d'élévation par rapport à l'horizon, et où <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> représente le rayon de l'orbite du satellite.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0080" num="0080">
<claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 78, dans lequel la commande de l'angle de faisceau comprend la projection d'un faisceau d'émission vers l'arrière sous un angle de faisceau arrière égal à l'angle <b>λ,</b> dans lequel, pour une position de latitude donnée sur l'orbite du satellite, l'angle de faisceau arrière <b>λ</b> sous lequel le faisceau est projeté est déterminé par l'expression :<!-- EPO <DP n="87"> --> <maths id="math0072" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">λ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>γ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>β</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0072" file="imgb0072.tif" wi="57" he="12" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> où <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> représente le rayon de la Terre, où <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> représente le rayon de l'orbite du satellite, où <b>γ</b> représente un angle aigu entre l'horizon et le vecteur à l'emplacement d'un point sur la Terre où une station terrestre GEO pointe vers un satellite géostationnaire, et où <b>β</b> représente un angle de bande de garde de protection GEO autour du vecteur défini entre la station terrestre GEO et le satellite GEO vers lequel il pointe, qui forme l'angle <b>γ</b> par rapport à l'horizon, et où <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> représente le rayon de l'orbite du satellite.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0081" num="0081">
<claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 78, dans lequel la commande de l'angle de faisceau comprend la projection d'un faisceau d'émission vers l'avant sous un angle de faisceau avant égal à <b>ψ,</b> et dans lequel, pour une position de latitude donnée sur l'orbite du satellite, l'angle de faisceau avant <b>ψ</b> sous lequel le faisceau est projeté est déterminé par l'expression : <maths id="math0073" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">ψ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0073" file="imgb0073.tif" wi="51" he="12" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths>
<claim-text>où <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> représente le rayon de la Terre, où <b>α</b> représente l'angle d'élévation par rapport à l'horizon, et où <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> représente le rayon de l'orbite du satellite ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel la commande de l'angle de faisceau comprend la projection d'un faisceau d'émission vers l'arrière sous un angle de faisceau arrière égal à l'angle <b>λ,</b> dans lequel, pour une position de latitude donnée sur l'orbite du satellite, l'angle de faisceau arrière <b>λ</b> sous lequel le faisceau est projeté est déterminé par l'expression : <maths id="math0074" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">λ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>γ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>β</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0074" file="imgb0074.tif" wi="57" he="12" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><!-- EPO <DP n="88"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>où <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> représente le rayon de la Terre, où <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> représente le rayon de l'orbite du satellite, où <b>γ</b> représente un angle aigu entre l'horizon et le vecteur à l'emplacement d'un point sur la Terre où une station terrestre GEO pointe vers un satellite géostationnaire, et où <b>β</b> représente un angle de bande de garde de protection GEO autour du vecteur défini entre la station terrestre GEO et le satellite GEO vers lequel il pointe, qui forme l'angle <b>γ</b> par rapport à l'horizon, et où <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> représente le rayon de l'orbite du satellite.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0082" num="0082">
<claim-text>Satellite en orbite terrestre basse, LEO, configuré pour fonctionner dans un plan orbital défini par une orbite polaire passant par les quatre quadrants de la Terre, comprenant :
<claim-text>a) un équipement de communication, ledit équipement de communications comprenant un équipement destiné à émettre des émissions RF ayant des fréquences destinées à être reçues par une station terrestre située sur la Terre, et un équipement de communications destiné à communiquer avec d'autres satellites ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) un mécanisme de commande comportant un composant de traitement et un logiciel ayant des instructions destinées à commander des émissions RF du satellite LEO vers une station terrestre ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) un émetteur destiné à émettre des émissions RF ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>d) au moins une antenne destinée à projeter les émissions RF à partir du satellite LEO, comportant un faisceau dirigé vers l'avant et un faisceau dirigé vers l'arrière ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>e) dans lequel ledit mécanisme de commande commande les émissions du satellite afin d'éviter d'émettre le long de la ligne de visée d'une antenne pointant vers un satellite GEO ; dans lequel le composant de traitement et le logiciel du mécanisme de commande sont configurés de manière à traiter les informations de localisation du satellite et à déterminer l'angle de faisceau devant être fourni par l'antenne satellite,<!-- EPO <DP n="89"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>f) dans lequel le mécanisme de commande dirige la couverture d'émission du satellite dans chaque quadrant du plan d'orbite de manière à former une image miroir de la couverture d'émission du satellite du faisceau dirigé vers l'arrière projeté dans le quadrant précédent de l'orbite du satellite ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>g) dans lequel le mécanisme de commande désactive les émissions du satellite vers la Terre au niveau de la transition entre des quadrants au niveau de l'équateur de manière à éviter d'émettre le long de la ligne de visée d'une antenne pointant vers un satellite en orbite terrestre géostationnaire, GEO ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>h) dans lequel les émissions RF à partir du satellite LEO vers une station terrestre sont effectuées en utilisant le spectre également utilisé par des satellites de communications GEO communiquant dans la même région.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0083" num="0083">
<claim-text>Satellite selon la revendication 82, dans lequel le mécanisme de commande commande le fonctionnement d'une ou plusieurs antennes du satellite de manière à produire un faisceau d'émission vers l'avant projeté sous un angle de faisceau avant et de manière à produire un faisceau d'émission vers l'arrière projeté sous un angle de faisceau arrière.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0084" num="0084">
<claim-text>Satellite selon la revendication 83, dans lequel le mécanisme de commande commande l'angle de faisceau de manière à projeter un faisceau d'émission vers l'avant sous un angle de faisceau avant égal à <b>ψ</b>, et dans lequel, pour une position de latitude donnée sur l'orbite du satellite, l'angle de faisceau avant <b>ψ</b> est déterminé par l'expression : <maths id="math0075" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">ψ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0075" file="imgb0075.tif" wi="51" he="12" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> où <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> représente le rayon de la Terre, où <b>α</b> représente l'angle d'élévation par rapport à l'horizon, et où <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> représente le rayon de l'orbite du satellite.<!-- EPO <DP n="90"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0085" num="0085">
<claim-text>Satellite selon la revendication 83, dans lequel le mécanisme de commande commande l'angle de faisceau de manière à projeter un faisceau d'émission vers l'arrière sous un angle de faisceau arrière égal à l'angle <b>λ,</b> dans lequel, pour une position de latitude donnée sur l'orbite du satellite, l'angle de faisceau arrière <b>λ</b> est déterminé par l'expression : <maths id="math0076" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">λ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>γ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>β</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0076" file="imgb0076.tif" wi="57" he="12" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> où <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> représente le rayon de la Terre, où <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> représente le rayon de l'orbite du satellite, où <b>γ</b> représente un angle aigu entre l'horizon et le vecteur à l'emplacement d'un point sur la Terre où une station terrestre GEO pointe vers un satellite géostationnaire, et où <b>β</b> représente un angle de bande de garde de protection GEO autour du vecteur défini entre la station terrestre GEO et le satellite GEO vers lequel il pointe, qui forme un angle <b>γ</b> par rapport à l'horizon, et où <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> représente le rayon de l'orbite du satellite.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0086" num="0086">
<claim-text>Satellite selon la revendication 83, dans lequel le mécanisme de commande commande l'angle de faisceau de manière à projeter un faisceau d'émission vers l'avant sous un angle de faisceau avant égal à <b>ψ,</b> et dans lequel, pour une position de latitude donnée sur l'orbite du satellite, l'angle de faisceau avant <b>ψ</b> est déterminé par l'expression : <maths id="math0077" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">ψ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0077" file="imgb0077.tif" wi="51" he="12" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths>
<claim-text>où <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> représente le rayon de la Terre, où <b>α</b> représente l'angle d'élévation par rapport à l'horizon, et où <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> représente le rayon de l'orbite du satellite ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel le mécanisme de commande commande l'angle de faisceau de manière à projeter un faisceau d'émission<!-- EPO <DP n="91"> --> vers l'arrière sous un angle de faisceau arrière égal à l'angle <b>λ,</b> dans lequel, pour une position de latitude donnée sur l'orbite du satellite, l'angle de faisceau arrière <b>λ</b> est déterminé par l'expression : <maths id="math0078" num=""><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">λ</mi><mo>=</mo><msup><mi>sin</mi><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msup><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>E</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>90</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>γ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>β</mi></mfenced></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>L</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0078" file="imgb0078.tif" wi="57" he="12" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></claim-text>
<claim-text>où <i>r<sub>E</sub></i> représente le rayon de la Terre, où <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> représente le rayon de l'orbite du satellite, où <b>γ</b> représente un angle aigu entre l'horizon et le vecteur à l'emplacement d'un point sur la Terre où une station terrestre GEO pointe vers un satellite géostationnaire, et où <b>β</b> représente un angle de bande de garde de protection GEO autour du vecteur défini entre la station terrestre GEO et le satellite GEO vers lequel il pointe, qui forme l'angle <b>γ</b> par rapport à l'horizon, et où <i>r<sub>L</sub></i> représente le rayon de l'orbite du satellite.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="92"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="126" he="220" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="93"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="121" he="223" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="94"> -->
<figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="148" he="227" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="95"> -->
<figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="136" he="220" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="96"> -->
<figure id="f0005" num="5"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="136" he="217" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="97"> -->
<figure id="f0006" num="6A"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="140" he="185" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="98"> -->
<figure id="f0007" num="6B"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="133" he="229" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="99"> -->
<figure id="f0008" num="7A"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="124" he="223" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="100"> -->
<figure id="f0009" num="7B"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="119" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="101"> -->
<figure id="f0010" num="8"><img id="if0010" file="imgf0010.tif" wi="150" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="102"> -->
<figure id="f0011" num="9"><img id="if0011" file="imgf0011.tif" wi="144" he="221" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="103"> -->
<figure id="f0012" num="10A"><img id="if0012" file="imgf0012.tif" wi="121" he="215" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="104"> -->
<figure id="f0013" num="10B"><img id="if0013" file="imgf0013.tif" wi="127" he="229" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="105"> -->
<figure id="f0014" num="11"><img id="if0014" file="imgf0014.tif" wi="149" he="163" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="106"> -->
<figure id="f0015" num="12"><img id="if0015" file="imgf0015.tif" wi="135" he="174" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="107"> -->
<figure id="f0016" num="13"><img id="if0016" file="imgf0016.tif" wi="130" he="216" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="108"> -->
<figure id="f0017" num="14A"><img id="if0017" file="imgf0017.tif" wi="150" he="231" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="109"> -->
<figure id="f0018" num="14B"><img id="if0018" file="imgf0018.tif" wi="132" he="107" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="110"> -->
<figure id="f0019" num="15A"><img id="if0019" file="imgf0019.tif" wi="156" he="228" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="111"> -->
<figure id="f0020" num="15B"><img id="if0020" file="imgf0020.tif" wi="132" he="103" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="112"> -->
<figure id="f0021" num="16A"><img id="if0021" file="imgf0021.tif" wi="150" he="227" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="113"> -->
<figure id="f0022" num="16B"><img id="if0022" file="imgf0022.tif" wi="133" he="106" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="114"> -->
<figure id="f0023" num="17"><img id="if0023" file="imgf0023.tif" wi="146" he="193" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<ep-reference-list id="ref-list">
<heading id="ref-h0001"><b>REFERENCES CITED IN THE DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0001" num=""><i>This list of references cited by the applicant is for the reader's convenience only. It does not form part of the European patent document. Even though great care has been taken in compiling the references, errors or omissions cannot be excluded and the EPO disclaims all liability in this regard.</i></p>
<heading id="ref-h0002"><b>Patent documents cited in the description</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0002" num="">
<ul id="ref-ul0001" list-style="bullet">
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0001" dnum="US6236834B1"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>6236834</doc-number><kind>B1</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0001">[0007]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0002" dnum="US5410728A"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>5410728</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0002">[0013]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0003" dnum="US5604920A"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>5604920</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0003">[0013]</crossref></li>
</ul></p>
</ep-reference-list>
</ep-patent-document>
