<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP09829802B1" file="EP09829802NWB1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="2370016" kind="B1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCY..TRBGCZEEHUPLSK..HRIS..MTNO....SM..................</B001EP><B003EP>*</B003EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  2100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>2370016</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT SPECIFICATION</B121></B120><B130>B1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>09829802.9</B210><B220><date>20091125</date></B220><B240><B241><date>20110628</date></B241><B242><date>20170711</date></B242></B240><B250>en</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B300><B310>118609 P</B310><B320><date>20081129</date></B320><B330><ctry>US</ctry></B330><B310>156440 P</B310><B320><date>20090227</date></B320><B330><ctry>US</ctry></B330></B300><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20111005</date><bnum>201140</bnum></B430><B450><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B450><B452EP><date>20210415</date></B452EP></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>A61B  18/20        20060101AFI20120503BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>A61B  18/20        20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>A61B  18/22        20130101 FI20190216BHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>Gerät zur Laserbehandlung mit einer Emissionsspitze für eine kontaktfreie Verwendung</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>Laser treatment device with an emission tip for contactless use</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>Dispositif de traitement au laser avec une pointe d'émission pour l'utilisation sans contact</B542></B540><B560><B561><text>EP-A1- 0 336 045</text></B561><B561><text>DE-A1- 3 800 555</text></B561><B561><text>US-A- 5 125 923</text></B561><B561><text>US-A- 5 374 266</text></B561><B561><text>US-A- 5 971 755</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2006 095 096</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2006 129 141</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2007 100 401</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2007 190 482</text></B561><B561><text>US-B1- 6 190 376</text></B561><B561><text>US-B2- 7 187 822</text></B561><B562><text>None</text></B562><B565EP><date>20120508</date></B565EP></B560></B500><B600><B620EP><parent><cdoc><dnum><anum>17170009.9</anum><pnum>3231385</pnum></dnum><date>20170508</date></cdoc></parent></B620EP></B600><B700><B720><B721><snm>BOUTOUSSOV, Dmitri</snm><adr><str>32811 Sail Way</str><city>Dana Point, CA 92629</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>ANDRIASYAN, Manvel</snm><adr><str>9207 Laurelhurst Court</str><city>San Diego, CA 92126</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B730><B731><snm>Biolase, Inc.</snm><iid>101342400</iid><irf>273.0031EP</irf><adr><str>4 Cromwell</str><city>Irvine, CA 92618</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B731></B730><B740><B741><snm>WBH Wachenhausen Patentanwälte PartG mbB</snm><iid>101642582</iid><adr><str>Müllerstraße 40</str><city>80469 München</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840><B860><B861><dnum><anum>US2009065950</anum></dnum><date>20091125</date></B861><B862>en</B862></B860><B870><B871><dnum><pnum>WO2010062969</pnum></dnum><date>20100603</date><bnum>201022</bnum></B871></B870></B800></SDOBI>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<heading id="h0001">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<heading id="h0002">1. <u>Field of the Invention</u></heading>
<p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates generally to a laser cutting device for cutting hard and/or soft materials and, more particularly, to a laser delivery system for supplying components to the laser treatment device.</p>
<heading id="h0003">2. <u>Description of Related Art</u></heading>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">A conventional medical handpiece comprises a waveguide (e.g., a fiber optic or trunk fiber) connected to a laser housing or module that provides electromagnetic (e.g., laser) energy that can be directed to a target surface such as bone or dental tissue by the handpiece in order to accomplish cutting of the tissue. <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a prior-art handpiece 100 comprising a waveguide 105 that receives laser energy from the laser housing. The energy is transmitted through a window 110 and is reflected from a 90-degree mirror 115. Energy reflected from the mirror 115 is directed to a tip or ferrule 120 that directs the laser energy to the target surface.</p>
<p id="p0003" num="0003"><figref idref="f0002">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref> illustrate isolated elements of handpieces generally similar to that of <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> and demonstrate representative prior-art designs of laser handpieces. <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates a device 200 comprising a waveguide 205 that emits laser energy and a flat window 210 through which the laser energy 212 is transmitted before reaching a concave reflector 215. Laser energy 217 reflected from the reflector 215 enters a tip 220 whence laser energy 222 output from the tip 220 may be directed to a target surface. Disadvantageously, the device 200 illustrated in <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> exhibits a diverging (e.g., spreading) of the laser energy 212 leaving the window 210. To the extent the concave reflector 215 may mitigate an effect of the spreading laser energy 212 by focusing the laser energy 217 entering the tip 220, such compensation in the example still does not provide an adequate net correction, as the tip 220 in the example continues to emit diverging laser energy 222.</p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">Considering <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 3</figref>, it illustrates a prior-art device 300 comprising a waveguide 305 and a convex lens 310 that may reduce a diverging effect of laser energy 307 at the pre-reflector stage, directing laser energy 312 onto a flat reflector 315 from which laser energy 317 is directed through a flat window or tip 320 thereby producing laser energy 322 that can be focused onto a target, typically a few millimeters in front of the window 320. The document <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="DE3800555A1"><text>DE 38 00 555 A1</text></patcit> relates to a laser ablation device with a focusing handpiece.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">In operation, each of the devices illustrated in <figref idref="f0001 f0002">FIGS. 1-3</figref> is typically disposed very near, or even touching, the target surface owing to a shape and/or distribution of the electromagnetic laser energy emitted from an emitting surface of the device. Accordingly, back reflection of components from the target including, for example, fluids, particles, debris, energy (e.g., pressure waves), power-beam and/or visible light can reach the emitting surface, thereby degrading performance of the laser device.</p>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">A need thus exists in the prior art for a design architecture of a medical laser handpiece that can attenuate or eliminate the mentioned performance degradation, and enhance a speed of cutting (e.g., provide high speed cutting) of biological tissue relative to the mentioned constructions. A further need exists for a more reliable system for delivering electromagnetic energy to a target surface at a distance (e.g., a distance greater than required by the mentioned conventional devices) from an emitting surface that minimizes, reduces and/or eliminates harmful and/or undesirable (e.g., user detectable and/or device degrading) back reflection.</p>
<heading id="h0004">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">The present invention addresses these needs by providing a handpiece for laser tissue cutting comprising a window that receives electromagnetic energy, and a reflector that redirects the electromagnetic energy received from the window to a tip, the tip directing the electromagnetic energy received from the reflector to a target surface (e.g., or other chosen vicinity, such as an "interaction zone" defined in the below-referenced Pat. <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="WO5574247A"><text>5,574,247</text></patcit>) at a distance (e.g., a selected distance) from an emitting surface of the tip. The selected distance is chosen to reduce back reflection of components from the target to the emitting surface to a level that negligibly impedes tissue cutting. An implementation herein disclosed focuses the electromagnetic energy directed to the target surface at the selected distance. One or more of the window, reflector, and tip may be adapted to provide a desired distribution of electromagnetic energy at the target surface (e.g., or other chosen vicinity). One or more of the window, reflector, and tip may be adapted to provide a desired disruption, as a consequence of, <i>inter alias,</i> the electromagnetic energy at the target surface.</p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">The emitting surface of the handpiece exhibits at least in part, and typically all of, the functionality of a converging lens.</p>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">The handpiece may comprise a fluid output adapted to emit fluid particles, whereby electromagnetic energy emitted from the emitting surface imparts energy into the fluid<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> -->particles to thereby apply disruptive forces to the target surface. Another handpiece includes a reference arm adapted to facilitate spacing of the tip from the target surface.</p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">Additional advantages and aspects of the present invention are apparent in the following detailed description and claims that follow.</p>
<heading id="h0005">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE FIGURES</heading>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li><figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a diagram of a prior-art laser handpiece;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic diagram of components of an example of a prior-art laser handpiece;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic diagram of components of another example of a prior-art laser handpiece;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 4</figref> is a schematic diagram of components of a laser handpiece;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 5A</figref> is a schematic diagram of an embodiment of a laser handpiece architecture;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 5B</figref> is a schematic diagram of components of another laser handpiece; and</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 6</figref> is a pictorial diagram of an embodiment of a laser handpiece incorporating a reference arm.</li>
</ul></p>
<heading id="h0006">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">Embodiments of the invention are now described and illustrated in the accompanying drawings. Use of like or the same reference designators in the drawings and description refers to the same, similar or analogous components and/or elements. Use of directional terms, such as, top, bottom, left, right, up, down, over, above, below, beneath, rear, and front, are to be construed literally. The present invention may be practiced in conjunction with various devices and techniques that are conventionally used in the art, and only so much of the commonly practiced process steps are included herein as are necessary to provide an understanding of the present invention. The present invention has applicability in the field of laser devices. For illustrative purposes, however, the following description pertains to a laser cutting device.</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">With reference to <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 4</figref>, depicted therein is a schematic diagram of components of a laser handpiece 400 comprising a waveguide 405,<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> which may be, for example, an optical fiber, that receives electromagnetic energy (e.g., laser energy) from a laser source (not shown). A laser beam 407, which comprises electromagnetic energy, may be emitted from the waveguide 405. A window 410 receives the laser beam 407 and may or may not shape the beam 407 into a modified laser beam 412 that impinges on a reflector 415. The reflector 415 may further modify the laser beam 412 to produce another laser beam 417 that is coupled to a tip 420.</p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">According to a feature of the present invention, the tip 420 modifies the laser beam 417. According to a further feature of the present invention, the tip 420, which typically may have a nominally cylindrical shape (but is not limited to such), operates as a lens to modify the laser beam 417. According to yet another feature of the present invention, the tip 420 converges the laser beam 417.</p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">In the illustrated example, the tip 420 emits a laser beam 422 having a minimum cross- sectional width or "waist" (cf. portion of laser beam 22 indicated by arrowhead tip of lead line 422). The part of laser beam 422 shown with the smallest cross-sectional width corresponds to the focal point or peak-concentration part of the laser beam 422, and may be directed to a target surface to accomplish relatively high-power or focused cutting of, for example, tissue.</p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">Many variations on the theme of the conceptual embodiment 400 may be designed by changing parameters of one or more of the window 410, the reflector 415, and the tip 420. <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 5A</figref> is a schematic diagram of one embodiment of a laser handpiece architecture. The illustrated embodiment comprises a waveguide 505 that may provide functionality as described <i>supra</i> with reference to the waveguide 405 in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 4</figref>. The window 410 in the embodiment of <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 4</figref> may be implemented as a window 510 in the embodiment of <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 5A</figref>. The window 510 may be formed of, for example, sapphire or glass transparent optical material, may or may not have an antireflective (AR) coating, and may be flat or lensed. Similarly, the reflector 415 in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 4</figref> may be implemented as a reflector 515 in the embodiment of <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 5A</figref>. The reflector 515 (e.g., a mirror) may be formed of, for example, metal, ceramic material, sapphire, gold or other highly reflective (HR) material coated or plated for maximum reflection. Exemplary shapes of the reflector 515 may include flat, toroidal, parabolic, and the like. For instance, in modified embodiments the reflector may resemble either of those shown in <figref idref="f0001">FIGS. 1</figref> or <figref idref="f0002">2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">The tip 420 of <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 4</figref> may be implemented as a tip 520 (that may be, for instance, a window) formed, for example, as a nominally cylindrical structure of, for example, one or more of sapphire and low OH glass. A typical tip 520 may be (but is not limited to) a non-coated<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> construction, and/or may have biconvex shapes 519 and 521 as illustrated. Representative dimensions of the tip 520 may include a length ranging from about 2 mm to about 5 mm with a diameter ranging from about 1 mm to about 3 mm.</p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018"><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 5B</figref> illustrates another variation on the theme of <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 4</figref>, the embodiment of <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 4</figref> being similar the embodiment of <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 5B</figref> with elements that evidently correspond to those of the embodiment of <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 4</figref>. The embodiment of <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 5B</figref> differs in that a single convex surface 621 is provided on an output of a tip 620, the input to the tip being implemented as a flat surface 619.</p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">With continuing reference to the embodiments illustrated in <figref idref="f0003">FIGS. 5A and 5B</figref>, the embodiments may generate output laser beams 522 and 622 that exhibit a minimum width portion or "waist" that can be designed to have specified dimensions (e.g., a distance from the tip 520/620 and/or a beam diameter at the waist) according to shapes and/or materials chosen for one or more of the window 510/610, the reflector 515/615, and the tip 520/620 in respective <figref idref="f0003">FIGS. 5A and 5B</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">Control of parameters of the waist can allow an improvement in high speed cutting of biological tissues (e.g., soft tissue, hard tissue, bone and/or hard tooth tissue) as compared with prior-art laser handpieces. Significantly increased reliability of the illustrated delivery systems (e.g., handpieces 500/600) due to an attenuation or complete absence of contact (e.g., direct contact), between the tip 521/621 (e.g., the emitting surface 521/621 of the tip) and target tissue, whereby, for example, a relatively long distance (e.g., 5 or more, or, alternatively, 6 to 10 mm), between the output-tip emitting surface and the cutting tissue plane (i.e., between the emitting surface and the waist), can be created. For instance, a relatively great distance (e.g., more than 5 mm), between the output-tip emitting surface and the cutting tissue plane, can advantageously or substantially reduce an amount of back reflection of, e.g., the power beam, back into the fiber emitting surface.</p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">One or more of these described effects on the beam path can be achieved by way of the new design of optical element(s) within the handpiece as described herein. The design(s) target the achievement of one or more of high density and uniformity (i.e., an about uniform cross-section) of electromagnetic energy (e.g., laser) power at a selected and controlled distance from output tip emitting surface. Another feature is to increase depth (e.g., to the target surface), wherein laser high-power density is kept relatively consistent at the increased depth.</p>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">Designs of laser handpieces as described utilize converging-beam shapes and/or functions at or adjacent to the emitting surface of the output tip. Thus, the present handpiece<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> incorporates a modification of the shape of the emitting surface. Designs of laser handpieces additionally and/or alternatively, may modify one, more than one, or all, of the other surfaces of the three optical elements (window, mirror and tip) to achieve, modify, control, and/or enhance the converging-beam function. In all, or at least certain, combination(s), the interrelation of the surfaces operate to achieve rapid, non-contact (i.e., without direct contact between the output tip and tissue, or with increased-spacing) cutting. According to a contemplated configuration, a relatively long distance (e.g., 5 or more mm) can be maintained between the emitting surface of the output tip and the cutting tissue plane, thereby measurably, substantially, advantageously, and/or dramatically reducing the effect of back reflection of components (e.g., fluids, particles, debris, energy, power-beam and/or visible light) to or into emitting surface(s), the reflection of which may impede tissue cutting.</p>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">An output tip is provided with an emitting surface that resembles and/or replicates a shape and/or functionality of a lens (e.g., that has a convex emitting surface 621 as shown in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 5B</figref>), and that provides one, more or all of the herein described advantages. The energy output of the handpiece can, consequently, provide, for example, a desired beam distribution (e.g., with the beam focus point or the peak concentration of the beam) at the cutting area. The cutting area can be spaced, for example, about 4 to about 10 mm, or, in particular and/or preferred examples, about 5 to about 7 mm, from the emitting surface. All three optical elements can be designed, in various combinations, to provide the desired beam distribution (e.g., a beam focus and/or a peak concentration of the beam) at the predetermined distances.</p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">In a typical implementation, such as illustrated in <figref idref="f0003">FIGS. 5A or 5B</figref>, the output tip 520/620 is first constructed to have an output surface 521/621 in a shape of, and/or with the functionality of, a lens, and, subsequently, one or more of other surfaces (e.g., five surfaces including output end of trunk fiber, i.e., waveguide 505/605, surfaces of window 510/610 and reflector 515/615, and input 519/619 of tip 520/620), are designed to possess, e.g., one or more of a flat and a curved surface.</p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">One of possible combinations is to keep the window 510 not changed, make the reflector 515 (e.g., 90-degree mirror) flat and add convex surfaces 519 and 521 to both ends of the output tip 520 (<figref idref="f0003">FIG. 5A</figref>). These choices may allow creating a beam waist having a diameter nearly the same as the diameter of the original fiber, i.e., waveguide 505, at a certain (e.g., predefined, e.g., 5, 6 or 7 mm) distance away from the tip surface. In addition, that implementation may allow maintenance of a relatively high power density (e.g., and/or of no, or no significant, variation) at the certain distance (e.g., around the<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> beam waist).</p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">According to one feature of the present invention, the output tip is interchangeable to allow switching between different output tips for functionality variation (e.g., of a converging characteristic performed on the beam, such as a change of the selected distance where the "waist" occurs and/or the width and/or cross-sectional shape and/or power density of the waist) and/or for cleaning <i>I</i> autoclaving. It is an advantage and difference compared to prior art (with protective window).</p>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">According to another feature as illustrated in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 6</figref>, as the tip is non-contact and works at a predetermined distance above the tissue, an embodiment of the laser handpiece is formed to include a reference arm 715, which is affixed to a housing 705 that supports a tip (not shown) within tip ferrule 710 (cf. tip ferrule of <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>) of a handpiece 700. The reference arm added to the design may comprise a straight, curved, spiral, or any other shape or shapes (e.g., of an elongate member or members) for facilitating spacing of the tip 710 from the tissue. The reference arm provides a visible and "feelable" reference to the location of the cutting area of the laser beam and/or a bottom of a cavity created by the cutting.</p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">The electromagnetic energy emitted by the handpiece may comprise laser energy and/or visible light and may operate to provide or promote one or more of cutting, ablating, desterilization, bacterial reduction, biostimulation (e.g., low-level light therapy), coagulation, remodeling, caries detection or treatment, and illumination (e.g., with visible light).</p>
<p id="p0029" num="0029">In certain implementations, the electromagnetic energy can comprise one or more of an electromagnetic energy source of ablation, and/or an electromagnetic energy source of illumination, and/or an electromagnetic energy source of tissue disruption, and/or an electromagnetic energy source of biostimulation.</p>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">The target surface may comprise, for example, one or more of tooth tissue, bone, cartilage and soft tissue such as skin or nasal-cavity tissue.</p>
<p id="p0031" num="0031">According to certain aspects, the energy output can comprise one or more of hard-tissue ablating electromagnetic energy, low-level light therapy (LLLT) electromagnetic energy, tissue-biostimulation electromagnetic energy, visible electromagnetic energy, coherent light, one or more of a wavelength within a range from about 2.69 to about 2.80 microns and a wavelength of about 2.94 microns, and electromagnetic energy generated by one or more of an Er:YAG laser, an Er:YSGG laser, an Er, a Cr:YSGG laser and a CTE:YAG laser.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032">In one implementation, a structure (e.g., cannula(s) or orifice(s)) can be configured to direct liquid in a direction toward the distal end of the output tip. For example, a fluid can be routed distally along an outer surface (e.g., the entire or substantially the entire outer surface, near the distal end) of the output tip.</p>
<p id="p0033" num="0033">In another implementation, fluid may be supplied through one or more gaps disposed between an outer surface of the waveguide (e.g., fiber optic) and the interior surface of a cannula. The fluid can be a liquid or may comprise a combination of liquid and gas. In certain implementations, the liquid is or comprises water, and in other implementations it is or comprises both air and water which, for example, can be mixed together either before or within the gap. For example, the fluid can comprise atomized fluid particles formed from a mixture of pressurized air and water and delivered through the gap to exit from the fluid output.</p>
<p id="p0034" num="0034">A volume between the tissue ablating and/or tissue-treating distal end and the distal end of a cannula (e.g., holding the output tip and one, more, or all of the other operating components of the handpiece, in which case the handpiece is not a handpiece but rather is an intra-luminal, lipo, orjoint surgery device) can be transparent to a wavelength of energy emitted from the source of electromagnetic energy. According to another implementation, in addition to or as an alternative to the preceding features, a volume between (a) the tissue ablating and/or tissue- treating distal end and (b) the distal end of the cannula does not obstruct atomized fluid particles traveling in the direction from the fluid output to the distal end of the cannula. According to yet another implementation, in addition to or as an alternative to any one or more features set forth in this paragraph, a volume between (a) the tissue ablating and/or tissue-treating distal end and (b) the target surface is not obstructed by any part of the apparatus.</p>
<p id="p0035" num="0035">According to other implementations, the apparatus can comprise a fluid output that is configured to emit fluid in a vicinity of the distal end of the apparatus, wherein: the fluid output comprises an atomizer configured to place atomized fluid particles into a volume above the target surface. Further, the electromagnetic energy waveguide is configured to impart relatively large amounts of energy into the atomized fluid particles in the volume above the target surface to thereby expand the atomized fluid particles and impart disruptive forces onto the target surface.</p>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">According to another aspect, a medical handpiece includes a handpiece housing and a source of electromagnetic energy disposed within the handpiece housing and adapted for emitting electromagnetic energy from a distal end of the handpiece<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> housing. An illumination source is disposed within the handpiece housing for projecting light from the distal end of the handpiece housing onto a target surface. The illumination source may include a fiber optic bundle. A medication line may also be disposed within the handpiece housing for outputting medication through a distal end of the handpiece housing onto a target surface.</p>
<p id="p0037" num="0037">According to certain implementations, laser energy from the trunk fiber is output from a power or treatment fiber, and is directed, for example, into fluid (e.g., an air and/or water spray or an atomized distribution of fluid particles from a water connection and/or a spray connection near an output end of a handpiece) that is emitted from a fluid output of a handpiece above a target surface (e.g., one or more of tooth, bone, cartilage and soft tissue). The fluid output may comprise a plurality of fluid outputs, concentrically arranged around a power fiber, as described in, for example, App. <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="WO11042824A"><text>11/042,824</text></patcit> and Prov. App. <patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="WO60601415A"><text>60/601,415</text></patcit>. The power or treatment fiber may be coupled to an electromagnetic energy source comprising one or more of a wavelength within a range from about 2.69 to about 2.80 microns and a wavelength of about 2.94 microns. In certain implementations the power fiber may be coupled to one or more of an Er:YAG laser, an Er:YSGG laser, an Er, Cr:YSGG laser and a CTE:YAG laser, and in particular instances may be coupled to one of an Er, Cr:YSGG solid state laser having a wavelength of about 2.789 microns and an Er:YAG solid state laser having a wavelength of about 2.940 microns. An apparatus including corresponding structure for directing electromagnetic energy into an atomized distribution of fluid particles above a target surface is disclosed, for example, in the below-referenced Pat. <patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="WO5574247A"><text>5,574,247</text></patcit>, which describes the impartation of laser energy into fluid particles to thereby apply disruptive forces to the target surface.</p>
<p id="p0038" num="0038">By way of the disclosure herein, a laser assembly has been described that can output electromagnetic radiation useful to diagnose, monitor and/or affect a target surface. In the case of procedures using fiber optic tip radiation, a probe can include one or more power or treatment fibers for transmitting treatment radiation to a target surface for treating (e.g., ablating) a dental structure, such as within a canal. In any of the embodiments described herein, the light for illumination and/or diagnostics may be transmitted simultaneously with, or intermittently with or separate from, transmission of treatment radiation and/or of the fluid from the fluid output or outputs.</p>
<p id="p0039" num="0039">Corresponding or related structure and methods are described in the following patents assigned to Biolase Technology, Inc.</p>
<p id="p0040" num="0040">Such patents include, but are not limited to Pat. <patcit id="pcit0006" dnum="WO7578622A"><text>7,578,622</text></patcit> entitled Contra-angle<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> rotating handpiece having tactile-feedback tip ferrule; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0007" dnum="WO7575381A"><text>7,575,381</text></patcit> entitled Fiber tip detector apparatus and related methods; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0008" dnum="WO7563226A"><text>7,563,226</text></patcit> entitled Handpieces having illumination and laser outputs; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0009" dnum="WO7467946A"><text>7,467,946</text></patcit> entitled Electromagnetic radiation emitting toothbrush and dentifrice system; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0010" dnum="WO7461982A"><text>7,461,982</text></patcit> entitled Contra-angle rotating handpiece having tactile-feedback tip ferrule; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0011" dnum="WO7461658A"><text>7,461,658</text></patcit> entitled Methods for treating eye conditions; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0012" dnum="WO7458380A"><text>7,458,380</text></patcit> entitled Methods for treating eye conditions; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0013" dnum="WO7424199A"><text>7,424,199</text></patcit> entitled Fiber tip fluid output device; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0014" dnum="WO7421186A"><text>7,421,186</text></patcit> entitled Modified-output fiber optic tips; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0015" dnum="WO7415050A"><text>7,415,050</text></patcit> entitled Electromagnetic energy distributions for electromagnetically induced mechanical cutting; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0016" dnum="WO7384419A"><text>7,384,419</text></patcit> entitled Tapered fused waveguide for delivering treatment electromagnetic radiation toward a target surface; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0017" dnum="WO7356208A"><text>7,356,208</text></patcit> entitled Fiber detector apparatus and related methods; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0018" dnum="WO7320594A"><text>7,320,594</text></patcit> entitled Fluid and laser system; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0019" dnum="WO7303397A"><text>7,303,397</text></patcit> entitled Caries detection using timing differentials between excitation and return pulses; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0020" dnum="WO7292759A"><text>7,292,759</text></patcit> entitled Contra-angle rotating handpiece having tactile-feedback tip ferrule; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0021" dnum="WO7290940A"><text>7,290,940</text></patcit> entitled Fiber tip detector apparatus and related methods; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0022" dnum="WO7288086A"><text>7,288,086</text></patcit> entitled High-efficiency, side-pumped diode laser system; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0023" dnum="WO7270657A"><text>7,270,657</text></patcit> entitled Radiation emitting apparatus with spatially controllable output energy distributions; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0024" dnum="WO7261558A"><text>7,261,558</text></patcit> entitled Electromagnetic radiation emitting toothbrush and dentifrice system; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0025" dnum="WO7194180A"><text>7,194,180</text></patcit> entitled Fiber detector apparatus and related methods; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0026" dnum="WO7187822A"><text>7,187,822</text></patcit> entitled Fiber tip fluid output device; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0027" dnum="WO7144249A"><text>7,144,249</text></patcit> entitled Device for dental care and whitening; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0028" dnum="WO7108693A"><text>7,108,693</text></patcit> entitled Electromagnetic energy distributions for electromagnetically induced mechanical cutting; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0029" dnum="WO7068912A"><text>7,068,912</text></patcit> entitled Fiber detector apparatus and related methods; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0030" dnum="WO6942658A"><text>6,942,658</text></patcit> entitled Radiation emitting apparatus with spatially controllable output energy distributions; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0031" dnum="WO6829427A"><text>6,829,427</text></patcit> entitled Fiber detector apparatus and related methods; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0032" dnum="WO6821272A"><text>6,821,272</text></patcit> entitled Electromagnetic energy distributions for electromagnetically induced cutting; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0033" dnum="WO6744790A"><text>6,744,790</text></patcit> entitled Device for reduction of thermal lensing; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0034" dnum="WO6669685A"><text>6,669,685</text></patcit> entitled Tissue remover and method; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0035" dnum="WO6616451A"><text>6,616,451</text></patcit> entitled Electromagnetic radiation emitting toothbrush and dentifrice system; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0036" dnum="WO6616447A"><text>6,616,447</text></patcit> entitled Device for dental care and whitening; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0037" dnum="WO6610053A"><text>6,610,053</text></patcit> entitled Methods of using atomized particles for electromagnetically induced cutting; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0038" dnum="WO6567582A"><text>6,567,582</text></patcit> entitled Fiber tip fluid output device; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0039" dnum="WO6561803A"><text>6,561,803</text></patcit> entitled Fluid conditioning system; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0040" dnum="WO6544256A"><text>6,544,256</text></patcit> entitled Electromagnetically induced cutting with atomized fluid particles for dermatological applications; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0041" dnum="WO6533775A"><text>6,533,775</text></patcit> entitled Light-activated hair treatment and removal device; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0042" dnum="WO6389193A"><text>6,389,193</text></patcit> entitled Rotating handpiece; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0043" dnum="WO6350123A"><text>6,350,123</text></patcit> entitled Fluid conditioning system; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0044" dnum="WO6288499A"><text>6,288,499</text></patcit> entitled Electromagnetic energy distributions for electromagnetically induced<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> mechanical cutting; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0045" dnum="WO6254597A"><text>6,254,597</text></patcit> entitled Tissue remover and method; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0046" dnum="WO6231567A"><text>6,231,567</text></patcit> entitled Material remover and method; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0047" dnum="WO6086367A"><text>6,086,367</text></patcit> entitled Dental and medical procedures employing laser radiation; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0048" dnum="WO5968037A"><text>5,968,037</text></patcit> entitled User programmable combination of atomized particles for electromagnetically induced cutting; Pat. <patcit id="pcit0049" dnum="WO5785521A"><text>5,785,521</text></patcit> entitled Fluid conditioning system; and Pat. <patcit id="pcit0050" dnum="WO5741247A"><text>5,741,247</text></patcit> entitled Atomized fluid particles for electromagnetically induced cutting.</p>
<p id="p0041" num="0041">Also, the above disclosure is intended to be operable or modifiable to be operable, in whole or in part, with corresponding or related structure and methods, in whole or in part, described in the following published applications, which applications are listed as follows: App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0051" dnum="WO20090225060A"><text>20090225060</text></patcit> entitled Wrist-mounted laser with animated, page-based graphical user-interface; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0052" dnum="WO20090143775A"><text>20090143775</text></patcit> entitled Medical laser having controlled-temperature and sterilized fluid output; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0053" dnum="WO20090141752A"><text>20090141752</text></patcit> entitled Dual pulse-width medical laser with presets; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0054" dnum="WO20090105707A"><text>20090105707</text></patcit> entitled Drill and flavored fluid particles combination; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0055" dnum="WO20090104580A"><text>20090104580</text></patcit> entitled Fluid and pulsed energy output system; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0056" dnum="WO20090076490A"><text>20090076490</text></patcit> entitled Fiber tip fluid output device; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0057" dnum="WO20090075229A"><text>20090075229</text></patcit> entitled Probes and biofluids for treating and removing deposits from tissue surfaces; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0058" dnum="WO20090067189A"><text>20090067189</text></patcit> entitled Contra- angle rotating handpiece having tactile-feedback tip ferrule; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0059" dnum="WO20090062779A"><text>20090062779</text></patcit> entitled Methods for treating eye conditions with low-level light therapy; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0060" dnum="WO20090056044A"><text>20090056044</text></patcit> entitled Electromagnetic radiation emitting toothbrush and dentifrice system; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0061" dnum="WO20090043364A"><text>20090043364</text></patcit> entitled Electromagnetic energy distributions for Electromagnetically induced mechanical cutting; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0062" dnum="WO20090042171A"><text>20090042171</text></patcit> entitled Fluid controllable laser endodontic cleaning and disinfecting system; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0063" dnum="WO20090035717A"><text>20090035717</text></patcit> entitled Electromagnetic radiation emitting toothbrush and transparent dentifrice system; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0064" dnum="WO20090031515A"><text>20090031515</text></patcit> entitled Transparent dentifrice for use with electromagnetic radiation emitting toothbrush system; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0065" dnum="WO20080317429A"><text>20080317429</text></patcit> entitled Modified-output fiber optic tips; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0066" dnum="WO20080276192A"><text>20080276192</text></patcit> entitled Method and apparatus for controlling an electromagnetic energy output system; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0067" dnum="WO20080240172A"><text>20080240172</text></patcit> entitled Radiation emitting apparatus with spatially controllable output energy distributions; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0068" dnum="WO20080221558A"><text>20080221558</text></patcit> entitled Multiple fiber-type tissue treatment device and related method; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0069" dnum="WO20080219629A"><text>20080219629</text></patcit> entitled Modified-output fiber optic tips; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0070" dnum="WO20080212624A"><text>20080212624</text></patcit> entitled Dual pulse-width medical laser; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0071" dnum="WO20080203280A"><text>20080203280</text></patcit> entitled Target-close electromagnetic energy emitting device; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0072" dnum="WO20080181278A"><text>20080181278</text></patcit> entitled Electromagnetic energy output system; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0073" dnum="WO20080181261A"><text>20080181261</text></patcit> entitled Electromagnetic energy output system; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0074" dnum="WO20080157690A"><text>20080157690</text></patcit> entitled Electromagnetic energy distributions for<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> electromagnetically induced mechanical cutting; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0075" dnum="WO20080151953A"><text>20080151953</text></patcit> entitled Electromagnet energy distributions for electromagnetically induced mechanical cutting; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0076" dnum="WO20080138764A"><text>20080138764</text></patcit> entitled Fluid and laser system; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0077" dnum="WO20080125677A"><text>20080125677</text></patcit> entitled Methods for treating hyperopia and presbyopia via laser tunneling; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0078" dnum="WO20080125676A"><text>20080125676</text></patcit> entitled Methods for treating hyperopia and presbyopia via laser tunneling; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0079" dnum="WO20080097418A"><text>20080097418</text></patcit> entitled Methods for treating eye conditions; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0080" dnum="WO20080097417A"><text>20080097417</text></patcit> entitled Methods for treating eye conditions; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0081" dnum="WO20080097416A"><text>20080097416</text></patcit> entitled Methods for treating eye conditions; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0082" dnum="WO20080070185A"><text>20080070185</text></patcit> entitled Caries detection using timing differentials between excitation and return pulses; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0083" dnum="WO20080069172A"><text>20080069172</text></patcit> entitled Electromagnetic energy distributions for electromagnetically induced mechanical cutting; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0084" dnum="WO20080065057A"><text>20080065057</text></patcit> entitled High-efficiency, side-pumped diode laser system; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0085" dnum="WO20080065055A"><text>20080065055</text></patcit> entitled Methods for treating eye conditions; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0086" dnum="WO20080065054A"><text>20080065054</text></patcit> entitled Methods for treating hyperopia and presbyopia via laser tunneling; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0087" dnum="WO20080065053A"><text>20080065053</text></patcit> entitled Methods for treating eye conditions; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0088" dnum="WO20080033411A"><text>20080033411</text></patcit> entitled High efficiency electromagnetic laser energy cutting device; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0089" dnum="WO20080033409A"><text>20080033409</text></patcit> entitled Methods for treating eye conditions; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0090" dnum="WO20080033407A"><text>20080033407</text></patcit> entitled Methods for treating eye conditions; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0091" dnum="WO20080025675A"><text>20080025675</text></patcit> entitled Fiber tip detector apparatus and related methods; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0092" dnum="WO20080025672A"><text>20080025672</text></patcit> entitled Contra-angle rotating handpiece having tactile-feedback tip ferrule; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0093" dnum="WO20080025671A"><text>20080025671</text></patcit> entitled Contra-angle rotating handpiece having tactile-feedback tip ferrule; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0094" dnum="WO20070298369A"><text>20070298369</text></patcit> entitled Electromagnetic radiation emitting toothbrush and dentifrice system; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0095" dnum="WO20070263975A"><text>20070263975</text></patcit> entitled Modified-output fiber optic tips; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0096" dnum="WO20070258693A"><text>20070258693</text></patcit> entitled Fiber detector apparatus and related methods; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0097" dnum="WO20070208404A"><text>20070208404</text></patcit> entitled Tissue treatment device and method; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0098" dnum="WO20070208328A"><text>20070208328</text></patcit> entitled Contra-angel rotating handpiece having tactile-feedback tip ferrule; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0099" dnum="WO20070190482A"><text>20070190482</text></patcit> entitled Fluid conditioning system; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0100" dnum="WO20070184402A"><text>20070184402</text></patcit> entitled Caries detection using real-time imaging and multiple excitation frequencies; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0101" dnum="WO20070128576A"><text>20070128576</text></patcit> entitled Output attachments coded for use with electromagnetic-energy procedural device; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0102" dnum="WO20070104419A"><text>20070104419</text></patcit> entitled Fiber tip fluid output device; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0103" dnum="WO20070060917A"><text>20070060917</text></patcit> entitled High-efficiency, side-pumped diode laser system; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0104" dnum="WO20070059660A"><text>20070059660</text></patcit> entitled Device for dental care and whitening; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0105" dnum="WO20070054236A"><text>20070054236</text></patcit> entitled Device for dental care and whitening; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0106" dnum="WO20070054235A"><text>20070054235</text></patcit> entitled Device for dental care and whitening; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0107" dnum="WO20070054233A"><text>20070054233</text></patcit> entitled Device for dental care and whitening; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0108" dnum="WO20070042315A"><text>20070042315</text></patcit> entitled Visual feedback implements for electromagnetic energy output devices; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0109" dnum="WO20070016176A"><text>20070016176</text></patcit> entitled Laser handpiece<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> architecture and methods; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0110" dnum="WO20070014517A"><text>20070014517</text></patcit> entitled Electromagnetic energy emitting device with increased spot size; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0111" dnum="WO20070014322A"><text>20070014322</text></patcit> entitled Electromagnetic energy distributions for electromagnetically induced mechanical cutting; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0112" dnum="WO20070009856A"><text>20070009856</text></patcit> entitled Device having activated textured surfaces for treating oral tissue; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0113" dnum="WO20070003604A"><text>20070003604</text></patcit> entitled Tissue coverings bearing customized tissue images; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0114" dnum="WO20060281042A"><text>20060281042</text></patcit> entitled Electromagnetic radiation emitting toothbrush and dentifrice system; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0115" dnum="WO20060275016A"><text>20060275016</text></patcit> entitled Contra- angle rotating handpiece having tactile-feedback tip ferrule; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0116" dnum="WO20060241574A"><text>20060241574</text></patcit> entitled Electromagnetic energy distributions for electromagnetically induced disruptive cutting; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0117" dnum="WO20060240381A"><text>20060240381</text></patcit> entitled Fluid conditioning system; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0118" dnum="WO20060210228A"><text>20060210228</text></patcit> entitled Fiber detector apparatus and related methods; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0119" dnum="WO20060204203A"><text>20060204203</text></patcit> entitled Radiation emitting apparatus with spatially controllable output energy distributions; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0120" dnum="WO20060142745A"><text>20060142745</text></patcit> entitled Dual pulse-width medical laser with presets; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0121" dnum="WO20060142744A"><text>20060142744</text></patcit> entitled Identification connector for a medical laser handpiece; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0122" dnum="WO20060142743A"><text>20060142743</text></patcit> entitled Medical laser having controlled-temperature and sterilized fluid output; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0123" dnum="WO20060126680A"><text>20060126680</text></patcit> entitled Dual pulse-width medical laser; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0124" dnum="WO20060099548A"><text>20060099548</text></patcit> entitled Caries detection using timing differentials between excitation and return pulses; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0125" dnum="WO20060083466A"><text>20060083466</text></patcit> entitled Fiber tip detector apparatus and related methods; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0126" dnum="WO20060043903A"><text>20060043903</text></patcit> entitled Electromagnetic energy distributions for electromagnetically induced mechanical cutting; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0127" dnum="WO20050283143A"><text>20050283143</text></patcit> entitled Tissue remover and method; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0128" dnum="WO20050281887A"><text>20050281887</text></patcit> entitled Fluid conditioning system; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0129" dnum="WO20050281530A"><text>20050281530</text></patcit> entitled Modified-output fiber optic tips; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0130" dnum="WO20050256517A"><text>20050256517</text></patcit> entitled Electromagnetically induced treatment devices and methods; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0131" dnum="WO20050256516A"><text>20050256516</text></patcit> entitled Illumination device and related methods; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0132" dnum="WO20040106082A"><text>20040106082</text></patcit> entitled Device for dental care and whitening; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0133" dnum="WO20040092925A"><text>20040092925</text></patcit> entitled Methods of using atomized particles for electromagnetically induced cutting; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0134" dnum="WO20040091834A"><text>20040091834</text></patcit> entitled Electromagnetic radiation emitting toothbrush and dentifrice system; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0135" dnum="WO20040068256A"><text>20040068256</text></patcit> entitled Tissue remover and method; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0136" dnum="WO20030228094A"><text>20030228094</text></patcit> entitled Fiber tip fluid output device; App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0137" dnum="WO20020149324A"><text>20020149324</text></patcit> entitled Electromagnetic energy distributions for electromagnetically induced mechanical cutting; and App. Pub. <patcit id="pcit0138" dnum="WO20020014855A"><text>20020014855</text></patcit> entitled Electromagnetic energy distributions for electromagnetically induced mechanical cutting.</p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> -->
<claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>A handpiece (600, 700) for laser treating a tissue target surface, comprising:
<claim-text>a housing (705);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a waveguide (605) configured and arranged to receive electromagnetic energy from a laser source;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a window (610) configured and arranged to receive the electromagnetic energy from the waveguide (605) and output electromagnetic energy;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an output tip (620, 710);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a reflector (615) aligned to redirect electromagnetic energy to the output tip (620, 710), wherein the reflector (615) is configured to redirect electromagnetic energy received from the window (610), wherein the output tip (620, 710) comprises an emitting surface (621) configured and arranged to receive and converge electromagnetic energy received from the reflector (615) and focus it at a selected and controlled distance,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the selected distance is chosen to reduce back reflection of components from the target to the emitting surface to a level that negligibly impedes tissue cutting; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a reference arm (715) affixed to the housing, the reference arm (715) being configured and arranged to provide a visible and feelable reference to the location of the cutting area of the laser beam for facilitating spacing of the output tip (620; 710) from the tissue so that the output tip (620; 710) can work at the selected distance above the tissue.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>The handpiece as set forth in claim 1, wherein:<br/>
one or more of the window (610), reflector (615), and tip (620, 710) are adapted to provide a desired distribution of electromagnetic energy at the target surface.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>The handpiece as set forth in claim 1 or 2, further comprising a fluid output adapted to emit fluid particles, whereby electromagnetic energy emitted from the emitting surface (621) can impart energy into the fluid particles to thereby apply disruptive forces to the target surface.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>The handpiece as set forth in any one of claims 1 to 3, wherein the output tip (620, 710) is interchangeable and the handpiece further comprises a plurality of output tips (620, 710) having different beam-converging characteristics.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>The handpiece as set forth in any one of claims 1 to 4, wherein:
<claim-text>the window (610) comprises sapphire or glass transparent optical material;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the reflector (615) comprises metal, ceramic material, or sapphire and has a flat, toroidal, or parabolic shape; and<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>the output tip (620, 710) comprises sapphire or glass and has an approximately cylindrical shape.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>The handpiece as set forth in any one of claims 1 to 5, wherein the output tip (620, 710) has a length ranging from about 2 mm to about 5 mm.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>The handpiece as set forth in any one of claims 1 to 6, wherein the output tip (620, 710) has a diameter ranging from about 1 mm to about 3 mm.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>The handpiece as set forth in any one of claims 1 to 7, wherein the emitting surface (621) of the output tip (620, 710) provides the functionality of a lens.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>The handpiece as set forth in any one of claims 1 to 8, wherein the emitting surface (621) comprises a convex lens.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>The handpiece as set forth in any one of claim 1 to 9, wherein a reflecting surface of the reflector (615) has a flat shape.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>The handpiece as set forth in any one of claims 1 to 10, wherein the handpiece is configured such that electromagnetic energy directed to the tissue target surface is focused at the selected distance, which ranges from about 5 mm to about 10 mm.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims02" lang="de"><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> -->
<claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Handstück (600, 700) zur Laserbehandlung einer Gewebezielfläche, aufweisend:
<claim-text>ein Gehäuse (705);</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Wellenleiter (605), welcher eingerichtet und ausgebildet ist,</claim-text>
<claim-text>elektromagnetische Energie von einer Laserquelle zu erhalten;</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Fenster (610), welches eingerichtet und ausgebildet ist, die elektromagnetische Energie von dem Wellenleiter (605) zu erhalten und</claim-text>
<claim-text>elektromagnetische Energie auszugeben;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Ausgangsspitze (620, 710);</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Reflektor (615), welcher ausgerichtet ist, elektromagnetische Energie zu der Ausgangsspitze (620, 710) umzulenken, wobei der Reflektor (615) eingerichtet ist, elektromagnetische Energie, welche von dem Fenster (610) erhalten worden ist, umzulenken, wobei die Ausgangsspitze (620, 710) eine Emissionsfläche (621) aufweist, welche eingerichtet und ausgebildet ist,</claim-text>
<claim-text>elektromagnetische Energie, welche von dem Reflektor (615) erhalten worden ist, zu erhalten und zu konvergieren und sie auf eine ausgewählte und kontrollierte Distanz zu fokussieren,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei die ausgewählte Distanz gewählt ist, Rückreflektion von Komponenten des Ziels zu der Emissionsfläche auf ein Level zu reduzieren, welches Schneiden von Gewebe vernachlässigbar behindert; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Referenzarm (715), welcher an dem Gehäuse angebracht ist, wobei der Referenzarm (715) eingerichtet und ausgebildet ist, eine sichtbare und spürbare Referenz zu der Position des Schneidebereichs des Laserstrahls bereitzustellen,</claim-text>
<claim-text>um Beabstandung der Ausgangsspitze (620; 710) von dem Gewebe zu erleichtern, sodass die Ausgangsspitze (620; 710) bei der ausgewählten Distanz über dem Gewebe arbeiten kann.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Handstück nach Anspruch 1, wobei:<br/>
eines oder mehrere von dem Fenster (610), Reflektor (615) und der Spitze (620, 710) adaptiert sind, eine gewünschte Verteilung von elektromagnetischer Energie auf der Zielfläche bereitzustellen.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Handstück nach Anspruch 1 oder 2, ferner einen Fluidausgang aufweisend, welcher adaptiert ist, Fluidpartikel zu emittieren, wobei elektromagnetische Energie, welche von der Emissionsfläche (621) emittiert wird, Energie in die Fluidpartikel vermitteln kann, um dadurch disruptive Kräfte auf die Zielfläche anzuwenden.<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Handstück nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 3, wobei die Ausgangsspitze (620, 710) auswechselbar ist und das Handstück ferner eine Vielzahl von Ausgangsspitzen (620, 710) aufweist, welche unterschiedliche Strahlkonvergierende Charakteristiken haben.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Handstück nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 4, wobei:
<claim-text>das Fenster (610) transparentes optisches Saphir- oder Glas-Material aufweist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>der Reflektor (615) Metall, keramisches Material oder Saphir aufweist und eine flache, toroidale oder parabolische Form hat; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>die Ausgangsspitze (620, 710) Saphir oder Glas aufweist und eine in etwa zylindrische Form hat.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Handstück nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 5, wobei die Ausgangsspitze (620, 710) eine Länge im Bereich von etwa 2 mm bis etwa 5 mm hat.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Handstück nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 6, wobei die Ausgangsspitze (620, 710) einen Durchmesser im Bereich von etwa 1 mm bis etwa 3 mm hat.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>Handstück nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 7, wobei die Emissionsfläche (621) der Ausgangsspitze (620, 710) die Funktionalität einer Linse bereitstellt.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>Handstück nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 8, wobei die Emissionsfläche (621) eine konvexe Linse aufweist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>Handstück nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 9, wobei eine reflektierende Fläche des Reflektors (615) eine flache Form hat.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>Handstück nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 10, wobei das Handstück eingerichtet ist, sodass elektromagnetische Energie, welche auf die Gewebezielfläche gerichtet ist, auf die ausgewählte Distanz fokussiert wird, welche von etwa 5 mm bis etwa 10 mm reicht.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims03" lang="fr"><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> -->
<claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Pièce à main (600, 700) pour traiter au laser une surface cible de tissu, comprenant :
<claim-text>un boîtier (705) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un guide d'ondes (605) configuré et agencé pour recevoir une énergie électromagnétique d'une source laser;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une fenêtre (610) configurée et agencée pour recevoir l'énergie électromagnétique en provenance du guide d'ondes (605) et délivrer une énergie électromagnétique en sortie ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une pointe de sortie (620, 710) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un réflecteur (615) aligné pour rediriger une énergie électromagnétique vers la pointe de sortie (620, 710),</claim-text>
<claim-text>le réflecteur (615) étant configuré pour rediriger une énergie électromagnétique reçue en provenance de la fenêtre (610), la pointe de sortie (620, 710) comprenant une surface d'émission (621) configurée et agencée pour recevoir et faire converger une énergie électromagnétique reçue en provenance du réflecteur (615) et la focaliser à une distance sélectionnée et commandée,</claim-text>
<claim-text>la distance sélectionnée étant choisie pour réduire la rétro-réflexion de composants de la cible vers la surface d'émission à un niveau qui empêche de manière négligeable la découpe de tissus ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un bras de référence (715) fixé au boîtier, le bras de référence (715) étant configuré et agencé pour fournir une référence visible et palpable à l'emplacement de la zone de coupe du faisceau laser pour faciliter l'espacement de la pointe de sortie (620 ; 710) du tissu de sorte que la pointe de sortie (620 ; 710) peut travailler à la distance sélectionnée au-dessus du tissu.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Pièce à main selon la revendication 1,<br/>
un ou plusieurs éléments parmi la fenêtre (610), le réflecteur (615) et la pointe (620, 710) étant adaptés pour fournir une distribution souhaitée d'énergie électromagnétique au niveau de la surface cible.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Pièce à main selon la revendication 1 ou 2, comprenant en outre une sortie de fluide adaptée pour émettre des particules de fluide, moyennant quoi une énergie électromagnétique émise par la surface d'émission (621) peut communiquer de l'énergie aux particules de fluide pour appliquer ainsi des forces perturbatrices à la surface cible.<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Pièce à main selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 3, la pointe de sortie (620, 710) étant interchangeable et la pièce à main comprenant en outre une pluralité de pointes de sortie (620, 710) ayant des caractéristiques de convergence de faisceau différentes.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Pièce à main selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 4,
<claim-text>la fenêtre (610) comprenant un matériau optique transparent en saphir ou en verre ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>le réflecteur (615) comprenant du métal, un matériau céramique ou du saphir et ayant une forme plate, toroïdale ou parabolique ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la pointe de sortie (620, 710) comprenant du saphir ou du verre et ayant une forme approximativement cylindrique.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Pièce à main selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 5, la pointe de sortie (620, 710) ayant une longueur dans la plage d'environ 2 mm à environ 5 mm.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Pièce à main selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 6, la pointe de sortie (620, 710) ayant un diamètre dans la plage d'environ 1 mm à environ 3 mm.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>Pièce à main selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 7, la surface d'émission (621) de la pointe de sortie (620, 710) fournissant la fonctionnalité d'une lentille.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>Pièce à main selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 8, la surface d'émission (621) comprenant une lentille convexe.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>Pièce à main selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 9, une surface réfléchissante du réflecteur (615) ayant une forme plate.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>Pièce à main selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 10, la pièce à main étant configurée de telle sorte qu'une énergie électromagnétique dirigée vers la surface cible du tissu est focalisée à la distance sélectionnée, qui est dans la plage d'environ 5 mm à environ 10 mm.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="127" he="194" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="2,3"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="89" he="173" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> -->
<figure id="f0003" num="4,5A,5B,6"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="152" he="203" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<ep-reference-list id="ref-list">
<heading id="ref-h0001"><b>REFERENCES CITED IN THE DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0001" num=""><i>This list of references cited by the applicant is for the reader's convenience only. It does not form part of the European patent document. Even though great care has been taken in compiling the references, errors or omissions cannot be excluded and the EPO disclaims all liability in this regard.</i></p>
<heading id="ref-h0002"><b>Patent documents cited in the description</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0002" num="">
<ul id="ref-ul0001" list-style="bullet">
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0001" dnum="DE3800555A1"><document-id><country>DE</country><doc-number>3800555</doc-number><kind>A1</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0001">[0004]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0002" dnum="WO5574247A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>5574247</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0002">[0007]</crossref><crossref idref="pcit0005">[0037]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0003" dnum="WO11042824A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>11042824</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0003">[0037]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0004" dnum="WO60601415A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>60601415</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0004">[0037]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0005" dnum="WO7578622A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>7578622</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0006">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0006" dnum="WO7575381A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>7575381</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0007">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0007" dnum="WO7563226A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>7563226</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0008">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0008" dnum="WO7467946A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>7467946</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0009">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0009" dnum="WO7461982A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>7461982</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0010">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0010" dnum="WO7461658A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>7461658</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0011">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0011" dnum="WO7458380A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>7458380</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0012">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0012" dnum="WO7424199A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>7424199</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0013">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0013" dnum="WO7421186A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>7421186</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0014">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0014" dnum="WO7415050A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>7415050</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0015">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0015" dnum="WO7384419A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>7384419</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0016">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0016" dnum="WO7356208A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>7356208</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0017">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0017" dnum="WO7320594A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>7320594</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0018">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0018" dnum="WO7303397A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>7303397</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0019">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0019" dnum="WO7292759A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>7292759</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0020">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0020" dnum="WO7290940A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>7290940</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0021">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0021" dnum="WO7288086A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>7288086</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0022">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0022" dnum="WO7270657A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>7270657</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0023">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0023" dnum="WO7261558A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>7261558</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0024">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0024" dnum="WO7194180A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>7194180</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0025">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0025" dnum="WO7187822A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>7187822</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0026">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0026" dnum="WO7144249A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>7144249</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0027">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0027" dnum="WO7108693A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>7108693</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0028">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0028" dnum="WO7068912A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>7068912</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0029">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0029" dnum="WO6942658A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>6942658</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0030">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0030" dnum="WO6829427A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>6829427</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0031">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0031" dnum="WO6821272A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>6821272</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0032">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0032" dnum="WO6744790A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>6744790</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0033">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0033" dnum="WO6669685A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>6669685</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0034">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0034" dnum="WO6616451A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>6616451</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0035">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0035" dnum="WO6616447A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>6616447</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0036">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0036" dnum="WO6610053A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>6610053</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0037">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0037" dnum="WO6567582A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>6567582</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0038">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0038" dnum="WO6561803A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>6561803</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0039">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0039" dnum="WO6544256A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>6544256</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0040">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0040" dnum="WO6533775A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>6533775</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0041">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0041" dnum="WO6389193A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>6389193</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0042">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0042" dnum="WO6350123A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>6350123</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0043">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0043" dnum="WO6288499A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>6288499</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0044">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0044" dnum="WO6254597A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>6254597</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0045">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0045" dnum="WO6231567A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>6231567</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0046">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0046" dnum="WO6086367A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>6086367</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0047">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0047" dnum="WO5968037A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>5968037</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0048">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0048" dnum="WO5785521A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>5785521</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0049">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0049" dnum="WO5741247A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>5741247</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0050">[0040]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0050" dnum="WO20090225060A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20090225060</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0051">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0051" dnum="WO20090143775A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20090143775</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0052">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0052" dnum="WO20090141752A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20090141752</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0053">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0053" dnum="WO20090105707A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20090105707</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0054">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0054" dnum="WO20090104580A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20090104580</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0055">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0055" dnum="WO20090076490A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20090076490</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0056">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0056" dnum="WO20090075229A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20090075229</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0057">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0057" dnum="WO20090067189A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20090067189</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0058">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0058" dnum="WO20090062779A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20090062779</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0059">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0059" dnum="WO20090056044A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20090056044</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0060">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0060" dnum="WO20090043364A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20090043364</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0061">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0061" dnum="WO20090042171A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20090042171</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0062">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0062" dnum="WO20090035717A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20090035717</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0063">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0063" dnum="WO20090031515A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20090031515</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0064">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0064" dnum="WO20080317429A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080317429</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0065">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0065" dnum="WO20080276192A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080276192</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0066">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0066" dnum="WO20080240172A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080240172</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0067">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0067" dnum="WO20080221558A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080221558</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0068">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0068" dnum="WO20080219629A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080219629</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0069">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0069" dnum="WO20080212624A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080212624</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0070">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0070" dnum="WO20080203280A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080203280</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0071">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0071" dnum="WO20080181278A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080181278</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0072">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0072" dnum="WO20080181261A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080181261</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0073">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0073" dnum="WO20080157690A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080157690</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0074">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0074" dnum="WO20080151953A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080151953</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0075">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0075" dnum="WO20080138764A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080138764</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0076">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0076" dnum="WO20080125677A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080125677</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0077">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0077" dnum="WO20080125676A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080125676</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0078">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0078" dnum="WO20080097418A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080097418</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0079">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0079" dnum="WO20080097417A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080097417</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0080">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0080" dnum="WO20080097416A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080097416</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0081">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0081" dnum="WO20080070185A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080070185</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0082">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0082" dnum="WO20080069172A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080069172</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0083">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0083" dnum="WO20080065057A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080065057</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0084">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0084" dnum="WO20080065055A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080065055</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0085">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0085" dnum="WO20080065054A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080065054</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0086">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0086" dnum="WO20080065053A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080065053</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0087">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0087" dnum="WO20080033411A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080033411</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0088">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0088" dnum="WO20080033409A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080033409</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0089">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0089" dnum="WO20080033407A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080033407</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0090">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0090" dnum="WO20080025675A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080025675</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0091">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0091" dnum="WO20080025672A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080025672</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0092">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0092" dnum="WO20080025671A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20080025671</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0093">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0093" dnum="WO20070298369A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20070298369</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0094">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0094" dnum="WO20070263975A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20070263975</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0095">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0095" dnum="WO20070258693A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20070258693</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0096">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0096" dnum="WO20070208404A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20070208404</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0097">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0097" dnum="WO20070208328A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20070208328</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0098">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0098" dnum="WO20070190482A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20070190482</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0099">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0099" dnum="WO20070184402A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20070184402</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0100">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0100" dnum="WO20070128576A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20070128576</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0101">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0101" dnum="WO20070104419A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20070104419</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0102">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0102" dnum="WO20070060917A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20070060917</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0103">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0103" dnum="WO20070059660A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20070059660</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0104">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0104" dnum="WO20070054236A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20070054236</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0105">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0105" dnum="WO20070054235A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20070054235</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0106">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0106" dnum="WO20070054233A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20070054233</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0107">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0107" dnum="WO20070042315A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20070042315</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0108">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0108" dnum="WO20070016176A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20070016176</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0109">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0109" dnum="WO20070014517A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20070014517</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0110">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0110" dnum="WO20070014322A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20070014322</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0111">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0111" dnum="WO20070009856A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20070009856</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0112">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0112" dnum="WO20070003604A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20070003604</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0113">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0113" dnum="WO20060281042A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20060281042</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0114">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0114" dnum="WO20060275016A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20060275016</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0115">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0115" dnum="WO20060241574A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20060241574</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0116">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0116" dnum="WO20060240381A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20060240381</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0117">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0117" dnum="WO20060210228A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20060210228</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0118">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0118" dnum="WO20060204203A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20060204203</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0119">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0119" dnum="WO20060142745A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20060142745</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0120">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0120" dnum="WO20060142744A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20060142744</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0121">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0121" dnum="WO20060142743A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20060142743</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0122">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0122" dnum="WO20060126680A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20060126680</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0123">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0123" dnum="WO20060099548A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20060099548</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0124">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0124" dnum="WO20060083466A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20060083466</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0125">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0125" dnum="WO20060043903A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20060043903</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0126">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0126" dnum="WO20050283143A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20050283143</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0127">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0127" dnum="WO20050281887A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20050281887</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0128">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0128" dnum="WO20050281530A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20050281530</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0129">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0129" dnum="WO20050256517A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20050256517</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0130">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0130" dnum="WO20050256516A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20050256516</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0131">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0131" dnum="WO20040106082A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20040106082</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0132">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0132" dnum="WO20040092925A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20040092925</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0133">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0133" dnum="WO20040091834A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20040091834</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0134">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0134" dnum="WO20040068256A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20040068256</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0135">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0135" dnum="WO20030228094A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20030228094</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0136">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0136" dnum="WO20020149324A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20020149324</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0137">[0041]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0137" dnum="WO20020014855A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>20020014855</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0138">[0041]</crossref></li>
</ul></p>
</ep-reference-list>
</ep-patent-document>
