<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP18845148B1" file="EP18845148NWB1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3624377" kind="B1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSK..HRIS..MTNORS..SM..................</B001EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  2100000/0</B007EP><B070EP>The file contains technical information submitted after the application was filed and not included in this specification</B070EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3624377</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT SPECIFICATION</B121></B120><B130>B1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>18845148.8</B210><B220><date>20180504</date></B220><B240><B241><date>20191129</date></B241><B242><date>20210203</date></B242></B240><B250>zh</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B300><B310>PCT/CN2017/096656</B310><B320><date>20170809</date></B320><B330><ctry>WO</ctry></B330><B310>PCT/CN2018/081785</B310><B320><date>20180403</date></B320><B330><ctry>WO</ctry></B330></B300><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20200318</date><bnum>202012</bnum></B430><B450><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B450><B452EP><date>20210702</date></B452EP></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>H04W  28/04        20090101AFI20200603BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="2"><text>H04L   1/18        20060101ALI20200603BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="3"><text>H04L   5/00        20060101ALI20200603BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="4"><text>H04W  72/04        20090101ALI20200603BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="5"><text>H04W  72/12        20090101ALI20200603BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>H04L   5/0094      20130101 LI20200520BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>H04L   1/1854      20130101 FI20200520BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="3"><text>H04W  28/04        20130101 LI20190309BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="4"><text>H04W  72/12        20130101 LI20190314BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="5"><text>H04L   1/1864      20130101 LI20200520BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="6"><text>H04W  72/04        20130101 LI20190314BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="7"><text>H04L   5/0055      20130101 LI20200520BHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>VERFAHREN ZUR BESTIMMUNG DER GESAMTZAHL VON BITS VON RÜCKMELDUNGSANTWORTINFORMATIONEN UND ZUGEHÖRIGES PRODUKT</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>METHOD FOR DETERMINING TOTAL NUMBER OF BITS OF FEEDBACK RESPONSE INFORMATION AND RELATED PRODUCT</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>PROCÉDÉ DE DÉTERMINATION DU NOMBRE TOTAL DE BITS D'INFORMATIONS DE RÉPONSE DE RÉTROACTION ET PRODUIT ASSOCIÉ</B542></B540><B560><B561><text>WO-A1-2016/208726</text></B561><B561><text>CN-A- 102 687 414</text></B561><B561><text>CN-A- 102 870 388</text></B561><B562><text>CATT: "HARQ and scheduling timing design for LTE sTTI", 3GPP DRAFT; R1-1707446, 3RD GENERATION PARTNERSHIP PROJECT (3GPP), MOBILE COMPETENCE CENTRE ; 650, ROUTE DES LUCIOLES ; F-06921 SOPHIA-ANTIPOLIS CEDEX ; FRANCE , vol. RAN WG1, no. Hangzhou; 20170515 - 20170519 14 May 2017 (2017-05-14), XP051272655, Retrieved from the Internet: URL:http://www.3gpp.org/ftp/Meetings_3GPP_ SYNC/RAN1/Docs/ [retrieved on 2017-05-14]</text></B562><B562><text>ERICSSON: "On HARQ Codebook", 3GPP DRAFT; R1-1711510, 3RD GENERATION PARTNERSHIP PROJECT (3GPP), MOBILE COMPETENCE CENTRE ; 650, ROUTE DES LUCIOLES ; F-06921 SOPHIA-ANTIPOLIS CEDEX ; FRANCE , vol. RAN WG1, no. Qingdao, China; 20170627 - 20170630 17 June 2017 (2017-06-17), XP051305638, Retrieved from the Internet: URL:http://www.3gpp.org/ftp/tsg_ran/WG1_RL 1/TSGR1_AH/NR_AH_1706/Docs/ [retrieved on 2017-06-17]</text></B562><B565EP><date>20200609</date></B565EP></B560></B500><B700><B720><B721><snm>LIN, Yanan</snm><adr><str>No.18 Haibin Road
Wusha
Chang'an</str><city>Dongguan
Guangdong 523860</city><ctry>CN</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B730><B731><snm>GUANGDONG OPPO MOBILE TELECOMMUNICATIONS 
CORP., LTD.</snm><iid>101838366</iid><irf>G24765PWOEP</irf><adr><str>No. 18 Haibin Road</str><city>Wusha, Chang'an
Dongguan,
Guangdong 523860</city><ctry>CN</ctry></adr></B731></B730><B740><B741><snm>Manitz Finsterwald 
Patent- und Rechtsanwaltspartnerschaft mbB</snm><iid>100060405</iid><adr><str>Martin-Greif-Strasse 1</str><city>80336 München</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840><B860><B861><dnum><anum>CN2018085678</anum></dnum><date>20180504</date></B861><B862>zh</B862></B860><B870><B871><dnum><pnum>WO2019029202</pnum></dnum><date>20190214</date><bnum>201907</bnum></B871></B870></B800></SDOBI>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<heading id="h0001"><b>CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</b></heading>
<p id="p0001" num="0001">The application claims priority to PCT Application No. <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="CN2017096656W" dnum-type="L"><text>PCT/CN2017/096656, field on August 09, 2017</text></patcit>, entitled "Method for Determining Feedback Response Information and Related Product" and PCT Application No. <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="WO2018081785A"><text>PCT/2018/081785, field on April 03, 2018</text></patcit>, entitled "Method for Determining Length of Feedback Response Information and Related Product".</p>
<heading id="h0002"><b>TECHNICAL FIELD</b></heading>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">The disclosure relates to the field of communication technologies, and more particularly to a method and device for determining a total number of bits of feedback response information. The features of the preamble of the independent claims are known from CATT: "HARQ and scheduling timing design for LTE sTTI", 3GPP DRAFT; R1-1707446.</p>
<heading id="h0003"><b>BACKGROUND</b></heading>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">Hybrid Automatic Repeat Request (HARQ) integrates storage, retransmission request and merging demodulation. A receiving party, in case of a failure in decoding, stores received data and requests a sending party to retransmit data, and the receiving party merges retransmitted data and the previously received data for decoding.</p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">A New Radio (NR) system supports dynamic indication of HARQ timing. In a technical solution of HARQ timing, a length (i.e., the number of bits) of an Acknowledgement (ACK)/Negative Acknowledgement (NACK) fed back within a transmission time unit (for example, a time slot) cannot be determined, so that an related NR system cannot support multiplexing transmission of an ACK/NACK.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p>
<heading id="h0004"><b>SUMMARY</b></heading>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">The present invention is defined in the appended independent claims. Advantageous features are set out in the appended dependent claims.</p>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">Implementations of the disclosure provide a method and device for determining a total number of bits of feedback response information, which may implement multiplexing transmission of an ACK/NACK in an NR system.</p>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">According to a first aspect of the invention, the implementations of the disclosure provide a method for determining a total number of bits of feedback response information, which includes the following operations.</p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">A terminal receives configuration signaling transmitted by a network device, here, the configuration signaling includes an indication about a maximum transmission delay for feedback response information.</p>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">The terminal determines a total number of bits of feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum transmission delay and a minimum transmission delay.</p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">In an implementation, after the operation that the terminal determines the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum transmission delay and the minimum transmission delay, the method may further include the following operation.</p>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">The terminal transmits to the network device the feedback response information to be transmitted with the total number of bits.</p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">In an implementation, a time unit, which is used by the terminal to transmit to the network device the feedback response information to be transmitted with the total number of bits, may be determined by the terminal according to dynamically determined HARQ feedback timing.</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">In an implementation, the operation that the terminal determines the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum transmission delay and the minimum transmission delay may include the following operation.</p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">The terminal determines the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to a difference between the maximum transmission delay and the minimum transmission delay.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">In an implementation, the operation that the terminal determines the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum transmission delay and the minimum transmission delay may include the following operation.</p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">The total number of bits N=C*(T<sub>max</sub>-T<sub>min</sub>).</p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">Here, T<sub>max</sub> may be the maximum transmission delay, T<sub>min</sub> may be a nonnegative integer less than T<sub>max</sub>, and C may be a positive integer.</p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">In an implementation, T<sub>min</sub> may be the minimum transmission delay for transmission of the feedback response information by the terminal, or T<sub>min</sub> may be a parameter configured by the network device.</p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">In an implementation, C may be a maximum number of bits of feedback response information corresponding to a Physical Downlink Shared Channel (PDSCH), or C may be a set constant, or C may be a parameter configured by the network device.</p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">In an implementation, the maximum number of bits of the feedback response information corresponding to the PDSCH may be: a maximum number of Transport Blocks (TBs) carried in the PDSCH; or a maximum number of Code Block (CB) groups carried in the PDSCH.</p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">In an implementation, the operation that the terminal transmits to the network device the feedback response information to be transmitted with the total number of bits may include the following operations.</p>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">The terminal transmits the feedback response information on which a joint encoding has been performed; or the terminal transmits the feedback response information through a physical channel.</p>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">According to a second aspect of the invention, implementations of the disclosure provide a device for determining a total number of bits of feedback response information, which includes a processing unit and a transceiver unit connected with the processing unit.</p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">The transceiver unit is configured to receive configuration signaling transmitted by a network device, here, the configuration signaling includes an indication about a maximum transmission delay for feedback response information.</p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">The processing unit is configured to determine a total number of bits of feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> transmission delay and a minimum transmission delay.</p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">In an implementation, the transceiver unit may further be configured to transmit, by a terminal, to the network device the feedback response information to be transmitted with the total number of bits.</p>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">In an implementation, a time unit used by the terminal to transmit to the network device the feedback response information to be transmitted with the total number of bits may be determined by the terminal according to dynamically determined HARQ feedback timing.</p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">In an implementation, the processing unit may specifically be configured to determine the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to a difference between the maximum transmission delay and the minimum transmission delay.</p>
<p id="p0029" num="0029">In an implementation, the processing unit may specifically be configured to determine the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum transmission delay and the minimum transmission delay, the total number of bits N=C*(T<sub>max</sub>-T<sub>min</sub>).</p>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">Here, T<sub>max</sub> may be the maximum transmission delay, T<sub>min</sub> may be a nonnegative integer less than T<sub>max</sub>, and C may be a positive integer.</p>
<p id="p0031" num="0031">In an implementation, T<sub>min</sub> may be the minimum transmission delay for transmission of the feedback response information by the terminal, or T<sub>min</sub> may be a parameter configured by the network device.</p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032">In an implementation, C may be a maximum number of bits of feedback response information corresponding to a PDSCH, or C may be a set constant, or C may be a parameter configured by the network device.</p>
<p id="p0033" num="0033">In an implementation, the maximum number of bits of the feedback response information corresponding to the PDSCH may be: a maximum number of TBs carried in the PDSCH; or a maximum number of CB groups carried in the PDSCH.</p>
<p id="p0034" num="0034">In an implementation, the transceiver unit may specifically be configured to transmit the feedback response information on which a joint encoding has been performed. Or the transceiver unit may specifically be configured to transmit the feedback response information through a physical channel.</p>
<p id="p0035" num="0035">According to a third aspect not being part of the invention, implementations of the disclosure provide a method for determining a total number of bits of feedback<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> response information, which may include the following operations.</p>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">A network device transmits configuration signaling to a terminal, here, the configuration signaling includes an indication about a maximum transmission delay for feedback response information.</p>
<p id="p0037" num="0037">The network device determines a total number of bits of feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum transmission delay and a minimum transmission delay.</p>
<p id="p0038" num="0038">In an implementation, after the operation that the network device determines the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum transmission delay and the minimum transmission delay, the method may further include the following operation.</p>
<p id="p0039" num="0039">The network device receives from the terminal the feedback response information to be transmitted with the total number of bits.</p>
<p id="p0040" num="0040">In an implementation, a time unit for the feedback response information to be transmitted with the total number of bits, which information is received by the network device, may be determined by the terminal according to dynamically determined HARQ feedback timing.</p>
<p id="p0041" num="0041">In an implementation, the operation that the network device determines the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum transmission delay and the minimum transmission delay may include the following operation.</p>
<p id="p0042" num="0042">The network device determines the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to a difference between the maximum transmission delay and the minimum transmission delay.</p>
<p id="p0043" num="0043">In an implementation, the operation that the network device determines the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum transmission delay and the minimum transmission delay may include the following operation.</p>
<p id="p0044" num="0044">The total number of bits N=C*(T<sub>max</sub>-T<sub>min</sub>).</p>
<p id="p0045" num="0045">Here, T<sub>max</sub> may be the maximum transmission delay, T<sub>min</sub> may be a nonnegative integer less than T<sub>max</sub>, and C may be a positive integer.</p>
<p id="p0046" num="0046">In an implementation, T<sub>min</sub> may be the minimum transmission delay for feedback response information transmission of the terminal. Or T<sub>min</sub> may be a<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> parameter configured by the network device.</p>
<p id="p0047" num="0047">In an implementation, C may be a maximum number of bits of feedback response information corresponding to a PDSCH. Or C may be a set constant. Or C may be a parameter configured by the network device.</p>
<p id="p0048" num="0048">In an implementation, the maximum number of bits of the feedback response information corresponding to the PDSCH may be: a maximum number of TBs carried in the PDSCH; or a maximum number of CB groups carried in the PDSCH.</p>
<p id="p0049" num="0049">In an implementation, the operation that the network device receives from the terminal the feedback response information to be transmitted with the total number of bits may include the following operations.</p>
<p id="p0050" num="0050">The network device receives from the terminal the feedback response information on which a joint encoding has been performed.</p>
<p id="p0051" num="0051">Or the network device receives the feedback response information that is transmitted by the terminal through a physical channel.</p>
<p id="p0052" num="0052">According to a fourth aspect not being part of the invention, implementations of the disclosure provide a device for determining a total number of bits of feedback response information, which may include a processing unit and a transceiver unit connected with the processing unit.</p>
<p id="p0053" num="0053">The transceiver unit may be configured to transmit configuration signaling to a terminal, here, the configuration signaling includes an indication about a maximum transmission delay for feedback response information.</p>
<p id="p0054" num="0054">The processing unit may be configured to determine a total number of bits of feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum transmission delay and a minimum transmission delay.</p>
<p id="p0055" num="0055">According to a fifth aspect, implementations of the disclosure provide a terminal not being part of the invention, which may include one or more processors, a memory, a transceiver and one or more programs. The one or more programs may be stored in the memory and configured to be executed by the one or more processors, and the programs may include instructions configured to execute the operations in the method provided in the first aspect.</p>
<p id="p0056" num="0056">According to a sixth aspect not being part of the invention, implementations of the disclosure provide a computer-readable storage medium, which may store a computer program for electronic data exchange, here, the computer program enables a<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> computer to execute the method provided in the first aspect.</p>
<p id="p0057" num="0057">According to a seventh aspect not being part of the invention, implementations of the disclosure provide a computer program product, which may include a non-transitory computer-readable storage medium storing a computer program, the computer program is operable to enable a computer to execute the method provided in the first aspect.</p>
<p id="p0058" num="0058">According to an eighth aspect not being part of the invention, implementations of the disclosure provide a network device, which may include one or more processors, a memory, a transceiver and one or more programs. The one or more programs may be stored in the memory and configured to be executed by the one or more processors, and the programs may include instructions configured to execute the operations in the method provided in the third aspect.</p>
<p id="p0059" num="0059">According to a ninth aspect not being part of the invention, implementations of the disclosure provide a computer-readable storage medium, which may store a computer program for electronic data exchange, here, the computer program enables a computer to execute the method provided in the third aspect</p>
<p id="p0060" num="0060">According to a tenth aspect not being part of the invention, implementations of the disclosure provide a computer program product, which may include a non-transitory computer-readable storage medium storing a computer program, the computer program is operable to enable a computer to execute the method provided in the third aspect</p>
<p id="p0061" num="0061">From the above, in the implementations of the disclosure, the terminal receives a maximum transmission delay transmitted by a base station, calculates a length of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum transmission delay and transmits to the base station the feedback response information with the length, so that multiplexing transmission of an ACK/NACK in a transmission time unit may be supported by an NR system, and the advantage of supporting multiplexing transmission of the feedback response information in the NR system is achieved.</p>
<heading id="h0005"><b>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF DRAWINGS</b></heading>
<p id="p0062" num="0062">The drawings used for descriptions about the implementations or related arts<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> will be simply introduced below.
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li><figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a structure diagram of an exemplary communication system.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> is a structure diagram of an exemplary NR communication system.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2A</figref> is a diagram of exemplary transmission time units.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> is a flowchart of a method for determining a length of feedback response information according to an implementation of the disclosure.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref> is a diagram of transmission time units according to an implementation of the disclosure.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0004">FIG. 3B</figref> is a flowchart of a method for determining a length of feedback response information not being part of the invention.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0004">FIG. 3C</figref> is a flowchart of another method for determining a length of feedback response information not being part of the invention.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0005">FIG. 4</figref> is a block diagram of functional units of a terminal according to an implementation of the disclosure.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0005">FIG. 4A</figref> is a block diagram of functional units of a network device not being part of the invention.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0005">FIG. 5</figref> is a hardware structure diagram of a terminal not being part of the invention.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0006">FIG. 5A</figref> is a hardware structure diagram of a network device not being part of the invention.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0006">FIG. 6</figref> is a structure diagram of another terminal not being part of the invention.</li>
</ul></p>
<heading id="h0006"><b>DETAILED DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
<p id="p0063" num="0063">The technical solutions in the implementations of the disclosure will be described below in combination with the drawings.</p>
<p id="p0064" num="0064">Referring to <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1, FIG. 1</figref> is a possible network architecture of an exemplary communication system according to an implementation of the disclosure. The exemplary communication system may be a 5th-Generation (5G) NR communication system, and specifically includes a network device and a terminal. When the terminal accesses a mobile communication network provided by the network device, the terminal may establish a communication connection with the network device through<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> a radio link. Such a communication connection manner may be a single-connection manner or a dual-connection manner or a multi-connection manner. When the communication connection manner is the single-connection manner, the network device may be a Long Term Evolution (LTE) base station or an NR Node B (NR-NB) (also called a gNB). When the communication manner is the dual-connection manner (which may specifically be implemented by a Carrier Aggregation (CA) technology or implemented by multiple network devices) and the terminal is connected with multiple network devices, the multiple network devices may include a Master Cell Group (MCG) and a Secondary Cell Group (SCG), data backhaul is performed between the cell groups through backhaul links, the MCG may be an NR base station and each SCGs may be an NR base station.</p>
<p id="p0065" num="0065">In the implementations of the disclosure, terms "network" and "system" are usually used alternately and meanings of the terms may be understood by those skilled in the art. A terminal involved in the implementations of the disclosure may include a handheld device with wireless communication functions, a vehicle-mounted device, a wearable device, a computing device or other processing devices connected to a wireless modem, as well as various forms of User Equipment (UE), Mobile Station (MS), terminal device and the like. For convenient description, the devices mentioned above are collectively referred to as terminals.</p>
<p id="p0066" num="0066">Referring to <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2, FIG. 2</figref> is a structure diagram of a 5G NR network. As illustrated in <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>, there may be one or more Transmission Reception Points (TRPs) under an NR-NB, and there may be one or more terminals within a range of the one or more TRPs. In an NR system illustrated in <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>, for Downlink (DL) data, a terminal needs to feed back to the gNB through HARQ whether the DL data is successfully received. That is, the terminal needs to feed back a HARQ ACK/NACK to the gNB. In the NR system, HARQ timing for ACK/NACK feedback information for data (mainly the DL data) is dynamically indicated by the gNB, in the following, a transmission time unit is, for example, a slot. Referring to <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2A, FIG. 2A</figref> is a diagram of transmission time units for HARQ timing in an NR system. Here, there is made such a hypothesis that the HARQ timing is indicated in a slot n. As illustrated in <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2A</figref>, there is made such a hypothesis that the HARQ timing is five slots, and in the five slots, the slot n is used to carry DL data for DL transmission, the slot n+1 is used to carry Uplink (UL) data for UL transmission, the slot n+2 is used to carry DL<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> data, the slot n+3 is used to carry DL data, the slot n+4 is empty and the slot n+5 is a slot through which the terminal feeds back an ACK/NACK to the gNB. Since both the slot n+2 and the slot n+3 are used to carry the DL data, the ACK/NACK corresponding to the slot n+2 and the ACK/NACK corresponding to the slot n+3 are also needed to be fed back. For example, if the gNB dynamically indicates that HARQ timing for the ACK/NACK corresponding to the slot n+2 is three slots and HARQ timing for the ACK/NACK corresponding to the slot n+3 is two slots, then for the slot n+5, there are ACK/NACKs for three slots, that is, multiplexing transmission of the ACKs/NACKs for the three slots are performed in the slot n+5. In the NR system illustrated in <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>, the terminal cannot implement multiplexing transmission of the ACKs/NACKs for the three slots, in the slot n+5.</p>
<p id="p0067" num="0067">Referring to <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3, FIG. 3</figref> illustrates a method for determining a length of feedback response information according to an implementation of the disclosure. The method is performed by a terminal. As illustrated in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref>, the method includes the following operations.</p>
<p id="p0068" num="0068">In S301, the terminal receives configuration signaling transmitted by a network device (for example, a base station). The configuration signaling includes an indication about a maximum transmission delay for feedback response information.</p>
<p id="p0069" num="0069">The configuration signaling in S301 may be DL control signaling for scheduling a PDSCH transmission. Specifically, the maximum transmission delay may be indicated in a DL grant for scheduling the PDSCH. Here, a transmission time unit is, for example, a slot. There is made such a hypothesis that a first transmission time unit in which the configuration signaling is received is a slot n, and the maximum transmission delay may be the number of slots. Specifically, the maximum transmission delay may be, for example, k1, and then k1 is indicated in a DL grant of the slot n for scheduling the PDSCH.</p>
<p id="p0070" num="0070">In S302, the terminal dynamically determines HARQ feedback timing.</p>
<p id="p0071" num="0071">An implementation method for S302 may specifically be as follows. The terminal parses the configuration signaling to obtain the maximum transmission delay, a transmission time unit obtained after delaying the maximum transmission delay from the first transmission time unit in which the configuration signaling is received is namely a transmission time unit for HARQ feedback response information. Here, the transmission time unit is also, for example, a slot. If the configuration signaling is<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> carried in a slot n for transmission and the maximum transmission delay corresponding to the configuration signaling is k1, the determined HARQ feedback timing is k1, and the transmission time unit for the HARQ feedback response information may be slot n+k1.</p>
<p id="p0072" num="0072">In S303, the terminal determines a length (i.e., a total number of bits) of feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum transmission delay.</p>
<p id="p0073" num="0073">In an implementation, the terminal determines the total number of bits of the feedback response information according to the maximum transmission delay and a minimum transmission delay.</p>
<p id="p0074" num="0074">In an implementation, the terminal determines the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to a difference between the maximum transmission delay and the minimum transmission delay.</p>
<p id="p0075" num="0075">In an implementation not being part of the invention, the terminal determines the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum transmission delay, the minimum transmission delay and M<sub>non-DL</sub>, here, M<sub>non-DL</sub> is a value less than the maximum transmission delay.</p>
<p id="p0076" num="0076">In an implementation not being part of the invention, the terminal determines the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to a value obtained by subtracting the minimum transmission delay and M<sub>non-DL</sub> from the maximum transmission delay, here, M<sub>non-DL</sub> is a value less than the maximum transmission delay.</p>
<p id="p0077" num="0077">In S304, the terminal transmits a message containing the feedback response information with the determined length of the feedback response information to be transmitted.</p>
<p id="p0078" num="0078">An implementation method for S304 may specifically be as follows.</p>
<p id="p0079" num="0079">The terminal transmits the feedback response information on which a joint encoding has been performed.</p>
<p id="p0080" num="0080">Or the terminal transmits the feedback response information through a physical channel.</p>
<p id="p0081" num="0081">According to the technical solution provided by the implementation illustrated in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref>, a base station, when scheduling a PDSCH transmission, indicates the maximum transmission delay in a DL grant of the first transmission time unit for<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> scheduling the PDSCH, and the terminal, after receiving the first transmission time unit, acquires the maximum transmission delay, calculates the length of the HARQ feedback response information according to the maximum transmission delay, and transmits the HARQ feedback response information with the length to the base station, so that multiplexing transmission of an ACK/NACK in a transmission time unit is supported in an NR system.</p>
<p id="p0082" num="0082">A technical effect achieved by the implementation will be described below with an example. The transmission time unit illustrated in <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2A</figref> is transmitted in the NR illustrated in <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>. Herein, there is made such a hypothesis that each transmission time unit includes two TBs. If the terminal successfully receives the slot n and the slot n+2 and the terminal does not receive the slot n+3, for example, the terminal does not successfully receive the data in the slot n+3, a response corresponding to the slot n+3 is not fed back, so that the terminal does not carry, in the slot n+5, HARQ feedback response information corresponding to the slot n+3, and the feedback response information carried by the terminal in the slot n+5 may be 1111. The base station may not recognize, according to the 1111, that the terminal does not receive the slot n+3, and thus the base station may not accurately obtain the HARQ feedback response information of the terminal for subsequent operations, for example, data retransmission cannot be performed according to the HARQ feedback response information. According to the technical solution illustrated in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref>, the terminal receives, in the slot n, configuration signaling, here, the configuration signaling includes the maximum transmission delay which is 5 slots, the terminal determines according to the maximum transmission delay that the total number of bits of the HARQ feedback response information is 6 (the specific method for determining the total number of bits may refer to the following descriptions and will not be elaborated herein), and the terminal transmits, in the slot n+5, the 6-bit HARQ feedback response information and may specifically transmit 111100. The base station may know according to allocation of slots for DL data that the slot n and the slot n+2 are successfully transmitted and the slot n+3 is failed to be transmitted, and thereby achieving the advantage that multiplexing transmission of an ACK/NACK in a transmission time unit is supported in the NR system.</p>
<p id="p0083" num="0083">In an implementation, an implementation method for S303 may specifically be as follows.<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></p>
<p id="p0084" num="0084">The length, i.e., the total number of bits N, of the feedback response information is calculated according to the following formula (1). <maths id="math0001" num="(1)"><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">N</mi><mo>=</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">C</mi><mo>*</mo><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">T</mi><mi>max</mi></msub><mo>−</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">T</mi><mi>min</mi></msub></mfenced></math><img id="ib0001" file="imgb0001.tif" wi="46" he="5" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p>
<p id="p0085" num="0085">Here, C may be a positive integer, T<sub>max</sub> may be the maximum transmission delay, and T<sub>min</sub> may be a nonnegative integer not greater than T<sub>max</sub>.</p>
<p id="p0086" num="0086">Specifically, T<sub>min</sub> may be the minimum transmission delay for transmission of the feedback response information by the terminal. Of course, T<sub>min</sub> may also be a parameter configured by the network device, and the parameter may be a fixed value. Of course, during a practical application, a value of T<sub>min</sub> may also be carried in the configuration signaling.</p>
<p id="p0087" num="0087">C may be a maximum number of bits of feedback response information corresponding to a PDSCH. Or C may be a set constant (i.e., a value specified in a protocol or a value predetermined by a manufacturer). Or C may be a parameter configured by the network device.</p>
<p id="p0088" num="0088">The maximum number of bits of the feedback response information corresponding to the PDSCH may specifically be: a maximum number of TBs carried in the PDSCH; or a maximum number of CB groups carried in the PDSCH.</p>
<p id="p0089" num="0089">For example, the maximum number of the TBs carried in a slot for a PDSCH may be 2 (the number is only for exemplary description and a specific value of the number is not limited in the disclosure), this does not mean that each slot includes two TBs. In a practical application scenario, the slot may include one TB or no TB (for example, the slot n+4 illustrated in <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2A</figref>). The number of the CB groups carried in a slot for a PDSCH may be 4 (the number is only for exemplary description and a specific value of the number is not limited in the disclosure), and similarly, this also does not mean that each slot includes four CB groups. A method for determining a value of N will be described below with an exemplary. Referring to <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref>, the configuration signaling may be carried in the slot n, the maximum transmission delay in the configuration signaling is 4 slots, and the minimum transmission delay in the configuration signaling is 2 slots. There is made such a hypothesis that a total number of basic units for the feedback response information in each slot is two. Here, a basic unit for the feedback response information is, for example, a TB. Of course, during a practical application, the basic unit for the feedback response information may also be a CB group, here, the CB group includes at least one CB. The value is determined to<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> be 4 (bits) according to N=2*(4-2) =4 calculated by using the formula (1).</p>
<p id="p0090" num="0090">The above technical solution does not distinguish whether the feedback response information between T<sub>max</sub> and T<sub>min</sub> is needed to be fed back to the base station. As illustrated in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref>, the slot n+1 may be used to carry UL data, and for the slot n+1, no feedback response information is needed to be transmitted to the base station. In the technical solution, the feedback response information corresponding to the slot n+1 may be filled with a specific numerical value (for example, 1 or 0), and the base station only needs to identify the feedback response information corresponding to the slot n and the slot n+2, and may discard or not process the feedback response information corresponding to the slot n+1.</p>
<p id="p0091" num="0091">In an implementation not being part of the invention, the implementation method for S303 may specifically be as follows.</p>
<p id="p0092" num="0092">The length, i.e., the total number of bits N, of the feedback response information is calculated according to the following formula (2). <maths id="math0002" num="(2)"><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">N</mi><mo>=</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">C</mi><mo>*</mo><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">T</mi><mi>max</mi></msub><mo>−</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">T</mi><mi>min</mi></msub><mo>−</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">M</mi><mi>non-DL</mi></msub></mfenced></math><img id="ib0002" file="imgb0002.tif" wi="59" he="5" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p>
<p id="p0093" num="0093">Here, T<sub>min</sub> and M<sub>non-DL</sub> may be each a nonnegative integer and N is a nonnegative value, and meanings of C and T<sub>max</sub> may refer to the descriptions in the formula (1).</p>
<p id="p0094" num="0094">In an implementation not being part of the invention, M<sub>non-DL</sub> may specifically be: the number of all first-type time units between a transmission time unit Y-T<sub>max</sub> and a transmission time unit Y-T<sub>min</sub>, here, a transmission time unit Y is a transmission time unit for transmission of the feedback response information.</p>
<p id="p0095" num="0095">The first-type time unit may specifically include, but not limited to, one or any combination of: a UL time unit, a time unit in which no physical shared channel is transmitted by the terminal and a time unit in which no DL control signaling is monitored by the terminal.</p>
<p id="p0096" num="0096">In the implementation of the disclosure, in addition to determining the length of the feedback response information by the formula (1) and the formula (2), another implementation manner may also be adopted to determine the length of the feedback response information according to the maximum transmission delay and the minimum transmission delay, or another implementation manner is adopted to determine the length of the feedback response information according to the maximum transmission delay, the minimum transmission delay and M<sub>non-DL</sub>. For simplicity, elaborations are<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> omitted herein.</p>
<p id="p0097" num="0097">A method for determining a value of N will be described below with an example. Referring to <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref>, the configuration signaling may be carried in the slot n, the maximum transmission delay in the configuration signaling is four slots, the minimum transmission delay in the configuration signaling is two slots, and a UL time unit between a slot Y-4 and a slot Y-1 is the slot n+1, so M<sub>non-DL</sub>=1. There is made such a hypothesis that the total number of the basic units for the feedback response information in each slot is 2. Herein, a basic unit for the feedback response information is, for example, a TB. Of course, during a practical application, the basic unit for the feedback response information may also be a CB group, here, the CB group includes at least one CB. The value is determined to be 2 (bits) according to N=2*(4-2-1)=2 calculated by using the formula (2).</p>
<p id="p0098" num="0098">The above technical solution distinguishes whether the feedback response information between T<sub>max</sub> and T<sub>min</sub> is needed to be fed back to the base station. As illustrated in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref>, the slot n+1 may be used carry UL data, and for the slot n+1, no feedback response information is needed to be transmitted to the base station. According to the technical solution, no information is fed back, for the slot n+1, in the feedback response information.</p>
<p id="p0099" num="0099">Referring to <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 3B, FIG. 3B</figref> illustrates a method for determining a length of feedback response information not being part of the invention. A network device in the implementation is, for example, a base station. The method is performed between a terminal and base station illustrated in <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>. Transmission time units between the terminal and the base station are illustrated in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref>. As illustrated in <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 3B</figref>, the method includes the following operations.</p>
<p id="p0100" num="0100">In S301B, the base station transmits configuration signaling to the terminal in a slot n, here, the configuration signaling includes an indication about a maximum transmission delay (which is 4 slots) for feedback response information.</p>
<p id="p0101" num="0101">In S302B, the terminal acquires the maximum transmission delay in the configuration signaling and dynamically determines HARQ feedback timing to be four slots.</p>
<p id="p0102" num="0102">In S303B, the terminal determines a total number of bits N=2*(4-2-1)=2 of feedback response information to be transmitted according to the formula (2).</p>
<p id="p0103" num="0103">In S304B, the base station determines the total number of bits N=2*(4-2-1)=2<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to the formula (2).</p>
<p id="p0104" num="0104">In S305B, the terminal transmits the 2-bit feedback response information to the base station in a slot n+4. According to the technical solution of the disclosure, the terminal calculates the total number of bits of the feedback response information and then transmits the feedback response information with the total number of bits to the base station, thereby achieving, in the slot n+4, multiplexing transmission of feedback response information for the slot n and slot n+2.</p>
<p id="p0105" num="0105">Referring to <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 3C, FIG. 3C</figref> illustrates another method for determining a length of feedback response information not being part of the invention. The method is performed by a network device, and the network device may be a base station illustrated in <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> or <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>. As illustrated in <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 3C</figref>, the method includes the following operations.</p>
<p id="p0106" num="0106">In S301C, the network device transmits configuration signaling to a terminal, here, the configuration signaling includes an indication about a maximum transmission delay for feedback response information.</p>
<p id="p0107" num="0107">In S302C, the network device determines HARQ feedback timing dynamically determined by that the terminal.</p>
<p id="p0108" num="0108">In S303C, the network device determines a total number of bits of feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum transmission delay.</p>
<p id="p0109" num="0109">In an implementation, the network device determines the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum transmission delay and a minimum transmission delay.</p>
<p id="p0110" num="0110">In an implementation, the network device determines the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to a difference between the maximum transmission delay and the minimum transmission delay.</p>
<p id="p0111" num="0111">In an implementation, the network device determines the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum transmission delay, the minimum transmission delay and M<sub>non-DL</sub>, here, M<sub>non-DL</sub> is a value less than the maximum transmission delay.</p>
<p id="p0112" num="0112">In an implementation, the network device determines the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to a value obtained by subtracting the minimum transmission delay and M<sub>non-DL</sub> from the maximum transmission delay, here, M<sub>non-DL</sub> is a value less than the maximum transmission delay.<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></p>
<p id="p0113" num="0113">In S304C, the network device receives from the terminal the feedback response information to be transmitted with the total number of bits.</p>
<p id="p0114" num="0114">The method of the implementation illustrated in <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 3C</figref> supports implementation of the method of the implementation illustrated in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref>, and thus has the advantage that multiplexing transmission of an ACK/NACK in a transmission time unit is supported in an NR system.</p>
<p id="p0115" num="0115">In an optional solution, the total number of bits N=C*(T<sub>max</sub>-T<sub>min</sub>).</p>
<p id="p0116" num="0116">Here, T<sub>max</sub> is the maximum transmission delay, T<sub>min</sub> is a nonnegative integer less than T<sub>max</sub>, and C is a positive integer.</p>
<p id="p0117" num="0117">In another optional solution, the total number of bits N=C*(T<sub>max</sub>-T<sub>min</sub>-M<sub>non-DL</sub>).</p>
<p id="p0118" num="0118">Here, T<sub>max</sub> is the maximum transmission delay, T<sub>min</sub> and M<sub>non-DL</sub> are each a nonnegative integer less than T<sub>max</sub>, and C is a positive integer.</p>
<p id="p0119" num="0119">In an implementation, in the optional solution or the another optional solution, T<sub>min</sub> is the maximum transmission delay for transmission of feedback response information by the terminal. Or T<sub>min</sub> is a parameter configured by the network device.</p>
<p id="p0120" num="0120">In an implementation, in the optional solution or the another optional solution, C is a maximum number of bits of feedback response information corresponding to a PDSCH. Or C is a set constant. Or C is a parameter configured by the network device.</p>
<p id="p0121" num="0121">In an implementation, in the another optional solution, M<sub>non-DL</sub> is the number of all first-type time units between a transmission time unit Y-T<sub>max</sub> and a transmission time unit Y-T<sub>min</sub>, here, a transmission time unit Y is a time unit for transmission of the feedback response information to be transmitted.</p>
<p id="p0122" num="0122">In an implementation, the first-type time unit includes one or any combination of: a UL time unit, a time unit in which the terminal does not transmit a physical shared channel, and a time unit in which the terminal does not monitor DL control signaling.</p>
<p id="p0123" num="0123">In an implementation, the maximum number of bits of the feedback response information corresponding to the PDSCH is: a maximum number of TBs carried in the PDSCH; or a maximum number of CB groups carried in the PDSCH.</p>
<p id="p0124" num="0124">In an implementation, the operation that the network device receives from the terminal the feedback response information to be transmitted with the total number of bits may include the following operations.</p>
<p id="p0125" num="0125">The network device receives from the terminal the feedback response<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> information on which a joint encoding has been performed.</p>
<p id="p0126" num="0126">Or the network device receives the feedback response information that is transmitted by the terminal through a physical channel.</p>
<p id="p0127" num="0127">Referring to <figref idref="f0005">FIG. 4, FIG. 4</figref> illustrates a device for determining a length of feedback response information. The device for determining the length of the feedback response information is configured in a terminal. Detailed solutions and technical effects in the implementation illustrated in <figref idref="f0005">FIG. 4</figref> refers to descriptions in the implementation illustrated in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> or <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 3B</figref>. The terminal includes a processing unit 401 and a transceiver unit 402 connected with the processing unit 401.</p>
<p id="p0128" num="0128">The transceiver unit 402 is configured to receive configuration signaling transmitted by a network device, here, the configuration signaling includes an indication about a maximum transmission delay for feedback response information.</p>
<p id="p0129" num="0129">The processing unit 401 is configured to dynamically determine HARQ feedback timing and determine a total number of bits of feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum transmission delay.</p>
<p id="p0130" num="0130">The transceiver unit 402 is configured to transmit to the network device the feedback response information to be transmitted with the total number of bits.</p>
<p id="p0131" num="0131">In an implementation, the processing unit 401 is specifically configured to: determine the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum transmission delay and a minimum transmission delay.</p>
<p id="p0132" num="0132">In an implementation, the processing unit 401 is specifically configured to: determine the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to a difference between the maximum transmission delay and the minimum transmission delay.</p>
<p id="p0133" num="0133">In an implementation not being part of the invention, the processing unit 401 is specifically configured to: determine the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum transmission delay, the minimum transmission delay and M<sub>non-DL</sub>, here, M<sub>non-DL</sub> is a value less than the maximum transmission delay.</p>
<p id="p0134" num="0134">In an implementation not being part of the invention, the processing unit 401 is specifically configured to: determine the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to a value obtained by subtracting<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> the minimum transmission delay and M<sub>non-DL</sub> from the maximum transmission delay, here, M<sub>non-DL</sub> is a value less than the maximum transmission delay.</p>
<p id="p0135" num="0135">In an implementation, the processing unit 401 is specifically configured to determine the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum transmission delay, the total number of bits N=C*(T<sub>max</sub>-T<sub>min</sub>).</p>
<p id="p0136" num="0136">Here, T<sub>max</sub> is the maximum transmission delay, T<sub>min</sub> is a nonnegative integer less than T<sub>max</sub>, and C is a positive integer.</p>
<p id="p0137" num="0137">In an implementation not being part of the invention, the processing unit 401 is specifically configured to determine the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum transmission delay, the total number of bits N=C*(T<sub>max</sub>-T<sub>min</sub>-M<sub>non-DL</sub>).</p>
<p id="p0138" num="0138">Here, T<sub>max</sub> is the maximum transmission delay, T<sub>min</sub> and M<sub>non-DL</sub> are each a nonnegative integer less than T<sub>max</sub>, and C is a positive integer.</p>
<p id="p0139" num="0139">In an implementation, T<sub>min</sub> is the minimum transmission delay for transmission of feedback response information by the terminal or T<sub>min</sub> is a parameter configured by the network device.</p>
<p id="p0140" num="0140">In an implementation not being part of the invention, M<sub>non-DL</sub> is the number of all first-type time units between a transmission time unit Y-T<sub>max</sub> and a transmission time unit Y-T<sub>min</sub>, here, a transmission time unit Y is a time unit for transmission of the feedback response information to be transmitted.</p>
<p id="p0141" num="0141">The first-type time unit includes, but not limited to, one or any combination of: a UL time unit, a time unit in which no physical shared channel is transmitted by the terminal and a time unit in which no DL control signaling is monitored by the terminal.</p>
<p id="p0142" num="0142">In an implementation, C may specifically be as follows.</p>
<p id="p0143" num="0143">C may be a maximum number of bits of feedback response information corresponding to a PDSCH. Or C is a set constant. Or C is a parameter configured by the network device.</p>
<p id="p0144" num="0144">Specifically, the maximum number of bits of the feedback response information corresponding to the PDSCH may be: a maximum number of TBs carried in the PDSCH; or a maximum number of CB groups carried in the PDSCH.</p>
<p id="p0145" num="0145">In an implementation, the transceiver unit 402 is specifically configured to<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> transmit the feedback response information on which a joint encoding has been performed.</p>
<p id="p0146" num="0146">Or the transceiver unit 402 is specifically configured to transmit the feedback response information through a physical channel.</p>
<p id="p0147" num="0147">Referring to <figref idref="f0005">FIG. 4A, FIG. 4A</figref> illustrates a network device not being part of the invention, which includes a processing unit 408 and a transceiver 409 connected with the processing unit.</p>
<p id="p0148" num="0148">The transceiver unit 408 is configured to transmit configuration signaling to a terminal, here, the configuration signaling includes an indication about a maximum transmission delay for feedback response information.</p>
<p id="p0149" num="0149">The processing unit 409 is configured to determine HARQ feedback timing dynamically determined by the terminal and determine a total number of bits of feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum transmission delay.</p>
<p id="p0150" num="0150">The transceiver unit 408 is configured to receive from the terminal the feedback response information to be transmitted with the total number of bits. In the implementation illustrated in <figref idref="f0005">FIG. 4A</figref>, a manner for calculating the total number of bits may refer to descriptions in the implementation illustrated in <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 3C</figref>, and will not be elaborated herein.</p>
<p id="p0151" num="0151">The disclosure also provides a terminal, as illustrated in <figref idref="f0005">FIG. 5</figref> not being part of the invention, includes one or more processors 501, a memory 502, a transceiver 503 and one or more programs 504. The one or more programs are stored in the memory 502 and configured to be executed by the one or more processors 501, and the programs include instructions configured to execute the operations executed by the terminal in the method provided by the implementation illustrated in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> or <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 3B</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0152" num="0152">The disclosure also provides a network device, as illustrated in <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 5A</figref> not being part of the invention, includes one or more processors 505, a memory 506, a transceiver 507 and one or more programs 508. The one or more programs are stored in the memory 506 and configured to be executed by the one or more processors 505, and the programs include instructions configured to execute the operations executed by the network device in the method provided by the implementation illustrated in <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 3C or FIG. 3B</figref>.<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --></p>
<p id="p0153" num="0153">The processor may be a processor or a controller, for example, a Central Processing unit (CPU), a Digital Signal Processor (DSP), an Application Specific Integrated Circuit (ASIC), a Field Programmable Gate Array (FPGA) or another programmable logical device, transistor logical device, hardware component or any combination thereof. The processor may implement or execute various exemplary logical blocks, modules and circuits described in combination with the contents disclosed in the disclosure. The processor may also be a combination realizing a calculation function, for example, including a combination of one or more microprocessors and a combination of a DSP and a microprocessor. The transceiver 503 may be a communication interface or an antenna.</p>
<p id="p0154" num="0154">An implementation of the disclosure also provides a computer-readable storage medium, which stores a computer program for electronic data exchange, here, the computer program enables a computer to execute the method executed by the terminal in the implementation illustrated in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> or <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 3B</figref>. Of course, the computer program enables the computer to execute the method executed by the network device in the implementation illustrated in <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 3C or FIG. 3B</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0155" num="0155">An implementation of the disclosure also provides a computer program product. The computer program product includes a non-transitory computer-readable storage medium storing a computer program. The computer program may be operable to enable a computer to execute the method executed by the terminal in the implementation illustrated in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> or <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 3B</figref>. Of course, the computer program enables the computer to execute the method executed by the network device in the implementation illustrated in <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 3C or FIG. 3B</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0156" num="0156">The solutions of the implementations of the disclosure are introduced mainly from the angle of interactions between various network elements. It can be understood that for realizing the functions, the terminal and the network device include corresponding hardware structures and/or software modules executing each function. Those skilled in the art may easily realize that the units and algorithm operations of each example described in combination with the implementations disclosed in the disclosure may be implemented by hardware or a combination of the hardware and computer software in the disclosure. Whether a certain function is executed by the hardware or in a manner of driving the hardware by the computer software depends on specific applications and design constraints of the technical solutions.<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> Professionals may realize the described functions for each specific application by use of different methods, but such realization shall fall within the scope of the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p0157" num="0157">According to the implementations of the disclosure, functional units of the terminal and the network device may be divided according to the abovementioned method examples. For example, each functional unit may be divided correspondingly for each function and two or more than two functions may also be integrated into a processing unit. The integrated unit may be implemented in a hardware form and may also be implemented in form of software program module. The division of the units in the implementation of the disclosure is schematic and only is a logical function division and another division manner may be adopted during practical implementation.</p>
<p id="p0158" num="0158">An implementation of the disclosure also provides another terminal. As illustrated in <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 6</figref>, for convenient description, only parts related to the implementation of the disclosure are illustrated, and specific technical details which are undisclosed refer to parts of the method of the implementations of the disclosure. The terminal may be any terminal device including a mobile phone, a tablet computer, a Personal Digital Assistant (PDA), a Point of Sales (POS), a vehicle-mounted computer and the like. For example, the terminal is a mobile phone.</p>
<p id="p0159" num="0159"><figref idref="f0006">FIG. 6</figref> is a block diagram of part structure of a mobile phone related to a terminal not being part of the invention. Referring to <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 6</figref>, the mobile phone includes components such as a Radio Frequency (RF) circuit 910, a memory 920, an input unit 930, a display unit 940, a sensor 950, an audio circuit 960, a Wireless Fidelity (WiFi) module 970, a processor 980 and a power supply 990. Those skilled in the art should know that the structure of the mobile phone illustrated in <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 6</figref> is not intended to limit the mobile phone and may include components more or fewer than those illustrated in the figure or some components are combined or different component arrangements are adopted.</p>
<p id="p0160" num="0160">Each component of the mobile phone will be specifically introduced below in combination with <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 6</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0161" num="0161">The RF circuit 910 may be configured to receive and send information. The RF circuit 910 usually includes, but not limited to, an antenna, at least one amplifier, a transceiver, a coupler, a Low Noise Amplifier (LNA), a duplexer and the like. In addition, the RF circuit 910 may also communicate with a network and another device<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> through wireless communication. Any communication standard or protocol may be adopted for wireless communication, including, but not limited to, a Global System of Mobile communication (GSM), a General Packet Radio Service (GPRS), Code Division Multiple Access (CDMA), Wideband Code Division Multiple Access (WCDMA), Long Term Evolution (LTE), an electronic mail, Short Messaging Service (SMS) and the like.</p>
<p id="p0162" num="0162">The memory 920 may be configured to store a software program and a module. The processor 980 runs the software program and module stored in the memory 920, thereby executing various function applications and data processing of the mobile phone. The memory 920 may mainly include a program storage region and a data storage region. The program storage region may store an operating system, an application program required by at least one function and the like. The data storage region may store data created according to use of the mobile phone and the like. In addition, the memory 920 may include a high-speed Random Access Memory (RAM) and may further include a nonvolatile memory, for example, at least one disk storage device, flash memory device or other volatile solid-state storage device.</p>
<p id="p0163" num="0163">The input unit 930 may be configured to receive input digital or character information and generate key signal input related to user setting and function control of the mobile phone. Specifically, the input unit 930 may include a fingerprint recognition module 931 and other input device 932. The fingerprint recognition module 931 may acquire fingerprint data of a user thereon. In addition to the fingerprint recognition module 931, the input unit 930 may further include the other input device 932. Specifically, the other input device 932 may include, but not limited to, one or more of: a touch screen, a physical keyboard, a function key (for example, a volume control button and a switch button), a trackball, a mouse, a stick and the like.</p>
<p id="p0164" num="0164">The display unit 940 may be configured to display information input by the user or information provided for the user and various menus of the mobile phone. The display unit 940 may include a display screen 941. In an implementation, the display screen 941 may be configured in form of Liquid Crystal Display (LCD) and Organic Light-Emitting Diode (OLED). In <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 6</figref>, the fingerprint recognition module 931 and the display screen 941 realize input and output functions of the mobile phone as two independent components. However, in some implementations, the fingerprint recognition module 931 and the display screen 941 may be integrated to realize the<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> input and play functions of the mobile phone.</p>
<p id="p0165" num="0165">The mobile phone may further include at least one sensor 950, for example, a light sensor, a motion sensor and another sensor. Specifically, the light sensor may include an environmental light sensor and a proximity sensor. The environmental light sensor may regulate brightness of the display screen 941 according to brightness of environmental light, and the proximity sensor may turn off the display screen 941 and/or backlight when the mobile phone is moved to an ear. An accelerometer sensor as a motion sensor may detect a magnitude of an acceleration in each direction (usually three axes), may detect a magnitude and direction of the gravity under a static condition, and may be configured for an application recognizing a posture of the mobile phone (for example, landscape and portrait switching, a related game and magnetometer posture calibration), a function related to vibration recognition and the like (for example, a pedometer and knocking). Other sensors, for example, a gyroscope, a barometer, a hygrometer, a thermometer and an infrared sensor, which may be configured in the mobile phone will not be elaborated herein.</p>
<p id="p0166" num="0166">The audio circuit 960, a speaker 961, and a microphone 962 may provide audio interfaces between the user and the mobile phone. The audio circuit 960 may transmit to the speaker 961 an electric signal obtained by converting received audio data, and the speaker 961 converts the electric signal into a sound signal for playing. On the other hand, the microphone 962 converts a collected sound signal into an electric signal, the audio circuit 960 receives and converts the electric signal into audio data, and the audio data is processed by the processor 980 and transmitted to, for example, another mobile phone through the RF circuit 910, or the audio data is played to the memory 920 for further processing.</p>
<p id="p0167" num="0167">WiFi is a short-distance wireless transmission technology. The mobile phone may help the user through the WiFi module 970 to receive and send an electronic mail, browse a webpage, access streaming media and the like, and wireless wideband Internet access is provided for the user. Although the WiFi module 970 is illustrated in <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 6</figref>, it can be understood that it is not a necessary composition of the mobile phone and may completely be omitted according to a requirement without changing the scope of the essence of the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p0168" num="0168">The processor 980 is a control center of the mobile phone, connects each part of the whole mobile phone by use of various interfaces and lines and executes various<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> functions and data processing of the mobile phone by running or executing the software program and/or module stored in the memory 920 and calling data stored in the memory 920, thereby monitoring the whole mobile phone. In an implementation, the processor 980 may include one or more processing units. The processor 980 may integrate an application processor and a modulation and demodulation processor. The application processor mainly processes the operating system, a user interface, an application program and the like. The modulation and demodulation processor mainly processes wireless communication. It can be understood that the modulation and demodulation processor may also not be integrated into the processor 980.</p>
<p id="p0169" num="0169">The mobile phone further includes the power supply 990 (e.g., battery) supplying power to each part. The power supply may be logically connected with the processor 980 through a power management system, thereby realizing functions of charging and discharging management, power consumption management and the like through the power management system.</p>
<p id="p0170" num="0170">Although not illustrated in the figure, the mobile phone may further include a camera, a Bluetooth module and the like, which will not be elaborated herein.</p>
<p id="p0171" num="0171">In the implementation illustrated in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> or <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 3B</figref>, the flow on a terminal side in each operation of the method may be implemented on the basis of the structure of the mobile phone.</p>
<p id="p0172" num="0172">In the implementation illustrated in <figref idref="f0005">FIG. 4 or FIG. 5</figref>, each functional unit may be implemented on the basis of the structure of the mobile phone.</p>
<p id="p0173" num="0173">The operations of the method or algorithm described in the implementations of the disclosure may be implemented in a hardware manner, and may also be implemented in a manner of executing, by a processor, software. A software instruction may consist of a corresponding software module, and the software module may be stored in a RAM, a flash memory, a Read Only Memory (ROM), an Erasable Programmable ROM (EPROM), an Electrically EPROM (EEPROM), a register, a hard disk, a mobile hard disk, a Compact Disc-ROM (CD-ROM) or a storage medium in any other form well known in the field. An exemplary storage medium is coupled to the processor, thereby enabling the processor to read information from the storage medium and write information into the storage medium. Of course, the storage medium may also be a component of the processor. The processor and the storage medium may be located in an ASIC. In addition, the ASIC may be located in an<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> access network device, a target network device or a core network device. Of course, the processor and the storage medium may also exist in the access network device, the target network device or the core network device as discrete components.</p>
<p id="p0174" num="0174">Those skilled in the art may realize that in one or more abovementioned examples, all or part of the functions described in the implementations of the disclosure may be realized through software, hardware or any combination thereof. During implementation with the software, the implementations may be implemented completely or partially in form of computer program product. The computer program product includes one or more computer instructions. When the computer program instruction is loaded and executed on a computer, the flows or functions according to the implementations of the disclosure are completely or partially generated. The computer may be a universal computer, a dedicated computer, a computer network or another programmable device. The computer instruction may be stored in a computer-readable storage medium or transmitted from a computer-readable storage medium to another computer-readable storage medium. For example, the computer instruction may be transmitted from a website, computer, server or data center to another website, computer, server or data center in a wired (for example, coaxial cable, optical fiber and Digital Subscriber Line (DSL)) or wireless (for example, infrared, wireless and microwave) manner. The computer-readable storage medium may be any available medium accessible for the computer or may be a data storage device including such as a server and a data center integrated by one or more available media. The available medium may be a magnetic medium (for example, a floppy disk, a hard disk and a magnetic tape), an optical medium (for example, a Digital Video Disc (DVD)), a semiconductor medium (for example, a Solid State Disk (SSD)) or the like.</p>
<p id="p0175" num="0175">The abovementioned specific implementation modes further describe the purposes, technical solutions and beneficial effects of the implementations of the disclosure in detail. It is to be understood that the above is only the specific implementation mode of the implementations of the disclosure and not intended to limit the scope of protection of the implementations of the disclosure. The scope of protection of the disclosure should be determined by the scope of the claims.</p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> -->
<claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>A method for determining a total number of bits of feedback response information, comprising:<br/>
receiving (S301), by a terminal, configuration signaling transmitted by a network device, the configuration signaling comprising an indication about a maximum timing value for feedback response information and an indication about a minimum timing value for the feedback response information; <b>characterized by</b> further comprising:
<claim-text>determining (S303), by the terminal, a total number of bits of feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum timing value and the minimum timing value,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the maximum timing value is a maximum time interval between a time unit where downlink data is carried and a time unit where the feedback response information for the downlink data is carried, and the minimum timing value is a minimum time interval between a time unit where downlink data is carried and a time unit where the feedback response information for the downlink data is carried.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>The method of claim 1, further comprising:
<claim-text>after determining, by the terminal, the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum timing value and the minimum timing value,</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting (S304), by the terminal, to the network device the feedback response information to be transmitted with the total number of bits.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>The method of claim 2, wherein a time unit used by the terminal to transmit to the network device the feedback response information to be transmitted with the total number of bits is determined by the terminal according to dynamically determined Hybrid Automatic Repeat Request, HARQ, feedback timing.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>The method of any one of claims 1-3, wherein determining, by the terminal, the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum timing value and the minimum timing value comprises:<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> -->determining, by the terminal, the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to a difference between the maximum timing value and the minimum timing value.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>The method of any one of claims 1-4, wherein determining, by the terminal, the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum timing value and the minimum timing value comprises:
<claim-text>the total number of bits N=C*(T<sub>max</sub>-T<sub>min</sub>),</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein T<sub>max</sub> is the maximum timing value, T<sub>min</sub> is a non-negative integer less than T<sub>max</sub>, and C is a positive integer.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>The method of any one of claims 2-5, wherein transmitting, by the terminal, to the network device the feedback response information to be transmitted with the total number of bits comprises:
<claim-text>transmitting, by the terminal, the feedback response information on which a joint encoding has been performed; or</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting, by the terminal, the feedback response information through a physical channel.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>A device for determining a total number of bits of feedback response information, comprising a processing unit (401) and a transceiver unit (402) connected with the processing unit (401), wherein<br/>
the transceiver unit (402) is configured to receive configuration signaling transmitted by a network device, the configuration signaling comprising an indication about a maximum timing value for feedback response information and an indication about a minimum timing value for the feedback response information; <b>characterized in that</b>:
<claim-text>the processing unit (401) is configured to determine a total number of bits of feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum timing value and the minimum timing value,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the maximum timing value is a maximum time interval between a time unit where downlink data is carried and a time unit where the feedback response<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --> information for the downlink data is carried, and the minimum timing value is a minimum time interval between a time unit where downlink data is carried and a time unit where the feedback response information for the downlink data is carried.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>The device of claim 7, wherein the transceiver unit (402) is further configured to:<br/>
transmit, by a terminal, to the network device the feedback response information to be transmitted with the total number of bits.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>The device of claim 8, wherein a time unit used by the terminal to transmit to the network device the feedback response information to be transmitted with the total number of bits is determined by the terminal according to dynamically determined Hybrid Automatic Repeat Request, HARQ, feedback timing.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>The device of any one of claims 7-9, wherein the processing unit (401) is configured to:<br/>
determine the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to a difference between the maximum timing value and the minimum timing value.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>The device of any one of claims 7-10, wherein
<claim-text>the processing unit (401) is configured to determine the total number of bits of the feedback response information to be transmitted according to the maximum timing value, the total number of bits N=C*(T<sub>max</sub>-T<sub>min</sub>),</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein T<sub>max</sub> is the maximum timing value, T<sub>min</sub> is a non-negative integer less than T<sub>max</sub>, and C is a positive integer.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>The device of claim 11, wherein T<sub>min</sub> is the minimum timing value for transmission of the feedback response information by the terminal.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>The device of claim 11 or 12, wherein C is a maximum number of bits of feedback response information corresponding to a Physical Downlink Shared Channel, PDSCH; or
<claim-text>C is a set constant; or<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>C is a parameter configured by the network device.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>The device of claim 13, wherein the maximum number of bits of the feedback response information corresponding to the PDSCH is:
<claim-text>a maximum number of Transport Blocks, TBs, carried in the PDSCH;</claim-text>
<claim-text>or a maximum number of Code Block, CB, groups carried in the PDSCH.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0015" num="0015">
<claim-text>The device of any one of claims 8-14, wherein
<claim-text>the transceiver unit (402) is configured to transmit the feedback response information on which a joint encoding has been performed; or</claim-text>
<claim-text>the transceiver unit (402) is configured to transmit the feedback response information through a physical channel.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims02" lang="de"><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> -->
<claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Verfahren zum Bestimmen einer Gesamtzahl von Bits von Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen, umfassend:<br/>
Empfangen (S301) einer durch eine Netzwerkvorrichtung übertragenen Konfigurationssignalisierung durch ein Endgerät, wobei die Konfigurationssignalisierung eine Angabe über einen maximalen Zeitwert für Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen und eine Angabe über einen minimalen Zeitwert für die Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen umfasst; <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> sie ferner umfasst:
<claim-text>Bestimmen (S303), durch das Endgerät, einer Gesamtzahl von Bits von Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen, die gemäß dem maximalen Zeitwert und dem minimalen Zeitwert übertragen werden sollen,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei der maximale Zeitwert ein maximales Zeitintervall zwischen einer Zeiteinheit, in der Downlinkdaten getragen werden, und einer Zeiteinheit, in der die Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen für die Downlinkdaten getragen werden, ist, und der minimale Zeitwert ein minimales Zeitintervall zwischen einer Zeiteinheit, in der Downlinkdaten getragen werden, und einer Zeiteinheit, in der die Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen für die Downlinkdaten getragen werden, ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, ferner umfassend:
<claim-text>nach dem Bestimmen, durch das Endgerät, der Gesamtzahl von Bits von Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen, die gemäß<!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --> dem maximalen Zeitwert und dem minimalen Zeitwert übertragen werden sollen,</claim-text>
<claim-text>Übertragen (S304), durch das Endgerät, der Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen, die mit der Gesamtanzahl der Bits an die Netzwerkvorrichtung übertragen werden sollen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 2, wobei eine Zeiteinheit, die von dem Endgerät verwendet wird, um die Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen, die mit der Gesamtzahl der Bits übertragen werden sollen, an die Netzwerkvorrichtung zu übertragen, von dem Endgerät gemäß dynamisch bestimmtem Rückmeldungs-Timing von "Hybrid Automatic Repeat Request", HARQ, bestimmt wird.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 1-3, wobei das Bestimmen, durch das Endgerät, der Gesamtzahl der Bits der Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen, die gemäß dem maximalen Zeitwert und dem minimalen Zeitwert übertragen werden sollen, umfasst:<br/>
Bestimmen, durch das Endgerät, der Gesamtzahl der Bits von Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen, die gemäß einer Differenz zwischen dem maximalen Zeitwert und dem minimalen Zeitwert übertragen werden sollen.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 1-4, wobei das Bestimmen, durch das Endgerät, der Gesamtzahl der Bits der Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen, die gemäß dem maximalen Zeitwert und dem minimalen Zeitwert übertragen werden sollen, umfasst:
<claim-text>die Gesamtzahl der Bits N=C*(T<sub>max</sub>-T<sub>min</sub>),</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei T<sub>max</sub> der maximale Zeitwert ist, T<sub>min</sub> eine nichtnegative ganze Zahl ist, die kleiner als T<sub>max</sub> ist, und C eine positive ganze Zahl ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 2-5, wobei das Übertragen an die Netzwerkvorrichtung, durch das Endgerät, der Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen, die mit der Gesamtanzahl der Bits übertragen werden sollen, umfasst:<!-- EPO <DP n="33"> -->
<claim-text>Übertragen, durch das Endgerät, der Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen, an denen ein gemeinsames Codieren durchgeführt worden ist; oder</claim-text>
<claim-text>Übertragen, durch das Endgerät, der Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen über einen physischen Kanal.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Bestimmen einer Gesamtzahl von Bits von Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen, umfassend eine Verarbeitungseinheit (401) und eine Transceivereinheit (402), die mit der Verarbeitungseinheit (401) verbunden ist, wobei<br/>
die Transceivereinheit (402) dazu ausgelegt ist, eine von einer Netzwerkvorrichtung übertragene Konfigurationssignalisierung zu empfangen, wobei die Konfigurationssignalisierung eine Angabe über einen maximalen Zeitwert für Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen und eine Angabe über einen minimalen Zeitwert für die Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen umfasst; <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b>:
<claim-text>die Verarbeitungseinheit (401) dazu ausgelegt ist, eine Gesamtzahl von Bits von Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen zu bestimmen, die gemäß dem maximalen Zeitwert und dem minimalen Zeitwert übertragen werden sollen,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei der maximale Zeitwert ein maximales Zeitintervall zwischen einer Zeiteinheit, in der Downlinkdaten getragen werden, und einer Zeiteinheit, in der die Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen für die Downlinkdaten getragen werden, ist, und der minimale Zeitwert ein minimales Zeitintervall zwischen einer Zeiteinheit, in der Downlinkdaten getragen werden, und einer Zeiteinheit, in der die Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen für die Downlinkdaten getragen werden, ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 7, wobei die Transceivereinheit (402) ferner dazu ausgelegt ist:<br/>
durch das Endgerät die Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen an die Netzwerkvorrichtung zu übertragen, die mit der Gesamtzahl der Bits übertragen werden sollen.<!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 8, wobei eine Zeiteinheit, die von dem Endgerät verwendet wird, um die Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen, die mit der Gesamtzahl der Bits übertragen werden sollen, an die Netzwerkvorrichtung zu übermitteln, von dem Endgerät gemäß dynamisch bestimmtem Rückmeldungs-Timing von "Hybrid Automatic Repeat Request", HARQ, bestimmt wird.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>Vorrichtung nach einem der Ansprüche 7-9, wobei die Verarbeitungseinheit (401) dazu ausgelegt ist:<br/>
die Gesamtzahl der Bits der Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen, die gemäß einer Differenz zwischen dem maximalen Zeitwert und dem minimalen Zeitwert übertragen werden sollen, zu bestimmen.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>Vorrichtung nach einem der Ansprüche 7-10, wobei die Verarbeitungseinheit (401) dazu ausgelegt ist, die Gesamtzahl der Bits der Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen, die gemäß dem maximalen Zeitwert übertragen werden sollen, zu bestimmen, wobei die Gesamtzahl der Bits N=C*(T<sub>max</sub>-T<sub>min</sub>) ist,<br/>
wobei T<sub>max</sub> der maximale Zeitwert ist, T<sub>min</sub> eine nichtnegative ganze Zahl ist, die kleiner als T<sub>max</sub> ist, und C eine positive ganze Zahl ist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 11, wobei T<sub>min</sub> der minimale Zeitwert für das Übertragen der Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen durch das Endgerät ist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 11 oder 12, wobei C eine maximale Anzahl von Bits von Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen ist, die einem "Physical Downlink Shared Channel", PDSCH, entsprechen, oder
<claim-text>C eine eingestellte Konstante ist; oder</claim-text>
<claim-text>C ein durch die Netzwerkvorrichtung ausgelegter Parameter ist.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 13, wobei die maximale Anzahl von Bits der Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen, die dem PDSCH entsprechen, beträgt:
<claim-text>eine maximale Anzahl von Transportblöcken, TBs, die im PDSCH getragen werden;</claim-text>
<claim-text>oder eine maximale Anzahl von im PDSCH getragenen Code Block, CB-, Gruppen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0015" num="0015">
<claim-text>Vorrichtung nach einem der Ansprüche 8-14, wobei die Transceivereinheit (402) dazu ausgelegt ist, die Rückmeldungsantwortinformation zu übertragen, an der eine gemeinsame Codierung durchgeführt worden ist; oder die Transceivereinheit (402) dazu ausgelegt ist, die Rückmeldungsantwortinformationen über einen physikalischen Kanal zu übertragen.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims03" lang="fr"><!-- EPO <DP n="36"> -->
<claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Procédé destiné à déterminer un nombre total de bits d'informations de réponse de retour, comprenant :<br/>
la réception (S301), par un terminal, d'une signalisation de configuration transmise par un dispositif réseau, la signalisation de configuration comprenant une indication sur une valeur maximale de minutage pour des informations de réponse de retour et une indication sur une valeur minimale de minutage pour les informations de réponse de retour ; <b>caractérisé en ce qu'</b>il comprend en outre :
<claim-text>la détermination (S303), par le terminal, d'un nombre total de bits d'informations de réponse de retour à transmettre en fonction de la valeur maximale de minutage et de la valeur minimale de minutage,</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel la valeur maximale de minutage est un intervalle de temps maximal entre une unité de temps où des données en liaison descendante sont transportées et une unité de temps où les informations de réponse de retour pour les données en liaison descendante sont transportées, et la valeur minimale de minutage est un intervalle de temps minimal entre une unité de temps où des données en liaison descendante sont transportées et une unité de temps où les informations de réponse de retour pour les données en liaison descendante sont transportées.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Procédé de la revendication 1, comprenant en outre :<!-- EPO <DP n="37"> -->
<claim-text>après la détermination, par le terminal, du nombre total de bits des informations de réponse de retour à transmettre en fonction de la valeur maximale de minutage et de la valeur minimale de minutage,</claim-text>
<claim-text>la transmission (S304), par le terminal au dispositif réseau, des informations de réponse de retour à transmettre avec le nombre total de bits.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Procédé de la revendication 2, dans lequel une unité de temps utilisée par le terminal pour transmettre au dispositif réseau les informations de réponse de retour à transmettre avec le nombre total de bits est déterminée par le terminal en fonction d'un minutage de retour de requête de répétition automatique hybride, HARQ, déterminé dynamiquement.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Procédé de l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 3, dans lequel la détermination, par le terminal, du nombre total de bits des informations de réponse de retour à transmettre en fonction de la valeur maximale de minutage et de la valeur minimale de minutage comprend :<br/>
la détermination, par le terminal, du nombre total de bits des informations de réponse de retour à transmettre en fonction d'une différence entre la valeur maximale de minutage et la valeur minimale de minutage.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Procédé de l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 4, dans lequel la détermination, par le terminal, du nombre total de bits des informations de réponse de retour à transmettre en fonction de la valeur maximale de minutage et de la valeur minimale de minutage comprend :
<claim-text>le nombre total de bits N = C*(T<sub>max</sub>-T<sub>min</sub>),</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel T<sub>max</sub> est la valeur maximale de minutage, T<sub>min</sub> est un entier non négatif inférieur à T<sub>max</sub>, et C est un entier positif.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Procédé de l'une quelconque des revendications 2 à 5, dans lequel la transmission, par le terminal au<!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --> dispositif réseau, des informations de réponse de retour à transmettre avec le nombre total de bits comprend :
<claim-text>la transmission, par le terminal, des informations de réponse de retour sur lesquelles un codage conjoint a été effectué ; ou</claim-text>
<claim-text>la transmission, par le terminal, des informations de réponse de retour par un canal physique.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Dispositif destiné à déterminer un nombre total de bits d'informations de réponse de retour, comprenant une unité de traitement (401) et une unité émettrice-réceptrice (402) reliée à l'unité de traitement (401), dans lequel
<claim-text>l'unité émettrice-réceptrice (402) est configurée pour recevoir une signalisation de configuration transmise par un dispositif réseau, la signalisation de configuration comprenant une indication sur une valeur maximale de minutage pour des informations de réponse de retour et une indication sur une valeur minimale de minutage pour les informations de réponse de retour ; <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> :</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'unité de traitement (401) est configurée pour déterminer un nombre total de bits d'informations de réponse de retour à transmettre en fonction de la valeur maximale de minutage et de la valeur minimale de minutage,</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel la valeur maximale de minutage est un intervalle de temps maximal entre une unité de temps où des données en liaison descendante sont transportées et une unité de temps où les informations de réponse de retour pour les données en liaison descendante sont transportées, et la valeur minimale de minutage est un intervalle de temps minimal entre une unité de temps où des données en liaison descendante sont transportées et une unité de temps où les informations de réponse de retour pour les données en liaison descendante sont transportées.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>Dispositif de la revendication 7, dans lequel l'unité émettrice-réceptrice (402) est également configurée pour :<br/>
transmettre, par un terminal au dispositif réseau, les informations de réponse de retour à transmettre avec le nombre total de bits.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>Dispositif de la revendication 8, dans lequel une unité de temps utilisée par le terminal pour transmettre au dispositif réseau les informations de réponse de retour à transmettre avec le nombre total de bits est déterminée par le terminal en fonction d'un minutage de retour de requête de répétition automatique hybride, HARQ, déterminé dynamiquement.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>Dispositif de l'une quelconque des revendications 7 à 9, dans lequel l'unité de traitement (401) est configurée pour :<br/>
déterminer le nombre total de bits des informations de réponse de retour à transmettre en fonction d'une différence entre la valeur maximale de minutage et la valeur minimale de minutage.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>Dispositif de l'une quelconque des revendications 7 à 10, dans lequel
<claim-text>l'unité de traitement (401) est configurée pour déterminer le nombre total de bits des informations de réponse de retour à transmettre en fonction de la valeur maximale de minutage, le nombre total de bits N = C*(T<sub>max</sub>-T<sub>min</sub>),</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel T<sub>max</sub> est la valeur maximale de minutage, T<sub>min</sub> est un entier non négatif inférieur à T<sub>max</sub>, et C est un entier positif.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>Dispositif de la revendication 11, dans lequel T<sub>min</sub> est la valeur minimale de minutage pour la transmission des informations de réponse de retour par le terminal.<!-- EPO <DP n="40"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>Dispositif de la revendication 11 ou 12, dans lequel C est un nombre maximal de bits d'informations de réponse de retour correspondant à un canal physique partagé de liaison descendante, PDSCH ; ou
<claim-text>C est une constante définie ; ou</claim-text>
<claim-text>C est un paramètre configuré par le dispositif réseau.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>Dispositif de la revendication 13, dans lequel le nombre maximal de bits des informations de réponse de retour correspondant au PDSCH est :
<claim-text>un nombre maximal de blocs de transport, TB, transportés dans le PDSCH ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>ou un nombre maximal de groupes de blocs de code, CB, transportés dans le PDSCH.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0015" num="0015">
<claim-text>Dispositif de l'une quelconque des revendications 8 à 14, dans lequel
<claim-text>l'unité émettrice-réceptrice (402) est configurée pour transmettre les informations de réponse de retour sur lesquelles un codage conjoint a été effectué ; ou</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'unité émettrice-réceptrice (402) est configurée pour transmettre les informations de réponse de retour par un canal physique.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="41"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1,1A"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="136" he="176" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="42"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="2,2A"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="136" he="188" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="43"> -->
<figure id="f0003" num="3,3A"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="134" he="187" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="44"> -->
<figure id="f0004" num="3B,3C"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="127" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="45"> -->
<figure id="f0005" num="4,4A,5"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="95" he="208" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="46"> -->
<figure id="f0006" num="5A,6"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="143" he="194" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<ep-reference-list id="ref-list">
<heading id="ref-h0001"><b>REFERENCES CITED IN THE DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0001" num=""><i>This list of references cited by the applicant is for the reader's convenience only. It does not form part of the European patent document. Even though great care has been taken in compiling the references, errors or omissions cannot be excluded and the EPO disclaims all liability in this regard.</i></p>
<heading id="ref-h0002"><b>Patent documents cited in the description</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0002" num="">
<ul id="ref-ul0001" list-style="bullet">
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0001" dnum="CN2017096656W" dnum-type="L"><document-id><country>CN</country><doc-number>2017096656</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20170809</date></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0001">[0001]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0002" dnum="WO2018081785A"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2018081785</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20180403</date></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0002">[0001]</crossref></li>
</ul></p>
</ep-reference-list>
</ep-patent-document>
