<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP21155881A1" file="EP21155881NWA1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3889253" kind="A1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSK..HRIS..MTNORS..SM..................</B001EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  1100000/0</B007EP><B053EP>This application was filed on 08-02-2021 as a divisional application to the application mentioned under INID code 62.</B053EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3889253</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT APPLICATION</B121></B120><B130>A1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>21155881.2</B210><B220><date>20161222</date></B220><B250>en</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B300><B310>15202329</B310><B320><date>20151223</date></B320><B330><ctry>EP</ctry></B330><B310>16190399</B310><B320><date>20160923</date></B320><B330><ctry>EP</ctry></B330></B300><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B430></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>C12N   5/0784      20100101AFI20210723BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>C12N   5/0639      20130101 LI20170327BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>C12N2510/00        20130101 LA20170310BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="3"><text>C12N2502/1114      20130101 LA20190517BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="4"><text>C12N2501/22        20130101 LA20190103BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="5"><text>C07K2319/03        20130101 LA20170921BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="6"><text>C12N2501/2304      20130101 LA20190103BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="7"><text>C12N   5/0638      20130101 LI20190517BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="8"><text>C12N2506/115       20130101 LA20190103BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="9"><text>C07K  14/4748      20130101 FI20190104BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="10"><text>C12N2501/24        20130101 LA20190103BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="11"><text>A61K2039/5154      20130101 LA20170310BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="12"><text>C07K2319/02        20130101 LA20170921BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="13"><text>C07K2319/06        20130101 LA20170310BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="14"><text>A61K  38/00        20130101 LI20170810BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="15"><text>A61P  35/00        20180101 LI20190103BHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>ZUSAMMENSETZUNG AUS DENDRITISCHEN ZELLEN</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>DENDRITIC CELL COMPOSITION</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>COMPOSITION DE CELLULES DENDRITIQUES</B542></B540><B590><B598>NONE</B598></B590></B500><B600><B620><parent><pdoc><dnum><anum>16825765.7</anum><pnum>3394248</pnum></dnum><date>20161222</date></pdoc></parent></B620></B600><B700><B710><B711><snm>Medigene Immunotherapies GmbH</snm><iid>101528132</iid><irf>M10978WOEPD1/DJB</irf><adr><str>Lochhamer Straße 11</str><city>82152 Planegg-Martinsried</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B711><B711><snm>Helmholtz Zentrum München Deutsches 
Forschungszentrum für Gesundheit 
und Umwelt (GmbH)</snm><iid>101007319</iid><irf>M10978WOEPD1/DJB</irf><adr><str>Ingolstädter Landstrasse 1</str><city>85764 Neuherberg</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B711></B710><B720><B721><snm>MILOSEVIC, Slavoljub</snm><adr><str>Maria-Montessori-Str. 6</str><city>81829 München</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>ELLINGER, Christian</snm><adr><str>Reisingerstr. 3</str><city>80337 München</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>WEHNER, Carina</snm><adr><str>Helene-Mayer-Ring 12</str><city>80809 München</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>SCHENDEL, Dolores</snm><adr><str>Hans-Sachs-Str. 12 IV</str><city>80469 München</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B740><B741><snm>Wünsche, Annelie</snm><iid>101675371</iid><adr><str>Maiwald Patentanwalts- und 
Rechtsanwaltsgesellschaft mbH 
Elisenhof 
Elisenstraße 3</str><city>80335 München</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840></B800></SDOBI>
<abstract id="abst" lang="en">
<p id="pa01" num="0001">The present invention contemplates dendritic cell compositions. The dendritic cell compositions employ MHC class-II targeting signals fused to an antigen or fragment thereof to obtain MHC II presentation of the antigen or fragment thereof.</p>
<p id="pa02" num="0002">In particular, the invention refers to a dendritic cell vaccine comprising dendritic cells expressing a MHC class-II targeting signal fused to an antigen or fragment thereof. Dendritic cell vaccines for the stimulation of an immune response against melanoma-associated antigen are also described.</p>
</abstract>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<heading id="h0001"><b>FIELD OF THE INVENTION</b></heading>
<p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention contemplates dendritic cell compositions. The dendritic cell compositions employ MHC class-II targeting signals fused to an antigen or fragment thereof to obtain MHC II presentation of the antigen or fragment thereof.</p>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">In particular, the invention refers to a dendritic cell vaccine comprising dendritic cells expressing a MHC class-II targeting signal fused to an antigen or fragment thereof. Dendritic cell vaccines for the stimulation of an immune response against melanoma-associated antigen are also described.</p>
<heading id="h0002"><b>BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</b></heading>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">Dendritic cells represent a very potent agent in immune therapy because they can efficiently prime naive T cells during development of T cell-mediated immunity and stimulate adaptive immune responses. Dendritic cells have the ability to activate immune responses not only against pathogens, but also against malignant cells. In vivo, immature- or intermediate-stage dendritic cells patrol peripheral tissues to capture and process antigens. Under the influence of local cytokines and danger signals, dendritic cells undergo complex maturation processes and migrate to regional lymph nodes, where they form immunological synapses with T cells and present peptides derived from collected antigens in context with MHC class-I or -II molecules. CD4+ T cell activation is dependent on MHC-II complex binding, while CD8+ interaction is dependent on MHC I binding.</p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">The dendritic cell licensing model describes an indirect CD4<sup>+</sup> T cell help for CD8<sup>+</sup> T cells by interaction mediated activation that enables dendritic cells to provide costimulatory signals. Thus, for an efficient immune response against tumors, CD4<sup>+</sup> T cell help has acquired an essential role as more and more is known about their important role for the expansion and memory generation of antigen-specific CD8<sup>+</sup> T cells. Moreover, as tumor-antigens are mostly self-antigens which do not provide a "danger signal" like pathogenic antigens (e.g. PAMPs: pathogen-associated molecular patterns) the CD4<sup>+</sup> T cell help is crucial for the induction of a CD8<sup>+</sup> T cell memory.</p>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">As a consequence, improved dendritic cell vaccines that facilitate that the immune system of a patient can attack his own tumor cells and build long-lasting immunity are needed. It is desired that the vaccine induces higher proliferation of T cells, enhanced activation induced IFN γ secretion of T cells and higher tumor killing capacity of T cells.</p>
<heading id="h0003"><b>OBJECTIVES AND SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</b></heading>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">Therefore, it is an objective of the invention to provide an advanced dendritic cell vaccine<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> that allows the presentation of the antigen on the MHC II complex.</p>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">Therefore, a first aspect of the invention contemplates a dendritic cell composition comprising dendritic cells expressing at least one fusion protein comprising
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="dash" compact="compact">
<li>at least one antigen or a fragment thereof,</li>
<li>an endoplasmatic reticulum (ER)- translocation signal sequence preceding the N-terminus of the antigen, and</li>
<li>a transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence following the C-terminus of the antigen.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">Further, the additional stimulation of antigen-specific CD8+ T cells for an improved immune response is desired.</p>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">Thus, in a preferred embodiment the dendritic cell composition further comprises dendritic cells expressing at least one antigen or a fragment thereof wherein the antigen is not fused to a targeting signal sequence that promotes the MHC II presentation of the antigen or fragment thereof.</p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">Typically, the targeting signal sequence that promotes the MHC II presentation is at least one selected from the group consisting of
<ul id="ul0002" list-style="dash" compact="compact">
<li>an endoplasmatic reticulum (ER)-translocation signal sequence preceding the N-terminus of the antigen, and</li>
<li>a transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence following the C-terminus of the antigen.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">Usually, the fusion protein and the antigen (which is not fused to a targeting signal sequence) are transiently or stably expressed, preferably stably expressed. For example, the transient expression may be carried out by introducing ivt-RNA.</p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">In some embodiments, the endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence is derived from DC-LAMP. Preferably, the endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence is human. One embodiment refers to a dendritic cell composition as described herein, wherein the endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence comprises the sequence SEQ ID NO: 3 or a fragment thereof. In a specific embodiment, the endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence comprises the sequence SEQ ID NO: 14 or a fragment thereof.</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">The ER translocation signal sequence may be derived from an endosomal/lysosomal associated protein. Preferably, the ER translocation signal sequence is derived from LAMP1. More preferably the ER translocation signal sequence comprises the sequence SEQ ID NO: 1 or a fragment thereof.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">In some embodiments, the dendritic cells are mature dendritic cells generated by a method comprising the following steps:
<ol id="ol0001" compact="compact" ol-style="">
<li>(i) provision of monocytes;</li>
<li>(ii) incubation of the monocytes of step i) with IL-4 and GM-CSF;</li>
<li>(iii) incubation of the monocytes of step ii) with IL-4 and GM-CSF in combination with a maturation cocktail.</li>
</ol></p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">For example, the maturation cocktail comprises a combination of IL-β, TNF-α, IFN-γ, TLR7/8 agonist, PGE2 and TLR3 agonist. The incubation of step ii) may last at least 2 days. The incubation of step iii) may last at least 12 hours, preferably 24 hours. Preferably the TLR7/8 agonist is R848 and the TLR3 agonist is poly(I:C).</p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">In specific embodiments the antigen is MELAN-A.</p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">Another aspect of the invention refers to a dendritic cell vaccine comprising the dendritic cell composition as described herein. Preferably, the dendritic cells are autologous cells.</p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">Typically, the dendritic cell composition and the dendritic cell vaccine are pharmaceutically acceptable fluid compositions.</p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">Another aspect of the invention refers to a dendritic cell composition according to the invention or dendritic cell vaccine according to the invention for use as a medicament.</p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">One embodiment of the invention relates to a dendritic cell vaccine as described herein for use in the treatment of cancer.</p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">Specific embodiments refer to a dendritic cell composition or dendritic cell vaccine according to the invention for use in stimulating an immune response against a melanoma-associated antigen. In a specific embodiment, the melanoma-associated antigen is MELAN-A.</p>
<heading id="h0004"><b>FIGURE LEGENDS</b></heading>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">
<ul id="ul0003" list-style="none">
<li><figref idref="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref><b>: Experimental overview of the vaccination procedure.</b><br/>
On day one, 16 mice divided into four different groups were engrafted each with 10 × 106 million human PBMC from a healthy HLA-A*02:01-positive donor. The peripheral T cell repertoire was reconstituted within the following 14 days. Vaccination was applied on day 14 and on day 21, administering 1 × 10<sup>6</sup> mature dendritic cells transfected with either conventional ivt-RNA (2) or CrossTAg-ivt-RNA (3). In addition, one group received a 1:1 mixture of mature dendritic cells transfected with either CrossTAg- or conventional ivt-RNA<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> (4). The control group was not vaccinated (1). On day 28, splenic cells were isolated and screened for Melan-A specific CD8+ T cells by multimer staining using an HLA-A*02:01-Melan-A-specific multimer. Remaining splenic cells were restimulated in vitro with appropriate dendritic cells and expanded for another 10 days. Splenic cells isolated from the control group received only human IL-2 for further in vitro cultivation. Quantification of Melan-A specific CD8+ T cells and functionality tests, like IFN-γ-secretion assays and cytotoxicity assays, were conducted on day 38.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002"><b>Figure 2</b></figref><b>: Maturation and electroporation of dendritic cells.</b><br/>
Mature dendritic cells used for vaccination on day 14 (1. vaccination) and day 21 (2. vaccination) were generated by isolation of monocytes from a healthy HLA-A*02:01 blood donor which were then matured following the 3d DC protocol comprising IL-β, TNF-α, IFN-γ, the TLR7/8 agonist R848, PGE2 and TLR3. (A) To verify the maturation status, dendritic cells were stained with monoclonal antibodies binding to different surface markers specific for either mature (CD80, CD83, CD86, CD40, CCR7, CD209 and HLA-DR) or immature (CD14) cells and analyzed by FACS analysis. Isotype control antibodies served as a negative control. (B) Prior to administration, mature dendritic cells were transfected with either CrossTAg-Melan-A- or conventional Melan-A-ivt-RNA. After 6 hours of incubation, Melan-A expression was validated by intracellular staining (APC) of Melan-A protein.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003"><b>Figure 3</b></figref><b>: Multimer-staining of isolated in vitro expanded splenocytes.</b><br/>
(A) Schematic illustration of multimer-stainings: MHC-molecules (HLA-A*02:01) are interlinked and labeled by a fluorescence marker (phycoerythrine, PE). For comparison of induction efficiency of different DC vaccines, CD8- and multimer-double positive cells were taken into account. Number of Melan-A specific CD8+ T cells in splenic populations was measured (B) ex vivo and after (C) in vitro expansion for another 10 days with corresponding dendritic cells and IL-2 (control group was only treated with IL-2). Cells were stained with HLA-A*02:01-Melan-A-multimer and monoclonal antibodies for CD8. Each graph summarizes percentage of Melan-A specific CD8+ T cells from each NSG recipient in an exemplary experiment. Analyzed were 3 individual experiments with a total of 16 mice per experiment.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0004"><b>Figure 4</b></figref><b>: Capability of cytokine secretion by Melan-A specific CD8+ T cells.</b><br/>
(A) Reactivity of Melan-A specific CD8+ T cells was investigated by IFN-γ secretion 10 days after in vitro restimulation of the splenocytes. Expanded splenocytes were cocultured in a 1:1 ratio with target cells for 24 hours. Applied target cells were K562 cells (MHC-I and -II negative), K562-A2 (HLA-A02:01+) incubated with or without Melan-A-peptide for 2 hours and Mel624.38 (HLA-A02:01+, Melan-A+). Number of IFN-γ spots was detected with an ELISpot-reader (C.T.L.). Every data point shown in the graph represents the number of FN-g spots from activated T cells derived from one mouse. Analyzed were three individual experiments with a total of 16 mice in each experiment (one exemplary experiment shown).<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> (B) NMC-I and -II expression on the target cell line Mel624.38 was analyzed using monoclonal panMHC-I or panMHC-II antibodies. Mini-Epstein-Barr virus-(EBV)-transformed lymphoblastoid cell line (mLCL) served as a positive control, unstained cells functioned as a negative control.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0005"><b>Figure 5</b></figref><b>: Killing capacity of expanded splenocytes.</b><br/>
Target cells were labeled with radioactive chromium which can be detected in the supernatant if the cells were lysed. Different tumor cell lines were used as target cells. Expanded splenocytes were cocultured in different ratios with target cells (splenocytes:APC = 80:1; 40:1; 20:1; 10:1) for 4 hours before released radioactive chromium in the supernatants was measured. Various target cells were applied: to envision the NK cell activity within the splenocyte population K562 (MHC-I-/-II-) were chosen. As positive controls K562-A2 (Melan-A-, HLA-A*02:01+) loaded with Melan-A-peptide or Mel624.38 (Melan A+, HLA-A*02:01+) were used. MelA375 (Melan A-, HLA-A*02:01+) served as a negative control. Every data point shown in the graph represents the mean value shown with standard deviation calculated from two measured values. Analyzed were three individual experiments with a total of 16 mice in each experiment (one exemplary experiment shown).</li>
</ul></p>
<heading id="h0005"><b>DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</b></heading>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">Before the invention is described in detail with respect to some of its preferred embodiments, the following general definitions are provided.</p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">The present invention as illustratively described in the following may suitably be practiced in the absence of any element or elements, limitation or limitations, not specifically disclosed herein.</p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">The present invention will be described with respect to particular embodiments and with reference to certain figures but the invention is not limited thereto but only by the claims.</p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">Where the term "comprising" is used in the present description and claims, it does not exclude other elements. For the purposes of the present invention, the term "consisting of' is considered to be a preferred embodiment of the term "comprising of'. If hereinafter a group is defined to comprise at least a certain number of embodiments, this is also to be understood to disclose a group which preferably consists only of these embodiments.</p>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">Where an indefinite or definite article is used when referring to a singular noun, e.g. "a", "an" or "the", this includes a plural of that noun unless something else is specifically stated.</p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">As used herein, the term "expression" refers to the process by which a polypeptide is produced based on the nucleic acid sequence of a gene. Accordingly, the term "expressed"<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> protein or polypeptide comprises, without limitation, intracellular, transmembrane and secreted proteins or polypeptides.</p>
<p id="p0029" num="0029">Technical terms are used by their common sense. If a specific meaning is conveyed to certain terms, definitions of terms will be given in the following in the context of which the terms are used.</p>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">One aspect of the present invention refers to a dendritic cell composition comprising dendritic cells expressing an antigen or fragment thereof wherein the antigen or fragment thereof is fused to a targeting signal sequence that promotes the MHC II presentation of the antigen or fragment thereof.</p>
<p id="p0031" num="0031">More specifically, the present invention refers to a dendritic cell composition comprising dendritic cells expressing at least one fusion protein comprising
<ul id="ul0004" list-style="dash" compact="compact">
<li>at least one antigen or a fragment thereof,</li>
<li>an endoplasmatic reticulum (ER)- translocation signal sequence preceding the N-terminus of the antigen or fragment thereof, and</li>
<li>a transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence following the C-terminus of the antigen or fragment thereof.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032">The fragment may be a sequence of the antigen that is specific for this antigen, i.e. does not occur in another protein or peptide of a mammal, especially of a human. The fragment may be shorter than the sequence of the antigen, such as at least 5%, at least 10%, at least 30%, at least 50%, at least 70%, at least 90% shorter than the antigen. The fragment may have a length of at least 9, at least 10, at least 11, at least 12, at least 13, at least 14, at least 15 or more amino acids.</p>
<p id="p0033" num="0033">The administration of a dendritic cell composition comprising dendritic cells expressing the antigen fused to a targeting signal sequence leads to an increase of the antigen specific CD8<sup>+</sup> T cells compared to the administration of a dendritic cell composition comprising dendritic cells expressing the conventional antigen without fusion to a targeting signal sequence. Therefore dendritic cells expressing the antigen fused to a targeting signal sequence provide a superior induction capacity, an improved capability of IFN-γ secretion upon stimulation and a high killing capacity compared to dendritic cells solely expressing the conventional antigen without fusion to a targeting signal sequence.</p>
<p id="p0034" num="0034">In a specific embodiment the dendritic cell composition further comprises dendritic cells expressing at least one antigen or a fragment thereof wherein the antigen is not fused to a targeting signal sequence that promotes the MHC II presentation of the antigen or fragment thereof.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p>
<p id="p0035" num="0035">That means that the dendritic cell composition comprises (i) dendritic cells expressing at least one antigen which is fused to a targeting signal sequence that promotes the MHC II presentation of the antigen or fragment thereof and (ii) dendritic cells expressing at least one antigen or fragment thereof which is not fused to a targeting signal sequence that promotes the MHC II presentation of the antigen or fragment thereof.</p>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">In other words, the present invention refers to a dendritic cell composition comprising
<ol id="ol0002" compact="compact" ol-style="">
<li>(i) dendritic cells expressing at least one fusion protein comprising
<ul id="ul0005" list-style="dash" compact="compact">
<li>at least one antigen or a fragment thereof,</li>
<li>an endoplasmatic reticulum (ER)- translocation signal sequence preceding the N-terminus of the antigen or fragment thereof, and</li>
<li>a transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence following the C-terminus of the antigen or fragment thereof, and</li>
</ul></li>
<li>(ii) dendritic cells expressing at least one antigen or a fragment thereof without
<ul id="ul0006" list-style="dash" compact="compact">
<li>an endoplasmatic reticulum (ER)- translocation signal sequence preceding the N-terminus of the antigen or fragment thereof, and</li>
<li>a transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence following the C-terminus of the antigen or fragment thereof.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol></p>
<p id="p0037" num="0037">In a preferred embodiment, the antigen of (i) and (ii) is the same antigen. For example, this means that a specific embodiment of the invention refers to a dendritic cell composition comprising
<ol id="ol0003" compact="compact" ol-style="">
<li>(i) dendritic cells expressing at least one fusion protein comprising
<ul id="ul0007" list-style="dash" compact="compact">
<li>MELAN-A antigen or a fragment thereof,</li>
<li>an endoplasmatic reticulum (ER)- translocation signal sequence preceding the N-terminus of the MELAN-A antigen or a fragment thereof, and</li>
<li>a transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence following the C-terminus of the MELAN-A antigen or a fragment thereof, and</li>
</ul></li>
<li>(ii) dendritic cells expressing the MELAN-A antigen or a fragment thereof without
<ul id="ul0008" list-style="dash" compact="compact">
<li>an endoplasmatic reticulum (ER)- translocation signal sequence preceding the N-terminus of the MELAN-A antigen or fragment thereof, and</li>
<li>a transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence following the C-terminus of the MELAN-A antigen or fragment thereof.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol></p>
<p id="p0038" num="0038">The administration of a mixture of dendritic cells expressing the antigen fused to a targeting signal sequence and dendritic cells expressing the antigen without fusion to a<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> targeting signal sequence leads to an increase of the antigen specific CD8<sup>+</sup> T cells. Therefore, said mixture provides a superior induction capacity compared to dendritic cells solely expressing the antigen without fusion to a targeting signal sequence or dendritic cells solely expressing the antigen with fusion to a targeting signal sequence. The mixture also showed a high capability of IFN-γ secretion upon stimulation and a high killing capacity.</p>
<p id="p0039" num="0039">The antigen be it with or without fusion to a targeting signal sequence that promotes MHC II presentation may be introduced into the dendritic cells, for example by means of transient expression or stable expression. In other words, expression of the antigen, be it with or without fusion to a targeting signal sequence that promotes MHC II presentation, may be transient expression or stable expression. In preferred embodiments the expression is transient expression, for example by introducing ivt-RNA coding for the at least one fusion protein. The expression of ivt-RNA has the advantage that quality-controlled ivt-RNA can be rapidly produced and carries no immunogenic protein contaminants.</p>
<p id="p0040" num="0040">The ER translocation signal sequence may be derived from an endosomal/lysosomal associated protein.</p>
<p id="p0041" num="0041">The ER-translocation signal sequence used in the disclosed method may be the sorting sequence of an endosomal/lysosomal localized protein. Endosomal/lysosomal localized proteins as used herein refer to proteins which are localized in the membrane or the lumen of the endosomes and/or the lysosomes of a cell.</p>
<p id="p0042" num="0042">Examples for endosomal or lysosomal localized proteins are glycosidases such as, alpha-galactosidase A/GLA, endo-beta-N-acetylglucosaminidase H/Endo H, alpha-N-acetylgalactosaminidase/NAGA, galactosylceramidase/GALC, alpha-N-acetylglucosaminidase/NAGLU, glucosylceramidase/GBA, alpha-galactosidase/a-Gal, heparanase/HPSE, alpha-L-fucosidase, heparinase I, tissue alpha-L-fucosidase/FUCA1, heparinase II, beta-galactosidase-1/GLB1, heparinase III, beta-glucuronidase/GUSB, hexosaminidase A/HEXA, beta (1-3)-galactosidase, hyaluronan Lyase, beta (1-4)-galactosidase, hyaluronidase 1/HYAL1, chitinase 3-like 1, hyaluronidase 4/HYAL4, chitinase 3-like 2, alpha-L-iduronidase/IDUA, chitinase 3-like 3/ECF-L, chitobiase/CTBS, chitotriosidase/CHIT1, lactase-like protein/LCTL, chondroitin B Lyase/chondroitinase B, lysosomal alpha-glucosidase, chondroitinase ABC, MBD4, chondroitinase AC, NEU-1/Sialidase-1, cytosolic beta-glucosidase/GBA3, O-GlcNAcase/OGA, endo-beta-N-acetylglucosaminidase F1/Endo F1, PNGase F, endo-beta-N-acetylglucosaminidase F3/Endo F3, SPAM1; lysosomal proteases such as, AMSH/STAMBP, cathepsin H, cathepsin 3, cathepsin K, cathepsin 6, cathepsin L, cathepsin 7/cathepsin 1, cathepsin O, cathepsin A/lysosomal carboxypeptidase A, cathepsin S, cathepsin B, cathepsin V, cathepsin C/DPPI, cathepsin X/Z/P, cathepsin D, galactosylceramidase/GALC, cathepsin<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> F, öegumain/asparaginyl endopeptidase; sulfatases such as arylsulfatase A/ARSA, iduronate 2-sulfatase/IDS, arylsulfatase B/ARSB, N-acetylgalactosamine-6-sulfatase/GALNSv, arylsulfatase G/ARSG, sulfamidase/SGSH, glucosamine (N-acetyl)-6-sulfatase/GNS, sulfatase-2/SULF2; or other lysosomal proteins such as BAD-LAMP/LAMP5; hyaluronidase 1/HYAL1; CD63; LAMP1/CD107a; CD-M6PR; LAMP2/CD107b; clathrin Heavy Chain 1/CHC17; Rab27a; clathrin Heavy Chain 2/CHC22; UNC13D, CD68, CDlb or DC-LAMP</p>
<p id="p0043" num="0043">The ER translocation signal sequence may be derived from an endosomal/lysosomal associated protein. The endosomal/lysosomal associated protein may be LAMP1, LAMP2, DC-LAMP, CD68 or CD1b, preferably LAMP1. Preferably, the ER translocation signal is human. The ER translocation signal sequence may comprise the sequence of at least one of SEQ ID NO: 1, SEQ ID NO: 6, SEQ ID NO: 8, SEQ ID NO: 10 and SEQ ID NO: 12. In some embodiments the ER translocation signal sequence may comprise the sequence of at least one of the sequences selected from the group consisting of SEQ ID NO: 2, SEQ ID NO: 7, SEQ ID NO: 9, SEQ ID NO: 11, SEQ ID NO: 13. In some embodiments the ER translocation signal sequence may consist of one of the sequences selected from the group consisting of SEQ ID NO: 2, SEQ ID NO: 7, SEQ ID NO: 9, SEQ ID NO: 11, SEQ ID NO: 13. In specific embodiments the ER translocation signal sequence comprises the sequence SEQ ID NO: 1 or a fragment thereof. In more specific embodiments the ER translocation signal sequence consists of the sequence SEQ ID NO: 2.</p>
<p id="p0044" num="0044">The endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence may be derived from LAMP1 or DC-LAMP, preferably DC-LAMP. The endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence is typically a part of a transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain. Thus, the transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence may be derived from LAMP1 or DC-LAMP, preferably DC-LAMP. Preferably the transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence is human. Typically the endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence comprises the motif Y-XX followed by a hydrophobic amino acid (SEQ ID NO: 4). Preferably, the endosomal/lysosomal targeting signal sequence is YQRI (SEQ ID NO: 5). For example, the transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence may comprise the sequence SEQ ID NO: 14 or a fragment thereof.</p>
<p id="p0045" num="0045">The term hydrophobic amino acid is well known to the skilled person. Examples for hydrophobic amino acids are Ala, Ile, Leu, Phe, Val, Pro, Gly, Met, Trp, Tyr, Pro, Cys.</p>
<p id="p0046" num="0046">The dendritic cells may comprise different populations of antigen presenting cells, each population expressing a different antigen fusion protein.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></p>
<p id="p0047" num="0047">Typically, the dendritic cells are mature dendritic cells, generated by a method comprising the following steps: i) provision of monocytes; ii) incubation of the monocytes of step i) with IL-4 and GM-CSF; iii) incubation of the monocytes of step ii) with IL-4 and GM-CSF in combination with a maturation cocktail.</p>
<p id="p0048" num="0048">The maturation cocktail may comprise at least one of the components selected from the group consisting of IL-β, TNF-α, IFN-γ, TLR7/8 agonist, PGE2 and TLR3 agonist or a combination thereof. The TLR7/8 agonist may be R848 or CL075. The TLR3 agonist may be poly(I:C). For example, the maturation cocktail may comprise a combination of IFN-γ, TLR7/8 agonist, PGE2, such as a combination of IFN-γ, TLR7/8 agonist, PGE2, and TLR3 agonist. In a specific embodiment, the maturation cocktail may comprise a combination of IL-β, TNF-α, IFN-γ, TLR7/8 agonist and PGE2. In another specific embodiment, the maturation cocktail may comprise a combination of IL-β, TNF-α, IFN-γ, TLR7/8 agonist, PGE2 and TLR3 agonist. The invention also relates to maturation cocktails as described herein. Further, the invention also relates to <i>in vitro</i> maturation of at least one immature dendritic cell, comprising stimulating at least one immature dendritic cell with the maturation cocktails as described herein.</p>
<p id="p0049" num="0049">The incubation of step ii) may last for at least 2 days. The incubation of step iii) may last for at least 12 hours, preferably 24 hours.</p>
<p id="p0050" num="0050">Typically, the antigen is a tumor antigen or a viral antigen. The tumor antigen may be selected from the group consisting of viral tumor antigen, tumor-specific antigen, tumor associated antigen and an antigen carrying patient specific mutations and being expressed in tumor cells of the patient. Preferably the antigen carrying patient specific mutations and being expressed in tumor cells of the patient is not expressed in non-cancerous cells of the patient.</p>
<p id="p0051" num="0051">Viral tumor antigens also termed oncogenic viral antigens are antigens of oncogenic viruses, such as the oncogenic DNA viruses for example viruses, such as hepatitis B viruses, herpesviruses, and papillomaviruses and oncogenic RNA viruses. Tumor specific antigens refer to tumor associated mutations which are exclusively expressed by tumor cells. The group of tumor associated antigens comprises for example tissue specific cancer/testis antigens or tissue differentiation antigens such as MART-1 (MELAN-A), Tyrosinase or CD20. The tumor antigen may be a tumor associated antigen, optionally the tumor associated antigen is a cancer/testis antigen (C/T antigen). The C/T antigen may be selected from the group comprising of MAGE family members, for example MAGE-A1, MAGE-A3, MAGE-A4, but not limited to these, tumor antigens comprising single point mutations, NY-ESO1, tumor/testis-antigen 1B, GAGE-1, SSX-4, XAGE-1, BAGE, GAGE, SCP-1, SSX-2, SSX-4, CTZ9, CT10, SAGE and CAGE. Preferably the C/T antigen may be selected from the group consisting of GAGE-1, SSX-4 and XAGE-1.<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></p>
<p id="p0052" num="0052">Preferably the tumor antigen is a tissue differentiation antigen such as MART-1, Tyrosinase or CD20.</p>
<p id="p0053" num="0053">More preferably the tumor antigen is MART-1, which is also known as MELAN-A. Thus, in specific embodiments the invention refers to a dendritic cell composition comprising dendritic cells expressing at least one fusion protein comprising
<ul id="ul0009" list-style="dash" compact="compact">
<li>at least one antigen or a fragment thereof,</li>
<li>an endoplasmatic reticulum (ER)- translocation signal sequence preceding the N-terminus of the antigen or fragment thereof, and</li>
<li>a transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence following the C-terminus of the antigen or fragment thereof;</li>
</ul>
wherein the fusion protein is MELAN-A.</p>
<p id="p0054" num="0054">Specific embodiments of the invention refer to a dendritic cell composition comprising dendritic cells expressing at least one antigen or a fragment thereof wherein the antigen is not fused to a targeting signal sequences that promotes the MHC II presentation of the antigen or fragment thereof wherein said dendritic cells do not express an antigen or fragment thereof wherein the antigen is fused to a targeting signal sequence that promotes the MHC II presentation of the antigen or fragment thereof, wherein the antigen is MELAN-A.</p>
<p id="p0055" num="0055">In specific embodiments, the dendritic cell composition comprises (i) dendritic cells expressing at least one antigen which is fused to a targeting signal sequence that promotes the MHC II presentation of the antigen or fragment thereof and (ii) dendritic cells expressing at least one antigen or fragment thereof which is not fused to a targeting signal sequence that promotes the MHC II presentation of the antigen or fragment thereof and dendritic cells, wherein the antigen is MELAN-A.</p>
<p id="p0056" num="0056">Therefore, the invention refers also the dendritic cell composition for use as a medicament. Also contemplated is a dendritic cell vaccine for use as a medicament.</p>
<p id="p0057" num="0057">Another aspect of the invention refers to the dendritic cell composition for use in the treatment of cancer. Specific embodiments relate to the dendritic cell composition for use in stimulating an immune response against a melanoma-associated antigen.</p>
<p id="p0058" num="0058">A further aspect of the invention refers to the dendritic cell vaccine for use in the treatment of cancer. Specific embodiments relate to the dendritic cell vaccine for use in stimulating an immune response against a melanoma-associated antigen.<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></p>
<p id="p0059" num="0059">The activation profile of the treatment with the composition of the invention can be determined for example by measuring activation-induced cytokine release or antigen-directed killing capacity of T cells isolated from an organism to which the dendritic cell composition of the invention is administered.</p>
<p id="p0060" num="0060">To measure activation-induced cytokine secretion, T cells may be co-cultured with antigen-loaded dendritic cells. Different effector cell to target cell (E:T) ratios may be employed. T cells incubated with control antigen presenting, i.e. mock-transfected APCs, or in the absence of stimulating cells may be used as negative controls. The culture supernatants are assessed by a standard enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA). Examples for markers are, without limitation, granulocyte-macrophage colony-stimulating factor (GM-CSF), interferon-γ (IFN-γ), IL-2 and TNF-α secretion. IFN-γ, IL-2 and TNF-α secretion upon antigen encounter correlates with enhanced anti-tumor function and is therefore particularly useful when measuring antigen-induced cytokine secretion of CD8<sup>+</sup> cytotoxic T cells. Additionally, IFN-γ and granulocyte-macrophage colony-stimulating factor (GM-CSF) are well-defined cytokines for the assessment of antigen-specific CD4<sup>+</sup> T helper-1 (Th1)-polarized T cell clones.</p>
<p id="p0061" num="0061">The cytotoxic activity of T cells activated by the dendritic cell population of the invention may be measured for example by chromium release assays. In such assays, target cells are labeled with radioactive chromium and exposed to T cells. Upon killing, radioactive chromium is released into the supernatant and detectable within 4 hours after the start of the co-culture. Specific chromium release is normalized to spontaneous release assessed by incubating target cells in the absence of effector cells. Accordingly, high amounts of chromium in the supernatant correlate with excellent cytolytic T cell activity. Chromium release assays are preferably performed to screen for tumor antigen-specific CD8<sup>+</sup> T cells.</p>
<p id="p0062" num="0062">Donor derived antigen presenting cells may be for example isolated monocytes which are maturated to dendritic cells. Maturated dendritic cells exhibit optimal activation capacity.</p>
<p id="p0063" num="0063">Typically, the dendritic cells are autologous cells, <i>i.e.</i> cells obtained from a patient which are treated according to teaching of the invention and then administered to the same patient. For example, monocytes are isolated from a patient, matured to dendritic cells and treated as described herein to express the desired antigen and then administered to the same patient.</p>
<p id="p0064" num="0064">The present invention refers also to a dendritic cell vaccine comprising the dendritic cell composition as described herein.</p>
<p id="p0065" num="0065">The active components of the present invention, such as the dendritic cell composition, are preferably used in a pharmaceutical composition, in doses mixed with an acceptable carrier<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> or carrier material, that the disease can be treated or at least alleviated. Such a composition can (in addition to the active component and the carrier) include filling material, salts, buffer, stabilizers, solubilizers and other materials, which are known state of the art.</p>
<p id="p0066" num="0066">The term "pharmaceutically acceptable" defines a non-toxic material, which does not interfere with effectiveness of the biological activity of the active component, i.e. the dendritic cells of the invention. The choice of the carrier is dependent on the application.</p>
<p id="p0067" num="0067">The pharmaceutical composition may contain additional components which enhance the activity of the active component or which supplement the treatment. Such additional components and/or factors can be part of the pharmaceutical composition to achieve synergistic effects or to minimize adverse or unwanted effects.</p>
<p id="p0068" num="0068">Techniques for the formulation or preparation and application/medication of active components of the present invention are published in "<nplcit id="ncit0001" npl-type="b"><text>Remington's Pharmaceutical Sciences", Mack Publishing Co., Easton, PA, latest editi</text></nplcit>on. An appropriate application is a parenteral application, for example intradermal, intramuscular, subcutaneous, intramedular injections as well as intrathecal, direct intraventricular, intravenous, intranodal, intraperitoneal or intratumoral injections. The intravenous injection is the preferred treatment of a patient.</p>
<p id="p0069" num="0069">The pharmaceutical composition may be an injectable composition i.e. a pharmaceutically acceptable fluid composition comprising at least one active ingredient, e.g. a dendritic cell composition of the invention. The active ingredient is usually dissolved or suspended in a physiologically acceptable carrier, and the composition can additionally comprise minor amounts of one or more non-toxic auxiliary substances, such as emulsifying agents, preservatives, and pH buffering agents and the like. Such injectable compositions that are useful for use with the dendritic cells of this disclosure are conventional; appropriate formulations are well known to those of ordinary skill in the art.</p>
<p id="p0070" num="0070">Formulations suitable for parenteral administration, such as, by intraarticular (in the joints), intravenous, intramuscular, intradermal, intracutan, intraperitoneal, and subcutaneous routes (preferably intradermal, intranodal, intracutan or subcutaneous) include aqueous isotonic sterile injection solutions, which can contain antioxidants, buffers, bacteriostats, and solutes that render the formulation isotonic with the blood of the intended recipient, and aqueous and non-aqueous sterile suspensions that can include suspending agents, solubilizers, thickening agents, stabilizers, and preservatives. Intradermal, intracutan, subcutan or intranodal administration are the preferred method of administration for dendritic cells of the invention.<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></p>
<p id="p0071" num="0071">The dose of the dendritic cells administered to a patient, in the context of the present invention should be sufficient to effect a beneficial therapeutic response in the patient over time, or to inhibit growth of cancer cells, or to inhibit infection. Thus, cells are administered to a patient in an amount sufficient to elicit an effective CTL response to the virus or tumor antigen and/or to alleviate, reduce, cure or at least partially arrest symptoms and/or complications from the disease or infection. An amount adequate to accomplish this is defined as a "therapeutically effective dose." The dose will be determined by the activity of dendritic cell produced and the condition of the patient. The size of the dose also will be determined by the existence, nature, and extent of any adverse side-effects that accompany the administration of a particular cell in a particular patient. In determining the effective amount of the cell to be administered in the treatment or prophylaxis of diseases such as cancer, the physician needs to evaluate CTL toxicity, progression of the disease, and the induction of immune response against any introduced cell type.</p>
<p id="p0072" num="0072">Prior to administration, blood samples are obtained and saved for analysis. Generally, at about 10<sup>4</sup> to 10<sup>6</sup> and more preferably 10<sup>6</sup> to 10<sup>10</sup> cells are administered into a 70 kg patient in form of a single dose or multiple doses via intracutan, intranodal, subcutan or intradermal injection. Preferably, cell numbers of at least 2<sup>∗</sup>10<sup>6</sup>-10<sup>7</sup> pervaccination are used. The injections may be administered once per week for a period of 4 weeks followed by 1 administration/injection per month and should be given preferably near lymph nodes, directly into lymph nodes or by intradermal, intracutan or subcutaneous injections. Booster injections may additionally be performed. As stated, cell reinfusions are preferably repeated every month for a total of 10-12 treatments in a one-year period. After the first treatment, infusions can be performed on an outpatient basis at the discretion of the clinician. If the reinfusion is given as an outpatient, the participant is monitored for at least 4 hours following the therapy.</p>
<p id="p0073" num="0073">The dendritic cell composition/dendritic cell vaccine may be administered at least once, ate least twice, at least 3, at least 4, at least 5, at least 6, at least 7, at least 8, at least 9, at least10 times. The vaccine may be administered not more than 15 times, 18 times, 20 times, 25 times, 30 times. The interval between the administrations is at least 3 days, at least 7 days, at least 14 days or at least 4 weeks. Preferably the vaccine is administered once a week for a period of 4 weeks followed by 1 administration per month for a total of 10 to 12 treatments.</p>
<p id="p0074" num="0074">For administration, cells of the present invention can be administered at a rate determined by the LD-50 (or other measure of toxicity) of the cell type, and the side-effects of the cell type at various concentrations, as applied to the mass and overall health of the patient. Administration can be accomplished via single or divided doses. The cells of this invention can supplement other treatments for a condition by known conventional therapy, including<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> cytotoxic agents, nucleotide analogues and biologic response modifiers. Similarly, biological response modifiers are optionally added for treatment by the dendritic cells.</p>
<p id="p0075" num="0075">The invention also relates to a composition, comprising
<ol id="ol0004" compact="compact" ol-style="">
<li>a) an expression vector comprising
<ul id="ul0010" list-style="dash" compact="compact">
<li>a human ER-translocation signal sequence,</li>
<li>a human transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence, and</li>
<li>at least one antigen or fragment thereof; and</li>
</ul></li>
<li>b) an expression vector comprising at least one antigen or fragment thereof, but lacking an ER-translocation signal sequence and a human transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence.</li>
</ol></p>
<p id="p0076" num="0076">The invention further relates to a kit, comprising:
<ol id="ol0005" compact="compact" ol-style="">
<li>a) an expression vector comprising
<ul id="ul0011" list-style="dash" compact="compact">
<li>a human ER-translocation signal sequence,</li>
<li>a human transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence, and</li>
<li>at least one antigen or fragment thereof; and</li>
</ul></li>
<li>b) an expression vector comprising at least one antigen or fragment thereof, but lacking an ER-translocation signal sequence and a human transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence.</li>
</ol></p>
<p id="p0077" num="0077">A "vector" is any molecule or composition that has the ability to carry a nucleic acid sequence into a suitable host cell where synthesis of the encoded polypeptide can take place. Typically and preferably, a vector is a nucleic acid that has been engineered, using recombinant DNA techniques that are known in the art, to incorporate a desired nucleic acid sequence (e.g., a nucleic acid of the invention). The vector may comprise DNA or RNA and/or comprise liposomes. The vector may be a plasmid, shuttle vector, phagemide, cosmid, expression vector, retroviral vector, adenoviral vector or particle and/or vector to be used in gene therapy. A vector may include nucleic acid sequences that permit it to replicate in a host cell, such as an origin of replication. A vector may also include one or more selectable marker genes and other genetic elements known to those of ordinary skill in the art. A vector preferably is an expression vector that includes a nucleic acid according to the present invention operably linked to sequences allowing for the expression of said nucleic acid.<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></p>
<heading id="h0006"><b>Examples</b></heading>
<heading id="h0007"><b>1.1 Activation of Melan-A specific CD8+ T cells in a NSG mouse model</b></heading>
<p id="p0078" num="0078">To develop a humanized mouse model to study our DC vaccination in vivo, we used NOD-scid/ Il2rγ-/- (NSG) mice xenografted with human PBMC. As NSG mice are immune deficient (lacking NK, T and B cells) (SPRANGER, S. et al. 2012. NOD/scid IL-2Rg(null) mice: a preclinical model system to evaluate human dendritic cell-based vaccine strategies in vivo.<nplcit id="ncit0002" npl-type="s"><text> J Transl Med, 10, 30</text></nplcit>.), the resulting niche in the immune cell population allows a very efficient engraftment with human PBMC (<nplcit id="ncit0003" npl-type="s"><text>SHULTZ, et al. 2007. Humanized mice in translational biomedical research. Nat Rev Immunol, 7, 118-30</text></nplcit>.).</p>
<p id="p0079" num="0079">16 NSG recipient mice were divided into four groups and xenografted with human HLA-A*02:01 PBMC over 14 days. Vaccination of mice in different groups consisted of two intravenous injections of autologous freshly prepared mature dendritic cells electroporated with either CrossTAg-Melan-A-ivt-RNA, conventional Melan-A-ivt-RNA or mixed ivt-RNA given twice with a one-week interval between injections. After a further seven days, and after a subsequent in vitro restimulation, splenic populations were analyzed by FACS to enumerate Melan-A-specific CD8+ T cells. Cytotoxicity and the capability of secreting IFN-γ of Melan-A-specific T cells of all 4 groups were also analyzed by chromium-release and ELISpot assays (<figref idref="f0001">Figure 1</figref>).</p>
<heading id="h0008"><b>1.2 Maturation status and Melan-A-expression of transfected mature dendritic cells</b></heading>
<p id="p0080" num="0080">Monocytes derived from a healthy HLA-A*02:01-donor were isolated and matured as described in <nplcit id="ncit0004" npl-type="s"><text>Spranger et al. (2010. Generation of Th1-polarizing dendritic cells using the TLR7/8 agonist CL075. J Immunol, 185, 738-47</text></nplcit>) in vitro within 3 days. To verify the in vitro maturation of dendritic cells for later administration to humanized mice in vivo, we determined expression of cell surface molecules typically expressed on immature dendritic cells and mature dendritic cells by FACS analysis (<nplcit id="ncit0005" npl-type="s"><text>Burdek et al. 2010. Three-day dendritic cells for vaccine development: antigen uptake, processing and presentation. J Transl Med, 8, 90</text></nplcit>). Analyzed dendritic cells expressed a mature phenotype (<figref idref="f0002">Figure 2 A</figref>). Mature dendritic cells were transfected with either CrossTAg-Melan-A- or conventional Melan-A-ivt-RNA following electroporation conditions for mature 3d dendritic cells (Burdek et al., 2010). Transfection efficiency was examined (6 hours after electroporation) by intracellular staining of Melan-A protein with monoclonal antibodies (<figref idref="f0002">Figure 2 B</figref>).</p>
<heading id="h0009"><b>1.3 Quantification of Melan-A specific CD8+ T cells</b></heading>
<p id="p0081" num="0081">Reconstituted mice were vaccinated twice, with a one-week interval, before splenic cells were isolated and analyzed. To compare the induction efficiency of the different DC vaccines, the number of Melan-A specific CD8+ T cells was detected by a fluorescence-labeled HLA-A*02:01-multimer loaded with a Melan-A-epitope (<figref idref="f0003">Figure 3 A)</figref>.<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></p>
<p id="p0082" num="0082">The ex vivo analysis of splenic cells already revealed a higher number of Melan-A-specific CD8+ T cells in the CrossTAg-DC-group or mixed group compared to the conventional DC group, which showed only a slightly higher number of specific cells compared with the control group. Moreover, we detected a significantly higher percentage of CD8+ T cells in the CrossTAg-group compared to the conventional-group (<figref idref="f0003">Figure 3 B)</figref>. Subsequently, remaining splenocytes were further expanded in vitro by Melan-A transfected dendritic cells and hIL-2, whereas the control group was only treated with hIL-2. Reanalysis of expanded cells demonstrated an even clearer discrepancy between CrossTAg-Melan-A-containing dendritic cells and conventional Melan-A dendritic cells concerning the average number of Melan-A specific CD8+ T cells. A significantly greater number of Melan-A-specific CD8+ T cells could be seen in the CrossTAg-group compared with the conventional-group (<figref idref="f0003">Figure 3 C</figref>). Thus, vaccination with dendritic cells loaded with CrossTAg-Melan-A-ivt-RNA resulted in a superior induction-capacity, demonstrated by greater proliferation of Melan-A specific CD8+ T cells. An even stronger induction-capacity is demonstrated for the vaccination with a combination of dendritic cells loaded with CrossTAg-Melan-A-ivt-RNA and dendritic cells loaded with Melan-A-ivt RNA without fusion to the CrossTAg.</p>
<heading id="h0010"><b>1.4 Functional analysis of induced Melan-A specific CD8+ T cells</b></heading>
<p id="p0083" num="0083">We demonstrated a superior induction efficiency of antigen-specific CD8+ T cells by CrossTAg-transfected dendritic cells indicating a clear benefit of RNA constructs having included CrossTAg-sequences flanking the target antigen. For the establishment of a CD8+ T cell memory as well as for successful tumor regression a pivotal role of CD4+ T cells has been previously shown (<nplcit id="ncit0006" npl-type="s"><text>Mortenson, et al. 2013. Effective anti-neu-initiated antitumor responses require the complex role of CD4+ T cells. Clin Cancer Res, 19, 1476-86</text></nplcit>; <nplcit id="ncit0007" npl-type="s"><text>Rosenberg et al. Cancer immunotherapy: moving beyond current vaccines. Nat Med, 10, 909-15</text></nplcit>). Thus, the enhanced immune response induced in NSG mice vaccinated with CrossTAg-Melan-A-containing dendritic cells might be explained by the enabled CD4+ T cell help provided by the CrossTAg-sequences leading to the Melan-A-presentation on NMC-I and -II.<br/>
To further examine the functionality of the induced T cells, the next important issue to clarify was whether the induced Melan-A specific CD8+ T cells were also able to secret IFN-γ which is critical for an appropriate immune response. Thus, the capability of Melan-A specific CD8+ T cells to secrete IFN-γ upon stimulation was analyzed. In vitro expanded splenocytes were cocultured with various tumor cell lines as stimulating cells to evaluate IFN γ secretion. Unstimulated splenocytes were found to be completely unreactive. NK cell activity, within in the splenocyte population, was determined by using the HLA-negative tumor cell line K562, as NK cells are activated by target cells lacking any MHC molecules. No NK cell activity was detected. Only stimulator cells expressing Melan-A or loaded with specific peptide led to a strong activation of splenocytes, whereas Melan-A-negative cells did not stimulate the splenocytes. In average, more IFN-γ spots could be<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> detected from CD8+ T cells isolated from CrossTAg- or the mixed group compared to the conventional group or the control group (<figref idref="f0004">Figure 4 A)</figref>.<br/>
To address the question whether the reactivity observed in the ELISpot assay could be traced back to CD8+ T cells and not to CD4+ T cells as well, the MHC-II expression on the stimulator cells was examined. The stimulator cell line was positive for NMC-I but not for MHC-II (<figref idref="f0004">Figure 4 B)</figref>. Even after IFN-γ treatment of stimulator cells overnight did not lead to an induced expression of MHC-II molecules (data not shown). Thus, only MHC-I-restricted T cells could be activated, indicating that the observed reactivity was originating from activated CD8+ T cells, as CD4+ T cells would require antigen-presentation on MHC-II to be activated.</p>
<p id="p0084" num="0084">It is also important for CD8+ T cells to be cytotoxic in order to be able to kill tumor cells. Therefore, cytotoxic capacity of Melan A-specific T cells was assessed by a chromium-release assay (<figref idref="f0005">Figure 5</figref>). The cytotoxicity results demonstrated that expanded splenocytes specifically lysed only Melan-A-peptide presenting cells but not the control cell line which was negative for the target antigen. Cells from the control group did not show any killing activity. The NK cell activity was also very low within splenocytes in all groups. Notably, cells from CrossTAg-DC-group and mixed group showed a much higher killing capacity compared to splenocytes from the conventional DC-group.</p>
<heading id="h0011"><b>Methods</b></heading>
<heading id="h0012"><b>Genetic Constructs</b></heading>
<p id="p0085" num="0085">The pGEM-eGFP-A120 vector was used as the starting construct for the CrossTAg-vector. This polyA120 variant of the original pGEM vector renders transcribed RNA with higher stability and led to improved protein expression. The plasmid further contained a unique Agel site at the 5' end of the eGFP cDNA, as well as a unique EcoRI site at the 3' end. The poly-A tail is followed by a Spel site that allows linearization of the plasmid for ivt-RNA production.<br/>
The pGEM-CrossTAg-A120 plasmid was cloned by replacing eGFP with cDNA coding for the CrossTAg targeting signal. The CrossTAg sequence consists of the ER-translocation signal of the human lysosome-associated membrane protein-1 (LAMP-1, accession: NP_005552, aa 1-28) fused 5' to the transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain of DC-LAMP (accession: NP_055213, aa 376-416). For insertion of antigen-encoding cDNA, the distinct CrossTAg sequences are separated by an 18-bp spacer containing Nhel, Kpnl and PstI restriction sites without disrupting the LAMP1 open reading frame (ORF). The codon optimized Cross-TAg sequence was designed virtually using computational cloning software and synthesized by (GeneArt, Regensburg, Germany). The complete CrossTAg sequence was subsequently cut from plasmid DNA using Agel (5' end) and EcoRI (3' end) restriction sites and ligated into the MCS of the equally digested pGEM-A120 vector.<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --></p>
<p id="p0086" num="0086">For cloning of various C/T antigen-CrossTAg constructs (pGEM-GAGE-1-CrossTAg-A120, pGEM-MAGE-A4-CrossTAg-A120, pGEM-NY-ESO-1-CrossTAg-A120, pGEM-SSX-4-CrossTAg-A120, pGEM-XAGE-1-CrossTAg-A120) antigen cDNA was amplified from plasmids by PCR (accessions: GAGE-1, U19142; MAGE-A4, NM_001011550; NY-ESO1, AJ003149; SSX-4, U90841; XAGE-1, AF251237) using forward and reverse gene-specific primers and ligated via Nhel and PstI/NotI restriction sites. All antigen sequences were inserted into the split CrossTAg signal of pGEM-CrossTAg-A120 without disrupting the initial ORF.<br/>
For the validation of CD4<sup>+</sup> T cell epitopes, complementary oligonucleotides were synthesized (Metabion, Planegg, Germany) and annealed. Cohesive ends, generated upon annealing, were used for direct ligation of these short antigen sequences into the CrossTAg vector.</p>
<heading id="h0013"><b>Production of ivt-RNA</b></heading>
<p id="p0087" num="0087">Following Spel linearization, pGEM-plasmids were used as templates for single-species in vitro transcribed (ivt)-RNA production using the mMESSAGE mMACHINE T7 kit (ThermoFisher Scientific, Massachusetts, USA), according to the manufacturer's instructions. For quality control, ivt-RNA product length was analyzed by agarose gel electrophoresis. Concentration and purity were determined by means of the Nanodrop ND-1000 spectrophotometer (ThermoFisher Scientific, Massachusetts).</p>
<heading id="h0014"><b>Cell culture</b></heading>
<p id="p0088" num="0088">Monocyte-derived 3d mature dendritic cells were generated and transfected as described in <nplcit id="ncit0008" npl-type="s"><text>Bürdek et al. (Journal of Translational Medicine 2010, 8:90</text></nplcit>.) RNA transfection of mature dendritic cells: Mini-Epstein-Barr virus-(EBV)-transformed lymphoblastoid cell lines (mLCL) were achieved by electroporation.</p>
<heading id="h0015"><b>Surface phenotyping of dendritic cells</b></heading>
<p id="p0089" num="0089">Surface markers expressed by dendritic cells were detected with the following antibodies: PE-conjugated CCR7-specific antibody (3D12) (eBioscience, Frankfurt, Germany), Hz450-conjugated CD4-specific anti-body (RPA-T4), Hz500-conjugated CD8-specific antibody (RPA-T8), FITC-conjugated CD14-specific antibody (M5E2), PE-conjugated CD40-specific antibody (5C3), PE-conjugated CD40L-specific antibody (TRAP1), PE-conjugated CD80-specific antibody (L307.4), FITC-conjugated CD83-specific antibody (HB15e), FITC-conjugated CD86-specific antibody (2331), APC-conjugated CD137-specific antibody (4B4-1), FITC-conjugated DC-SIGN-specific antibody (DCN46), PE-conjugated HLA-DR-specific antibody (G46-6) (all from BD Biosciences, Heidelberg, Germany). After washing, cells were stained for 30 min at 4 °C and propidium iodid (2 µg/ml) was added for the exclusion of dead cells. Expression of all surface markers was analyzed by flow cytometry (LSRII, BD). Post-acquisition data analysis was done using FlowJo 8 software (TreeStar). The analysis of CD40L surface expression on T cells was<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> performed as described (<nplcit id="ncit0009" npl-type="s"><text>Frentsch, M. et al. (2005) Direct access to CD4+ T cells specific for defined antigens according to CD154 expression. Nat Med 11(10): 1118-1124</text></nplcit>) using 2 µg/ml αCD40 antibody (clone G28.5, provided by M. Frentsch, Berlin-Brandenburg Center for Regenerative Therapies) and assessed 6 h after the start of the T cell:APC co-culture.</p>
<heading id="h0016"><b>De novo priming of PBL with RNA-transfected dendritic cells</b></heading>
<p id="p0090" num="0090">3d mature dendritic cells of a healthy donor were transfected with CrossTAg-RNA coding for the MELAN-A. After electroporation the transfected mature dendritic cells were harvested and mixed mature dendritic cells of this mixture were co-cultured within a 1:2 ratio peripheral blood lymphocytes (PBL), which were non-adherent during the plastic adherence of PBMC in the process of mature dendritic cells generation. The cells were cultured at 37°C in a humidified atmosphere. Interleukine-2 (IL-2, 20 U/ml; Chiron Behring, Marburg, Germany) and 5 ng IL-7/ml (Promokine, Heidelberg, Germany) were added after 1 day and then on every other day.</p>
<heading id="h0017"><b>Cytokine release assay</b></heading>
<p id="p0091" num="0091">To measure activation induced cytokine secretion, 5<sup>∗</sup>10<sup>4</sup> T cells were co-cultured with 1<sup>∗</sup>10<sup>5</sup> ivt-RNA-loaded antigen presenting cells DC in 200 µl T cell medium in roundbottom 96-well plates at 37°C in a humidified atmosphere. T cells with mock-transfected APCs or without stimulator cells were used as negative controls. After 16 h of co-culture, supernatants were harvested and assessed by enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) using the OptEIA Human IFN-γ or GM-CSF Set (both from BD Biosciences, Heidelberg, Germany).</p>
<heading id="h0018"><b>PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</b></heading>
<p id="p0092" num="0092">
<ol id="ol0006" ol-style="">
<li>1. Dendritic cell composition comprising dendritic cells expressing at least one fusion protein comprising
<ul id="ul0012" list-style="dash" compact="compact">
<li>at least one antigen or a fragment thereof,</li>
<li>an endoplasmatic reticulum (ER)- translocation signal sequence preceding the N-terminus of the antigen, and</li>
<li>a transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence following the C-terminus of the antigen.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>2. Dendritic cell composition according to embodiment 1,<br/>
wherein the dendritic cell composition further comprises dendritic cells expressing at least one antigen or a fragment thereof wherein the antigen is not fused to a targeting signal sequences that promotes the MHC II presentation of the antigen or fragment thereof.<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --></li>
<li>3. Dendritic cell composition according to embodiment 1 or embodiment 2, wherein the targeting signal sequence that promotes the MHC II presentation is at least one selected from the group consisting of
<ul id="ul0013" list-style="dash" compact="compact">
<li>an endoplasmatic reticulum (ER)-translocation signal sequence preceding the N-terminus of the antigen, and</li>
<li>a transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence following the C-terminus of the antigen.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>4. Dendritic cell composition according to any one of the preceding embodiments, wherein the fusion protein and the antigen are transiently or stably expressed, preferably stably expressed.</li>
<li>5. Dendritic cell composition according to embodiment 4, wherein the transient expression is carried out by introducing ivt-RNA.</li>
<li>6. Dendritic cell composition according to any one of the preceding embodiments, wherein the endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence is derived from DC-LAMP</li>
<li>7. Dendritic cell composition according to any one of the preceding embodiments, wherein the endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence is human.</li>
<li>8. Dendritic cell composition according to any one of the preceding embodiments, wherein the endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence comprises the sequence SEQ ID NO: 3 or a fragment thereof.</li>
<li>9. Dendritic cell composition according to any one of the preceding embodiments, wherein the endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence comprises the sequence SEQ ID NO: 14 or a fragment thereof.</li>
<li>10. Dendritic cell composition according to any one of the preceding embodiments, wherein the ER translocation signal sequence is derived from an endosomal/lysosomal associated protein.</li>
<li>11. Dendritic cell composition according to embodiment 10, wherein the endosomal/lysosomal associated protein is selected from the group comprising LAMP1, LAMP2, DC-LAP, CD68 and CD1b.</li>
<li>12. Dendritic cell composition according to any one of the preceding embodiments, wherein the ER translocation signal sequence is derived from LAMP1.<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --></li>
<li>13. Dendritic cell composition according to any one of the preceding embodiments, wherein the ER translocation signal sequence comprises the sequence SEQ ID NO: 1 or a fragment thereof.</li>
<li>14. Dendritic cell composition according to any one of the preceding embodiments, wherein the dendritic cells are mature dendritic cells generated by a method comprising the following steps:
<ol id="ol0007" compact="compact" ol-style="">
<li>(i) provision of monocytes;</li>
<li>(ii) incubation of the monocytes of step i) with IL-4 and GM-CSF;</li>
<li>(iii) incubation of the monocytes of step ii) with IL-4 and GM-CSF in combination with a maturation cocktail.</li>
</ol></li>
<li>15. Dendritic cell composition according to embodiment 14, wherein the maturation cocktail comprises a combination of IFN-γ, TLR7/8 agonist, PGE2 and optionally TLR 3 agonist.</li>
<li>16. Dendritic cell composition according to embodiment 15, wherein the maturation cocktail comprises a combination of IL-β, TNF-α, IFN-γ, TLR7/8 agonist, PGE2 and TLR3 agonist.</li>
<li>17. Dendritic cell composition according to embodiments 14 to 16, wherein incubation of step ii) lasts at least 2 days.</li>
<li>18. Dendritic cell composition according to embodiments 14 to 17, wherein incubation of step iii) lasts at least 12 hours, preferably 24 hours.</li>
<li>19. Dendritic cell composition according to embodiments 15 to 18, wherein the TLR7/8 agonist is R848 and wherein the TLR3 agonist is poly(I:C).</li>
<li>20. Dendritic cell composition according to any one of the preceding embodiments, wherein the antigen is MELAN-A.</li>
<li>21. Dendritic cell vaccine comprising the dendritic cell composition of any of embodiments 1 to 20.</li>
<li>22. Dendritic cell vaccine of embodiment 21, wherein the dendritic cells are autologous cells.</li>
<li>23. Dendritic cell vaccine of embodiment 22, wherein the dendritic cell vaccine is a pharmaceutically acceptable fluid composition.<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --></li>
<li>24. Dendritic cell composition of embodiments 1 to 20 or dendritic cell vaccine of embodiments 21 to 23 for use as a medicament.</li>
<li>25. Dendritic cell composition of embodiments 1 to 20 or dendritic cell vaccine of embodiments 21 to 23 for use in the treatment of cancer.</li>
<li>26. Dendritic cell composition of embodiments 1 to 20 or dendritic cell vaccine of embodiments 21 to 23 for use in stimulating an immune response against a melanoma-associated antigen.</li>
<li>27. Dendritic cell composition or dendritic cell vaccine for use according to embodiment 26 wherein the melanoma-associated antigen is MELAN-A.</li>
<li>28. Composition, comprising
<ol id="ol0008" compact="compact" ol-style="">
<li>a) an expression vector comprising
<ul id="ul0014" list-style="dash" compact="compact">
<li>a human ER-translocation signal sequence,</li>
<li>a human transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence, and</li>
<li>at least one antigen or fragment thereof; and</li>
</ul></li>
<li>b) an expression vector comprising at least one antigen or fragment thereof, but lacking an ER-translocation signal sequence and a human transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence.</li>
</ol></li>
<li>29. Kit, comprising
<ol id="ol0009" compact="compact" ol-style="">
<li>a) an expression vector comprising
<ul id="ul0015" list-style="dash" compact="compact">
<li>a human ER-translocation signal sequence,</li>
<li>a human transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence, and</li>
<li>at least one antigen or fragment thereof; and</li>
</ul></li>
<li>b) an expression vector comprising at least one antigen or fragment thereof, but lacking an ER-translocation signal sequence and a human transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence.</li>
</ol></li>
</ol><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> -->
<img id="ib0001" file="imgb0001.tif" wi="133" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> -->
<img id="ib0002" file="imgb0002.tif" wi="134" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="26"> -->
<img id="ib0003" file="imgb0003.tif" wi="133" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> -->
<img id="ib0004" file="imgb0004.tif" wi="137" he="183" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="28"> -->
<claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Dendritic cell composition comprising dendritic cells expressing at least one fusion protein comprising
<claim-text>- at least one antigen or a fragment thereof,</claim-text>
<claim-text>- an endoplasmic reticulum (ER)- translocation signal sequence preceding the N-terminus of the antigen, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>- a transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence following the C-terminus of the antigen,</claim-text>
wherein the dendritic cell composition further comprises dendritic cells expressing at least one antigen or a fragment thereof wherein the antigen is not fused to a targeting signal sequence that promotes the MHC II presentation of the antigen or fragment thereof.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Dendritic cell composition according to claim 1, wherein the targeting signal sequence that promotes the MHC II presentation is at least one selected from the group consisting of
<claim-text>- an endoplasmic reticulum (ER)-translocation signal sequence preceding the N-terminus of the antigen, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>- a transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence following the C-terminus of the antigen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Dendritic cell composition according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein the fusion protein and the antigen are transiently or stably expressed, preferably stably expressed.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Dendritic cell composition according to claim 3, wherein the transient expression is carried out by introducing ivt-RNA.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Dendritic cell composition according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein the endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence is derived from DC-LAMP, and/or wherein the the endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence is human.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Dendritic cell composition according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein the endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence comprises the sequence SEQ ID NO: 3 or a fragment thereof, preferably wherein the endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --> comprises the sequence SEQ ID NO: 14 or a fragment thereof.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Dendritic cell composition according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein the ER translocation signal sequence is derived from an endosomal/lysosomal associated protein, preferably, wherein the endosomal/lysosomal associated protein is selected from the group comprising LAMP1, LAMP2, DC-LAP, CD68 and CD1b.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>Dendritic cell composition according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein the ER translocation signal sequence is derived from LAMP1, preferably wherein the ER translocation signal sequence comprises the sequence SEQ ID NO: 1 or a fragment thereof.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>Dendritic cell composition according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein the dendritic cells are mature dendritic cells generated by a method comprising the following steps:
<claim-text>(i) provision of monocytes;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) incubation of the monocytes of step i) with IL-4 and GM-CSF;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(iii) incubation of the monocytes of step ii) with IL-4 and GM-CSF in combination with a maturation cocktail.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>Dendritic cell composition according to claim 9, wherein the maturation cocktail comprises a combination of IFN-γ, TLR7/8 agonist, PGE2 and optionally TLR 3 agonist, preferably wherein the maturation cocktail comprises a combination of IL-β, TNF-α, IFN-γ, TLR7/8 agonist, PGE2 and TLR3 agonist, more preferably wherein the TLR7/8 agonist is R848 and wherein the TLR3 agonist is poly(I:C).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>Dendritic cell vaccine comprising the dendritic cell composition of any of claims 1 to 10, preferably wherein the dendritic cells are autologous cells, more preferably wherein the dendritic cell vaccine is a pharmaceutically acceptable fluid composition.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>Dendritic cell composition of claims 1 to 10 or dendritic cell vaccine of claim 11 for use as a medicament.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>Dendritic cell composition of claims 1 to 10 or dendritic cell vaccine of claim 11 for use in the treatment of cancer.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>Composition, comprising
<claim-text>a) an expression vector comprising
<claim-text>- a human ER-translocation signal sequence,</claim-text>
<claim-text>- a human transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence, and<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>- at least one antigen or fragment thereof; and</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>b) an expression vector comprising at least one antigen or fragment thereof, but lacking an ER-translocation signal sequence and a human transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0015" num="0015">
<claim-text>Kit, comprising
<claim-text>a) an expression vector comprising
<claim-text>- a human ER-translocation signal sequence,</claim-text>
<claim-text>- a human transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>- at least one antigen or fragment thereof; and</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>b) an expression vector comprising at least one antigen or fragment thereof, but lacking an ER-translocation signal sequence and a human transmembrane and cytoplasmic domain comprising an endosomal/lysosomal targeting sequence.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="145" he="232" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="2A,2B"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="162" he="184" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="33"> -->
<figure id="f0003" num="3A,3B,3C"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="162" he="203" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="34"> -->
<figure id="f0004" num="4A,4B"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="157" he="187" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="35"> -->
<figure id="f0005" num="5"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="164" he="187" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<search-report-data id="srep" lang="en" srep-office="EP" date-produced=""><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="151" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="151" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0003" file="srep0003.tif" wi="151" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0004" file="srep0004.tif" wi="155" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data><search-report-data date-produced="20210721" id="srepxml" lang="en" srep-office="EP" srep-type="ep-sr" status="n"><!--
 The search report data in XML is provided for the users' convenience only. It might differ from the search report of the PDF document, which contains the officially published data. The EPO disclaims any liability for incorrect or incomplete data in the XML for search reports.
 -->

<srep-info><file-reference-id>M10978WOEPD1/DJB</file-reference-id><application-reference><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>21155881.2</doc-number></document-id></application-reference><applicant-name><name>Medigene Immunotherapies GmbH</name></applicant-name><srep-established srep-established="yes"/><srep-invention-title title-approval="yes"/><srep-abstract abs-approval="yes"/><srep-figure-to-publish figinfo="none-suggested"/><srep-info-admin><srep-office><addressbook><text>MN</text></addressbook></srep-office><date-search-report-mailed><date>20210729</date></date-search-report-mailed></srep-info-admin></srep-info><srep-for-pub><srep-fields-searched><minimum-documentation><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr><text>C12N</text></classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr></minimum-documentation></srep-fields-searched><srep-citations><citation id="sr-cit0001"><nplcit id="sr-ncit0001" medium="online" npl-type="w"><online><author><name>Ellinger et al.</name></author><online-title>MHC Class-II Expression Targeting (CrossTAg) for the Generation of Tumor-Antigen-Specific CD4</online-title><pubdate>20130501</pubdate><avail>http://www.medigene.de/sites/default/files/downloads/12_ellinger_-_mhc_class-ii_expression_targeting_crosstag_-cimt_2013.pdf</avail><srchdate><date>20160418</date></srchdate><refno>XP055266213</refno></online></nplcit><category>Y</category><rel-claims>1-15</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* the whole document *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0002"><nplcit id="sr-ncit0002" npl-type="s"><article><author><name>WU TZYY-CHOOU ET AL</name></author><atl>Engineering an intracellular pathway for major histocompatibility complex class II presentation of antigens</atl><serial><sertitle>PROCEEDINGS NATIONAL ACADEMY OF SCIENCES PNAS, NATIONAL ACADEMY OF SCIENCES, US</sertitle><pubdate>19950101</pubdate><vid>92</vid><ino>25</ino><doi>10.1073/PNAS.92.25.11671</doi><issn>0027-8424</issn></serial><location><pp><ppf>11671</ppf><ppl>11675</ppl></pp></location><refno>XP002180963</refno></article></nplcit><category>Y</category><rel-claims>1-15</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* the whole document *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0003"><nplcit id="sr-ncit0003" npl-type="s"><article><author><name>DANIEL G KAVANAGH ET AL</name></author><atl>Expansion of HIV-specific CD4+ and CD8+ T cells by dendritic cells transfected with mRNA encoding cytoplasm- or lysosome- targeted Nef</atl><serial><sertitle>BLOOD, AMERICAN SOCIETY OF HEMATOLOGY, US</sertitle><pubdate>20060301</pubdate><vid>107</vid><ino>5</ino><doi>10.1182/BLOOD-2005-04-1513</doi><issn>0006-4971</issn></serial><location><pp><ppf>1963</ppf><ppl>1969</ppl></pp></location><refno>XP008141565</refno></article></nplcit><category>Y</category><rel-claims>1-15</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* the whole document *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0004"><nplcit id="sr-ncit0004" npl-type="s"><article><author><name>L. B. ARRUDA ET AL</name></author><atl>Dendritic Cell-Lysosomal-Associated Membrane Protein (LAMP) and LAMP-1-HIV-1 Gag Chimeras Have Distinct Cellular Trafficking Pathways and Prime T and B Cell Responses to a Diverse Repertoire of Epitopes</atl><serial><sertitle>THE JOURNAL OF IMMUNOLOGY</sertitle><imprint><text>US</text></imprint><pubdate>20060803</pubdate><vid>177</vid><ino>4</ino><doi>10.4049/jimmunol.177.4.2265</doi><issn>0022-1767</issn></serial><location><pp><ppf>2265</ppf><ppl>2275</ppl></pp></location><refno>XP055266226</refno></article></nplcit><category>Y</category><rel-claims>1-15</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* the whole document *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0005"><nplcit id="sr-ncit0005" npl-type="s"><article><author><name>CARINA WEHNER ET AL</name></author><atl>Generation of tumor antigen-specific CD4+ and CD8+ T cells by simultaneous MHC-I and -II epitope presentation in vitro and in vivo</atl><serial><sertitle>JOURNAL FOR IMMUNOTHERAPY OF CANCER, BIOMED CENTRAL LTD, LONDON, UK</sertitle><pubdate>20141106</pubdate><vid>2</vid><ino>Suppl 3</ino><doi>10.1186/2051-1426-2-S3-P65</doi><issn>2051-1426</issn></serial><location><pp>page P65</pp></location><refno>XP021202581</refno></article></nplcit><category>Y</category><rel-claims>1-15</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* the whole document *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0006"><patcit dnum="US2005112141A1" id="sr-pcit0001" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=US2005112141&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2005112141</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>TERMAN DAVID S [US]</name><date>20050526</date></document-id></patcit><category>Y</category><rel-claims>1-15</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* paragraphs [0113],  [0257],  [0295]; example 23 *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0007"><patcit dnum="EP2700708A2" id="sr-pcit0002" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=EP2700708&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2700708</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><name>UNIV BRUXELLES [BE]</name><date>20140226</date></document-id></patcit><category>Y</category><rel-claims>1-15</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* paragraphs [0151],  [0188],  [0174],  [0189] - [0191] *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0008"><nplcit id="sr-ncit0006" medium="online" npl-type="w"><online><author><name>Carina Wehner</name></author><online-title>Induktion Tumorantigen-spezifischer CD8 + T-Lymphozyten in vitro und in vivo - Dissertation</online-title><pubdate>20130701</pubdate><avail>https://edoc.ub.uni-muenchen.de/20384/1/Wehner_Carina.pdf</avail><srchdate><date>20170324</date></srchdate><refno>XP055358705</refno></online></nplcit><category>X</category><rel-claims>1-15</rel-claims><category>Y</category><rel-claims>1-15</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* the whole document *</passage></rel-passage><rel-passage><passage>* pages 113, 116 *</passage><passage>* page 139 - page 140 *</passage><passage>* page 49 - page 50 *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0009"><nplcit id="sr-ncit0007" medium="online" npl-type="w"><online><author><name>Christian Ellinger</name></author><online-title>Gezielte MHC-Klasse-II-­Kreuzpräsentation für die Generierung und Isolierung Tumor/Testis-­Antigen- spezifischer CD4 + T-- Lymphozyten - Dissertation</online-title><pubdate>20130716</pubdate><avail>https://edoc.ub.uni-muenchen.de/19870/1/Ellinger_Christian.pdf</avail><srchdate><date>20170324</date></srchdate><refno>XP055358711</refno></online></nplcit><category>Y</category><rel-claims>1-15</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* page 34 - page 35 *</passage><passage>* the whole document *</passage><passage>* page 61 - page 71 *</passage><passage>* page 107 - page 112 *</passage></rel-passage></citation></srep-citations><srep-admin><examiners><primary-examiner><name>Offermann, Stefanie</name></primary-examiner></examiners><srep-office><addressbook><text>Munich</text></addressbook></srep-office><date-search-completed><date>20210721</date></date-search-completed></srep-admin><!--							The annex lists the patent family members relating to the patent documents cited in the above mentioned European search report.							The members are as contained in the European Patent Office EDP file on							The European Patent Office is in no way liable for these particulars which are merely given for the purpose of information.							For more details about this annex : see Official Journal of the European Patent Office, No 12/82						--><srep-patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2005112141</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20050526</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2005112141</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20050526</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2009155231</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20090618</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2011059901</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20110310</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2700708</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20140226</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>DK</country><doc-number>2700708</doc-number><kind>T3</kind><date>20171023</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2700708</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20140226</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>3255143</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20171213</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>3453754</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20190313</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>ES</country><doc-number>2643943</doc-number><kind>T3</kind><date>20171127</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>HU</country><doc-number>E034907</doc-number><kind>T2</kind><date>20180328</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>PL</country><doc-number>2700708</doc-number><kind>T3</kind><date>20180131</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>PT</country><doc-number>2700708</doc-number><kind>T</kind><date>20171025</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2013108663</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20130502</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family></srep-patent-family></srep-for-pub></search-report-data>
<ep-reference-list id="ref-list">
<heading id="ref-h0001"><b>REFERENCES CITED IN THE DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0001" num=""><i>This list of references cited by the applicant is for the reader's convenience only. It does not form part of the European patent document. Even though great care has been taken in compiling the references, errors or omissions cannot be excluded and the EPO disclaims all liability in this regard.</i></p>
<heading id="ref-h0002"><b>Non-patent literature cited in the description</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0002" num="">
<ul id="ref-ul0001" list-style="bullet">
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0001" npl-type="b"><article><atl/><book><book-title>Remington's Pharmaceutical Sciences</book-title><imprint><name>Mack Publishing Co.</name></imprint></book></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0001">[0068]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0002" npl-type="s"><article><atl/><serial><sertitle>J Transl Med</sertitle><vid>10</vid></serial><location><pp><ppf>30</ppf><ppl/></pp></location></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0002">[0078]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0003" npl-type="s"><article><author><name>SHULTZ et al.</name></author><atl>Humanized mice in translational biomedical research</atl><serial><sertitle>Nat Rev Immunol</sertitle><pubdate><sdate>20070000</sdate><edate/></pubdate><vid>7</vid></serial><location><pp><ppf>118</ppf><ppl>30</ppl></pp></location></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0003">[0078]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0004" npl-type="s"><article><author><name>SPRANGER et al.</name></author><atl>Generation of Th1-polarizing dendritic cells using the TLR7/8 agonist CL075</atl><serial><sertitle>J Immunol</sertitle><pubdate><sdate>20100000</sdate><edate/></pubdate><vid>185</vid></serial><location><pp><ppf>738</ppf><ppl>47</ppl></pp></location></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0004">[0080]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0005" npl-type="s"><article><author><name>BURDEK et al.</name></author><atl>Three-day dendritic cells for vaccine development: antigen uptake, processing and presentation</atl><serial><sertitle>J Transl Med</sertitle><pubdate><sdate>20100000</sdate><edate/></pubdate><vid>8</vid></serial><location><pp><ppf>90</ppf><ppl/></pp></location></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0005">[0080]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0006" npl-type="s"><article><author><name>MORTENSON et al.</name></author><atl>Effective anti-neu-initiated antitumor responses require the complex role of CD4+ T cells</atl><serial><sertitle>Clin Cancer Res</sertitle><pubdate><sdate>20130000</sdate><edate/></pubdate><vid>19</vid></serial><location><pp><ppf>1476</ppf><ppl>86</ppl></pp></location></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0006">[0083]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0007" npl-type="s"><article><author><name>ROSENBERG et al.</name></author><atl>Cancer immunotherapy: moving beyond current vaccines</atl><serial><sertitle>Nat Med</sertitle><vid>10</vid></serial><location><pp><ppf>909</ppf><ppl>15</ppl></pp></location></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0007">[0083]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0008" npl-type="s"><article><author><name>BÜRDEK et al.</name></author><atl/><serial><sertitle>Journal of Translational Medicine</sertitle><pubdate><sdate>20100000</sdate><edate/></pubdate><vid>8</vid></serial><location><pp><ppf>90</ppf><ppl/></pp></location></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0008">[0088]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0009" npl-type="s"><article><author><name>FRENTSCH, M. et al.</name></author><atl>Direct access to CD4+ T cells specific for defined antigens according to CD154 expression</atl><serial><sertitle>Nat Med</sertitle><pubdate><sdate>20050000</sdate><edate/></pubdate><vid>11</vid><ino>10</ino></serial><location><pp><ppf>1118</ppf><ppl>1124</ppl></pp></location></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0009">[0089]</crossref></li>
</ul></p>
</ep-reference-list>
</ep-patent-document>
