<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP20167870A1" file="EP20167870NWA1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3888737" kind="A1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSKBAHRIS..MTNORSMESMMAKHTNMD..........</B001EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  1100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3888737</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT APPLICATION</B121></B120><B130>A1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>20167870.3</B210><B220><date>20200403</date></B220><B250>en</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B430></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>A61N   1/36        20060101AFI20200921BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="2"><text>A61N   1/04        20060101ALN20200921BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>A61N   1/36189     20130101 LA20200915BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>A61N   1/36128     20130101 FI20200915BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="3"><text>A61N   1/36071     20130101 LA20200915BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="4"><text>A61N   1/36167     20130101 LI20201110BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="5"><text>A61N   1/36062     20170801 LI20201110BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="6"><text>A61N   1/0456      20130101 LA20200915BHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>VERFAHREN UND SYSTEM ZUR BEREITSTELLUNG VON NEUROMODULATION</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>METHOD AND SYSTEM FOR PROVIDING NEUROMODULATION</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>PROCÉDÉ ET SYSTÈME DE FOURNITURE DE NEUROMODULATION</B542></B540><B590><B598>1</B598></B590></B500><B700><B710><B711><snm>ONWARD Medical B.V.</snm><iid>101885842</iid><irf>36044.GTE.P100EP</irf><adr><str>High Tech Campus 32</str><city>5656 AE Eindhoven</city><ctry>NL</ctry></adr></B711></B710><B720><B721><snm>KLEIBEUKER, Johan Gerard</snm><adr><str>Weegbree 5</str><city>5258HR Helvoirt</city><ctry>NL</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B740><B741><snm>DTS Patent- und Rechtsanwälte 
Schnekenbühl und Partner mbB</snm><iid>100061369</iid><adr><str>Marstallstrasse 8</str><city>80539 München</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840><B844EP><B845EP><ctry>BA</ctry></B845EP><B845EP><ctry>ME</ctry></B845EP></B844EP><B848EP><B849EP><ctry>KH</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>MA</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>MD</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>TN</ctry></B849EP></B848EP></B800></SDOBI>
<abstract id="abst" lang="en">
<p id="pa01" num="0001">A system (10) for neuromodulation, at least comprising:<br/>
- A timeline definition module (12) configured to define a timeline in which neuromodulation may be provided;<br/>
- A timeline dividing module (14) for divide the timeline into a series of time slots;<br/>
- several neuromodulation entities (16), each entity (16) being capable to claim at least one slot exclusively for providing neuromodulation.</p>
<p id="pa02" num="0002">The invention further relates to a method for neuromodulation.
<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="129" he="114" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p>
</abstract>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<p id="p0001" num="0001">The present disclosure relates to a method and system for providing neuromodulation.</p>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">Epidural electrostimulation (EES) shows promising results for spinal cord injury therapy. The mechanisms are still unclear and under investigation, but EES can both stimulate the leg muscles through the proprioceptive afferent fibers and restore the neuronal network in the spinal cord. EES uses a multi-electrode array placed on the dorsal side of the spinal cord on top of the dura matter. In rats, the combination of serotonergic agonists and EES was able to acutely transform spinal networks from non-functional to highly functional and adaptive states as early as 1 week after injury (<nplcit id="ncit0001" npl-type="s"><text>Courtine G, et al., Transformation of nonfunctional spinal circuits into functional states after the loss of brain input. Nature neuroscience 12, 1333-1342, (2009</text></nplcit><i>)</i>)<i>.</i> Moreover, EES also restores voluntary control of locomotion by rewiring the injured spinal cord area (<nplcit id="ncit0002" npl-type="s"><text>Wenger N, et al., Spatiotemporal neuromodulation therapies engaging muscle synergies improve motor control after spinal cord injury, Nature Medicine 22, 138-145 (2016</text></nplcit><i>)</i>)<i>.</i></p>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">Because of the complexity of the spinal cord, delivering EES stimulation on the multi-electrode array (lead) implanted is quite challenging. Computational models were designed and tested on both rats and human (<nplcit id="ncit0003" npl-type="s"><text>Capogrosso M, et al., A Computational Model for Epidural Electrical Stimulation of Spinal Sensorimotor Circuits, Journal of Neuroscience 4 December 2013, 33 (49) 19326-19340</text></nplcit>) to evaluate the neuronal and muscular response to the stimulation, as well as closed-loop neuromodulation systems that refined locomotion after complete spinal cord injury (<nplcit id="ncit0004" npl-type="s"><text>Wenger N, et al., Closed-loop neuromodulation of spinal sensorimotor circuits controls refined locomotion after complete spinal cord injury, in Science Translational Medicine, vol. 6, num. 255, 2014</text></nplcit>).</p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">The degree of control required on the neurostimulation restricts largely the available stimulation settings (stimulus space). The stimulation settings must comply with hardware limitations, with requirements on the predictive capability of the system and with safety regulatory norms. For instance, the hardware has a limited power supply, the stimulation outcome (muscle activation) must be controlled, and the electrode chemical stability must be insured independently of the stimulation settings used.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">Moreover, each muscle has a different response according to the nerve fibers stimulation settings. Each muscle is associated with nerve fibers and a stimulation area on the implanted lead. This association is called a functional muscle block (FMB), also referred to as stimulation block (SB). The muscle response will vary with the amplitude, but also with the frequency, the pulse shape, or the use of burst of pulses rather than continuous frequency stimulation. Thus, during a gait cycle, the different FMBs need to be stimulated simultaneously with different pulsed electrical waveforms at different frequencies and amplitudes, sometimes with different pattern of pulses, in order to reproduce a normal-like cycle. In other words, multiple stimulation blocks may exist at the same time. Multiple channels (i.e. multiple FMBs/SBs, pulsed electrical waveforms) variable frequency neurostimulation is harder to control since the neurostimulation's pulses might temporally overlap in time. Overlapping of pulses creates several issues:
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="dash">
<li>It is hardly possible to output 2 pulses on the same electrode simultaneously;</li>
<li>If the electrodes are different, the overlapping of 2 pulses will require a higher voltage on the power supply line, and thus will draw out more power from the battery than if they were outputted one after the other. This second point is critical in implantable devices since the battery lifetime is one of the main concerns;</li>
<li>The muscle response (outcome) achieved with temporally overlapping pulses will potentially differ from the outcome reached with the same pulses taken separately. Current knowledge of the muscle response induce by spinal cord neurostimulation is limited to strictly orthogonal pulsing.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">A stimulation block may be managed by a neuromodulation entity that may require multiple electrodes and at least one pulse generator to implement the required stimulation block.</p>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">The pulse generator may be an implantable pulse generator or a non-implantable pulse generator.</p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">The multiple electrodes may be arranged in an electrode lead and/or electrode array.</p>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">To stimulate in a controlled fashion and in a secure way a solution to avoid temporal overlap of the pulses and/or stimulation blocks is needed.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">One method to avoid overlap of the pulses between pulsed electrical waveforms is to allow only one pulse at a time, and to delay the others. The method, called the "token approach", is described in the patent <i>"</i><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US20110054568A1"><text>US20110054568A1</text></patcit><i>"</i> assigned to the <i>"Boston Scientific Neuromodulation Corporation".</i> If 2 pulse generators want to output a pulse at the same time, one gets the priority and the other is delayed. Other patents on close-by methods identified as pulse positioning methods were also filed by the same company (<i>"</i><patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="US8543200B2"><text>US8543200B2</text></patcit><i>", "</i><patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="US8768481B2"><text>US8768481B2</text></patcit><i>'</i>). They aim to place the pulses on the timeline in such a way that pulses don't bump into each other, in other words, that overlap is avoided. With these methods, each pulsed electrical waveform will not have a constant frequency, but an instantaneous frequency within a jitter specification. For instance, the requirement can bound the jitter at 10% of the nominal frequency for each pulsed electrical waveform. Thus, at any given instant, a pulsed electrical waveform at the nominal frequency 40 Hz will have its instantaneous frequency between 36 Hz and 44 Hz.</p>
<p id="p0011" num="0011"><patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="US4398537A"><text>US 4,398,537</text></patcit> relates to an independently rate-adjusting multiple channel controller for nerve stimulator transmitter to be used in conjunction with implanted stimulation pulse output unit, wherein an event that two or more trigger signals coincide in the transmitting circuit, the rate control circuit blocks and delays the latter occurring trigger signal with only minor or insignificant effect on a trigger signal rate.</p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012"><patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="US20110160810A1"><text>US 2011/0160810 A1</text></patcit> relates to a multi-channel neurostimulation system comprising a plurality of electrical terminals configured for being respectively coupled to a plurality of electrodes, stimulation output circuitry including electrical source circuitry of the same polarity configured for generating a polarity of pulse electrical waveforms in a plurality of timing channels. Furthermore, there is a control circuitry configured for instructing the stimulation output circuitry to serially couple the electrical source circuitry to different sets of the electrodes when pulses of the respective pulsed electrical waveforms do not temporarily overlap each other, and for instructing the stimulation output circuitry to couple the electrical source circuitry to a union of the different electrode sets when pulses of the respective pulsed electrical waveforms temporarily overlap each other.</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013"><patcit id="pcit0006" dnum="US8543200B2"><text>US 8,543,200 B2</text></patcit> relates to methods to avoid frequency locking and a multi-channel neurostimulation system using pulse placement. A plurality of pulse electrical waveforms is respectively delivered within a plurality of timing channels of the neurostimulation system,<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> thereby treating the patient. Sets of stimulation pulses within the electrical waveforms that will potentially overlap temporarily are predicted. Each of the potentially overlapping pulse sets is substituted with a replacement stimulation pulse, such that each replacement stimulation pulse is delivered within at least one of the respective timing channels, thereby preventing temporal overlap between the stimulation pulses of the respective electrical waveforms while preventing frequency locking between the timing channels.</p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">It is an object of the present invention to provide a solution for a method and system that can avoid partial and/or full overlap of pulses of neuromodulation/neurostimulation, in particular of multichannel and/or variable neuromodulation/neurostimulation, without blocking, replacing, delaying and/or deleting pulses.</p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">This object is solved by the method according to claim 1. Accordingly, a method for providing neuromodulation comprising at least the following steps:
<ul id="ul0002" list-style="dash">
<li>Define a timeline in which neuromodulation may be provided;</li>
<li>Divide the timeline into a series of time slots;</li>
<li>Provide several neuromodulation entities, each entity being capable to claim at least one slot exclusively for providing neuromodulation.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">The invention is based on the basic idea that a temporal overlapping of stimulation events (with stimulation events happening in one or more pulse trains), which can happen in neuromodulation, e.g. multi-channel and/or variable frequency neurostimulation, has to be avoided or minimized to limit the potential adverse impact (e.g. therapeutic side effects, loss of efficacy and/or unsafe situations) on the intended therapy. A timeline is divided into a series of time slots. Each slot can be claimed by a neuromodulation entity (which may manage a stimulation block) for stimulation of a group of electrodes where the electrodes may have different state like anodic, cathodic, floating or grounding. A neuromodulation entity that claimed a time slot may use that reserved time to apply stimulation. This may guarantee that no pulses are colliding (and thus causing therapeutic side effects) due to the exclusivity rights regarding respective time slots.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">A stimulation block may be managed by a neuromodulation entity that may require one or multiple electrodes and at least one pulse generator to implement the required stimulation block.</p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">The pulse generator may be an implantable pulse generator or a non-implantable pulse generator.</p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">The multiple electrodes may be arranged in an electrode lead and/or electrode array.</p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">It may be generally possible that two or more neuromodulation entities share one or more electrodes and/or a pulse generator.</p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">A neuromodulation entity may claim a series of time slots equally spaced to deliver stimulation at regular intervals, representing a stimulation frequency. This may be advantageous where repetitive responses to the neuromodulation provided are expected, for example during continuous motion sequences, including but not limited to walking, running, swimming, stepping, running, rowing. Further, this may be advantageous for stimulating autonomic function, smooth muscle function, sphincter function, etc.</p>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">Alternatively, a neuromodulation entity may claim a series of time slots not equally spaced, e.g. to implement other features like frequency ramping. This may be advantageous where discontinuous responses to the neuromodulation provided are expected, for example during discontinuous movements, including but not limited to standing up, sitting down, grasping, jumping.</p>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">Alternatively, and/or additionally, a neuromodulation entity may claim alternating series to allow other stimulation entities having their series interleaved. This may be advantageous where neuromodulation is provided in order to evoke complex physiological responses with multiple FMBs/SBs included, wherein the responses to the neuromodulation do not have the same duration.</p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">In particular, the neuromodulation may be or may comprise neurostimulation. In general, neurostimulation may be or may comprise electrical neurostimulation. However, alternatively and/or additionally, mechanical neurostimulation and/or pharmacological neurostimulation could be generally possible.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">It is generally possible, that electrical neurostimulation comprises transcutaneous electrical stimulation (TENS), epidural electrical stimulation (EES), functional electrical stimulation (FES), intramuscular stimulation (IMS), dorsal root ganglion stimulation, subdural stimulation, cardiac stimulation system, optogenetics, optotrodes, patch-clamp, intra-cellular electrodes and/or extra-cellular electrodes.</p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">Neuromodulation, in particular neurostimulation may be or may comprise central nervous system (CNS) stimulation and/or peripheral nervous system stimulation (PNS).</p>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">The method may comprise the further step of providing an arbitration unit, wherein by means of the arbitration unit a slot is assigned to one of the claiming neuromodulation entities. In other words, when more than one neuromodulation entity wants to claim a time slot, the arbitration unit may assign the time slot to one of the claiming stimulation entities.</p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">It may be understood that also multiple sots may be assigned.</p>
<p id="p0029" num="0029">The assignment may be random or based on at least one predefined rule or predefined set of rules.</p>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">Thus, it may be possible that the arbitration unit assigns the slot randomly. This may have the advantage that no neuromodulation entity is preferred compared to other stimulation entities.</p>
<p id="p0031" num="0031">Alternatively, and/or additionally, the arbitration unit may assign the slot based on at least one predefined rule or a set of predefined rules. This may have the advantage that a neuromodulation entity with certain priority is preferred compared to other stimulation entities.</p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032">A predefined rule or a set of predefined rules may use various properties to make the decision which neuromodulation entity may get which time slot or which time slots.</p>
<p id="p0033" num="0033">It may be possible to use the stimulation properties of the neuromodulation entity, like amplitude, repetition frequency, pulse width and/or stimulation mode (burst stimulation or no burst stimulation).<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p>
<p id="p0034" num="0034">To implement burst stimulations that do have a higher time resolution then the slots, the stimulation may claim multiple adjacent slots to implement such burst stimulation, for instance, when a neuromodulation entity wants to position a number of pulses on at least two adjacent slots. Only when both claims are honored the neuromodulation entity may continue its stimulation output at the slot boundary between both claimed slots.</p>
<p id="p0035" num="0035">Alternatively, and/or additionally, it may be possible to use therapeutic properties, e.g. prioritization of e.g. particular nerve stimulation and/or tonic background stimulation. For instance, a neuromodulation entity for providing stimulation to maintain blood pressure may be prioritized compared to stimulation entities for providing stimulation to evoke motor responses. Further, for instance, a certain motor response may be prioritized compared to at least one other motor response.</p>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">Alternatively, and/or additionally, it may be possible to use electronic properties, e.g. prioritization of pulses using less energy. This may be advantageous for the system in order to save energy and/or battery power.</p>
<p id="p0037" num="0037">Alternatively, and/or additionally, it may be possible to use spatial properties, e.g. when two or more stimulation entities claim the same time slot but require electrode configurations that do not corrupt each other based on the stimulation properties, e.g. because they are spaced in a certain distance from each other, e.g. on an electrode array, the arbitration unit may honor the claims of each neuromodulation entity.</p>
<p id="p0038" num="0038">Alternatively, and/or additionally, it may be possible to use safety properties, e.g. when claims lead to safety issues, like too high charge density, the arbitration unit may use this for arbitration. Alternatively, when grounding is required remaining charge may be removed. This may help to prevent damage of the hardware.</p>
<p id="p0039" num="0039">Alternatively, and/or additionally, it may be possible to use starvation, in particular to prevent that claims of a particular neuromodulation entity are refused subsequently.</p>
<p id="p0040" num="0040">Apart from arbitration on the time slot, the arbitration unit may additionally and/or alternatively overrule requesting stimulation parameters of a claiming neuromodulation entity such that two claims on the same slot can be honored by using this new stimulation setting.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></p>
<p id="p0041" num="0041">It may be possible that the slots are at least partially equally spaced and/or arranged.</p>
<p id="p0042" num="0042">In particular, the slots may be at least partially unequally spaced and/or arranged, especially to create, time base, ramping scenarios or the like.</p>
<p id="p0043" num="0043">In case that multiple stimulation entities want to operate independently from each other they shall have series (repetitions) that do not collide. Frequencies may be selected such that they may be maximally interleaved without collisions. Aligning input frequency in series of power of two may result in interleaving them such in the free sots without the need of slot arbitration.</p>
<p id="p0044" num="0044">Furthermore, the present invention relates to a system for neuromodulation, at least comprising:
<ul id="ul0003" list-style="dash">
<li>A timeline definition module configured to define a timeline in which neuromodulation may be provided;</li>
<li>A timeline dividing module to divide the timeline into a series of time slots;</li>
<li>several neuromodulation entities, each entity being capable to claim at least one slot exclusively for providing neuromodulation.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0045" num="0045">The system may comprise or may be a neurostimulation system. In particular, the neurostimulation system may be an electrical neurostimulation system, a mechanical stimulation system and/or a pharmacological stimulation system.</p>
<p id="p0046" num="0046">Thus, the neuromodulation entities may be neurostimulation entities.</p>
<p id="p0047" num="0047">It is generally possible, that electrical neurostimulation system comprises a transcutaneous electrical stimulation system (TENS), epidural electrical stimulation system (EES), functional electrical stimulation system (FES), intramuscular stimulation system (IMS), dorsal root ganglion stimulation system, subdural stimulation system, cardiac stimulation system, optogenetics, optotrodes, patch-clamp, intra-cellular electrodes and/or extra-cellular electrodes.<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></p>
<p id="p0048" num="0048">It may be generally possible that the neuromodulation system is a central nervous system (CNS) stimulation system and/or peripheral nervous system stimulation (PNS) system.</p>
<p id="p0049" num="0049">The system may further comprise an arbitration unit, wherein the arbitration unit is configured to assign at least one slot to one of the claiming neuromodulation entities.</p>
<p id="p0050" num="0050">The arbitration unit may assign the slot randomly.</p>
<p id="p0051" num="0051">Alternatively, and/or additionally, the arbitration unit may assign the slot based on at least one predefined rule or a set of predefined rules.</p>
<p id="p0052" num="0052">In particular the slots may be at least partially equally spaced and/or arranged.</p>
<p id="p0053" num="0053">In particular, the slots may be at least partially unequally spaced and/or arranged, especially to create ramping scenarios or the like.</p>
<p id="p0054" num="0054">In particular, the system may be configured to perform the method according to one of claims 1 to 7.</p>
<p id="p0055" num="0055">Further details and advantages of the present invention shall now be disclosed in connection with the drawings.</p>
<p id="p0056" num="0056">It is shown in
<dl id="dl0001">
<dt>Fig. 1</dt><dd>a schematical overview of an embodiment of the system for neuromodulation according to the present invention, with which the method according to the present invention can be performed;</dd>
<dt>Fig. 2</dt><dd>an example of frequencies/ series selection with the system and method according to the present invention;</dd>
<dt>Fig. 3</dt><dd>an example for interleaving frequencies, defined according to the present invention;<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></dd>
<dt>fig. 4</dt><dd>a further example for interleaving frequencies, defined according to the present invention; and</dd>
<dt>Fig. 5</dt><dd>an example of frequencies/ series selection with the system and method according to the present invention (cf. <figref idref="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>), comprising a second series that can be added with minimal impact on the first series.</dd>
</dl></p>
<p id="p0057" num="0057"><figref idref="f0001"><b>Fig. 1</b></figref> shows a schematical overview of an embodiment of the system 10 for neuromodulation, with which the method according to the present invention can be performed.</p>
<p id="p0058" num="0058">The system 10 comprises a timeline definition module 12.</p>
<p id="p0059" num="0059">In this embodiment, the system 10 further comprises a timeline dividing module 14.</p>
<p id="p0060" num="0060">In this embodiment, the system 10 further comprises two neuromodulation entities 16.</p>
<p id="p0061" num="0061">In an alternative embodiment the system 10 could further comprise more than two neuromodulation entities 16.</p>
<p id="p0062" num="0062">The timeline definition module 12 is connected to the timeline dividing module 14.</p>
<p id="p0063" num="0063">In this embodiment, the connection between the timeline definition module 12 and the timeline dividing module 14 is a direct connection.</p>
<p id="p0064" num="0064">However, alternatively, the connection between the timeline definition module 12 and the timeline dividing module 14 could be an indirect connection.</p>
<p id="p0065" num="0065">In this embodiment, the connection between the timeline definition module 12 and the timeline dividing module 14 is a bidirectional connection.</p>
<p id="p0066" num="0066">However, alternatively, the connection between the timeline definition module 12 and the timeline dividing module 14 could be a unidirectional connection (from the timeline definition module 12 to the timeline dividing module 14 or vice versa).<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></p>
<p id="p0067" num="0067">In this embodiment, the connection between the timeline definition module 12 and the timeline dividing module 14 is a wireless connection.</p>
<p id="p0068" num="0068">However, alternatively, the connection between the timeline definition module 12 and the timeline dividing module 14 could be a cable bound connection.</p>
<p id="p0069" num="0069">The timeline dividing module 14 is connected to the two neuromodulation entities 16.</p>
<p id="p0070" num="0070">In this embodiment, the connections between the timeline dividing module 14 and the two stimulation entities 16 are direct connections.</p>
<p id="p0071" num="0071">However, alternatively, the connections between the timeline dividing module 14 and the two stimulation entities 16 could be indirect connections.</p>
<p id="p0072" num="0072">In this embodiment, the connections between the timeline dividing module 14 and the two stimulation entities 16 are bidirectional connections.</p>
<p id="p0073" num="0073">However, alternatively, the connections between the timeline definition module 14 and the two stimulation entities 16 could be unidirectional connections (from the timeline definition module 14 to the two stimulation entities 16 or vice versa).</p>
<p id="p0074" num="0074">In this embodiment, the connections between the timeline dividing module 14 and the two stimulation entities 16 are wireless connections.</p>
<p id="p0075" num="0075">However, alternatively, the connection between the timeline dividing module 14 and the two neuromodulation entities 16 could cable bound connections.</p>
<p id="p0076" num="0076">Not shown in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is that the two neuromodulation entities 16 could be connected to each other, via a direct or indirect connection, a unidirectional or bidirectional direction and/or a wireless or cable-bound connection.</p>
<p id="p0077" num="0077">The timeline definition module 12 defines a timeline T in which neuromodulation may be provided.<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></p>
<p id="p0078" num="0078">In general, the timeline T may be a timeline with a defined start and a defined end or an endless timeline, thus with endless repetitions.</p>
<p id="p0079" num="0079">In this embodiment, the timeline dividing module 14 divides the timeline T into a series of time slots.</p>
<p id="p0080" num="0080">In this embodiment, the neuromodulation entities 16 claim at least one slot exclusively for providing neuromodulation.</p>
<p id="p0081" num="0081">Not shown in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is that the neuromodulation system 10 is a neurostimulation system 10.</p>
<p id="p0082" num="0082">Alternatively, and/or additionally, the neuromodulation system 10 could comprise a neurostimulation system 10.</p>
<p id="p0083" num="0083">Not shown in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is that the system 10 could further comprise an arbitration unit 18.</p>
<p id="p0084" num="0084">No shown in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is that the arbitration unit 18 could be connected to each of the other subsystems, i.e. the timeline definition module 12 and/or the timeline dividing module 14 and/or each of the neuromodulation entities 16.</p>
<p id="p0085" num="0085">Not shown in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is that each connection could be a direct or indirect connection, a cable-bound or wireless connection and/or a unidirectional or bidirectional connection.</p>
<p id="p0086" num="0086">Not shown in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is that the arbitration unit 18 could be configured to assign at least one slot to one of the claiming neuromodulation entities 16.</p>
<p id="p0087" num="0087">Not shown in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is that the arbitration unit 18 could assign the slot randomly.</p>
<p id="p0088" num="0088">Further not shown in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is that the arbitration unit 18 could assign the slot based on at least one predefined rule or a set of predefined rules.</p>
<p id="p0089" num="0089">Not shown in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is that the arbitration unit 18 could assign multiple slots.</p>
<p id="p0090" num="0090">Further not shown in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is that the slots could be at least partially equally spaced and/or arranged.<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></p>
<p id="p0091" num="0091">Further not shown in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is that the slots could be at least partially unequally spaced and/or arranged, especially to create ramping scenarios or the like.</p>
<p id="p0092" num="0092">Further not shown in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is that the system 10 could be configured to perform the following method:<br/>
A method for providing neuromodulation comprising at least the following steps:
<ul id="ul0004" list-style="dash">
<li>Define a timeline T in which neuromodulation may be provided;</li>
<li>Divide the timeline T into a series of time slots;</li>
<li>Provide several neuromodulation entities, 16 each entity 16 being capable to claim at least one slot exclusively for providing neuromodulation.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0093" num="0093">The neuromodulation could comprise or could be neurostimulation.</p>
<p id="p0094" num="0094">The method could further comprise the further step of providing an arbitration unit 18, wherein by means of arbitration unit 18 at least one slot is assigned to one of the claiming neuromodulation entities 16.</p>
<p id="p0095" num="0095">The arbitration unit 18 could assign the slot randomly.</p>
<p id="p0096" num="0096">Alternatively, and/or additionally, the arbitration unit 18 could assign the slot based on at least one predefined rule or a set of predefined rules.</p>
<p id="p0097" num="0097">The slots could be at least partially equally spaced and/or arranged.</p>
<p id="p0098" num="0098">The slots could be at least partially unequally spaced and/or arranged, especially to create, time base, ramping scenarios or the like.</p>
<p id="p0099" num="0099">Not shown in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is that, when the arbitration unit 18 assigns the slot based on at least one predefined rule or a set of predefined rules, the predefined rule or set of predefined rules<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> could use various properties to make the decision which neuromodulation entity 16 may get the time slot.</p>
<p id="p0100" num="0100">It could be possible to use the stimulation properties of the neuromodulation entity, like amplitude, repetition frequency, pulse width and/or stimulation mode (burst stimulation or no burst stimulation).</p>
<p id="p0101" num="0101">Alternatively, and/or additionally, it could be possible to use therapeutic properties, e.g. prioritization of e.g. particular nerve stimulation and/or tonic background stimulation.</p>
<p id="p0102" num="0102">Alternatively, and/or additionally, it could be possible to use electronic properties, e.g. prioritization of pulses using less energy.</p>
<p id="p0103" num="0103">Alternatively, and/or additionally, it could be possible to use spatial properties, e.g. when two or more stimulation entities claim the same time slot but require electrode configurations that do not corrupt each other based on the stimulation properties, the arbitration unit may honor both claims.</p>
<p id="p0104" num="0104">Alternatively, and/or additionally, it could be possible to use safety properties, e.g. when claims lead to safety issues, like too high charge density, the arbitration unit can may use this for arbitration.</p>
<p id="p0105" num="0105">Alternatively, when grounding is required remaining charge could be removed.</p>
<p id="p0106" num="0106">Alternatively, and/or additionally, it could be possible to use starvation, in particular to prevent that claims of a particular neuromodulation entity are refused subsequently.</p>
<p id="p0107" num="0107">In other words, the system 10 disclosed in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is used for performing a method according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p0108" num="0108">When multiple neuromodulation entities 16 want to operate independently from each other they shall have series (repetitions) that do not collide.</p>
<p id="p0109" num="0109">Frequencies are selected such that it could be maximally interleaved without collisions.<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --></p>
<p id="p0110" num="0110">The input frequency in series of power of two is aligned such that they can be interleaved in the free slots without the need of slot arbitration.</p>
<p id="p0111" num="0111">In this example, 600 equally spaced slots with 1666 microseconds each are assumed.</p>
<p id="p0112" num="0112">However, additionally and/or alternatively, any number and duration of slots could be generally possible.</p>
<p id="p0113" num="0113">If one selects the following frequencies (as a power of 2) the following results occur:<br/>
600 Hz, 300 Hz, 150 Hz, 75 Hz, 37.5 Hz, 18.75 Hz, 9,375 Hz, etc.</p>
<p id="p0114" num="0114">Those frequencies have the corresponding repletion frequencies as disclosed in <figref idref="f0002"><b>Fig. 2</b></figref><b>.</b></p>
<p id="p0115" num="0115">With this set it is possible to make any combination as along as the sum of the frequencies do extend beyond 600 Hz:
<ul id="ul0005" list-style="none">
<li>As an example, the following combination could be possible: 1x300 Hz, 1x150 Hz, 3x75 Hz.</li>
<li>As another example, the following combination could possible: 2x150 Hz + 3x75 Hz, cf. <figref idref="f0003"><b>Fig. 3</b></figref><b>.</b></li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0116" num="0116">In particular, <figref idref="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> shows a timeline T in which neuromodulation could be provided.</p>
<p id="p0117" num="0117">The timeline T disclosed in <figref idref="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> is provided by the system 10 disclosed in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, and the corresponding method.</p>
<p id="p0118" num="0118">The timeline T is divided into a series of time slots (indicated as space between two adjacent vertical lines).</p>
<p id="p0119" num="0119">In this embodiment, the slots are equally spaced and/or arranged.</p>
<p id="p0120" num="0120">In particular, relation to several neuromodulation entities 16 are indicated, and each neuromodulation entity 16 is capable to claim at least one slot exclusively for providing neuromodulation.<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></p>
<p id="p0121" num="0121">In other words, several neuromodulation entities 16, each entity 16 being capable to claim several slots exclusively for providing neuromodulation are indicated.</p>
<p id="p0122" num="0122"><figref idref="f0004"><b>Fig. 4</b></figref> discloses an example of interleaving two burst frequencies (three pulses every 37.5 Hz, indicated as 37.5B) and three regular frequencies of 75 Hz.</p>
<p id="p0123" num="0123">In particular, <figref idref="f0004">Fig. 4</figref> shows a timeline T in which neuromodulation could be provided.</p>
<p id="p0124" num="0124">The timeline T disclosed in <figref idref="f0004">Fig. 4</figref> is provided by the system 10 disclosed in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, and the corresponding method.</p>
<p id="p0125" num="0125">The timeline T is divided into a series of time slots (indicated as space between two adjacent vertical lines).</p>
<p id="p0126" num="0126">In this embodiment, the slots are equally spaced and/or arranged.</p>
<p id="p0127" num="0127">In particular, relation to several neuromodulation entities 16 are indicated, and each neuromodulation entity 16 is capable to claim at least one slot exclusively for providing neuromodulation.</p>
<p id="p0128" num="0128">To implement burst stimulations that do have a higher time resolution then the time slots, respective stimulation entities 16 claim multiple adjacent slots to implement such burst stimulation.</p>
<p id="p0129" num="0129">To accommodate more frequencies between the power of two, a second series can be added to a first series (cf. example shown in <figref idref="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>), the second series minimally impacting the first series, cf. <figref idref="f0005"><b>Fig. 5</b></figref><b>.</b></p>
<p id="p0130" num="0130">Series 1 S1 and series 2 S2 are shown.</p>
<p id="p0131" num="0131">Note that not all frequencies need to be part of the series S1, S2.<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></p>
<p id="p0132" num="0132">If the bold marked frequencies are excluded, repeats that are multiples of four are provided, which can be interleaved resulting in a set of frequencies that are spaced and can be combined according to their repletion nature.<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></p>
<p id="p0133" num="0133"><b><u>References</u></b>
<dl id="dl0002" compact="compact">
<dt>10</dt><dd>system</dd>
<dt>12</dt><dd>timeline definition module</dd>
<dt>14</dt><dd>timeline dividing module</dd>
<dt>16</dt><dd>neuromodulation entity</dd>
<dt>18</dt><dd>arbitration unit</dd>
</dl>
<dl id="dl0003" compact="compact">
<dt>S1</dt><dd>series 1</dd>
<dt>S2</dt><dd>series 2</dd>
<dt>T</dt><dd>Timeline</dd>
</dl></p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> -->
<claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>A method for providing neuromodulation comprising at least the following steps:
<claim-text>- Define a timeline (T) in which neuromodulation may be provided;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- Divide the timeline (T) into a series of time slots;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- Provide several neuromodulation entities (16), each entity (16) being capable to claim at least one slot exclusively for providing neuromodulation.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>The method according to claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b> the neuromodulation comprises or is neurostimulation.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>The method of claim 1 or claim 2, <b>characterized in that</b> the method comprises the further step of
<claim-text>- Providing an arbitration unit (18), wherein by means of arbitration unit (18) a slot is assigned to one of the claiming neuromodulation entities (16).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>The method of claim 3, <b>characterized in that</b> the arbitration unit assigns the slot randomly.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>The method of claim 3, <b>characterized in that</b> the arbitration unit (18) assigns the slot based on at least one predefined rule or a set of predefined rules.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>The method according to one of the preceding claims, <b>characterized in that</b> the slots are at least partially equally spaced and/or arranged.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>The method according to one of the preceding claims, <b>characterized in that</b> the slots are at least partially unequally spaced and/or arranged, especially to create, time base, ramping scenarios or the like.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>A system (10) for neuromodulation, at least comprising:
<claim-text>- A timeline definition module (12) configured to define a timeline (T) in which neuromodulation may be provided;<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>- A timeline dividing module (14) to divide the timeline (T) into a series of time slots;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- several neuromodulation entities (16), each entity (16) being capable to claim at least one slot exclusively for providing neuromodulation.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>The system (10) according to claim 8, <b>characterized in that</b> the system (10) for neuromodulation comprises or is a system (10) for neurostimulation.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>The system (10) of claim 9 or claim 10, <b>characterized in that</b> the system (10) further comprises
<claim-text>- an arbitration unit (18), wherein the arbitration unit is configured to assign a slot to one of the claiming neuromodulation entities.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>The system (10) of claim 10, <b>characterized in that</b> the arbitration unit (18) assigns the slot randomly.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>The system (10) of claim 10, <b>characterized in that</b> the arbitration unit (18) assigns the slot based on at least one predefined rule or a set of predefined rules.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>The system (10) according to one of the claims 8 to 12, <b>characterized in that</b> the slots are at least partially equally spaced and/or arranged.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>The system (10) according to one of the claims 8 to 13, <b>characterized in that</b> the slots are at least partially unequally spaced and/or arranged, especially to create ramping scenarios or the like.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0015" num="0015">
<claim-text>The system (10) according to one of claims 8 to 14, <b>characterized in that</b> the system (10) is configured to perform the method according to one of claims 1 to 7.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="163" he="148" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="157" he="83" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> -->
<figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="118" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> -->
<figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="114" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> -->
<figure id="f0005" num="5"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="146" he="148" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<search-report-data id="srep" lang="en" srep-office="EP" date-produced=""><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="157" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="155" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data><search-report-data date-produced="20200915" id="srepxml" lang="en" srep-office="EP" srep-type="ep-sr" status="n"><!--
 The search report data in XML is provided for the users' convenience only. It might differ from the search report of the PDF document, which contains the officially published data. The EPO disclaims any liability for incorrect or incomplete data in the XML for search reports.
 -->

<srep-info><file-reference-id>36044.GTE.P100EP</file-reference-id><application-reference><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>20167870.3</doc-number></document-id></application-reference><applicant-name><name>GTX medical B.V.</name></applicant-name><srep-established srep-established="yes"/><srep-invention-title title-approval="yes"/><srep-abstract abs-approval="yes"/><srep-figure-to-publish figinfo="by-applicant"><figure-to-publish><fig-number>1</fig-number></figure-to-publish></srep-figure-to-publish><srep-info-admin><srep-office><addressbook><text>MN</text></addressbook></srep-office><date-search-report-mailed><date>20200925</date></date-search-report-mailed></srep-info-admin></srep-info><srep-for-pub><srep-fields-searched><minimum-documentation><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr><text>A61N</text></classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr></minimum-documentation></srep-fields-searched><srep-citations><citation id="sr-cit0001"><patcit dnum="US2011054570A1" id="sr-pcit0001" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=US2011054570&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2011054570</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>LANE COURTNEY [US]</name><date>20110303</date></document-id></patcit><category>X</category><rel-claims>1-10,12,13,15</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* abstract; figures 1-12 *</passage><passage>* paragraphs [0031] - [0064] *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0002"><patcit dnum="US2011054567A1" id="sr-pcit0002" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=US2011054567&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2011054567</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>LANE COURTNEY [US] ET AL</name><date>20110303</date></document-id></patcit><category>A</category><rel-claims>1-15</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* abstract; figures 1-22 *</passage><passage>* paragraphs [0044] - [0098] *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0003"><patcit dnum="US2014005753A1" id="sr-pcit0003" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=US2014005753&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2014005753</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>CARBUNARU RAFAEL [US]</name><date>20140102</date></document-id></patcit><category>A</category><rel-claims>1-15</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* abstract; figures 1-17 *</passage><passage>* paragraphs [0042] - [0092] *</passage></rel-passage></citation></srep-citations><srep-admin><examiners><primary-examiner><name>Mendelevitch, L</name></primary-examiner></examiners><srep-office><addressbook><text>Munich</text></addressbook></srep-office><date-search-completed><date>20200915</date></date-search-completed></srep-admin><!--							The annex lists the patent family members relating to the patent documents cited in the above mentioned European search report.							The members are as contained in the European Patent Office EDP file on							The European Patent Office is in no way liable for these particulars which are merely given for the purpose of information.							For more details about this annex : see Official Journal of the European Patent Office, No 12/82						--><srep-patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2011054570</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20110303</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>AU</country><doc-number>2010286537</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20120315</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>CA</country><doc-number>2772570</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20110303</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2470261</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20120704</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>ES</country><doc-number>2599074</doc-number><kind>T3</kind><date>20170131</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>5542208</doc-number><kind>B2</kind><date>20140709</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2013503017</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20130131</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2011054570</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20110303</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2011025983</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20110303</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2011054567</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20110303</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2011054567</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20110303</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2017326365</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20171116</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2014005753</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140102</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>AU</country><doc-number>2013282356</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20141120</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2866888</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20150506</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>6163549</doc-number><kind>B2</kind><date>20170712</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2015521532</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20150730</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2014005753</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140102</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2016250472</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20160901</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2014005075</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140103</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family></srep-patent-family></srep-for-pub></search-report-data>
<ep-reference-list id="ref-list">
<heading id="ref-h0001"><b>REFERENCES CITED IN THE DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0001" num=""><i>This list of references cited by the applicant is for the reader's convenience only. It does not form part of the European patent document. Even though great care has been taken in compiling the references, errors or omissions cannot be excluded and the EPO disclaims all liability in this regard.</i></p>
<heading id="ref-h0002"><b>Patent documents cited in the description</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0002" num="">
<ul id="ref-ul0001" list-style="bullet">
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0001" dnum="US20110054568A1"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>20110054568</doc-number><kind>A1</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0001">[0010]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0002" dnum="US8543200B2"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>8543200</doc-number><kind>B2</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0002">[0010]</crossref><crossref idref="pcit0006">[0013]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0003" dnum="US8768481B2"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>8768481</doc-number><kind>B2</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0003">[0010]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0004" dnum="US4398537A"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>4398537</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0004">[0011]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0005" dnum="US20110160810A1"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>20110160810</doc-number><kind>A1</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0005">[0012]</crossref></li>
</ul></p>
<heading id="ref-h0003"><b>Non-patent literature cited in the description</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0003" num="">
<ul id="ref-ul0002" list-style="bullet">
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0001" npl-type="s"><article><author><name>COURTINE G et al.</name></author><atl>Transformation of nonfunctional spinal circuits into functional states after the loss of brain input</atl><serial><sertitle>Nature neuroscience</sertitle><pubdate><sdate>20090000</sdate><edate/></pubdate><vid>12</vid></serial><location><pp><ppf>1333</ppf><ppl>1342</ppl></pp></location></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0001">[0002]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0002" npl-type="s"><article><author><name>WENGER N et al.</name></author><atl>Spatiotemporal neuromodulation therapies engaging muscle synergies improve motor control after spinal cord injury</atl><serial><sertitle>Nature Medicine</sertitle><pubdate><sdate>20160000</sdate><edate/></pubdate><vid>22</vid></serial><location><pp><ppf>138</ppf><ppl>145</ppl></pp></location></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0002">[0002]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0003" npl-type="s"><article><author><name>CAPOGROSSO M et al.</name></author><atl>A Computational Model for Epidural Electrical Stimulation of Spinal Sensorimotor Circuits</atl><serial><sertitle>Journal of Neuroscience</sertitle><pubdate><sdate>20131204</sdate><edate/></pubdate><vid>33</vid><ino>49</ino></serial><location><pp><ppf>19326</ppf><ppl>19340</ppl></pp></location></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0003">[0003]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0004" npl-type="s"><article><author><name>WENGER N et al.</name></author><atl>Closed-loop neuromodulation of spinal sensorimotor circuits controls refined locomotion after complete spinal cord injury</atl><serial><sertitle>Science Translational Medicine</sertitle><pubdate><sdate>20140000</sdate><edate/></pubdate><vid>6</vid><ino>255</ino></serial></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0004">[0003]</crossref></li>
</ul></p>
</ep-reference-list>
</ep-patent-document>
