<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP21020180A1" file="EP21020180NWA1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3889567" kind="A1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSKBAHRIS..MTNORSMESMMAKHTNMD..........</B001EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  1100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3889567</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT APPLICATION</B121></B120><B130>A1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>21020180.2</B210><B220><date>20210401</date></B220><B250>pl</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260><B270><dnum><anum>43346620</anum></dnum><date>20200404</date><ctry>PL</ctry></B270></B200><B300><B310>43346620</B310><B320><date>20200404</date></B320><B330><ctry>PL</ctry></B330></B300><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B430></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>G01M   5/00        20060101AFI20210817BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>G01M   5/0041      20130101 FI20210810BHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>VERFAHREN ZUR MESSUNG DER AUSNUTZUNG DER LASTTRAGFÄHIGKEIT EINES GEBÄUDESTRUKTURELEMENTS</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>A METHOD FOR MEASURING THE UTILIZATION OF THE LOAD CARRYING CAPACITY OF THE BUILDING STRUCTURAL ELEMENT</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>PROCÉDÉ DE MESURE DE L'UTILISATION DE LA CAPACITÉ DE SUPPORT DE CHARGE DE L'ÉLÉMENT DE STRUCTURE DE BÂTIMENT</B542></B540><B590><B598>1</B598></B590></B500><B700><B710><B711><snm>WiSeNe Sp. z o.o.</snm><iid>101809833</iid><irf>P.433466/EP</irf><adr><str>Taneczna 27</str><city>02-829 Warszawa</city><ctry>PL</ctry></adr></B711></B710><B720><B721><snm>Osiniak, Marcin</snm><adr><str>ul. Makol?gwy 12 m. 1</str><city>02-811 Warszawa</city><ctry>PL</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>Antoszkiewicz, Edward</snm><adr><str>ul. Srebrnych Swierkow 43</str><city>05-509 Julianow</city><ctry>PL</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>Pioro, Zbigniew</snm><adr><str>ul. Przytulna 6</str><city>05-509 Julianow</city><ctry>PL</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>Wierzbicki, Stanislaw</snm><adr><str>ul. Krasnowolska 32H</str><city>02-849 Warszawa</city><ctry>PL</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B740><B741><snm>Orlinska, Dorota Irena</snm><iid>101808210</iid><adr><str>Sobajda &amp; Orlinska 
Kancelaria Patentowa sp. j. 
Ul. Dworkowa 2/67</str><city>00-784 Warszawa</city><ctry>PL</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840><B844EP><B845EP><ctry>BA</ctry></B845EP><B845EP><ctry>ME</ctry></B845EP></B844EP><B848EP><B849EP><ctry>KH</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>MA</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>MD</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>TN</ctry></B849EP></B848EP></B800></SDOBI>
<abstract id="abst" lang="en">
<p id="pa01" num="0001">A method is shown for measuring the utilization of the load carrying capacity of a building structural element subject to variable action, including measurements of the rotation angles of cross-sections of this building structural element, wherein the rotation is caused by the variable action, <b>characterised in that</b> the rotation angles <i>a1</i> and <i>α2</i> of the cross-sections of the building structural element around the axis (Z) perpendicular to the longitudinal section of this building structural element are measured in two points (A) and (B) of this building structural element, located symmetrically relative to its transverse axis of symmetry, and subsequently the greater of the measured values of the angles <i>α1</i> and <i>α2</i> is used as the measure of the utilization of the load carrying capacity of the building structural element.
<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="111" he="77" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p>
</abstract>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<p id="p0001" num="0001">The object of this invention is a method for measuring the utilization of the load carrying capacity of the building structural element subjected to variable actions, for example loaded with snow. The method can be used in systems for monitoring the utilization of the load carrying capacity (the level of safety risk) of roof structures of buildings, especially large-area buildings.</p>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">Monitoring the structure of buildings, in particular roof structural elements, leads to improvement of the safety of using these buildings. The basic group of methods used for this purpose includes methods for monitoring changes in the position of structural elements of a building using optical devices.</p>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">The specification of the Polish application <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="PLP381578"><text>P.381578</text></patcit> presents a method for detecting the achievement of predetermined utilization of the load carrying capacity based on directing a light beam below the beams of a roof structure. By excessive bending of at least one beam beyond a permitted, assumed value, the light beam is interrupted and then audible and visual alarms are activated.</p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">The Polish patent description <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="PL183116"><text>PL183116</text></patcit> discloses a method for measuring the twisting and deflection of a beam in static and dynamic systems, wherein at least one mirror is attached to the test element to which a laser beam is directed, which, after reflection, is read in a screen.</p>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">The applicants of the subject invention have developed a method for monitoring the vertical displacement component and vertical deflection component of structural elements of buildings using measurements made by laser rangefinders, disclosed in the patent <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="US8788240B2"><text>US 8788240 B2</text></patcit>. The distance measurements performed in this method are made in relation to fixed elements, such as the floor.</p>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">The description of the patent <patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="FI118701B"><text>FI118701B</text></patcit> discloses a method for monitoring the load of the roof structure using inclinometers, i.e. instruments measuring the inclination of the measurement axis of the inclinometer from a plane perpendicular to the direction of the gravity vector, wherein they are placed on the structural elements of buildings freely, e.g. on one side of the<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> structure of a roof or a building. The disadvantage of such a system is the possibility of the occurrence of large errors when measuring the utilization of the load carrying capacity of the structure in the case of an asymmetrical load on the roof.</p>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">The applicants of the present invention have developed a method for monitoring the variable actions on the roof structure with the use of inclinometers, which has been disclosed in the Polish patent description <patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="PL230522"><text>PL230522</text></patcit>. This patent uses the measurements of rotation angles of cross-sections, caused by the variable action, by means of two inclinometers mounted on the monitored structural element in two points, symmetrically relative to its transverse axis of symmetry. Subsequently, the sum of absolute values of these angles is used as the measure of its load carrying capacity utilization. This sum represents well the utilization of the load carrying capacity in the case of some building structural elements, e.g. in the case of a single-span frame-based structure, in a situation when the maximum value of the utilization of the load carrying capacity occurs in the corner of the frame, where the value of the bending moment is usually the highest. In other cases, the error of determining the utilization of the load carrying capacity by means of said sum can be unacceptably high.</p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">Known methods for monitoring the deflection of structural elements using laser rangefinders have limited applicability in cases when the ambient temperature is too low or too high, when the ground is uneven and soiled, or when there is high dustiness, which occurs, e.g. in the wood industry.</p>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">Known methods for monitoring the variable action on the roof structure using inclinometers are characterised by large measurement errors for a non-uniformly distributed load.</p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">The object of the invention is a method for measuring the utilization of the load carrying capacity of the building structural element, used to reliably determine the level of risk to the safety of use of a building caused by temporary external factors, e.g. atmospheric. This method should be insensitive to the asymmetry of the load of the building structural element and harsh environmental conditions, such as very low temperatures (lower than -20°C), frost, very high temperatures (higher than +50°C), high humidity, high<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> dustiness, contamination of the ground (e.g. snow or mud in open canopies), etc.</p>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">The object of the invention is a method for measuring the utilization of the load carrying capacity of a building structural element subject to variable action, comprising measurements of the rotation angles of cross-sections of this building structural element, wherein the rotation is caused by this variable action, characterised in that the rotation angles <i>α1</i> and <i>α2</i> of the cross-sections of the building structural element around the axis Z perpendicular to the longitudinal section of this building structural element are measured in two points <i>A</i> and <i>B</i> of this element, located symmetrically relative to its transverse axis of symmetry, and subsequently the higher of the measured values of the angles <i>α1</i> and <i>α2</i> is used as the measure of the utilization of the load carrying capacity of said element.</p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">Also, it is preferable when the values of rotation angles <i>γ</i>1 and <i>γ</i>2 of cross-sections of the building structural element around axes perpendicular to these sections are also measured in points <i>A</i> and <i>B</i> of the building structural element, and subsequently the values of angles <i>γ</i>1 and <i>γ</i>2 are used as an indicator of a stability loss of the given building structural element.</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">Also, it is preferable when the measurements of the angles are performed periodically and/or synchronously.</p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">The measurement of rotation angles is performed by means of inclinometers or other known devices or methods, such as geodetic methods.</p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">The utilization of the load carrying capacity of a building structural element subject to variable action, determined based on the measured values of rotation angles <i>α1</i> and <i>α2</i> of the cross-sections around the axis Z, or its loss of stability, determined based on the measured values of rotation angles <i>γ</i>1 and <i>γ</i>2 of its cross-sections around an axis perpendicular to these sections, means exceeding the limit states of the utilization of the load carrying capacity, meaning that the structure has reached a state threatening the safety of the building and its users. Here, stability of the structure is understood as the ability of the structure to retain its unchanged position and shape under the load.</p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">It is a common assumption that the deflection of a structural element is a good measure of the utilization of the load carrying capacity of this element,<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> wherein said deflection is preferably measured in the middle of its span. In a case when the load is distributed uniformly across the entire span of the element, the deflection measured in the middle of its span is a good measure of the utilization of the load carrying capacity. In the case of an asymmetrical load, deflection measured in the middle of its span can be a considerably worse representation of the utilization of the load carrying capacity of this element. Similar or much larger errors in determining the utilization of the load carrying capacity of the element can result from using a single measurement of the rotation angle of the cross-section at one of the ends of this element.</p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">The proposed method is free of the above mentioned disadvantages, and both in the case of symmetrical and asymmetrical loads it represents the utilization of the load carrying capacity of the building structural element with sufficient accuracy.</p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">The method according to the invention is presented in an embodiment in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, which presents the load diagram of a single-span, frame-based building structural element and the measurement scheme of rotation angles, wherein <i>Incl_1</i> and <i>Incl_2</i> are inclinometers measuring the rotation angles <i>α1</i> and <i>α2</i> caused by the variable action and shown by the arrows 7 and 8, of the frame cross-sections around the axis Z perpendicular to its cross-section, in two points <i>A</i> and <i>B</i> of the frame, positioned symmetrically relative to its transverse axis of symmetry 6. In a preferable embodiment, the inclinometers <i>Incl_1</i> and <i>Incl_2</i> also measure the values of rotation angles <i>γ</i>1 and <i>γ</i>2 of the cross-sections of the frame around an axis perpendicular to these sections.</p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019"><figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> presents schematically a sample building structural element in the form of a single-span frame. It will be evident to the skilled person that it is possible to use the method according to the invention to measure the utilization of the load carrying capacity of other types of structural elements, e.g. a beam, a truss, an arch or a part of an arch seated on vertical pillars or resting directly on the foundations.</p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020"><figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> shows an example of symmetric attachment of two inclinometers <i>Incl_1</i> and <i>Incl_2</i> on a frame-based building structural element at the same distance d from the transverse axis of symmetry 6 of this structural element. The upper part of the drawing shows with arrows the variable load <i>q(x)</i> of the<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> roof, e.g. due to snow, occurring over a part of the span with the length <i>L1</i>. The arrows 7 and 8 pointing downwards show the directions of rotation of the cross-sections of the structural element under a variable load in the region of attachment of the inclinometers <i>Incl_1</i> and <i>Incl_2.</i> In the two indicated points <i>A</i> and <i>B</i>, the rotations have opposite directions. It is assumed that the values of rotation angles following the arrows 7 and 8 are greater than zero.</p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">The points of attachment of the inclinometers <i>Incl_1</i> and <i>Incl_2</i> depend on the type of the structure, the type of the structural element and its span, indicated in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> by the letter <i>L</i> (the spacing of piles). It is preferable that the inclinometers be fixed in points where the absolute values of the rotation angles <i>α1</i> and <i>α2</i> of the cross-sections caused by the variable action are as large as possible, preferably close to the maximum values.</p>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">Table 1 lists the results of simulation calculations for the framework structure system with sample defined parameters presented in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, for the load q(x) changing from uniformly distributed across the entire length of the roof <i>(L1 = L,</i> case 1 in Table 1) to located in 1/5 of the span (<i>L1</i> = 0.2L, case 9 in Table 1).</p>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">Table 1: Deflection values <i>u</i> in the middle of the span, the rotation angles <i>α1, α2,</i> the maximum stress <i>σ<sub>max</sub></i> occurring in the element, the greater of the rotation angles <i>α<sub>max</sub></i> and errors of measuring the utilization of the load carrying capacity for: deflection - <i>δ1</i>, the smaller of the rotation angles - <i>δ2</i>, the greater of the rotation angles - <i>δ3</i>, and the average value of the rotation angles - <i>δ4</i>, for the frame shown in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> (<i>L</i> = 29.5 m and <i>d</i> = 11.25 m), for various load patterns - from one uniformly distributed across the entire length of the roof (<i>L1</i> = <i>L</i>) to one located only in 1/5 of the span (<i>L1</i> = 0.2<i>L</i>).
<tables id="tabl0001" num="0001">
<table frame="all">
<tgroup cols="12">
<colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="10mm"/>
<colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="12mm"/>
<colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="13mm"/>
<colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="17mm"/>
<colspec colnum="5" colname="col5" colwidth="14mm"/>
<colspec colnum="6" colname="col6" colwidth="20mm"/>
<colspec colnum="7" colname="col7" colwidth="18mm"/>
<colspec colnum="8" colname="col8" colwidth="17mm"/>
<colspec colnum="9" colname="col9" colwidth="11mm"/>
<colspec colnum="10" colname="col10" colwidth="13mm"/>
<colspec colnum="11" colname="col11" colwidth="14mm"/>
<colspec colnum="12" colname="col12" colwidth="12mm"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry align="center" valign="top"><b>No</b> ·</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top"><b>L1/L</b></entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top"><b>u</b> [mm]</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top"><b>α1</b> [°]</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top"><b>α2</b> [°]</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top"><b>σ<sub>max</sub></b> [MPa]</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top"><b>α<sub>max</sub></b> [°]</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top"><b>a<sub>av</sub></b> [°]</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top"><b>δ1*</b> [%]</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top"><b>δ2**</b> [%]</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top"><b>δ3***</b> [%]</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top"><b>δ4****</b> [%]</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center" valign="top">a</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top">b</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top">c</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top">d</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top">e</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top">f</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top">g</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top">h</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top">i</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top">j</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top">k</entry>
<entry align="center" valign="top">l</entry></row></thead>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry align="center">1</entry>
<entry align="center">1.0</entry>
<entry align="center">60.0 = u<sub>0</sub></entry>
<entry align="center">0.277 = α1<sub>0</sub></entry>
<entry align="center">0.277</entry>
<entry align="center">113.33 = σ<sub>max0</sub></entry>
<entry align="center">0.277 = α<sub>max0</sub></entry>
<entry align="center">0.227 = α<sub>av0</sub></entry>
<entry align="right">0</entry>
<entry align="right">0</entry>
<entry align="right">0</entry>
<entry align="right">0</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center">2</entry>
<entry align="center">0.9</entry>
<entry align="center">59.4</entry>
<entry align="center">0.262</entry>
<entry align="center">0.282</entry>
<entry align="center">110.40</entry>
<entry align="center">0.282</entry>
<entry align="center">0.272</entry>
<entry align="right">2</entry>
<entry align="right">-3</entry>
<entry align="right">4</entry>
<entry align="right">1</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center">3</entry>
<entry align="center">0.8</entry>
<entry align="center">56.8</entry>
<entry align="center">0.213</entry>
<entry align="center">0.293</entry>
<entry align="center">113.82</entry>
<entry align="center">0.293</entry>
<entry align="center">0.253</entry>
<entry align="right">-6</entry>
<entry align="right">-31</entry>
<entry align="right">5</entry>
<entry align="right">-10</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center">4</entry>
<entry align="center">0.7</entry>
<entry align="center">50.9</entry>
<entry align="center">0.145</entry>
<entry align="center">0.297</entry>
<entry align="center">112.90</entry>
<entry align="center">0.297</entry>
<entry align="center">0.221</entry>
<entry align="right">-17</entry>
<entry align="right">-90</entry>
<entry align="right">7</entry>
<entry align="right">-25</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center">5</entry>
<entry align="center">0.6</entry>
<entry align="center">41.6</entry>
<entry align="center">0.078</entry>
<entry align="center">0.285</entry>
<entry align="center">101.51</entry>
<entry align="center">0.285</entry>
<entry align="center">0.182</entry>
<entry align="right">-29</entry>
<entry align="right">-218</entry>
<entry align="right">13</entry>
<entry align="right">-37</entry></row><!-- EPO <DP n="6"> -->
<row>
<entry align="center">6</entry>
<entry align="center">0.5</entry>
<entry align="center">30.0</entry>
<entry align="center">0.025</entry>
<entry align="center">0.252</entry>
<entry align="center">82.95</entry>
<entry align="center">0.252</entry>
<entry align="center">0.139</entry>
<entry align="right">-46</entry>
<entry align="right">-711</entry>
<entry align="right">20</entry>
<entry align="right">-46</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center">7</entry>
<entry align="center">0.4</entry>
<entry align="center">18.4</entry>
<entry align="center">-0.008</entry>
<entry align="center">0.199</entry>
<entry align="center">66.82</entry>
<entry align="center">0.199</entry>
<entry align="center">0.096</entry>
<entry align="right">-92</entry>
<entry align="right">2142</entry>
<entry align="right">18</entry>
<entry align="right">-71</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center">8</entry>
<entry align="center">0.3</entry>
<entry align="center">9.1</entry>
<entry align="center">-0.020</entry>
<entry align="center">0.132</entry>
<entry align="center">47.23</entry>
<entry align="center">0.132</entry>
<entry align="center">0.056</entry>
<entry align="right">-175</entry>
<entry align="right">677</entry>
<entry align="right">13</entry>
<entry align="right">-106</entry></row>
<row>
<entry align="center">9</entry>
<entry align="center">0.2</entry>
<entry align="center">3.2</entry>
<entry align="center">-0.016</entry>
<entry align="center">0.064</entry>
<entry align="center">26.13</entry>
<entry align="center">0.064</entry>
<entry align="center">0.024</entry>
<entry align="right">-332</entry>
<entry align="right">499</entry>
<entry align="right">0</entry>
<entry align="right">-166</entry></row>
<row rowsep="0">
<entry namest="col1" nameend="col12" align="left">* δ1 = [(u/u<sub>0</sub> - σ<sub>max</sub>/σ<sub>max0</sub>)/(u/u<sub>0</sub>)]*100%</entry></row>
<row rowsep="0">
<entry namest="col1" nameend="col12" align="left">** δ2 = [(α1/α1<sub>0</sub> - σ<sub>max</sub>/σ<sub>max0</sub>)/(α1/α1<sub>0</sub>)]*100%</entry></row>
<row rowsep="0">
<entry namest="col1" nameend="col12" align="left">*** δ3 = [(α<sub>max</sub>/α<sub>max0</sub> - σ<sub>max</sub>/σ<sub>max0</sub>)/(α<sub>max</sub>/α<sub>max0</sub>)]*100%</entry></row>
<row>
<entry namest="col1" nameend="col12" align="left">**** δ4 = [(α<sub>av</sub>/α<sub>av0</sub> - σ<sub>max</sub>/σ<sub>max0</sub>)/(α<sub>av</sub>/α<sub>av0</sub>)]*100%</entry></row></tbody></tgroup>
</table>
</tables></p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">A reference value determining the utilization of the load carrying capacity of the presented frame is the maximum value of the stress <i>σ<sub>max</sub></i> (column f in Table 1) in the frame (in any place).</p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">An analysis of the calculation results presented in Table 1 shows that the values of the deflection <i>u</i> in middle of the span (column c in Table 1) and the smaller of the two measured rotation angles, in this case <i>α1</i> (column d in Table 1), behave completely differently as a function of the change in load distribution (cases 2-9 in Table 1) from the maximum stress <i>σ<sub>max</sub></i> (column f in Table 1) occurring in the frame. The use of these values (<i>u</i> and <i>α1</i>) as a measure of the utilization of the load carrying capacity of the structural element for a nonuniform load could result in very large errors (column i in Table 1 for the deflection <i>u</i> and column j in Table 1 for the angle <i>α1</i>). The method for measuring the utilization of the load carrying capacity based on measuring any of the two possible rotation angles, thus also including <i>α1,</i> is used - without any reservations - to monitor the building structure according to the prior art, i.e. the specification of <patcit id="pcit0006" dnum="FI118701B"><text>FI118701B</text></patcit>.</p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">Another method, disclosed in <patcit id="pcit0007" dnum="PL230522"><text>PL230522</text></patcit>, is based on the measurement of the average value of the rotation angles <i>α<sub>av</sub></i> (column h in Table 1). The use of this value as the measure of the utilization of the load carrying capacity results in errors (column I in Table 1) reaching even -166% for a highly uneven load. An error value of less than zero additionally means that the current utilization of the load carrying capacity will be higher than the measured one (determined based on the measured values of the angle <i>α<sub>av</sub></i>).</p>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">It is quite the opposite in the case of using the greater of the rotation angles <i>σ<sub>max</sub></i> (column g in Table 1), in this case <i>σ<sub>max</sub></i> = <i>α2,</i> of two cross-sections as a value representing the utilization of the load carrying capacity of the frame.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> The ratio of the value of the greater of the rotation angles <i>α1</i> and <i>α2</i> of the cross-sections <i>σ<sub>max</sub></i> (column g in Table 1) to the value of maximum stress <i>σ<sub>max</sub></i> (column f in Table 1) is constant, with an error of no more than 20% for the presented frame (column k in Table 1), for changes in the unevenness of load within a wider range than what is observed in practice - from the uniformly distributed load across the entire length of the roof to one located only in 1/5 of the span. Such a value of the error is acceptable in the investigated application, especially since it is always higher than zero, which means that the current utilization of the load carrying capacity will be lower than the measured one (determined based on the measured value of the angle <i>α<sub>max</sub></i>). Such a situation is safe; it poses no risk of overloading the structure by excessive utilization of its load carrying capacity.</p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">In the case of using the deflection <i>u</i>, measured in the middle of the span of the frame (column c in Table 1), for determining the utilization of its load carrying capacity, the error of such determination (column h in Table 1) reaches a value of approx. -50% for a load located only on one roof surface (<i>L1</i> = 0.5L), or even on the order of -330% for a load located in 1/5 of the span. In addition, this error has a value lower than zero, which means that the current utilization of the load carrying capacity in this case would be higher than the measured one. Therefore, such a situation would be dangerous and it could pose a risk of overloading the structure.</p>
<p id="p0029" num="0029">The measurement of the utilization of the load carrying capacity of the building structural element (based on the measurements of the rotation angles <i>α1</i> and <i>α2</i>) is possible when the building structural element is stable. The loss of stability means reaching the limit state of the utilization of the load carrying capacity regardless of the measured value of the utilization of the load carrying capacity. A loss of stability of the building structural element can be detected by means of optionally measured rotation angles <i>γ</i>1 and <i>γ</i>2, where a considerable change in one or both rotation angles can indeed mean a loss of stability.</p>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">Therefore, in structural systems of the single-bay frame type, the value of the greater of the rotation angles of cross-sections around the axis <i>Z</i> perpendicular to its cross-section, measured in two points of the structural system, situated symmetrically relative to the transverse axis of symmetry of the<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> building structural element, caused by a variable action, represents the utilization of the load carrying capacity of the structure with sufficient accuracy for practice, within a scope of load changes which is real from a practical point of view. Similar error values are also obtained as a result of calculations for other types of structures, such as beams or trusses. In addition, the values of the rotation angles of cross-sections around axes perpendicular to these sections may serve the detection of a loss of stability of this system.</p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="9"> -->
<claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>A method for measuring the utilization of the load carrying capacity of a structural element of a building subject to variable action, comprising measuring of rotation angles of cross-sections of the structural element, wherein the rotation is caused by said variable action, <b>characterised in that</b> the measuring of rotation angles comprises measuring a rotation angle <i>α1</i> and a rotation angle <i>α2</i> of the cross-sections of the structural element around an axis (Z) perpendicular to a longitudinal section of the structural element at two points (A, B) of the structural element located symmetrically relative to a transverse axis of symmetry, and subsequently using a greater of a measured value of the angle <i>α1</i> and a measured value of the angle <i>α2</i> as a measure of the utilization of the load carrying capacity of the structural element.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>The method according to claim 1, <b>characterised in that</b> the measuring of the rotation angle <i>γ</i>1 and the rotation angle <i>γ</i>2 of the structural element cross-sections around axes perpendicular to the cross-sections comprises also measuring at the two points (A, B) of the structural element, and subsequently using the value of angle <i>γ</i>1 and the value of angle <i>γ</i>2 as an indicator of stability loss of the structural element of the building.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>The method according to claim 1 or 2, <b>characterised in that</b> the measuring of rotation angles is performed periodically.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>The method according to claim 1 or 2 or 3, <b>characterised in that</b> the measuring of rotation angles is performed synchronously.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="10"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="150" he="109" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<search-report-data id="srep" lang="en" srep-office="EP" date-produced=""><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="157" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="155" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data><search-report-data date-produced="20210811" id="srepxml" lang="en" srep-office="EP" srep-type="ep-sr" status="n"><!--
 The search report data in XML is provided for the users' convenience only. It might differ from the search report of the PDF document, which contains the officially published data. The EPO disclaims any liability for incorrect or incomplete data in the XML for search reports.
 -->

<srep-info><file-reference-id>P.433466/EP</file-reference-id><application-reference><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>21020180.2</doc-number></document-id></application-reference><applicant-name><name>WiSeNe Sp. z o.o.</name></applicant-name><srep-established srep-established="yes"/><srep-invention-title title-approval="yes"/><srep-abstract abs-approval="yes"/><srep-figure-to-publish figinfo="by-applicant"><figure-to-publish><fig-number>1</fig-number></figure-to-publish></srep-figure-to-publish><srep-info-admin><srep-office><addressbook><text>DH</text></addressbook></srep-office><date-search-report-mailed><date>20210823</date></date-search-report-mailed></srep-info-admin></srep-info><srep-for-pub><srep-fields-searched><minimum-documentation><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr><text>G01M</text></classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr></minimum-documentation></srep-fields-searched><srep-citations><citation id="sr-cit0001"><patcit dnum="EP3312555A1" id="sr-pcit0001" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=EP3312555&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>3312555</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>WISENE SP Z O O [PL]</name><date>20180425</date></document-id></patcit><category>X</category><rel-claims>1-4</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* abstract; figures 1-3 *</passage><passage>* claims 1-3 *</passage><passage>* paragraphs [0009],  [0017],  [0020] - [0029]; claims 1-3 *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0002"><patcit dnum="US2019390955A1" id="sr-pcit0002" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=US2019390955&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2019390955</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>PIORO ZBIGNIEW [PL] ET AL</name><date>20191226</date></document-id></patcit><category>A</category><rel-claims>1-4</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* abstract; figure 1 *</passage></rel-passage></citation></srep-citations><srep-admin><examiners><primary-examiner><name>Daman, Marcel</name></primary-examiner></examiners><srep-office><addressbook><text>The Hague</text></addressbook></srep-office><date-search-completed><date>20210811</date></date-search-completed></srep-admin><!--							The annex lists the patent family members relating to the patent documents cited in the above mentioned European search report.							The members are as contained in the European Patent Office EDP file on							The European Patent Office is in no way liable for these particulars which are merely given for the purpose of information.							For more details about this annex : see Official Journal of the European Patent Office, No 12/82						--><srep-patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>3312555</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20180425</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>3312555</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20180425</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>PL</country><doc-number>230522</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20181130</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2019390955</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20191226</date></document-id></priority-application><text>NONE</text></patent-family></srep-patent-family></srep-for-pub></search-report-data>
<ep-reference-list id="ref-list">
<heading id="ref-h0001"><b>REFERENCES CITED IN THE DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0001" num=""><i>This list of references cited by the applicant is for the reader's convenience only. It does not form part of the European patent document. Even though great care has been taken in compiling the references, errors or omissions cannot be excluded and the EPO disclaims all liability in this regard.</i></p>
<heading id="ref-h0002"><b>Patent documents cited in the description</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0002" num="">
<ul id="ref-ul0001" list-style="bullet">
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0001" dnum="PLP381578"><document-id><country>PL</country><doc-number>P381578</doc-number></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0001">[0003]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0002" dnum="PL183116"><document-id><country>PL</country><doc-number>183116</doc-number></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0002">[0004]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0003" dnum="US8788240B2"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>8788240</doc-number><kind>B2</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0003">[0005]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0004" dnum="FI118701B"><document-id><country>FI</country><doc-number>118701</doc-number><kind>B</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0004">[0006]</crossref><crossref idref="pcit0006">[0025]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0005" dnum="PL230522"><document-id><country>PL</country><doc-number>230522</doc-number></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0005">[0007]</crossref><crossref idref="pcit0007">[0026]</crossref></li>
</ul></p>
</ep-reference-list>
</ep-patent-document>
