<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP20167191A1" file="EP20167191NWA1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3889906" kind="A1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSKBAHRIS..MTNORSMESMMAKHTNMD..........</B001EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  1100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3889906</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT APPLICATION</B121></B120><B130>A1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>20167191.4</B210><B220><date>20200331</date></B220><B250>en</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B430></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>G06T   7/60        20170101AFI20200805BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="2"><text>B60D   1/00        20060101ALI20200805BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="3"><text>G06T   7/73        20170101ALI20200805BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>G06T   7/60        20130101 LI20200730BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>G06T2207/10016     20130101 LA20200730BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="3"><text>G06T2207/30252     20130101 LA20200730BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="4"><text>G06T   7/73        20170101 FI20200730BHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>VERFAHREN UND SYSTEM ZUR BERECHNUNG DES FAHRZEUGANHÄNGERWINKELS</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>METHOD AND SYSTEM FOR CALCULATING VEHICLE TRAILER ANGLE</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>PROCÉDÉ ET SYSTÈME DE CALCUL DE L'ANGLE D'UNE REMORQUE DE VÉHICULE</B542></B540><B590><B598>5</B598></B590></B500><B700><B710><B711><snm>Continental Automotive GmbH</snm><iid>101676895</iid><irf>2020P01195EP (NU)</irf><adr><str>Vahrenwalder Straße 9</str><city>30165 Hannover</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B711></B710><B720><B721><snm>Plowman, Robin - c/o Conti Temic microelectronic
GmbH</snm><adr><str>Intellectual Property - Sieboldstraße 19</str><city>90411 Nürnberg</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B740><B741><snm>Continental Corporation</snm><iid>101882523</iid><adr><str>c/o Conti Temic microelectronic GmbH 
Intellectual Property 
Sieboldstraße 19</str><city>90411 Nürnberg</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840><B844EP><B845EP><ctry>BA</ctry></B845EP><B845EP><ctry>ME</ctry></B845EP></B844EP><B848EP><B849EP><ctry>KH</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>MA</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>MD</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>TN</ctry></B849EP></B848EP></B800></SDOBI>
<abstract id="abst" lang="en">
<p id="pa01" num="0001">The invention relates to a method for determining the yaw angle (YA) of a trailer (2) with respect to the longitudinal axis (LAV) of a towing vehicle (1) based on at least one feature (F1, F2) included in multiple captured images by providing multiple algorithms for calculating at least one angle estimation (α1, α2).
<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="97" he="120" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p>
</abstract>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates generally to the field of vehicle assistance systems. More specifically, the present invention relates to a method and a system for calculating yaw angle of a trailer coupled with a towing vehicle based on image information provided by a camera of the vehicle.</p>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">Methods for calculating the angle of a trailer with respect to the towing vehicle based on image information provided by a camera of the vehicle are already known.</p>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">Specifically, a first type of methods is known which provides reliable approximations of trailer yaw angle without considering the location of pivot point of the trailer. However, the accuracy of yaw angle approximation of said first type of methods is low in case of great yaw angles.</p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">In addition, a second type of methods is known which considers the location of pivot point of the trailer. However, in certain circumstances, said second type of methods suffers from high noise.</p>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">It is an objective of the embodiments of the invention to provide a method for calculating yaw angle of a trailer with high robustness and high reliability. The objective is solved by the features of the independent claims. Preferred embodiments are given in the dependent claims. If not explicitly indicated otherwise, embodiments of the invention can be freely combined with each other.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">According to an aspect, the invention refers to a method for determining the yaw angle of a trailer with respect to the longitudinal axis of a towing vehicle. The method comprises the following steps:<br/>
First, at least a first and a second image of the trailer is captured using a camera. The first and second image is captured such that the orientation of the trailer with respect to the vehicle is different on the at least two images.</p>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">After capturing said images, at least a first feature of the trailer is determined. Said first feature has to be visible on first and second image.</p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">In addition, at least a first and a second algorithm for calculating angle estimations based on said at least first feature is provided. Said first algorithm may be an algorithm which investigates the geometry of rotation of the trailer, specifically, which considers the location of pivot point of the trailer. The second algorithm may be an algorithm which approximates the yaw angle of the trailer by considering two or more features in different rotational positions of the trailer. Said second algorithm may not investigate the geometry of rotation of the trailer.</p>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">Based on said first and/or second algorithm, at least a first angle estimation for said first feature is provided.</p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">According to a first embodiment, said provision of first angle estimation is performed by deciding based on one or more criteria for each feature if the first or the second algorithm should be used for calculating said first angle estimation and calculating said first angle estimation based on an algorithm selected for said first feature. So, in other words, the decision which algorithm to use is made before calculating angle estimation.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">According to a second embodiment, said provision of first angle estimation is performed by calculating a first angle estimation for the at least one feature based on said first and said second algorithm and by deciding, for each feature, based on one or more criteria if the first angle estimation obtained by the first algorithm or the first angle estimation obtained by the second algorithm is used for further processing. So, in other words, in the second embodiment, the first angle estimation is calculated based on multiple algorithms and the decision which angle estimation should be used is made by considering the results of said angle estimation calculations. So, in contrary to upper-mentioned first embodiment, the decision which algorithm to use is made after calculating first angle estimations.</p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">Finally, the yaw angle of the trailer is calculated at least based on said first angle estimation.</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">Said method is advantageous because due to taking a decision for each feature which method out of multiple methods should be used for providing angle estimations, the results of yaw angle determination are very accurate and robust because, for each feature, a suitable method can be chosen which provides most reliable angle estimation result.</p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">According to an embodiment, for each feature an attempt is made to calculate an angle estimation based on first algorithm, i.e. an algorithm which exploits the geometry of rotation of the trailer. If said first algorithm fails because one or more criteria, specifically predefined criteria, are not fulfilled, the second algorithm is used.</p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">According to an embodiment, the first algorithm is configured to perform the following steps:<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> -->
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="dash">
<li>A first ray between the camera and determined first feature on the first image is established and projected onto a horizontal plane thereby obtaining a first projected feature position. Similarly, a second ray between the camera and determined first feature on the second image is established and projected onto said horizontal plane thereby obtaining a second projected feature position;</li>
<li>A first perpendicular bisector is established between the location of the first projected feature position and the location of the second projected feature position. More in detail, the first perpendicular bisector may be a perpendicular straight line running through the centre of the line connecting the location of the first projected feature position and the location of the second projected feature position. Thus, first perpendicular bisector may be established in a horizontal plane.</li>
<li>After establishing first perpendicular bisector, a first intersection point of first perpendicular bisector with a reference axis or a further perpendicular bisector is established.</li>
<li>Based on said first perpendicular bisector, a first angle estimation is calculated. The first angle estimation refers to the angle between a first line running from first projected feature position to said first intersection point and a second line running from second projected feature position to said first intersection point in said horizontal plane.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">It is worth mentioning that the term "position of the first feature on the first/second image" refers to the 2D image coordinates of the image feature, or the corresponding optical ray (for instance, specified as a 3D<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> unit vector, or an azimuth/elevation). A 2D image coordinate can be converted into an optical ray using the cameras calibration information.</p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">Said first angle estimation may open from the towing vehicle towards the trailer.</p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">According to an embodiment, a second feature of the trailer is determined which is visible on first and second image, wherein said second feature is arranged at a different position of the trailer than the first feature. The first algorithm uses two or more features of the trailer for providing angle estimations. Specifically, the first algorithm is configured to:
<ul id="ul0002" list-style="dash" compact="compact">
<li>project a ray between the camera and determined second feature on the first image onto a horizontal plane thereby obtaining a third projected feature position and project a ray between the camera and determined second feature on the second image onto said horizontal plane thereby obtaining a fourth projected feature position;</li>
<li>establish a second perpendicular bisector between the location of the third projected feature position and the location of the fourth projected feature position;</li>
<li>determine a second intersection point of second perpendicular bisector with said reference axis, said first perpendicular bisector or a further perpendicular bisector; and</li>
<li>calculate a second angle estimation, said second angle estimation referring to the angle between a first line running from third projected feature position to said second intersection point and a second line running from fourth projected feature position to said second intersection point in said horizontal plane.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">Using two or more features allows calculating multiple angle estimations based on different features which reduce noise and mismatching effects.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">According to an embodiment, the second algorithm is configured to calculate a first angle estimation. The first angle estimation characterizes the pivot angle in a horizontal plane between the first feature on the first image and the first feature on the second image with respect to a fix point of the towing vehicle.</p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">According to an embodiment, a second feature of the trailer is determined which is visible on first and second image, wherein said second feature is arranged at different position of the trailer than the first feature and the second algorithm is configured to calculate a second angle estimation, the second angle estimation characterizing the pivot angle in a horizontal plane between the second feature on the first image and the second feature on the second image with respect to the fix point of the towing vehicle. Using two or more features in the second algorithm allows calculating multiple angle estimations based on different features which reduce noise and mismatching effects.</p>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">According to an embodiment, said step of determining based on one or more criteria comprises determining the length of a baseline between a feature on the first image and said feature on the second image and comparing said length with a length threshold value. Said length of the baseline may be determined after transferring first and second feature captured on first and second image in a common map or coordinate system, wherein said coordinate system may also comprise information regarding the position of one or more fix points of the vehicle, e.g. the position of the camera. Preferably, if the length of a baseline is below said length threshold value, the angle estimation is provided by the second algorithm instead of first algorithm. Thereby, inaccurate angle estimations suffering from high noise can be avoided.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">According to an embodiment, said step of determining based on one or more criteria comprises determining the roll and/or the pitch of the trailer and comparing the roll with a roll threshold and/or the pitch with a pitch threshold. Preferably, if the roll is above roll threshold and/or the pitch is above pitch threshold, the angle estimation is provided by the second algorithm instead of first algorithm. Thereby, inaccurate angle estimations suffering from high noise can be avoided.</p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">According to an embodiment, said step of determining based on one or more criteria comprises determining the vertical distance of a feature with respect to a horizontal reference plane and comparing said vertical distance with a distance threshold value. Said vertical distance may be determined after transferring at least one feature captured on first and second image in a common map or coordinate system. Said coordinate system may also comprise information regarding the height level of one or more fix points of the vehicle in vertical direction, e.g. the height level of the camera, specifically the height level of the camera with respect to horizontal reference plane. If the vertical distance is below said distance threshold value, the angle estimation is provided by the second algorithm instead of first algorithm. Thereby, inaccurate angle estimations suffering from high noise can be avoided.</p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">According to an embodiment, on first or second image, the yaw angle of the trailer with respect to the vehicle is zero. Thereby, said image can be used as "zero-pose image", i.e. as a reference of an exact alignment of the longitudinal axis of the vehicle with the longitudinal axis of the trailer. However, also another yaw angle value can be used as reference value, as long as said other yaw angle is known.</p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">According to an embodiment, in the second algorithm, calculating said at least one angle estimation comprises determining optical rays between<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> said fix point and said the at least one feature on first and second image. Said optical rays refer to straight lines which run between said fix point and respective feature. Based on said optical rays, the current pivot angle can be determined with reduced computational effort, e.g. based on geometrical methods.</p>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">According to an embodiment, specifically in the second algorithm, camera calibration information is used for converting the position of said first and/or second feature into optical rays. For example, having knowledge of camera position using camera calibration information, the position of a certain feature on the image can be transferred in location information depending on or being correlated with the position of the camera.</p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">According to an embodiment, camera calibration information is used for converting the position of said first and/or second feature from local domain of the image into local domain of the vehicle or of a certain fix point of the vehicle. For example, having knowledge of camera position using camera calibration information, the position of a certain feature on the image can be transferred in location information depending on or being correlated with the position of the camera included or attached to the vehicle.</p>
<p id="p0029" num="0029">According to an embodiment, in addition to said at least one feature, at least one further feature of the trailer is used for calculating the yaw angle. Said at least one further feature is arranged at a different position of the trailer than the first feature. For example, the first feature may be a conspicuous first characteristic at a first location and a second feature may be a conspicuous second characteristic at a second location of the trailer. Using two or more features leads to further angle estimations which further increase the robustness and reliability of yaw angle determination.<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></p>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">According to an embodiment, the yaw angle is calculated by establishing the median value based on the at least two angle estimations provided by first and second algorithm. Thereby, a very stable yaw angle determination can be obtained.</p>
<p id="p0031" num="0031">According to other embodiments, the yaw angle is calculated by establishing an average value of the at least two angle estimations or by using a statistical approach applied to said angle estimations provided by first and second algorithm.</p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032">According to an embodiment, the method further comprises the step of determining an angle window. Said angle window may comprise an upper and a lower bound around said yaw angle. In addition, a set of features is determined, said features within said set of features leading to angle estimations which are located within said angle window. Said determined set of features, preferably, only features included in said set of features are used for future yaw angle calculations. So, in other words, information of previous yaw angle determinations is used to determine two or more features of the trailer which lead to angle estimations quite close to determined yaw angle (i.e. within the angle window) and to not track those features which lead to angle estimations significantly deviating from determined yaw angle (i.e. out of the angle window). Thereby, the computational complexity and accuracy of angle estimation can be significantly reduced.</p>
<p id="p0033" num="0033">According to an embodiment, the value of calculated yaw angle is increased by a certain portion or percentage in order to remedy underestimations. For example, the calculated yaw angle may be scaled up by 5% to 15%, specifically 10% in order to remedy an underestimate of calculation result.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></p>
<p id="p0034" num="0034">According to an embodiment, in the first algorithm, the reference axis is the longitudinal axis of the towing vehicle if the camera and the towball of the vehicle are arranged in a vertically oriented plane which comprises said longitudinal axis of the towing vehicle.</p>
<p id="p0035" num="0035">According to another embodiment, in the first algorithm, the reference axis is a straight line running between the camera and the towball if the camera and/or the towball have a lateral offset with respect to the longitudinal axis of the towing vehicle. Thereby, a lateral offset between the camera and the towball can be compensated.</p>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">According to an embodiment, the camera is the rear view camera of the vehicle. Based on the rear view camera, images of the trailer can be captured with reduced technical effort.</p>
<p id="p0037" num="0037">According to a further aspect, a system for determining the yaw angle of a trailer with respect to the longitudinal axis of a towing vehicle is disclosed. The system comprises a camera for capturing images of the trailer and a processing entity for processing said captured images. The system is further configured to execute the steps of:
<ul id="ul0003" list-style="dash" compact="compact">
<li>capturing at least a first and a second image of the trailer using a camera, the orientation of the trailer with respect to the vehicle being different on the at least two images;</li>
<li>determining at least a first feature of the trailer which is visible on first and second image;</li>
<li>providing at least a first and a second algorithm for calculating at least one angle estimation based on said at least first feature;</li>
<li>providing at least a first angle estimation for said first feature by
<ul id="ul0004" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>∘ deciding based on one or more criteria for each feature if the first or the second algorithm should be used for calculating said<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> first angle estimation and calculating said first angle estimation based on an algorithm selected for first feature; or</li>
<li>∘ calculating first angle estimation for said first feature based on said first and said second algorithm and deciding based on one or more criteria if the first angle estimation obtained by the first algorithm or the first angle estimation obtained by the second algorithm is used for further processing; and</li>
</ul></li>
<li>calculating the yaw angle based on said first angle estimation.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0038" num="0038">Any upper-mentioned feature described as an embodiment of the method is also applicable as a system feature in a system according to the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p0039" num="0039">According to yet another embodiment, a vehicle comprising a system according to anyone of upper-mentioned embodiments is disclosed.</p>
<p id="p0040" num="0040">The term "vehicle" as used in the present disclosure may refer to a car, truck, bus, train or any other crafts.</p>
<p id="p0041" num="0041">The term "yaw angle" as used in the present disclosure may refer to a pivot angle between the longitudinal axis of the vehicle and the longitudinal axis of the trailer.</p>
<p id="p0042" num="0042">The term "median" as used in the present disclosure may refer to a value separating a higher half from a lower half of a data sample or a probability distribution.</p>
<p id="p0043" num="0043">The term "essentially" or "approximately" as used in the invention means deviations from the exact value by +/- 10%, preferably by +/- 5% and/or deviations in the form of changes that are insignificant for the function and/or for the traffic laws.<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></p>
<p id="p0044" num="0044">Various aspects of the invention, including its particular features and advantages, will be readily understood from the following detailed description and the accompanying drawings, in which:
<ul id="ul0005" list-style="none">
<li><figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> shows an exemplary top view on a vehicle towing a trailer;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0001">Fig. 2</figref> schematically illustrates an angle estimation based on a first feature captured by camera images in different pivot angles between the trailer and the towing vehicle according to a first algorithm;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">Fig. 3</figref> schematically illustrates two angle estimations based on a first and a second feature captured by camera images in different pivot angles between the trailer and the towing vehicle according to a first algorithm;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">Fig. 4</figref> schematically illustrates angle estimations based on a first and a second feature captured by camera images in different pivot angles between the trailer and the towing vehicle according to a second algorithm; and</li>
<li><figref idref="f0004">Fig. 5</figref> shows a schematic block diagram illustrating the steps of a method for determining the yaw angle of a trailer with respect to the longitudinal axis of a towing vehicle.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0045" num="0045">The present invention will now be described more fully with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which example embodiments are shown. The embodiments in the figures may relate to preferred embodiments, while all elements and features described in connection with embodiments may be used, as far as appropriate, in combination with any other embodiment and feature as discussed herein, in particular related to any other embodiment discussed further above. However, this invention<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> should not be construed as limited to the embodiments set forth herein. Throughout the following description similar reference numerals have been used to denote similar elements, parts, items or features, when applicable.</p>
<p id="p0046" num="0046">The features of the present invention disclosed in the specification, the claims, examples and/or the figures may both separately and in any combination thereof be material for realizing the invention in various forms thereof.</p>
<p id="p0047" num="0047"><figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> shows a top view illustration of a vehicle 1 towing a trailer 2. The vehicle 1 comprises a longitudinal axis LAV which runs through the centre of the vehicle 1. Similarly, the trailer 2 comprises a longitudinal axis LAT which runs through the centre of the trailer 2. The trailer 2 is coupled with the vehicle 1 by means of a trailer hitch comprising a towball 4.</p>
<p id="p0048" num="0048">In certain driving situations, the longitudinal axis LAV of the vehicle 1 and the longitudinal axis LAT of the trailer 2 may not be aligned in parallel or may not fall into one another but the axes may confine a yaw angle YA. In other words, the yaw angle YA defines the angular deviation of the longitudinal axis LAT of the trailer 2 with respect to the longitudinal axis LAV of the vehicle 1. The yaw angle YA may be measured in a horizontal plane which includes the longitudinal axis LAT of the trailer 2 as well as the longitudinal axis LAV of the vehicle 1.</p>
<p id="p0049" num="0049">The knowledge of yaw angle YA is - inter alia - advantageous in trailer assistance systems, for example.</p>
<p id="p0050" num="0050">For determining the yaw angle YA, multiple images of at least a portion of the trailer 2 are captured by means of a camera 3. The camera 3 may be, for example, a rear view camera of the vehicle 1, which may also be used<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> for capturing images of the surroundings of the vehicle 1 when driving backwards. One of the captured images may refer to a known angular arrangement of the trailer 2 with respect to the towing vehicle 1. Said image may be used as reference for calculating the yaw angle YA. In said known angular arrangement of the trailer 2 with respect to the towing vehicle 1, the yaw angle YA may be 0° or any other angle value.</p>
<p id="p0051" num="0051"><figref idref="f0001">Fig. 2</figref> shows a schematic diagram showing the angular relationship of a first feature of the trailer 2 at different points of time at which the trailer 2 has a different yaw angle YA with respect to the towing vehicle 1.</p>
<p id="p0052" num="0052">The camera 3 may capture two or more images at different points of time at which the angular position of the trailer 2 with respect to the vehicle 1 is different. For example, an image series may be captured.</p>
<p id="p0053" num="0053">In the present example, the second image may show an orientation of the trailer with respect to the vehicle at a yaw angle YA = 0°.</p>
<p id="p0054" num="0054">Because of the angular movement of trailer 2 over time, a certain feature detected at the trailer may appear at different positions in the first and second image. In <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 2</figref>, the first feature is represented by a square.</p>
<p id="p0055" num="0055">The upper representation of first feature (associated with the solid optical ray R connecting the feature with the camera 3) is identified in a first image, the lower representation of first feature (associated with dashed optical ray R connecting the feature with the camera 3) is identified in a second image at a different point of time. For correlating the location of first feature in the respective image with the location of the vehicle 1, specifically a certain fix point of the vehicle 1, calibration information of the camera 3 may be used. Specifically, for determining the optical rays R connecting the first feature with the camera 3, calibration information of<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> the camera 3 may be used to transform the location of said first feature in image coordinates into optical rays. In other words, for associating camera position and feature position, the location of feature on the image is correlated with a position of a fix point of the vehicle based on calibration information of the camera 3.</p>
<p id="p0056" num="0056">Features on the trailer are located and matched using feature detection and matching algorithm. For example, the Harris Corner Detector, Scale-Invariant Feature Transform (SIFT) algorithm, Speeded Up Robust Features (SURF) algorithm, Binary Robust Invariant Scalable Keypoints (BRISK) algorithm, Binary Robust Independent Elementary Features (BRIEF), Oriented FAST and rotated BRIEF (ORB) algorithm or another suitable feature detection and matching algorithm could be used.</p>
<p id="p0057" num="0057">The feature detection and matching algorithm may detect image features that are on the trailer or not on the trailer. To segment the trailer features from the non-trailer features a number of different methods could be used. For instance, when driving forwards in a straight line, trailer features can be segmented from non-trailer features by looking for features that remain in the same position over time. Alternatively, the motion of background features can be modelled over time using the vehicle's known motion. This could be extracted from CAN data regarding speed and steering. Features which do not fit the Epipolar constraint of the Essential Matrix could then be considered as trailer features.</p>
<p id="p0058" num="0058">It appeared that depending on certain circumstances or conditions it might be preferable to choose a particular algorithm out of a set of algorithms instead of using only a single algorithm for determining at least one angle estimation α1, α2 being indicative for the yaw angle YA. In the following, a first and a second algorithm for determining at least one angle estimation<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> α1, α2 and a framework for deciding which algorithm to use for determining said at least one angle estimation α1, α2 is provided.</p>
<p id="p0059" num="0059">The determination of yaw angle YA based on first algorithm is illustrated in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 2</figref> in closer detail. The change of location of at least one feature between said first and second image is used for determining at least a first angle estimation α1.</p>
<p id="p0060" num="0060">After feature identification in the respective images, the first feature of first and second image is projected in a common horizontal plane. More in detail, the ray between the camera 3 and determined first feature on the first image is projected onto a horizontal plane thereby obtaining a first projected feature position PFP1a. In addition, the ray between the camera 3 and determined first feature on the second image is projected onto the same horizontal plane thereby obtaining a second projected feature position PFP1b. It is worth mentioning that said projection is made in vertical direction thereby only changing the elevation angle of optical rays but not the azimuth angle.</p>
<p id="p0061" num="0061">After determining first and second projected feature positions PFP1a, PFP1b, a first perpendicular bisector B1 is established based on said first and second projected feature positions PFP1a, PFP1b. As shown in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 2</figref>, the first perpendicular bisector B1 is a line being perpendicular to the line linking first and second projected feature positions PFP1a, PFP1b. In addition, the first perpendicular bisector B1 runs through the center of said linking line. Said first perpendicular bisector B1 crosses a reference axis, which is in the present embodiment the longitudinal axis of the vehicle LAV. Said intersection of first perpendicular bisector B1 and reference axis provides the point of rotation, around which the trailer 2 is rotated. More in detail, said intersection is indicative for the position of the towball 4.<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></p>
<p id="p0062" num="0062">Based on said first perpendicular bisector B1, a first angle estimation α1 is calculated. Said first angle estimation α1 refers to an angle provided between a first line L1 linking first projected feature position PFP1a and the intersection of first perpendicular bisector B1 and reference axis and a second line L2 linking second projected feature position PFP1b and the intersection of first perpendicular bisector B1 and reference axis. The intersection may be indicative for the position of towball 4. More in detail, the first angle estimation α1 characterizes the pivot angle of the trailer 2 in a horizontal plane between the location of the first feature in the first image projected on the horizontal plane and the location of the first feature in the second image projected on said horizontal plane around said first intersection point IP1 (which is at least roughly the position of towball 4).</p>
<p id="p0063" num="0063">In the present embodiment, the reference axis is the longitudinal axis LAV of the towing vehicle 1, because the camera 3 as well as the towball 4 are located on said longitudinal axis LAV of the vehicle 1. In other embodiments, if the camera 3 or the towball 4 has a lateral offset to the longitudinal axis LAV of the vehicle 1 or the lateral offset of the camera 3 and the towball 4 with respect to the longitudinal axis LAV of the vehicle 1 is different, the reference axis may be formed by a straight line linking the camera 3 and the towball 4.</p>
<p id="p0064" num="0064">The first angle estimation α1 is indicative for the yaw angle YA of the trailer 2 around its actual point of rotation.</p>
<p id="p0065" num="0065"><figref idref="f0002">Fig. 3</figref> illustrates an embodiment similar to <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 2</figref> which uses first algorithm and which uses a first and a second feature (i.e. two different features) of the trailer 2 captured at different points of time (at which the trailer 2 has a different yaw angle YA with respect to the towing vehicle 1) for establishing yaw angle YA.<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></p>
<p id="p0066" num="0066">On the images captured by the camera 3, multiple different features may be identifiable. As shown in <figref idref="f0002">Fig. 3</figref>, said features are identified at different angular positions with respect to a fix point of the vehicle 1. The first feature is illustrated by a square, the second feature is illustrated by a triangle. Said fix point may be the location of the camera 3 or may be the location of the towball 4.</p>
<p id="p0067" num="0067">In <figref idref="f0002">Fig. 3</figref>, the upper pair of first and second feature (indicated by PFP1a, PFP2a and associated with the solid optical rays connecting the features with the camera 3) are identified in a first image, the lower pair of first and second feature F1, F2 (indicated by PFP1b, PFP2b and associated with dashed optical rays connecting the features with the camera 3) are identified in a second image at a different point of time.</p>
<p id="p0068" num="0068">The determination of yaw angle YA is performed analogously to the embodiment of <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 2</figref>. The main difference is that two angle estimations α1, α2 are established and the yaw angle YA of the trailer is developed based on said two angle estimations α1, α2. More in detail, establishing first perpendicular bisector B1 and obtaining first angle estimation α1 is performed like described above.</p>
<p id="p0069" num="0069">In addition, second angle estimation α2 is obtained by establishing third projected feature position PFP2a and fourth projected feature position PFP2b, establishing a second perpendicular bisector B2 in order to obtain a second intersection point IP2 and connecting the third projected feature position PFP2a and the fourth projected feature position PFP2b with said second intersection point IP2. Said third projected feature position PFP2a is obtained by projecting second feature in the first image onto said horizontal plane and fourth projected feature position PFP2b is obtained by projecting second feature in the second image onto said horizontal plane. The second intersection point IP2 may be the point in which the<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> second perpendicular bisector B2 crosses the reference axis, in the present embodiment the longitudinal axis of the vehicle LAV. The second angle estimation α2 is the angle between a first line linking third projected feature position PFP2a and intersection point IP2 and a second line linking fourth projected feature position PFP2b and intersection point IP2.</p>
<p id="p0070" num="0070">Also in the embodiment of <figref idref="f0002">Fig. 3</figref>, the reference axis is the longitudinal axis LAV of the towing vehicle 1, because the camera 3 as well as the towball 4 is located on said longitudinal axis LAV of the vehicle 1. In other embodiments, if the camera 3 or the towball 4 has a lateral offset to the longitudinal axis LAV of the vehicle 1 or the lateral offset of the camera 3 and the towball 4 with respect to the longitudinal axis LAV of the vehicle 1 is different, the reference axis may be formed by a straight line linking the camera 3 and the towball 4.</p>
<p id="p0071" num="0071">It is worth mentioning that more than two features of the trailer 2 could determined and tracked over multiple images. In addition, preferably, more than two images are captured at different points of time in order to enhance the result of yaw angle estimation. Thereby, more than two angle estimations α1, α2 can be established for increasing the quality of yaw angle determination.</p>
<p id="p0072" num="0072">In the following, a second algorithm for determining at least one angle estimation α1, α2 is described based on <figref idref="f0003">Fig. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0073" num="0073"><figref idref="f0003">Fig. 4</figref> shows a schematic diagram illustrating the angular relationship of a first and a second feature F1, F2 of trailer 2, said features F1, F2 being identified at different points of time and at different angular positions with respect to a fix point of the vehicle 1.<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --></p>
<p id="p0074" num="0074">The camera 3 may capture two or more images at different points of time at which the angular position of the trailer 2 with respect to the vehicle 1 is different. For example, an image series may be captured. Said image series may comprise three or more, in particular, more than five images.</p>
<p id="p0075" num="0075">In the present example, the second image may show an orientation of the trailer 2 with respect to the vehicle at a yaw angle YA = 0°. However, according to other embodiments, the yaw angle YA may be any other reference yaw angle which is known in advance and which can be used for determining the current yaw angle.</p>
<p id="p0076" num="0076">On the images captured by the camera 3, multiple different features may be identifiable. In <figref idref="f0003">Fig. 4</figref>, features F1 and F2 are illustrated which are identified at different angular positions with respect to the position of the camera 3 of the vehicle 1 or a reference axis. The first feature F1 is illustrated by a square, the second feature F2 is illustrated by a triangle. It is worth mentioning that more than two features and more than two images can be used for yaw angle estimation. Also, usage of only one feature for estimating yaw angle is possible.</p>
<p id="p0077" num="0077">So, the upper pair of first and second feature F1, F2 (associated with the solid optical rays connecting the features F1 and F2 with the camera 3) may be identified in a first image, the lower pair of first and second feature F1, F2 (associated with dashed optical rays connecting the features F1 and F2 with the camera 3) may be identified in a second image at a different point of time.</p>
<p id="p0078" num="0078">Also in the second algorithm, features on the trailer 2 may be located and matched using feature detection and matching algorithm. For example, the Harris Corner Detector, Scale-Invariant Feature Transform (SIFT) algorithm, Speeded Up Robust Features (SURF) algorithm, Binary Robust<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> Invariant Scalable Keypoints (BRISK) algorithm, Binary Robust Independent Elementary Features (BRIEF), Oriented FAST and rotated BRIEF (ORB) algorithm or another suitable feature detection and matching algorithm could be used.</p>
<p id="p0079" num="0079">The feature detection and matching algorithm may detect image features that are on the trailer or not on the trailer. To segment the trailer features from the non-trailer features a number of different methods could be used. For instance, when driving forwards in a straight line, trailer features can be segmented from non-trailer features by looking for features that remain in the same position over time. Alternatively, the motion of background features can be modelled over time using the vehicle's known motion. This could be extracted from CAN data regarding speed and steering. Features which do not fit the Epipolar constraint of the Essential Matrix could then be considered as trailer features.</p>
<p id="p0080" num="0080">It is worth mentioning that first and second algorithm may use the same detected features for establishing angle estimations α1, α2. So in other words, feature detection has only to be performed once for both algorithms.</p>
<p id="p0081" num="0081">For determining angle estimations α1, α2, optical rays R connecting the features F1 and F2 with the camera 3 are used. In order to associate features F1 and F2 of the captured images with the position of the camera 3, calibration information of the camera 3 may be used to transform the location of features F1, F2 in image coordinates into the spatial domain of the camera 3, thereby enabling the provision of optical rays R linking the position of the respective feature F1, F2 with said camera position. In other words, for associating camera position and feature positions, the location of features F1, F2 on the images is transformed in the local<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> domain of the vehicle 1, respectively, the local domain of the camera 3 of the vehicle 1 based on calibration information of the camera 3.</p>
<p id="p0082" num="0082">After determining the optical rays R between the camera position and the one or more features in first and second image, the pivot angles of first feature F1 and/or second feature F2 are determined. In <figref idref="f0003">Fig. 4</figref>, α1 illustrates the angle estimation of pivot angle of first feature F1 between the two captured images and α2 illustrates the angle estimation of the pivot angle of second feature F2 between said images. According to embodiments, only one or more than two features of the trailer are determined and tracked over multiple images. In addition, preferably, more than two images are captured at different points of time in order to enhance the result of yaw angle estimation.</p>
<p id="p0083" num="0083">As mentioned before, one of the captured images may provide a reference image in which the angular position of the trailer 2 with respect to the vehicle 1 is known. In said known angular arrangement of the trailer 2 with respect to the towing vehicle 1, the yaw angle YA may be 0° or any other angle value. Therefore, based on said at least one angle estimation α1, α2, the yaw angle YA can be calculated. Again referring to <figref idref="f0003">Fig. 4</figref>, for example, the angular arrangement of the optical rays R indicated by dashed lines may be known because when capturing the image referring to said optical rays R, the trailer 2 has a known reference orientation with respect to the vehicle 1.</p>
<p id="p0084" num="0084">Upper-mentioned second algorithm is very robust, i.e. provides angle estimations also when the image quality is poor but the accuracy of angle estimations is low.</p>
<p id="p0085" num="0085">According to the present disclosure, for each feature F1, F2, one of presented algorithms (first or second algorithm) may be selected and used<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> for providing at least one angle estimation α1, α2. Said selection may be made by checking one or more conditions.</p>
<p id="p0086" num="0086">According to preferred embodiments, the first algorithm using at least one perpendicular bisector B1, B2 (<figref idref="f0001">Fig. 2</figref>, <figref idref="f0002">Fig. 3</figref>) may be preferably used for determining at least one angle estimation α1, α2. More in detail, multiple checks are performed for attempting to calculate at least one angle estimation α1, α2 based on said first algorithm. Depending on the results of said checks, first or second algorithm is used for determining angle estimation for a particular feature.</p>
<p id="p0087" num="0087">A first condition to be checked is the length L of the baseline BL which is used to create perpendicular bisector (cf. <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 2</figref>). Said baseline BL may be a straight line connecting the location of a particular feature F1, F2 in first and second image. If the length L is below a given length threshold value, the second algorithm is used instead of first algorithm because first algorithm may suffer from significant noise.</p>
<p id="p0088" num="0088">A second condition to be checked is if changes in pitch and/or roll of trailer 2 due to uneven ground in the series of captured images occur. If changes in pitch and/or roll are above given pitch/roll threshold values, the second algorithm is used instead of first algorithm because first algorithm may suffer from significant noise.</p>
<p id="p0089" num="0089">In addition, a third condition to be checked is the distance of a feature F1, F2 in vertical direction with respect to upper-mentioned horizontal plane which builds a reference plane in which the features are transformed before determining at least one angle estimation α1, α2. If the vertical distance of a certain feature with respect to said reference plane is below a given distance threshold value, the second algorithm is used instead of first algorithm because first algorithm may suffer from significant noise.<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --></p>
<p id="p0090" num="0090">So, if one or more of upper-mentioned criteria or conditions to be checked are fulfilled, the first algorithm is skipped and second algorithm is used for said at least one angle estimation α1, α2.</p>
<p id="p0091" num="0091">It is worth mentioning that for each feature F1, F2 a separate decision can be made, based on which algorithm the at least one angle estimation α1, α2 is determined. So, in other words, the angle estimations α1, α2 can be calculated based on the same or different algorithms.</p>
<p id="p0092" num="0092">Under ideal conditions, when establishing multiple angle estimations based on a certain algorithm, the first angle estimation α1 and the at least one further angle estimation α2 should be equal (α1 = α2) and should be indicative for the yaw angle YA. However, due to noise and mismatches, the values of angle estimations α1, α2 can be different. It is worth mentioning that more than two angle estimations can be established for increasing the quality of yaw angle determination.</p>
<p id="p0093" num="0093">For determining the yaw angle YA based on multiple angle estimations α1, α2 having different values, a statistical measure may be used. According to a first embodiment, the median of two or more angle estimations α1, α2 may be used to determine the yaw angle YA. According to other embodiments, a statistical method may be used to determine the yaw angle YA based on of two or more angle estimations α1, α2. The statistical method may be, for example, RANSAC-algorithm (RANSAC: random sample consensus) or least squares algorithm.</p>
<p id="p0094" num="0094">It appeared that not all features visible on the captured images are equally suitable for calculating yaw angle YA. In order to reduce computational complexity and robustness, those features are selected and further used for determining yaw angle YA, which provide pivot angles quite close to<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> actual yaw angle. For feature selection, only those features may be tracked in future images which provided angle estimations α1, α2 in a certain window around the actual yaw angle. For example, the window may be defined by an upper and a lower boundary, said upper and lower boundary defining an angular window around said actual yaw angle. For example, the window may span over a distance of 2° to 10°, more particular between 3° and 5°. All features which led to pivot angles within said window in the last two or more yaw angle determination steps are further tracked in the next captured images.</p>
<p id="p0095" num="0095">In case of tracking a particular trailer feature for multiple images, due to the movement of the trailer 2, the samples of said feature may be arranged on a circle segment. The centre of said circle segment represents the location of towball 4. Therefore, by tracking a particular trailer feature over multiple images, the location of towball 4 can be derived.</p>
<p id="p0096" num="0096">In order to mitigate noise, the determination of the location of towball 4 may consider multiple trailer features tracked for a period of time over multiple images. Each trailer feature may correspond to a circle segment with certain centre estimation. By applying a statistical method on said multiple centre estimations, the actual location of towball 4 can be developed. The statistical method may be, for example, RANSAC-algorithm or least squares algorithm.</p>
<p id="p0097" num="0097"><figref idref="f0004">Fig. 5</figref> shows a block diagram illustrating the method steps of a method for determining the yaw angle YA of a trailer 2 with respect to the longitudinal axis LAV of a towing vehicle 1.</p>
<p id="p0098" num="0098">As a first step, a first and a second image of the trailer is captured (S10).<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --></p>
<p id="p0099" num="0099">After image capturing, at least one feature of the trailer visible on the first and the second image is determined (S11).</p>
<p id="p0100" num="0100">In addition, at least a first and a second algorithm for calculating at least one angle estimation is provided (S12).</p>
<p id="p0101" num="0101">At least a first angle estimation for a first feature is provided. According to a first alternative, said at least one angle estimation is provided by deciding based on one or more criteria for said first feature if the first or the second algorithm should be used for calculating the angle estimation and calculating said first angle estimation based on an algorithm selected for said first feature (S13A).</p>
<p id="p0102" num="0102">According to a second alternative, said at least one angle estimation is provided by calculating an angle estimation for said first feature based on said first and said second algorithm and deciding based on one or more criteria if the angle estimation obtained by the first algorithm or obtained by the second algorithm is used for further processing (S13B).</p>
<p id="p0103" num="0103">Finally, the yaw angle is calculated based on said at least one angle estimation (S14).</p>
<p id="p0104" num="0104">It should be noted that the description and drawings merely illustrate the principles of the proposed invention. Those skilled in the art will be able to implement various arrangements that, although not explicitly described or shown herein, embody the principles of the invention.<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --></p>
<heading id="h0001"><b>List of reference numerals</b></heading>
<p id="p0105" num="0105">
<dl id="dl0001" compact="compact">
<dt>1</dt><dd>vehicle</dd>
<dt>2</dt><dd>trailer</dd>
<dt>3</dt><dd>camera</dd>
<dt>4</dt><dd>towball</dd>
</dl>
<dl id="dl0002" compact="compact">
<dt><i>α1</i></dt><dd>first angle estimation</dd>
<dt><i>α</i>2</dt><dd>second angle estimation</dd>
<dt>B1</dt><dd>first perpendicular bisector</dd>
<dt>B2</dt><dd>second perpendicular bisector</dd>
<dt>BL</dt><dd>baseline</dd>
<dt>F1</dt><dd>first feature</dd>
<dt>F2</dt><dd>second feature</dd>
<dt>IP1</dt><dd>first intersection point</dd>
<dt>IP2</dt><dd>second intersection point</dd>
<dt>L</dt><dd>length</dd>
<dt>LAT</dt><dd>longitudinal axis of trailer</dd>
<dt>LAV</dt><dd>longitudinal axis of vehicle</dd>
<dt>R</dt><dd>optical ray</dd>
<dt>YA</dt><dd>yaw angle</dd>
</dl></p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="28"> -->
<claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Method for determining the yaw angle (YA) of a trailer (2) with respect to the longitudinal axis (LAV) of a towing vehicle (1), the method comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>- capturing at least a first and a second image of the trailer (2) using a camera (3), the orientation of the trailer (2) with respect to the vehicle (1) being different on the at least two images (S10);</claim-text>
<claim-text>- determining at least a first feature (F1) of the trailer (2) which is visible on first and second image (S11);</claim-text>
<claim-text>- providing at least a first and a second algorithm for calculating at least one angle estimation based on said at least first feature (S12);</claim-text>
<claim-text>- providing at least a first angle estimation (α1) for said first feature (F1) by
<claim-text>∘ deciding based on one or more criteria for each feature (F1) if the first or the second algorithm should be used for calculating said first angle estimation (α1) and calculating said first angle estimation (α1) based on an algorithm selected for first feature (F1) (S13A); or</claim-text>
<claim-text>∘ calculating first angle estimation (α1) for said first feature (F1) based on said first and said second algorithm and deciding based on one or more criteria if the first angle estimation (α1) obtained by the first algorithm or first angle estimation (α1) obtained by the second algorithm is used for further processing (S13B); and</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>- calculating the yaw angle (YA) based on said first angle estimation (α1) (S14).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Method according to claim 1, wherein the first algorithm is configured to:<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> -->
<claim-text>- project a ray between the camera (3) and determined first feature on the first image onto a horizontal plane thereby obtaining a first projected feature position (PFP1a) and projecting a ray between the camera (3) and determined first feature on the second image onto said horizontal plane thereby obtaining a second projected feature position (PFP1b);</claim-text>
<claim-text>- establish a first perpendicular bisector (B1) between the location of the first projected feature position (PFP1a) and the location of the second projected feature position (PFP1b);</claim-text>
<claim-text>- determine a first intersection point (IP1) of first perpendicular bisector (B1) with a reference axis or a further perpendicular bisector (S14); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>- calculate a first angle estimation (α1), said first angle estimation (α1) referring to the angle between a first line running from first projected feature position (PFP1a) to said first intersection point (IP1) and a second line running from second projected feature position (PFP1b) to said first intersection point (IP1) in said horizontal plane.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Method according to claim 2, wherein a second feature (F2) of the trailer (2) is determined which is visible on first and second image, wherein said second feature (F2) is arranged at different position of the trailer (2) than the first feature (F1), wherein the first algorithm uses two or more features of the trailer (2) for providing angle estimations, wherein the first algorithm is configured to:
<claim-text>- project a ray between the camera (3) and determined second feature (F2) on the first image onto a horizontal plane thereby obtaining a third projected feature position (PFP2a) and projecting a ray between the camera (3) and determined second feature (F2) on the second image onto said horizontal<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --> plane thereby obtaining a fourth projected feature position (PFP2b);</claim-text>
<claim-text>- establish a second perpendicular bisector (B2) between the location of the third projected feature position (PFP2a) and the location of the fourth projected feature position (PFP2b);</claim-text>
<claim-text>- determine a second intersection point (IP2) of second perpendicular bisector (B2) with said reference axis, said first perpendicular bisector or a further perpendicular bisector; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>- calculate a second angle estimation (α2), said second angle estimation (α2) referring to the angle between a first line running from third projected feature position (PFP2a) to said second intersection point (IP2) and a second line running from fourth projected feature position (PFP2b) to said second intersection point (IP2) in said horizontal plane.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Method according to anyone of preceding claims, wherein the second algorithm is configured to calculate a first angle estimation (α1), the first angle estimation (α1) characterizing the pivot angle in a horizontal plane between the first feature (F1) on the first image and the first feature (F1) on the second image with respect to a fix point of the towing vehicle (1).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Method according to claim 4, wherein a second feature (F2) of the trailer (2) is determined which is visible on first and second image, wherein said second feature (F2) is arranged at different position of the trailer (2) than the first feature (F1), wherein the second algorithm is configured to calculate a second angle estimation (α2), the second angle estimation (α2) characterizing the pivot angle in a horizontal plane between the second feature (F2) on the first image and the second feature (F2) on the second image with respect to the fix point of the towing vehicle (1).<!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Method according to anyone of the preceding claims, wherein said step of determining based on one or more criteria comprises determining the length (L) of a baseline (BL) between a feature (F1, F2) on the first image and said feature (F1, F2) on the second image and comparing said length (L) with a length threshold value.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Method according to anyone of the preceding claims, wherein said step of determining based on one or more criteria comprises determining the roll and/or the pitch of the trailer (2) and comparing the roll with a roll threshold and/or the pitch with a pitch threshold.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>Method according to anyone of the preceding claims, wherein said step of determining based on one or more criteria comprises determining the vertical distance of a feature (F1, F2) with respect to a horizontal reference plane and comparing said vertical distance with a distance threshold value.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>Method according to anyone of preceding claims, wherein, in the second algorithm, calculating at least one angle estimation (α1, α2) comprises determining optical rays (R) between said fix point and said at least one feature (F1, F2) at first and second image.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>Method according to claim 9, wherein camera calibration information is used for converting the position of said first and/or second feature (F1, F2) from local domain of the image into local domain of the vehicle (1) in order to determine said optical rays (R).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>Method according to anyone of preceding claims, wherein in addition to said first and second feature (F1, F2), at least one further feature of the trailer (2) is used for calculating the yaw angle (YA).<!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>Method according to anyone of preceding claims, wherein the yaw angle (YA) is calculated by establishing the median value based on the at least two angle estimations, by establishing an average value of the at least two angle estimations or by using a statistical approach applied to said angle estimations.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>Method according to anyone of preceding claims, further comprising the step of determining an angle window, said angle window comprising an upper and a lower bound around yaw angle (YA), determining a set of features which lead to angle estimations within said angle window and using said determined set of features for future yaw angle (YA) calculations.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>System for determining the yaw angle (YA) of a trailer (2) with respect to the longitudinal axis (LAV) of a towing vehicle (1), the system comprising a camera (3) for capturing images of the trailer (2) and a processing entity for processing said captured images, the system further being configured to execute the steps of:
<claim-text>- capturing at least a first and a second image of the trailer (2) using a camera (3), the orientation of the trailer (2) with respect to the vehicle (1) being different on the at least two images (S10);</claim-text>
<claim-text>- determining at least a first feature (F1) of the trailer (2) which is visible on first and second image (S11);</claim-text>
<claim-text>- providing at least a first and a second algorithm for calculating at least one angle estimation based on said at least first feature (S12);</claim-text>
<claim-text>- providing at least a first angle estimation (α1) for said first feature (F1) by<!-- EPO <DP n="33"> -->
<claim-text>∘ deciding based on one or more criteria for each feature (F1) if the first or the second algorithm should be used for calculating said first angle estimation (α1) and calculating said first angle estimation (α1) based on an algorithm selected for first feature (F1) (S13A); or</claim-text>
<claim-text>∘ calculating first angle estimation (α1) for said first feature (F1) based on said first and said second algorithm and deciding based on one or more criteria if the first angle estimation (α1) obtained by the first algorithm or the first angle estimation (α1) obtained by the second algorithm is used for further processing (S13B); and</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>- calculating the yaw angle (YA) based on said first angle estimation (α1) (S14).</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0015" num="0015">
<claim-text>Vehicle comprising a system according to claim 14.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="34"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1,2"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="157" he="230" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="35"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="3"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="162" he="141" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="36"> -->
<figure id="f0003" num="4"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="150" he="135" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="37"> -->
<figure id="f0004" num="5"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="163" he="205" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<search-report-data id="srep" lang="en" srep-office="EP" date-produced=""><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="157" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="155" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data><search-report-data date-produced="20200731" id="srepxml" lang="en" srep-office="EP" srep-type="ep-sr" status="n"><!--
 The search report data in XML is provided for the users' convenience only. It might differ from the search report of the PDF document, which contains the officially published data. The EPO disclaims any liability for incorrect or incomplete data in the XML for search reports.
 -->

<srep-info><file-reference-id>2020P01195EP (NU)</file-reference-id><application-reference><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>20167191.4</doc-number></document-id></application-reference><applicant-name><name>Continental Automotive GmbH</name></applicant-name><srep-established srep-established="yes"/><srep-invention-title title-approval="yes"/><srep-abstract abs-approval="yes"/><srep-figure-to-publish figinfo="by-applicant"><figure-to-publish><fig-number>5</fig-number></figure-to-publish></srep-figure-to-publish><srep-info-admin><srep-office><addressbook><text>MN</text></addressbook></srep-office><date-search-report-mailed><date>20200811</date></date-search-report-mailed></srep-info-admin></srep-info><srep-for-pub><srep-fields-searched><minimum-documentation><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr><text>G06T</text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr><text>B60D</text></classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr></minimum-documentation></srep-fields-searched><srep-citations><citation id="sr-cit0001"><patcit dnum="EP3552926A1" id="sr-pcit0001" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=EP3552926&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>3552926</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>CONTINENTAL AUTOMOTIVE GMBH [DE]</name><date>20191016</date></document-id></patcit><category>X</category><rel-claims>1,4,9-11,14,15</rel-claims><category>Y</category><rel-claims>2,3</rel-claims><category>A</category><rel-claims>5,6,8,12,13</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* paragraphs [0001],  [0035]; claim 1; figures 6,11 *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0002"><patcit dnum="EP3537382A1" id="sr-pcit0002" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=EP3537382&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>3537382</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>CONTINENTAL AUTOMOTIVE GMBH [DE]</name><date>20190911</date></document-id></patcit><category>X</category><rel-claims>1,4,7,9,14</rel-claims><category>Y</category><rel-claims>2,3</rel-claims><category>A</category><rel-claims>5,6,8,12,13</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* paragraphs [0028] - [0031],  [0079] *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0003"><patcit dnum="DE102016117284A1" id="sr-pcit0003" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=DE102016117284&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>DE</country><doc-number>102016117284</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>CONNAUGHT ELECTRONICS LTD [IE]</name><date>20180315</date></document-id></patcit><category>Y</category><rel-claims>2,3</rel-claims><category>A</category><rel-claims>5,6,8,12,13</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* figure 2 *</passage></rel-passage></citation></srep-citations><srep-admin><examiners><primary-examiner><name>Tillier, Christophe</name></primary-examiner></examiners><srep-office><addressbook><text>Munich</text></addressbook></srep-office><date-search-completed><date>20200731</date></date-search-completed></srep-admin><!--							The annex lists the patent family members relating to the patent documents cited in the above mentioned European search report.							The members are as contained in the European Patent Office EDP file on							The European Patent Office is in no way liable for these particulars which are merely given for the purpose of information.							For more details about this annex : see Official Journal of the European Patent Office, No 12/82						--><srep-patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>3552926</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20191016</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>3552926</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20191016</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2021027490</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20210128</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2019197140</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20191017</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>3537382</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20190911</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>3537382</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20190911</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2020402257</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20201224</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2019170469</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20190912</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>DE</country><doc-number>102016117284</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20180315</date></document-id></priority-application><text>NONE</text></patent-family></srep-patent-family></srep-for-pub></search-report-data>
</ep-patent-document>
