<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP19891104A1" file="EP19891104NWA1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3889801" kind="A1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSKBAHRIS..MTNORSMESMMAKHTNMD..........</B001EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  1100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3889801</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT APPLICATION</B121><B121EP>published in accordance with Art. 153(4) EPC</B121EP></B120><B130>A1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>19891104.2</B210><B220><date>20191113</date></B220><B240><B241><date>20210518</date></B241></B240><B250>ja</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B300><B310>2018223786</B310><B320><date>20181129</date></B320><B330><ctry>JP</ctry></B330></B300><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B430></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>G06F  16/53        20190101AFI20200605BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="2"><text>E01D  22/00        20060101ALI20200605BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="3"><text>G06F  16/903       20190101ALI20200605BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="4"><text>G06Q  50/08        20120101ALI20200605BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>G06Q  50/08        20130101 LI20200625BCEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>E01D  22/00        20130101 LI20200625BCEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="3"><text>G06F  16/903       20190101 LI20200625BCEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="4"><text>G06F  16/53        20190101 LI20200625BCEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>SYSTEM ZUR BEWERTUNG DER URSACHE VON SCHÄDEN AN EINER STRUKTUR, VERFAHREN ZUR BEWERTUNG DER URSACHE VON SCHÄDEN UND SERVER ZUR BEWERTUNG DER URSACHE VON SCHÄDEN</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>SYSTEM FOR ASSESSING CAUSE OF DAMAGE TO STRUCTURE, METHOD FOR ASSESSING CAUSE OF DAMAGE, AND SERVER FOR ASSESSING CAUSE OF DAMAGE</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>SYSTÈME D'ÉVALUATION DE CAUSE D'ENDOMMAGEMENT D'UNE STRUCTURE, PROCÉDÉ D'ÉVALUATION DE CAUSE D'ENDOMMAGEMENT ET SERVEUR D'ÉVALUATION DE CAUSE D'ENDOMMAGEMENT</B542></B540><B590><B598>2</B598></B590></B500><B700><B710><B711><snm>FUJIFILM Corporation</snm><iid>101890000</iid><irf>M/FUJI-021-PC/EP</irf><adr><str>26-30, Nishiazabu 2-chome 
Minato-ku</str><city>Tokyo 106-8620</city><ctry>JP</ctry></adr></B711></B710><B720><B721><snm>HORITA Shuhei</snm><adr><str>c/o FUJIFILM Corporation, 7-3, Akasaka 9-chome,  
Minato-ku</str><city>Tokyo 107-0052</city><ctry>JP</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B740><B741><snm>Parker, Andrew James</snm><iid>101299091</iid><adr><str>Meissner Bolte Patentanwälte 
Rechtsanwälte Partnerschaft mbB 
Postfach 86 06 24</str><city>81633 München</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840><B844EP><B845EP><ctry>BA</ctry></B845EP><B845EP><ctry>ME</ctry></B845EP></B844EP><B848EP><B849EP><ctry>KH</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>MA</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>MD</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>TN</ctry></B849EP></B848EP><B860><B861><dnum><anum>JP2019044449</anum></dnum><date>20191113</date></B861><B862>ja</B862></B860><B870><B871><dnum><pnum>WO2020110717</pnum></dnum><date>20200604</date><bnum>202023</bnum></B871></B870></B800></SDOBI>
<abstract id="abst" lang="en">
<p id="pa01" num="0001">A structure damage cause estimation system, a structure damage cause estimation method, and a structure damage cause estimation server that enable a damage cause to be estimated with a high probability are provided. A structure damage cause estimation system (100) includes a database (110) that has data of a captured image and a damage cause of a structure, an image acquisition unit (115) that acquires a captured image of a target structure to be inspected, a damage detection unit (125) that detects damage from the captured image, a similar damage extraction unit (130) that extracts similar damage similar to the damage by using the database (110), and a damage cause presentation unit (135) that presents damage causes of the similar damage. Also provided are a damage cause estimation method that uses the structure damage cause estimation system (100), and a damage cause estimation server.<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="131" he="77" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p>
</abstract>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<heading id="h0001"><b>BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</b></heading>
<heading id="h0002">1. Field of the Invention</heading>
<p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a structure damage cause estimation system, a structure damage cause estimation method, and a structure damage cause estimation server. More particularly, the present invention relates to a damage cause estimation system, a damage cause estimation method, and a damage cause estimation server that estimate a damage cause by using a database including results about damage causes of structures inspected in the past.</p>
<heading id="h0003">2. Description of the Related Art</heading>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">Social infrastructure such as a bridge needs to be periodically inspected. In a periodic inspection, a damage cause is estimated and identified from a result of a visual inspection, and diagnosis such as determination of a countermeasure class (determination of the necessity of repair) is made.</p>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">Since estimation and identification of a damage cause require advanced skills and experience, the results may vary among inspectors (diagnosis-making persons). Thus, there may be cases where estimation of the damage cause is difficult. Shortage of skilled inspectors is also a factor that hinders an appropriate damage cause from being estimated.</p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">As a system for evaluating a defect of infrastructure including a structure such as a road, for example, <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="JP2015095143A"><text>JP2015-95143A</text></patcit> describes a system for assisting evaluation of a defect of infrastructure. The system generates a recommendation ranking list of pieces of defect information having high degrees of similarity to defect information to be processed, on the basis of co-occurrence information which is a co-occurrence probability for defect information and of the defect information to be processed.</p>
<heading id="h0004"><b>SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</b></heading>
<p id="p0005" num="0005"><patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="JP2015095143A"><text>JP2015-95143A</text></patcit> describes that the defect information may include a structure type name or, as other information, "a volume of traffic", "information on the structure",<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> "construction year", etc. in addition to a damage item name such as a crack or a free lime. However, for example, the volume of traffic or the information on the structure is merely one condition used for identifying a damage cause. Thus, it is not possible to determine that deterioration is caused by fatigue because the volume of traffic is large. Accordingly, a system for simply obtaining a damage cause is desired.</p>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">The present invention is made in view of such a circumstance, and an object of the present invention is to provide a structure damage cause estimation system, a structure damage cause estimation method, and a structure damage cause estimation server that extract and list damage examples similar to a damage state of a structure subjected to a current inspection by using a database including damage causes identified in past inspections so as to enable estimation of a damage cause with a high probability.</p>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">To accomplish the object of the present invention, a structure damage cause estimation system according to an aspect of the present invention includes a database that has data of a captured image of damage of a structure before repair and a damage cause of the structure; an image acquisition unit that acquires a captured image of a target structure to be inspected; an actual size information acquisition unit that acquires an actual size of a characteristic portion of the target structure in the captured image or an actual length of the target structure; a damage detection unit that detects damage from the captured image acquired by the image acquisition unit, and calculates a degree of the damage, based on information acquired by the actual size information acquisition unit; a similar damage extraction unit that determines a degree of similarity of the damage detected by the damage detection unit to damage of the structure in the database, and extracts one or more kinds of similar damage for which the degree of similarity is high; and a damage cause presentation unit that presents damage causes of the kinds of similar damage extracted by the similar damage extraction unit.</p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">To accomplish the object of the present invention, a structure damage cause estimation method according to an aspect of the present invention includes an image acquisition step of, with an image acquisition unit, acquiring a captured image of a target structure to be inspected; an actual size information acquisition step of, with an actual size information acquisition unit, acquiring an actual size of a characteristic portion of the target structure in the captured image or an actual length of the target structure; a damage detection step of, with a damage detection unit, detecting damage from the captured image acquired in the image acquisition step, and calculating a degree of the damage, based on information acquired in the actual size information acquisition step; a similar damage extraction step of, with a similar damage extraction unit, by using a database having data of a captured image of<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> damage of a structure before the repair and a damage cause of the structure, determining a degree of similarity of the damage detected in the damage detection step to damage of the structure in the database, and extracting one or more kinds of similar damage for which the degree of similarity is high; and a damage cause presentation step of, with a damage cause presentation unit, presenting damage causes of the kinds of similar damage extracted in the similar damage extraction step.</p>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">To accomplish the object of the present invention, a structure damage cause estimation server according to an aspect of the present invention is a structure damage cause estimation server that is connected to a user terminal via a network and estimates a damage cause of a target structure to be inspected and that includes a database that has data of a captured image of damage of a structure before repair and a damage cause of the structure; an image acquisition unit that acquires a captured image of a target structure to be inspected; an actual size information acquisition unit that acquires an actual size of a characteristic portion of the target structure in the captured image or an actual length of the target structure; a damage detection unit that detects damage from the captured image acquired by the image acquisition unit, and calculates a degree of the damage, based on information acquired by the actual size information acquisition unit; a similar damage extraction unit that determines a degree of similarity of the damage detected by the damage detection unit to damage of the structure in the database, and extracts one or more kinds of similar damage for which the degree of similarity is high; a damage cause presentation unit that presents damage causes of the kinds of similar damage extracted by the similar damage extraction unit; and a communication unit having a reception unit that receives the captured image from the user terminal via the network, and a transmission unit that transmits the damage causes presented by the damage cause presentation unit to the user terminal.</p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">The structure damage cause estimation system according to an aspect of the present invention is capable of extracting damage examples similar to a damage state of a target structure subjected to an inspection by using a database including damage causes identified in past inspections. By extracting damage having a high degree of similarity to the damage of the target subjected to the inspection from the database and listing damage causes, a user can refer to the result when identifying the damage cause. Thus, the accuracy of estimation of the damage cause can be increased.</p>
<heading id="h0005"><b>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</b></heading><!-- EPO <DP n="4"> -->
<p id="p0011" num="0011">
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li><figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is an external view of a bridge view from below;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> is a block diagram illustrating a configuration of a structure damage cause estimation system;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> is a graph illustrating a concept of determining a degree of similarity of damage;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0004">Fig. 4</figref> is a diagram describing a method of presenting damage causes;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0005">Fig. 5</figref> is a flowchart of a structure damage cause estimation method; and</li>
<li><figref idref="f0006">Fig. 6</figref> is a block diagram illustrating a configuration of a structure damage cause estimation server.</li>
</ul></p>
<heading id="h0006"><b>DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</b></heading>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">A structure damage cause estimation system, a structure damage cause estimation method, and a structure damage cause estimation server according to one embodiment of the present invention will be described below with reference to the accompanying drawings. Structure of Bridge</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013"><figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is a perspective view of a bridge 1, which is a structure, viewed from below. The bridge 1 illustrated in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> has a three-dimensional structure constituted by main girders 2, cross beams 3, sway bracings 4, lateral bracing 5, and deck slabs 6. These members are connected to each other with bolts, rivets, welding, and so on. The deck slabs 6 on which vehicles or the like travel are placed above the main girders 2 and so on. As the deck slabs 6, reinforced concrete deck slabs are typically used. The main girders 2 are members laid between abutments or piers to support the load of vehicles or the like on the deck slabs 6. The main girders 2 have surfaces (vertical surfaces) orthogonal to surfaces (horizontal surfaces) of the deck slabs 6. The cross beams 3 are members that connect the plurality of main girders 2 to each other so that the main girders 2 support the load. The sway bracings 4 and the lateral bracings 5 are members that connect the main girders 2 to each other to resist the lateral load imposed by winds and earthquakes. In the present embodiment, the structure is not limited to a bridge, and may be a tunnel, a building, and a road or the like.</p>
<heading id="h0007">Structure Damage Cause Estimation System</heading>
<p id="p0014" num="0014"><figref idref="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> is a block diagram illustrating schematic configurations of a damage cause estimation system 100 according to one embodiment of the present invention and of a digital camera 200.</p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">The damage cause estimation system 100 according to the present embodiment has a database 110, an image acquisition unit 115, an actual size information acquisition unit 120, a<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> damage detection unit 125, a similar damage extraction unit 130, and a damage cause presentation unit 135. The damage cause estimation system 100 may include an information acquisition unit 140 that acquires information on a target structure to be inspected, namely, other information such as a damage cause and structure information held in association with the structure in the database 110, a display control unit 145 that displays estimated damage causes, and an output unit 150 that outputs the estimated damage causes.</p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">The damage cause estimation system 100 is a system that detects damage from an image obtained by capturing an image of a target structure to be inspected and estimates a damage cause of the damage. The damage cause estimation system 100 is applicable to a digital camera, a smartphone, a tablet terminal, a personal computer, and the like. The image acquired by the image acquisition unit 115 can be captured by the digital camera 200. The digital camera 200 may be placed in a housing different from that of the damage cause estimation system 100, or may be integrated with the damage cause estimation system 100. The digital camera 200 may be incorporated as a portion of the damage cause estimation system 100 and may constitute the structure damage cause estimation system according to the present embodiment.</p>
<heading id="h0008">Configuration of Digital Camera</heading>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">The digital camera 200 captures an image with an imaging optical system 210 including an imaging lens (not illustrated) and an imaging element (not illustrated). Examples of the imaging element include a charge coupled device (CCD) imaging element and a complementary metal-oxide semiconductor (CMOS) imaging element. Color filters of red (R), green (G), and blue (B) are disposed on a light-receiving surface of the imaging element. Thus, the imaging element is capable of acquiring a color image of a photographic subject on the basis of signals of the respective colors. The digital camera 200 wirelessly communicates with the damage cause estimation system 100 via a wireless communication unit 220 and an antenna 222, so that the captured image is input to the image acquisition unit 115 and is subjected to processing described below.</p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">If an image of the entire structure or portion serving as a photographic subject cannot be captured in a single image-capturing operation performed with the digital camera 200, a group of images is acquired by capturing images of segments of the structure or portion serving as the photographic subject. The image acquisition unit 115 includes a panoramic combination unit 116 and may use an image resulting from panoramic combination processing performed on the group of images by the panoramic combination unit 116. The digital camera 200 may be, for example, a general-purpose compact digital camera having the number of<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> pixels of about 5000 × 4000 pixels.</p>
<heading id="h0009">Each Constituent of Structure Damage Cause Estimation System</heading>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">The damage cause estimation system 100 is constituted mainly by the database 110, the image acquisition unit 115, the actual size information acquisition unit 120, the damage detection unit 125, the similar damage extraction unit 130, and the damage cause presentation unit 135. These are connected to each other to transmit and receive necessary information. The damage cause estimation system 100 wirelessly communicates with the digital camera 200 via an antenna 117, and acquires a captured image captured by the digital camera 200.</p>
<heading id="h0010">Database</heading>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">The database 110 is a recording means for storing a captured image of a structure before repair and a damage cause of the structure.</p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">As damage causes of a concrete member, example of the damage cause include (1) deterioration due to fatigue (repeatedly imposed load), salt, neutralization, alkali-silica reaction, frost damage, chemical erosion, and so on; (2) construction-relating factors such as heat of hydration and drying shrinkage caused during construction; and (3) structural factors such as application of an excessive external force and an inappropriate design. As damage causes of a steel member, examples of the damage cause include (1) deterioration due to fatigue (repeatedly imposed load), salt, and so on; and (2) structural factors such as application of an excessive external force and an inappropriate design.</p>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">The information stored in the database 110 can include damage information of the structure. The damage information of the structure can include a type of damage, a position of the damage, and a degree of the damage (such as a length, a width, an area, a density, a depth, or the like, or an average value or maximum value thereof).</p>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">The information stored in the database 110 may include, as other information, structure information, environment information, and history information. Examples of the structure information include (1) a type of the structure which is, for example, a girder bridge, a rigid-frame bridge, a truss bridge, an arch bridge, a cable-stayed bridge, a suspension bridge, or the like in the case of a bridge; (2) a type of a member which is, for example, a deck slab, a pier, an abutment, a girder, or the like in the case of a bridge; and (3) a material, which is, for example, steel, reinforced concrete, prestressed concrete (PC), or the like.</p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">Examples of the environment information include a daily, monthly, yearly, or cumulative volume of traffic, a distance from the sea, and climates such as an average temperature, an average humidity, a rainfall, and a snowfall.</p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">Examples of the history information include construction conditions such as<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> temperatures during construction; the number of elapsed years; a repair history; a disaster history of earthquakes, typhoons, floods, and so on; and monitoring information on deflection, a vibration amplitude, a vibration period, and so on.</p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">The database 110 may further store at least one of captured images or damage information of damage of a structure at a plurality of past time points. By storing the past captured images and the damage information, a chronological change of the target structure can also be used in determination of the degree of similarity when the degree of similarity is determined.</p>
<heading id="h0011">Image Acquisition Unit</heading>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">The image acquisition unit 115 acquires a captured image of a target structure to be inspected. As the captured image, an image is acquired in units of structures or in units of members of the target structure.</p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">The image acquisition unit 115 acquires a captured image of the bridge 1 from the digital camera 200 (or a recording medium, a network, or the like). The captured image may be an image obtained by capturing the entire structure in a single image-capturing operation, or may be a plurality of images obtained by capturing images of segments of the target structure as a group of images when a region for which the captured image is to be acquired cannot be covered by a single image-capturing operation with a predetermined resolution. When a plurality of images are acquired, the panoramic combination unit 116 performs panoramic combination processing. In the panoramic combination processing, correspondence points between images are detected, and the captured images are combined together on the basis of the correspondence points between the images.</p>
<p id="p0029" num="0029">The image acquisition unit 115 may periodically acquire the captured image of the target structure to acquire chronological images of the target structure. When detecting similar damage, the similar damage extraction unit 130 described later can also use a chronological change in the target structure to determine the degree of similarity. Note that it is sufficient that at least an image at the previous inspection and an image at the current inspection are acquired as the chronological images.</p>
<heading id="h0012">Actual Size Information Acquisition Unit</heading>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">The actual size information acquisition unit 120 acquires an actual size of a characteristic portion of the target structure in the captured image acquired by the image acquisition unit 115 or an actual length of the target structure. In a method for obtaining an actual length of a structure, the actual length of the target structure can be obtained by acquiring a resolution representing an actual length of the target structure per unit pixel of the<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> captured image. In another method, the actual length of the target structure can be obtained by capturing an image of the structure together with an object with which the length of the structure is obtained, or by capturing an image by projecting a scale.</p>
<heading id="h0013">Damage Detection Unit</heading>
<p id="p0031" num="0031">The damage detection unit 125 detects damage from the captured image acquired by the image acquisition unit 115. The damage detection unit 125 also calculates a degree of the damage on the basis of information acquired by the actual size information acquisition unit 120.</p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032">In the case where the structure is a concrete member, the damage detection unit 125 detects, as damage to be detected, damage such as a crack, water leakage, free lime, peeling, exposure of a reinforcement steel, and delamination. In the case where the structure is a steel member, the damage detection unit 125 detects damage such as fracture, corrosion, and deterioration of anti-corrosion function. The damage detection unit 125 detects any one or more of these kinds of damage.</p>
<p id="p0033" num="0033">The detection can be performed through detection using a machine-learning-based detector and a detection algorithm.</p>
<p id="p0034" num="0034">For example, items to be measured for detecting a crack include a position, a size, a direction, a range, a shape, and the like. These items can be set according to conditions such as a type and characteristics of the structure. A crack can be detected by using various methods. For example, a crack detection method described in <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="JP4006007B"><text>JP4006007B</text></patcit> can be used. This method is a crack detection method having a step of creating a wavelet image and a step of determining a crack region on the basis of the wavelet image. In the step of creating a wavelet image, a wavelet coefficient corresponding to two densities to be compared is calculated, wavelet coefficients in the cases where the two densities are each changed are calculated to create a wavelet coefficient table, and wavelet transform is performed on an input image obtained by capturing an image of a concrete surface subjected to crack detection. In the step of determining a crack region, a wavelet coefficient corresponding to an average density of neighboring pixels in a local region and to a density of a pixel of interest in the wavelet coefficient table is set as a threshold value, and a crack region and a non-crack region are determined by comparing the wavelet coefficient of the pixel of interest with the threshold value.</p>
<heading id="h0014">Similar Damage Extraction Unit</heading>
<p id="p0035" num="0035">The similar damage extraction unit 130 determines a degree of similarity on the basis of the type of the damage, the position of the damage, and the degree of the damage, and<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> extracts one or more kinds of similar damage having high degrees of similarity from the database 110.</p>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">The similar damage extraction unit 130 may determine the degree of similarity on the basis of chronological changes in the position of the damage and the degree of damage in addition to the damage information. The similar damage extraction unit 130 may determine the degree of similarity on the basis of any one or more of the structure information, the environment information, the history information, the disaster information, and the inspection information in the database 110, and extract similar damage.</p>
<p id="p0037" num="0037">In determination of the degree of similarity, a distance between damage of an inspection-target structure and damage of another structure stored in the database is calculated in a feature space having the above information as feature vectors. Damage having this distance equal to or less than a certain threshold value is extracted as similar damage.</p>
<p id="p0038" num="0038"><figref idref="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> is a graph illustrating a concept of determining a degree of similarity. The feature space defined by feature vectors can be a multi-dimensional space defined by parameters selected from the group consisting of the type of the damage, the position of the damage, the degree of the damage, chronological changes in the position of the damage and the degree of damage, the structure information, the environment information, the history information, the disaster information, and the inspection information which are used when the degree of similarity is determined. Note that <figref idref="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> illustrates a two-dimensional space to simplify the description.</p>
<p id="p0039" num="0039">In <figref idref="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>, the maximum crack width is plotted as a first feature vector on a lateral axis, and the number of elapsed years after the start of use is plotted as a second feature vector on a vertical axis. A predetermined distance from damage of the target structure to be inspected is set as a threshold value, and damage having a distance less than or equal to this threshold value is extracted as similar damage. In <figref idref="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>, a circle centered at the target structure and represented by a broken line indicates that the distance is less than or equal to the threshold value.</p>
<p id="p0040" num="0040">When similar damage is extracted, a distance (Euclidean distance) based on parameters that are not weighted may be used, or a distance (Mahalanobis distance) based on weighted parameters may be used. How which parameter is weighted may be determined by a statistical method such as principal component analysis.</p>
<heading id="h0015">Damage Cause Presentation Unit</heading>
<p id="p0041" num="0041">The damage cause presentation unit 135 presents damage causes of similar damage extracted by the similar damage extraction unit 130. As for a method for presenting the<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> damage causes, for example, the damage causes can be presented in the following manner. <figref idref="f0004">Fig. 4</figref> is a diagram describing a method of presenting damage causes.</p>
<p id="p0042" num="0042">(1) Pieces of information on similar damage are presented in descending order of the degree of similarity.</p>
<p id="p0043" num="0043">Among kinds of similar damage extracted by the similar damage extraction unit 130, pieces of information on kinds of similar damage having high degrees of similarity, for example, pieces of information on kinds of similar damage having the top 100 degrees of similarity are listed in descending order of the evaluation score (EXAMPLE 1).</p>
<p id="p0044" num="0044">(2) Percentages of damage causes of similar damage are presented.</p>
<p id="p0045" num="0045">Occurrence frequencies (percentages) of damage causes of kinds of similar damage having high degrees of similarity, for example, kinds of similar damage having the top 100 degrees of similarity among the kinds of similar damage extracted by the similar damage extraction unit 130 are calculated and presented along with the respective damage causes. For example, in EXAMPLE 2 of <figref idref="f0004">Fig. 4</figref>, among 10 kinds of similar damage (A to J), the damage cause is fatigue in seven cases, the damage cause is salt in two cases, and the damage cause is alkali-silica reaction in one case. Thus, the damage causes are represented as fatigue (70%), salt (20%), and alkali-silica reaction (10%).</p>
<p id="p0046" num="0046">(3) Damage causes in the database are listed for the extracted similar damage.</p>
<p id="p0047" num="0047">Damage causes may be listed for the similar damage extracted by the similar damage extraction unit 130 without rearranging the order.</p>
<p id="p0048" num="0048"><figref idref="f0004">Fig. 4</figref> illustrates the 10 damage examples A to J as examples of damage to simplify the illustration. However, in practice, it is preferable to extract 100 damage examples up to the 100th place as described above and present the damage causes.</p>
<p id="p0049" num="0049">The information to be presented is not the damage causes alone, and information such as the captured image and the damage information (the type of damage, the position of damage, the degree of the damage (such as length, width, or area) of the target structure can be presented.</p>
<p id="p0050" num="0050">In one embodiment of the present invention, the damage causes to be presented are causes of damage that can be fixed by repair. For example, in the case of examples of the damage cause of a concrete member, deteriorations include fatigue, salt damage, neutralization, alkali-silica reaction, frost damage, chemical erosion, and so on. Construction-relating factors include heat of hydration, drying shrinkage, and so on caused during construction. Structural factors include application of an excessive external force, an inappropriate design, and so on. In the case of examples of the damage cause of a steel member, deteriorations include fatigue,<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> salt damage, and so on. Structural factors include application of an excessive external force and an inappropriate design.</p>
<heading id="h0016">Information Acquisition Unit</heading>
<p id="p0051" num="0051">The information acquisition unit 140 acquires structure information, environment information, and history information (hereinafter, also referred to as "information on the structure or the like") of the target structure to be inspected. As the structure information, the environment information, and the history information, information substantially the same as the information included in the database 110 described above is acquired.</p>
<p id="p0052" num="0052">When the information acquisition unit 140 acquires the information, the information can be input using an operation section (not illustrated). The operation section includes a keyboard and a mouse as input devices. When a monitor display unit 146 described later has a touch panel, the operation section also includes the touch panel. The user can input information on the structure or the like through these devices and the screen of the monitor display unit 146. The information acquisition unit 140 acquires the input information on the structure or the like.</p>
<heading id="h0017">Display Control Unit</heading>
<p id="p0053" num="0053">The display control unit 145 includes the monitor display unit 146, and causes the monitor display unit 146 to display information such as the acquired captured image, the damage causes of the extracted similar damage, and the information on the target structure to be inspected. The display control unit 145 controls the matters relating to the display screen such as information to be displayed on the monitor display unit 146. The monitor display unit 146 is a display device such as a liquid crystal display.</p>
<heading id="h0018">Output Unit</heading>
<p id="p0054" num="0054">The output unit 150 outputs the damage causes presented by the damage cause presentation unit 135 as text data or table data. The output unit 150 also outputs the acquired captured image. These pieces of information may be output as data of a figure.</p>
<heading id="h0019">Procedure of Damage Cause Estimation Method</heading>
<p id="p0055" num="0055">A damage cause estimation method used by the damage cause estimation system will be described. <figref idref="f0005">Fig. 5</figref> is a flowchart illustrating a procedure of the damage cause estimation method.</p>
<heading id="h0020">Image Acquisition Step</heading>
<p id="p0056" num="0056">An image acquisition step is a step of acquiring a captured image of a target structure to be inspected (step S12). The captured image is obtained by the digital camera 200. The damage cause estimation system 100 acquires a captured image via the digital camera 200 (the<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> imaging optical system 210, the wireless communication unit 220, and the antenna 222), the antenna 117, and the image acquisition unit 115.</p>
<p id="p0057" num="0057">In a case where the captured image is a plurality of captured images (a group of image images), panoramic combining processing for combining the plurality of captured images into a single image is performed. In combination of the captured images, calculation of combination information, for example, calculation of correspondence points between the captured images and calculation of a projective transformation matrix on the basis of the correspondence points, is performed, and the images are combined on the basis of the correspondence points.</p>
<heading id="h0021">Actual Size Information Acquisition Step</heading>
<p id="p0058" num="0058">In an actual size information acquisition step, an actual size of a characteristic portion of the target structure in the captured image acquired in the image acquisition step or an actual length of the target structure is acquired (step S14).</p>
<heading id="h0022">Damage Detection Step</heading>
<p id="p0059" num="0059">A damage detection step is a step of detecting damage from the captured image acquired in the image acquisition step (step S16). A degree of the damage is also calculated on the basis of the information acquired in the actual size information acquisition step.</p>
<heading id="h0023">Similar Damage Extraction Step</heading>
<p id="p0060" num="0060">In a similar damage extraction step, degrees of similarity of the damage detected in the damage detection step to kinds of damage of structures in the database 110 are determined using the database 110, and one or more kinds of similar damage having high degrees of similarity are extracted (step S18).</p>
<p id="p0061" num="0061">As for the extraction of similar damage, the structure may be periodically inspected after the repair. This inspection history may be recorded in the database 110. The degree of similarity may be determined on the basis of the chronological change based on this inspection record.</p>
<heading id="h0024">Damage Cause Presentation Step</heading>
<p id="p0062" num="0062">In a damage cause presentation step, damage causes of the kinds of similar damage extracted in the similar damage extraction step are presented (step S20). In presentation of the damage causes, the damage causes can be presented so that the damage cause is easily determined, by using a method of presenting damage causes in descending order of the degree of similarity for the respective kinds of similar damage or of presenting a percentage of each damage cause with respect to the extracted kinds of similar damage together with the damage cause.<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></p>
<heading id="h0025">Structure Damage Cause Estimation Server</heading>
<p id="p0063" num="0063"><figref idref="f0006">Fig. 6</figref> is a block diagram illustrating a schematic configuration of a damage cause estimation server 300 according to one embodiment of the present invention. The same components as those of the damage cause estimation system 100 illustrated in <figref idref="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> are denoted by the same reference signs, and description thereof will be omitted below.</p>
<p id="p0064" num="0064">The damage cause estimation server 300 according to the present embodiment has the database 110, the image acquisition unit 115, the actual size information acquisition unit 120, the damage detection unit 125, the similar damage extraction unit 130, the damage cause presentation unit 135, and a communication unit 305. The damage cause estimation server 300 may also include the information acquisition unit 140 that acquires information on a target structure to be inspected, namely, other information such as structure information of the structure held in the database 110.</p>
<p id="p0065" num="0065">The damage cause estimation server 300 includes the communication unit 305 and is connected to a user terminal 400 via a network. The communication unit 305 includes a reception unit 306 and a transmission unit 307. The reception unit 306 receives a captured image of a target structure to be inspected from the user terminal 400. The received captured image is transmitted to the image acquisition unit 115 and is processed in substantially the same manner as in the damage cause estimation system 100 illustrated in <figref idref="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>. The damage cause presentation unit 135 presents damage causes of the target structure to be inspected. The reception unit 306 may also receive information on the structure or the like input to the user terminal 400 and transmit the information to the information acquisition unit 140. The information may be used by the similar damage extraction unit 130 to determine the degree of similarity.</p>
<p id="p0066" num="0066">The damage causes presented by the damage cause presentation unit 135 are transmitted to the communication unit 305. The transmission unit 307 transmits the presented damage causes to the user terminal 400. A user checks the presented damage causes on the user terminal 400. In this manner, the accuracy of determining the damage cause can be increased.</p>
<p id="p0067" num="0067">As described above, the structure damage cause estimation system, the structure damage cause estimation method, and the structure damage cause estimation server according to the present embodiments enable a user to determine a damage cause with a high accuracy by extracting kinds of similar damage from the database 110 and presenting damage causes of the extracted kinds of similar damage.</p>
<p id="p0068" num="0068">In each of the embodiments described above, the hardware structure of the processing<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> units that perform various processes, such as the database 110, the image acquisition unit 115, the panoramic combination unit 116, the actual size information acquisition unit 120, the damage detection unit 125, the similar damage extraction unit 130, the damage cause presentation unit 135, the information acquisition unit 140, the display control unit 145, the output unit 150, the communication unit 305, the reception unit 306, and the transmission unit 307 is various processors as follows. The various processors include, for example, a central processing unit (CPU) which is a general-purpose processor that executes software (program) to function as the various processing units; a programmable logic device (PLD) which is a processor whose circuit configuration is changeable after manufacture, such as a field programmable gate array (FPGA); and a dedicated electric circuitry which is a processor having a circuit configuration designed exclusively for executing a specific process, such as an application-specific integrated circuit (ASIC).</p>
<p id="p0069" num="0069">A single processing unit may be implemented by one of these various processors, or may be implemented by two or more processors of the same kind or of different kinds (for example, a plurality of FPGAs or a combination of a CPU and an FPGA). In addition, the plurality of processing units may be implemented by a single processor. Examples in which the plurality of processing units are implemented by a single processor include a first configuration, as exemplified by a computer such as a client or a server, in which a combination of one or more CPUs and software constitutes a single processor and this processor functions as the plurality of processing units. The examples also include a second configuration, as exemplified by a system on chip (SoC) or the like, in which a processor that implements the functions of the entire system including the plurality of processing units with a single integrated circuit (IC) chip is used. As described above, the various processing units are implemented using one or more of the various processors described above in terms of the hardware structure.</p>
<p id="p0070" num="0070">Further, the hardware structure of these various processors is, more specifically, electric circuitry in which circuit elements such as semiconductor elements are combined.</p>
<p id="p0071" num="0071">The description above can be grasped as a structure damage cause estimation system described in Appendix 1 below.</p>
<heading id="h0026">[Appendix 1]</heading>
<p id="p0072" num="0072">A structure damage cause estimation system including:
<ul id="ul0002" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>a memory that stores data of a captured image of damage of a structure before repair and a damage cause of the structure; and</li>
<li>a processor, wherein<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --></li>
<li>the processor</li>
<li>acquires a captured image of a target structure to be inspected;</li>
<li>acquires an actual size of a characteristic portion of the target structure in the captured image or an actual length of the target structure;</li>
<li>detects damage from the captured image acquired, and calculates a degree of the damage, based on information acquired;</li>
<li>determines a degree of similarity of the detected damage to damage of the structure stored in the memory, and extracts one or more kinds of similar damage for which the degree of similarity is high; and</li>
<li>presents damage causes of the extracted kinds of similar damage.</li>
</ul></p>
<heading id="h0027">Reference Signs List</heading>
<p id="p0073" num="0073">
<dl id="dl0001" compact="compact">
<dt>1</dt><dd>bridge</dd>
<dt>2</dt><dd>main girder</dd>
<dt>3</dt><dd>cross beam</dd>
<dt>4</dt><dd>sway bracing</dd>
<dt>5</dt><dd>lateral bracing</dd>
<dt>6</dt><dd>deck slab</dd>
<dt>100</dt><dd>damage cause estimation system</dd>
<dt>110</dt><dd>database</dd>
<dt>115</dt><dd>image acquisition unit</dd>
<dt>116</dt><dd>panoramic combination unit</dd>
<dt>117,222</dt><dd>antenna</dd>
<dt>120</dt><dd>actual size information acquisition unit</dd>
<dt>125</dt><dd>damage detection unit</dd>
<dt>130</dt><dd>similar damage extraction unit</dd>
<dt>135</dt><dd>damage cause presentation unit</dd>
<dt>140</dt><dd>information acquisition unit</dd>
<dt>145</dt><dd>display control unit</dd>
<dt>146</dt><dd>monitor display unit</dd>
<dt>150</dt><dd>output unit</dd>
<dt>200</dt><dd>digital camera</dd>
<dt>210</dt><dd>imaging optical system</dd>
<dt>220</dt><dd>wireless communication unit<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></dd>
<dt>300</dt><dd>damage cause estimation server</dd>
<dt>305</dt><dd>communication unit</dd>
<dt>306</dt><dd>reception unit</dd>
<dt>307</dt><dd>transmission unit</dd>
<dt>400</dt><dd>user terminal</dd>
</dl></p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> -->
<claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>A structure damage cause estimation system comprising:
<claim-text>a database that has data of a captured image of damage of a structure before repair and a damage cause of the structure;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an image acquisition unit that acquires a captured image of a target structure to be inspected;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an actual size information acquisition unit that acquires an actual size of a characteristic portion of the target structure in the captured image or an actual length of the target structure;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a damage detection unit that detects damage from the captured image acquired by the image acquisition unit, and calculates a degree of the damage, based on information acquired by the actual size information acquisition unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a similar damage extraction unit that determines a degree of similarity of the damage detected by the damage detection unit to damage of the structure in the database, and extracts one or more kinds of similar damage for which the degree of similarity is high; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a damage cause presentation unit that presents damage causes of the kinds of similar damage extracted by the similar damage extraction unit.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>The structure damage cause estimation system according to claim 1, wherein the database has damage information of the structure, the damage information including a type of the damage, a position of the damage, and the degree of the damage.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>The structure damage cause estimation system according to claim 2, further comprising:
<claim-text>an information acquisition unit that acquires at least one or more pieces of information of structure information, environment information, or history information of the target structure, wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>the database has at least one or more pieces of information of structure information, environment information, or history information of the structure, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the similar damage extraction unit determines the degree of similarity, based on the at least one or more pieces of information of the structure information, the environment information, or the history information acquired by the information acquisition unit in addition to the damage information.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>The structure damage cause estimation system according to any one of claims 1 to 3, wherein the damage cause presentation unit presents the damage causes of the kinds of similar damage and pieces of information on the kinds of similar damage in descending order of the degree of similarity.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>The structure damage cause estimation system according to any one of claims 1 to 3, wherein the damage cause presentation unit calculates occurrence frequencies of the respective damage causes of the kinds of similar damage extracted by the similar damage extraction unit and presents the damage causes and the occurrence frequencies.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>The structure damage cause estimation system according to any one of claims 1 to 5, wherein
<claim-text>the image acquisition unit acquires a group of images obtained by capturing images of segments of the target structure, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the image acquisition unit has a panoramic combination unit that performs panoramic combination processing on the group of images.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>The structure damage cause estimation system according to any one of claims 1 to 6, wherein
<claim-text>the database has at least one of captured images or pieces of damage information of the damage of the structure at a plurality of past time points,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the image acquisition unit acquires chronological images of the target structure, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the similar damage extraction unit uses a chronological change in a position of the damage or the degree of the damage obtained from the captured images or the pieces of damage information of the damage of the structure at the plurality of past time points to determine the degree of similarity.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>The structure damage cause estimation system according to any one of claims 1 to 7, wherein the similar damage extraction unit weights each piece of information.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>A structure damage cause estimation method comprising:
<claim-text>an image acquisition step of, with an image acquisition unit, acquiring a captured image of a target structure to be inspected;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an actual size information acquisition step of, with an actual size information<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> acquisition unit, acquiring an actual size of a characteristic portion of the target structure in the captured image or an actual length of the target structure;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a damage detection step of, with a damage detection unit, detecting damage from the captured image acquired in the image acquisition step, and calculating a degree of the damage, based on information acquired in the actual size information acquisition step;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a similar damage extraction step of, with a similar damage extraction unit, by using a database having data of a captured image of damage of a structure before the repair and a damage cause of the structure, determining a degree of similarity of the damage detected in the damage detection step to damage of the structure in the database, and extracting one or more kinds of similar damage for which the degree of similarity is high; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a damage cause presentation step of, with a damage cause presentation unit, presenting damage causes of the kinds of similar damage extracted in the similar damage extraction step.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>A structure damage cause estimation server that is connected to a user terminal via a network and estimates a damage cause of a target structure to be inspected, the structure damage cause estimation server comprising:
<claim-text>a database that has data of a captured image of damage of a structure before repair and a damage cause of the structure;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an image acquisition unit that acquires a captured image of a target structure to be inspected;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an actual size information acquisition unit that acquires an actual size of a characteristic portion of the target structure in the captured image or an actual length of the target structure;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a damage detection unit that detects damage from the captured image acquired by the image acquisition unit, and calculates a degree of the damage, based on information acquired by the actual size information acquisition unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a similar damage extraction unit that determines a degree of similarity of the damage detected by the damage detection unit to damage of the structure in the database, and extracts one or more kinds of similar damage for which the degree of similarity is high;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a damage cause presentation unit that presents damage causes of the kinds of similar damage extracted by the similar damage extraction unit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a communication unit having a reception unit that receives the captured image from the user terminal via the network, and a transmission unit that transmits the damage causes presented by the damage cause presentation unit to the user terminal.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="161" he="131" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="131" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> -->
<figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="141" he="131" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> -->
<figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="137" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> -->
<figure id="f0005" num="5"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="83" he="135" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> -->
<figure id="f0006" num="6"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="145" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<search-report-data id="srep" lang="en" srep-office="EP" date-produced=""><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="165" he="225" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="165" he="227" type="tif"/></search-report-data>
<ep-reference-list id="ref-list">
<heading id="ref-h0001"><b>REFERENCES CITED IN THE DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0001" num=""><i>This list of references cited by the applicant is for the reader's convenience only. It does not form part of the European patent document. Even though great care has been taken in compiling the references, errors or omissions cannot be excluded and the EPO disclaims all liability in this regard.</i></p>
<heading id="ref-h0002"><b>Patent documents cited in the description</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0002" num="">
<ul id="ref-ul0001" list-style="bullet">
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0001" dnum="JP2015095143A"><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2015095143</doc-number><kind>A</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0001">[0004]</crossref><crossref idref="pcit0002">[0005]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0002" dnum="JP4006007B"><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>4006007</doc-number><kind>B</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0003">[0034]</crossref></li>
</ul></p>
</ep-reference-list>
</ep-patent-document>
