<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP15803123B1" file="EP15803123NWB1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3200376" kind="B1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSK..HRIS..MTNORS..SM..................</B001EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  2100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3200376</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT SPECIFICATION</B121></B120><B130>B1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>15803123.7</B210><B220><date>20150403</date></B220><B240><B241><date>20170323</date></B241></B240><B250>zh</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B300><B310>201410495662</B310><B320><date>20140924</date></B320><B330><ctry>CN</ctry></B330></B300><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20170802</date><bnum>201731</bnum></B430><B450><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B450><B452EP><date>20210528</date></B452EP></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>H04L   1/16        20060101AFI20171222BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="2"><text>H04L   1/18        20060101ALI20171222BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="3"><text>H04L   5/00        20060101ALI20171222BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="4"><text>H04L   1/00        20060101ALI20171222BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>H04L   1/1607      20130101 LI20171221BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>H04L   1/1621      20130101 LI20171020BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="3"><text>H04L   1/0026      20130101 LI20171221BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="4"><text>H04L   1/1692      20130101 LI20180514BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="5"><text>H04L   1/0057      20130101 LA20180514BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="6"><text>H04L   1/0081      20130101 LI20170810BHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>FEEDBACKVERFAHREN UND -VORRICHTUNG</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>FEEDBACK METHOD AND DEVICE</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>PROCÉDÉ ET DISPOSITIF DE RÉTROACTION</B542></B540><B560><B561><text>EP-A1- 2 413 627</text></B561><B561><text>EP-A1- 2 663 007</text></B561><B561><text>CN-A- 1 983 913</text></B561><B561><text>CN-A- 103 312 719</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2003 123 409</text></B561><B561><text>US-A1- 2013 195 055</text></B561><B562><text>MOTOROLA: "Number of HARQ Channels", 3GPP DRAFT; R1-062597 #HARQ CHANNELS, 3RD GENERATION PARTNERSHIP PROJECT (3GPP), MOBILE COMPETENCE CENTRE ; 650, ROUTE DES LUCIOLES ; F-06921 SOPHIA-ANTIPOLIS CEDEX ; FRANCE, vol. RAN WG1, no. Seoul, Korea; 20061009 - 20061013, 4 October 2006 (2006-10-04), XP050596158, [retrieved on 2006-10-04]</text></B562><B565EP><date>20180105</date></B565EP></B560></B500><B600><B620EP><parent><cdoc><dnum><anum>21193451.8</anum></dnum><date>20210827</date></cdoc></parent></B620EP></B600><B700><B720><B721><snm>XU, Jin</snm><adr><str>c/o ZTE CORPORATION
ZTE Plaza
Keji Road South
Hi-Tech Industrial Park
Nanshan</str><city>Shenzhen
Guangdong 518057</city><ctry>CN</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>XU, Jun</snm><adr><str>c/o ZTE CORPORATION
ZTE Plaza
Keji Road South
Hi-Tech Industrial Park
Nanshan</str><city>Shenzhen
Guangdong 518057</city><ctry>CN</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>DAI, Bo</snm><adr><str>c/o ZTE CORPORATION
ZTE Plaza
Keji Road South
Hi-Tech Industrial Park
Nanshan</str><city>Shenzhen
Guangdong 518057</city><ctry>CN</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B730><B731><snm>ZTE Corporation</snm><iid>101332789</iid><irf>BNT222437EPPC</irf><adr><str>ZTE Plaza, Keji Road South 
Hi-Tech Industrial Park 
Nanshan</str><city>Shenzhen, Guangdong 518057</city><ctry>CN</ctry></adr></B731></B730><B740><B741><snm>Novagraaf Technologies</snm><iid>100061566</iid><adr><str>Bâtiment O2 
2, rue Sarah Bernhardt 
CS90017</str><city>92665 Asnières-sur-Seine Cedex</city><ctry>FR</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840><B860><B861><dnum><anum>CN2015075891</anum></dnum><date>20150403</date></B861><B862>zh</B862></B860><B870><B871><dnum><pnum>WO2015184919</pnum></dnum><date>20151210</date><bnum>201549</bnum></B871></B870></B800></SDOBI>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<heading id="h0001"><b><u>Technical Field</u></b></heading>
<p id="p0001" num="0001">The disclosure relates to the technical field of information feedback, and in particular to a feedback method and device.</p>
<heading id="h0002"><b><u>Background</u></b></heading>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">In a Long-Term Evolution (LTE) system in the related art, a physical-layer data shared channel performs data transmission by taking a Transmission Block (TB) as a basic element. A receiver determines whether or not a current TB is correctly received through a Cyclic Redundancy Check (CRC) of the TB. When the TB is correctly received, the receiver feeds back an Acknowledgement (ACK) message to a sender. When the TB is not correctly received, the receiver feeds back a Negative Acknowledgement (NACK) message to the sender. The sender retransmits data to the receiver after receiving the NACK message, and retransmission is still performed by taking the TB as the element.</p>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">When a size of the TB exceeds a specified threshold, the sender is usually required to perform Code Block (CB) segmentation to segment the TB into multiple CBs, and operations of coding, rate matching, CB concatenation and the like are respectively performed on each CB for sending to the receiver.</p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">A CRC is added to each CB before coding, and in addition, each TB also has another CRC. In the LTE system, lengths of the two CRCs are both 24bit. A CB CRC is used for premature termination of decoding and the CB CRC may also check correctness of a CB. When the CB CRC succeeds in checking, it is indicated that the CB is a correct CB, and when the CB CRC fails in checking, it is indicated that the CB is an incorrect CB.</p>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">The TB CRC is used for correctness checking of a received TB. When the TB CRC fails in checking at the receiver, it is indicated that the TB is incorrectly received, and the TB is required to be retransmitted. When a TB includes a relatively larger number of CBs, relatively more resources are occupied by retransmission. For example, as shown in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, a TB includes 8 CBs, and only CB2 and CB5 are incorrectly decoded during first transmission. However, during retransmission, the other CBs without errors are also required to be retransmitted. This is because an ACK or NACK of the LTE system in the related art is fed back on a basis of a TB, there is no CB-based A or N feedback and CB-based feedback may cause extremely high uplink A or N feedback overhead.</p>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">Packet coding is a technology for coding between data packets, i.e. a process of<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> coding multiple source data packets to generate check data packets. As shown in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 2</figref>, a process of generating a check sequence at a position in a check data packet from an information sequence at a position in a source data packet corresponding to the position in the check data packet is packet coding. Each check data packet includes data at a corresponding position in each check sequence. There may be various packet coding methods. For example, check data packets may be generated in a manner of performing an exclusive OR operation on each source data packet, the check data packets may also be generated in a Reed-Solomon coding manner, and the check data packets may further be generated in a fountain code or network coding manner.</p>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">In a digital mobile communication system, a coding bit sequence obtained by rate matching is required to be modulated into a digital baseband signal for transmission. In the LTE system, common modulation constellation diagrams include Binary Phase Shift Keying (BPSK), Quadrature Phase Shift Keying (QPSK), 16 Quadrature Amplitude Modulation (16QAM), 64 Quadrature Amplitude Modulation (64QAM) and the like. All of these modulation constellation diagrams include some limited discrete constellation points used for representing amplitudes and phases of digital baseband signals, and geographical distances between the constellation points are called as Euclidean distances. When the Euclidean distances between adjacent constellation points are equal and each constellation point is uniformly distributed in a constellation diagram, the modulation constellation diagram is called as a uniform constellation diagram. For example, the modulation constellation diagrams such as QPSK, 16QAM and 64QAM adopted in the LTE system are all uniform constellation diagrams. On the contrary, when Euclidean distances between adjacent constellation points are unequal or each constellation point is nonuniformly distributed in a constellation diagram, the constellation diagram is called as a nonuniform constellation diagram.</p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">Documents D1(<patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="EP24136274A1"><text>EP 2413627 4 A1</text></patcit>), D2(3GPP DRAFT R1-062597), D3(<patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="US2013195055A1"><text>US 2013/195055 A1</text></patcit>) and D4 (<patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="EP2663007A1"><text>EP 2663007 A1</text></patcit>) provide related technical solutions; however, the above mentioned problem still remains unsolved.</p>
<heading id="h0003"><b><u>Summary</u></b></heading>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">The embodiments of the disclosure are intended to solve a technical problem of how to effectively reduce a retransmitted data volume and improve data retransmission efficiency during CB-based transmission.</p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">To this end, the technical solutions are implemented according to the feedback method of independent claim 1 and the corresponding apparatus claimed in independent claim 3.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p>
<heading id="h0004"><b><u>Brief Description of the Drawings</u></b></heading>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li><figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is a schematic diagram of a receiving condition of each CB in a TB;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0001">Fig. 2</figref> is a schematic diagram of packet coding;<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></li>
<li><figref idref="f0001">Fig. 3</figref> is a flowchart of a method according to a first example embodiment;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">Fig. 4</figref> is a schematic diagram of CB set division according to a first example;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">Fig. 5</figref> is a schematic diagram of packet coding of CB sets according to a first example;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">Fig. 6</figref> is a schematic diagram of CB error patterns of CB sets according to a third example;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">Fig. 7</figref> is a schematic diagram of CB error patterns of CB sets according to a fourth example;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">Fig. 8</figref> is a schematic diagram of a CB error pattern of a TB according to a fifth example;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">Fig. 9</figref> is a schematic diagram of CB error patterns of CB sets (when P=2) according to a fifth example;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">Fig. 10</figref> is a schematic diagram of CB error patterns of CB sets (when P=2) according to a fifth example;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">Fig. 11</figref> is a diagram of a nonuniform modulation constellation for ACK, NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub> according to a seventh example;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0004">Fig. 12</figref> is a schematic block diagram of a first example according to a second example embodiment; and</li>
<li><figref idref="f0004">Fig. 13</figref> is a schematic block diagram of a tenth example according to a second example embodiment.</li>
</ul></p>
<heading id="h0005"><b><u>Detailed Description</u></b></heading>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">The technical solutions of the disclosure will be described below with reference to the drawings and embodiments in more detail.</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">It is important to note that embodiments of the disclosure and each characteristic in the embodiments may be combined without conflicts, and these combinations all fall within the scope of protection of the disclosure. I n addition, although logical sequences are shown in the flowcharts, the shown or described steps may be executed in sequences different from the sequences shown here under some conditions.</p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">A feedback method is applied to a first transmission node, and the method includes that:
<ul id="ul0002" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>the first transmission node receives a signal including a TB from a second transmission node, in which the TB includes K CBs and the K CBs are divided into P CB sets, K and P are positive integers, K≥3 and 2≤P≤K;<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></li>
<li>the first transmission node obtains states of the P CB sets according to the signal including the TB; and</li>
<li>the first transmission node determines at least one kind of feedback information in a preset feedback information set according to the states of the P CB sets, and sends the determined feedback information to the second transmission node, in which the feedback information set at least includes: correctness indication information (ACK) and n kinds of incorrectness indication information (NACK<sub>1</sub>, NACK<sub>2</sub>, ..., NACK<sub>n</sub>), in which n is an integer more than or equal to 1.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">Alternatively, the first transmission node may be, but not limited to: any network element with data receiving and signaling sending functions such as a terminal, an evolved Node B and a relay.</p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">Alternatively, the second transmission node may be, but not limited to: any network element with a signaling receiving function such as a terminal, an evolved Node B and a relay.</p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">Alternatively, each CB set in the P CB sets includes at least one CB in the TB.</p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">Alternatively, each CB set in the P CB sets may be determined according to at least one preset CB set division manner and a number P of CB sets.</p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">Furthermore, the preset CB set division manner at least includes a continuous division manner or a discontinuous division manner.</p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">Furthermore, the continuous division manner refers to that at least two CBs at adjacent positions in the TB are divided into the same CB set.</p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">Furthermore, the discontinuous division manner refers to that CBs at any two adjacent positions in the TB may not be divided into the same CB set in the P CB sets.</p>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">Alternatively, the number P of the CB sets may be configured by the evolved Node B.</p>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">Furthermore, the number P of the CB sets is one of m preset positive integers, and is determined by the first transmission node and sent from the first transmission node to the second transmission node, and m≥1.</p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">Alternatively, the number P of the CB sets may be autonomously determined by the first transmission node and sent from the first transmission node to the second transmission node.</p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">Alternatively, the number P of the CB sets may also be determined according to a size of the TB.</p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">Furthermore, specifically, the size of the TB is divided into multiple value intervals according to a sequence from small to large, and each value interval corresponds to the<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> number P of the CB sets; and the number of the CB sets is determined according to a value interval of the size of the TB.</p>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">Alternatively, a number of CBs in each CB set may be determined according to the following method:
<ul id="ul0003" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>when K may be exactly divided by P, each CB set includes K/P CBs; and</li>
<li>when K may not be exactly divided by P, each CB set in <i>P</i><sub>1</sub> <i>= K</i> - <i>P</i> . [<i>K</i>/<i>P</i>] CB sets includes [<i>K</i>/<i>P</i>] CBs, and each CB set in <i>P<sub>2</sub></i> = <i>P</i> · [<i>K</i>/<i>P</i>] ― K CB sets includes [<i>K</i>/<i>P</i>] original CBs and a filling CB, in which operators [<i>x</i>] and [<i>x</i>] respectively represent a rounding-up or rounding-down operation over x, and P<sub>1</sub>+P<sub>2</sub>=P</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">Furthermore, a filling CB may be formed by any preset data, including, but not limited to: a CB formed by an all-1 bit sequence or an all-0 bit sequence, or any CB in the CB set.</p>
<p id="p0029" num="0029">Alternatively, the step that the first transmission node obtains the states of the P CB sets according to the signal including the TB includes that:<br/>
the first transmission node determines the states of the P CB sets according to at least one of the following parameters:<br/>
a number of incorrect (or correct) CB sets in the P CB sets, an incorrectness rate (or correctness rate) of the CB sets, CB error patterns of the incorrect CB sets in the P CB sets and a CB error pattern of the TB.</p>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">Furthermore, the correct CB sets refer to that each of the CB sets includes correct CBs.</p>
<p id="p0031" num="0031">Furthermore, the incorrect CB sets refer to that each of the CB sets includes at least one incorrect CB.</p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032">Furthermore, the incorrectness rate (or correctness rate) of the CB sets refers to dividing the number of the incorrect (or correct) CB sets in the P CB sets by P.</p>
<p id="p0033" num="0033">Furthermore, the CB error patterns of the incorrect CB sets refer to positions (indexes) of incorrect (or correct) CBs in the incorrect CB sets.</p>
<p id="p0034" num="0034">Furthermore, the CB error pattern of the TB refers to positions (indexes) of incorrect (or correct) CBs in the TB.</p>
<p id="p0035" num="0035">Alternatively, when the feedback information set includes correctness indication information ACK and one kind of incorrectness indication information NACK, the correctness indication information ACK is used for indicating that the first transmission node correctly receives the TB.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">Alternatively, when the feedback information set includes the correctness indication information ACK and the unique incorrectness indication information NACK, the unique incorrectness indication information NACK is used for indicating that the first transmission node does not correctly receive the TB.</p>
<p id="p0037" num="0037">Alternatively, when the feedback information set includes the correctness indication information ACK and the one kind of the incorrectness indication information NACK, the ACK is represented by a bit "0" and the NACK is represented by a bit "1"; or, the ACK is represented by the bit "1" and the "NACK" is represented by the bit "0".</p>
<p id="p0038" num="0038">Alternatively, when the feedback information set at least includes the correctness indication information ACK and two kinds of incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub>, the correctness indication information ACK is used for indicating that the first transmission node correctly receives the TB.</p>
<p id="p0039" num="0039">Alternatively, when the feedback information set at least includes the correctness indication information ACK and the two kinds of incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub>, the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> is used for indicating that retransmitted data at least includes part of data obtained by packet coding on M CB sets in the P CB sets, in which M is a positive integer and 2≤M≤P.</p>
<p id="p0040" num="0040">Furthermore, that the retransmitted data at least includes part of data obtained by packet coding on the M CB sets in the P CB sets refers to that:
<ul id="ul0004" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>the second transmission node performs packet coding on the M CB sets in the P CB sets to obtain S check CB sets, in which a length of each check CB set in the S check CB sets is T bits, M, S and T are all positive integers and 2≤M≤P; and</li>
<li>the retransmitted data at least includes Q bits in each check CB set, in which Q is a positive integer and 1≤Q≤T.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0041" num="0041">Furthermore, packet coding refers to that bits or symbols at the same index position of each CB set in the M CB sets are coded to generate the S check CB sets.</p>
<p id="p0042" num="0042">Furthermore, a coding operation may be, but not limited to, one of the following manners: bit exclusive or (or called as modular two addition) coding, Reed-Solomon coding, Bose, Ray-Chaudhuri and Hocquenghem (BCH) coding, linear coding such as digital fountain coding, symbol superimposition coding, network coding and the like.</p>
<p id="p0043" num="0043">Alternatively, when the feedback information set at least includes the correctness indication information ACK and the two kinds of incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub>, the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>2</sub> is used for<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> indicating that the retransmitted data should at least include part of data of the TB.</p>
<p id="p0044" num="0044">Alternatively, when the feedback information set at least includes the incorrectness indication information ACK and the two kinds of incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub>, the ACK, the NACK<sub>1</sub> and the NACK<sub>2</sub> are respectively represented by any two bits.</p>
<p id="p0045" num="0045">Alternatively, when the feedback information set at least includes the incorrectness indication information ACK and the two kinds of incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub>, the ACK, the NACK<sub>1</sub> and the NACK<sub>2</sub> are modulated by adopting a nonuniform constellation diagram. That is, on the modulation constellation diagram, a Euclidean distance between the ACK and the NACK<sub>1</sub> is longer than a Euclidean distance between the ACK<sub>1</sub> and the NACK<sub>2</sub>, and a Euclidean distance between the ACK and the NACK<sub>2</sub> is also longer than the Euclidean distance between the ACK<sub>1</sub> and the NACK<sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p0046" num="0046">Alternatively, the feedback information set further includes the number P of the CB sets.</p>
<p id="p0047" num="0047">Furthermore, the number P of the CB sets meets one of the following conditions: after the K CBs are divided into the P CB sets, a maximum of a number of incorrect CBs at the same index positions does not exceed a first preset threshold value G, in which G is a positive integer and 1≤G≤P;<br/>
or, the number P of the CB sets meets that: after the K CBs are divided into the P sets, the maximum of the number of the incorrect CBs at the same index positions is minimum in division solutions when P adopts different values. For example, when P is 2, after division, the maximum of the number of the incorrect CBs at the same index positions is x2; when P is 3, after division, the maximum of the number of the incorrect CBs at the same index positions is x3; when P is 4, after division, the maximum of the number of the incorrect CBs at the same index positions is x4; and if x3 is minimum, P is determined to be 3.</p>
<p id="p0048" num="0048">Furthermore, when multiple values of the number P of the CB sets meet one of the conditions, the number P of the CB sets in the feedback information set is a maximum value in the values meeting the condition.</p>
<p id="p0049" num="0049">Alternatively, the feedback information set further includes at least one CB set division manner.</p>
<p id="p0050" num="0050">Alternatively, the feedback information set further includes the number Z of the correct or incorrect CB sets, in which Z is a positive integer and 1≤Z≤P.<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></p>
<p id="p0051" num="0051">Alternatively, the feedback information set further includes the CB error patterns of the incorrect CB sets, or the CB error pattern of the TB.</p>
<p id="p0052" num="0052">Alternatively, the step that the first transmission node determines the at least one kind of feedback information in the preset feedback information set according to the states of the P CB sets includes that:
<ul id="ul0005" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>when the P CB sets are all correct CB sets, the first transmission node determines the correctness indication information ACK in the preset feedback information set as the feedback information (that is, the correctness indication information Ack is sent to the second transmission node);</li>
<li>furthermore, that the P CB sets are all correct CB sets is equal to one of the following conditions: the TB is a correct TB, or the K CBs are all correct CBs; and</li>
<li>when at least one CB set in the P CB sets is an incorrect CB set and the feedback information set includes one kind of incorrectness indication information NACK, the first transmission node determines the incorrectness indication information NACK in the preset feedback information set as the feedback information (that is, the incorrectness indication information NACK in the feedback information set is sent to the second transmission node).</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0053" num="0053">Of course, the other information in the preset feedback information set may further be determined as the feedback information together.</p>
<p id="p0054" num="0054">Alternatively, the step that the first transmission node determines the at least one kind of feedback information in the preset feedback information set according to the state of the P CB sets includes that: when the feedback information set at least includes the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub>, the first transmission node determines the incorrectness indication information in the preset feedback information set as the feedback information (namely: sent to the second transmission node) according to the number of the incorrect (or correct) CB sets in the P CB sets or according to the incorrectness rate (or correctness rate) of the CB sets. Specifically:
<ul id="ul0006" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>when the number of the incorrect CB sets (or the incorrectness rate of the CB sets) does not exceed a second preset threshold value, or when the number of the correct CB sets (or the correctness rate of the CB sets) exceeds a third preset threshold value, the first transmission node determines the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> in the preset feedback information set as the feedback information (that is, the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> is sent to the second transmission node); and</li>
<li>when the number of the incorrect CB sets (or the incorrectness rate of the CB sets)<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> exceeds the second preset threshold value, or when the number of the correct CB sets (or the correctness rate of the CB sets) does not exceed the third preset threshold value, the first transmission node determines the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>2</sub> in the preset feedback information set as the feedback information (that is, the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>2</sub> is sent to the second transmission node).</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0055" num="0055">Of course, the other information in the preset feedback information set may further be determined as the feedback information together.</p>
<p id="p0056" num="0056">Alternatively, the step that the first transmission node determines the at least one kind of feedback information in the preset feedback information set according to the state of the P CB sets includes that: when the feedback information set at least includes the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub>, the first transmission node determines the incorrectness indication information in the preset feedback information set as the feedback information (namely: sent to the second transmission node) according to the CB error patterns of the incorrect CB sets. Specifically:
<ul id="ul0007" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>when a number of the incorrect CBs at the same index positions in the incorrect CB sets does not exceed a fourth preset threshold value, the first transmission node determines the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> in the preset feedback information set as the feedback information (that is, the first incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> is sent to the second transmission node); and</li>
<li>when the number of the incorrect CBs at the same index positions in the incorrect CB sets exceeds the fourth preset threshold value, the first transmission node determines the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>2</sub> in the preset feedback information set as the feedback information (that is, the second incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>2</sub> is sent to the second transmission node).</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0057" num="0057">Of course, the other information in the preset feedback information set may further be determined as the feedback information together.</p>
<p id="p0058" num="0058">A feedback device is arranged in a first transmission node, and includes:
<ul id="ul0008" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>a receiving component, arranged to receive a signal including a TB from a second transmission node, wherein the TB includes K CBs and the K CBs are divided into P CB sets, wherein K and P are positive integers, K≥3 and 2≤P≤K;</li>
<li>a state determination component, arranged to obtain states of the P CB sets according to the signal including the TB;</li>
<li>a feedback information determination component, arranged to determine at least one kind of feedback information in a preset feedback information set according to the state of<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> the P CB sets, in which the feedback information set at least includes correctness indication information (ACK) and n kinds of incorrectness indication information (NACK<sub>1</sub>, NACK<sub>2</sub>, ..., NACK<sub>n</sub>), n is an integer more than or equal to 1; and</li>
<li>a sending component, arranged to send the determined feedback information to the second transmission node.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0059" num="0059">Alternatively, the first transmission node may be, but not limited to: any network element with data receiving and signaling sending functions such as a terminal, an evolved Node B and a relay.</p>
<p id="p0060" num="0060">Alternatively, the second transmission node may be, but not limited to: any network element with a signaling receiving function such as a terminal, an evolved Node B and a relay.</p>
<p id="p0061" num="0061">Alternatively, each CB set in the P CB sets includes at least one CB in the TB.</p>
<p id="p0062" num="0062">Alternatively, each CB set in the P CB sets may be determined according to at least one preset CB set division manner and a number P of the CB sets.</p>
<p id="p0063" num="0063">Furthermore, the preset CB set division manner at least includes a continuous division manner or a discontinuous division manner.</p>
<p id="p0064" num="0064">Furthermore, the continuous division manner refers to that at least two CBs at adjacent positions in the TB are divided into the same CB set.</p>
<p id="p0065" num="0065">Furthermore, the discontinuous division manner refers to that CBs at any two adjacent positions in the TB may not be divided into the same CB set in the P CB sets.</p>
<p id="p0066" num="0066">Alternatively, the number P of the CB sets may be configured by the evolved Node B.</p>
<p id="p0067" num="0067">Furthermore, the number P of the CB sets may be one of m preset positive integers, and is sent to a terminal by the evolved Node B through signaling, and m≥1.</p>
<p id="p0068" num="0068">Alternatively, the number P of the CB sets may be autonomously determined by the first transmission node and sent from the first transmission node to the second transmission node.</p>
<p id="p0069" num="0069">Alternatively, the number P of the CB sets may also be determined according to a size of the TB.</p>
<p id="p0070" num="0070">Furthermore, specifically, the size of the TB is divided into multiple value intervals according to a sequence from small to large, and each value interval corresponds to a number P of the CB sets; and the number of the CB sets is determined according to a value interval of the size of the TB.</p>
<p id="p0071" num="0071">Alternatively, a number of CBs in each CB set may be determined according to the following method:<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> -->
<ul id="ul0009" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>when K may be exactly divided by P, each CB set includes K/P CBs; and</li>
<li>when K may not be exactly divided by P, each CB set in <i>P</i><sub>1</sub> <i>= K</i> - <i>P</i> · [<i>K</i>/<i>P</i>] CB sets includes [<i>K</i>/<i>P</i>] CBs, and each CB set in <i>P</i><sub>2</sub> = <i>P</i> · [<i>K</i>/<i>P</i>] - <i>K</i> CB sets includes [<i>K</i>/<i>P</i>] original CBs and a filling CB, in which operators [<i>x</i>] and [<i>x</i>] respectively represent a rounding-up or rounding-down operation over x, and P<sub>1</sub>+P<sub>2</sub>=P</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0072" num="0072">Furthermore, the filling CB may be formed by any preset data, including, but not limited to: a CB formed by an all-1 bit sequence or an all-0 bit sequence, or any CB in the CB set.</p>
<p id="p0073" num="0073">Alternatively, the device may further include a CB set division element, arranged to divide the K CBs of the TB into the P CB sets according to the CB set division manner and the number P of the CB sets.</p>
<p id="p0074" num="0074">Alternatively, the operation that the state determination component obtains the state of the P CB sets according to the signal including the TB refers to that:<br/>
the state determination component determines the states of the P CB sets according to at least one of the following parameters: a number of incorrect (or correct) CB sets in the P CB sets, an incorrectness rate (or correctness rate) of the CB sets, CB error patterns of the incorrect CB sets in the P CB sets and a CB error pattern of the TB.</p>
<p id="p0075" num="0075">Furthermore, the correct CB sets refer to that each of the CB sets includes correct CBs.</p>
<p id="p0076" num="0076">Furthermore, the incorrect CB sets refer to that each of the CB sets includes at least one incorrect CB.</p>
<p id="p0077" num="0077">Furthermore, the incorrectness rate (or correctness rate) of the CB sets refers to dividing the number of the incorrect (or correct) CB sets in the P CB sets by P.</p>
<p id="p0078" num="0078">Furthermore, the CB error patterns of the incorrect CB sets refer to positions (indexes) of incorrect (or correct) CBs in the incorrect CB sets.</p>
<p id="p0079" num="0079">Furthermore, the CB error pattern of the TB refers to positions (indexes) of incorrect (or correct) CBs in the TB.</p>
<p id="p0080" num="0080">Alternatively, when the feedback information set includes correctness indication information ACK and one kind of incorrectness indication information NACK, the correctness indication information ACK is used for indicating that the first transmission node correctly receives the TB.</p>
<p id="p0081" num="0081">Alternatively, when the feedback information set includes the correctness indication information ACK and the unique incorrectness indication information NACK, the unique<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> incorrectness indication information NACK is used for indicating that the first transmission node does not correctly receive the TB.</p>
<p id="p0082" num="0082">Alternatively, when the feedback information set includes the correctness indication information ACK and the unique incorrectness indication information NACK, the ACK is represented by a bit "0" and the NACK is represented by a bit "1"; or, the ACK is represented by the bit "1" and the "NACK" is represented by the bit "0".</p>
<p id="p0083" num="0083">Alternatively, when the feedback information set at least includes the correctness indication information ACK and two kinds of incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub>, the correctness indication information ACK is used for indicating that the first transmission node correctly receives the TB.</p>
<p id="p0084" num="0084">Alternatively, when the feedback information set at least includes the correctness indication information ACK and the two kinds of incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub>, the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> is used for indicating that retransmitted data at least includes part of data obtained by packet coding on M CB sets in the P CB sets, in which M is a positive integer and 2≤M≤P.</p>
<p id="p0085" num="0085">Furthermore, that the retransmitted data at least includes part of data obtained by packet coding between the M CB sets in the P CB sets refers to that:
<ul id="ul0010" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>the second transmission node performs packet coding on the M CB sets in the P CB sets to obtain S check CB sets, in which a length of each check CB set is T bits, M, S and T are all positive integers and 2≤M≤P; and</li>
<li>the retransmitted data at least includes Q bits in each check CB set, in which Q is a positive integer and 1≤Q≤T.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0086" num="0086">Furthermore, packet coding refers to that bits or symbols at the same index positions in the M CB sets are coded to generate the S check CB sets.</p>
<p id="p0087" num="0087">Furthermore, a coding operation may be, but not limited to, one of the following manners: bit exclusive or (or called as modular two additions) coding, Reed-Solomon coding, BCH coding, linear coding such as digital fountain coding, symbol superimposition coding, network coding and the like.</p>
<p id="p0088" num="0088">Alternatively, when the feedback information set at least includes the correctness indication information ACK and the two kinds of incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub>, the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>2</sub> is used for indicating that the retransmitted data should at least include part of data of the TB.</p>
<p id="p0089" num="0089">Alternatively, when the feedback information set at least includes the incorrectness<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> indication information ACK and the two kinds of incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub>, the ACK, the NACK<sub>1</sub> and the NACK<sub>2</sub> are respectively represented by any two bits.</p>
<p id="p0090" num="0090">Alternatively, when the feedback information set at least includes the incorrectness indication information ACK and the two kinds of incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub>, the ACK, the NACK<sub>1</sub> and the NACK<sub>2</sub> are modulated by adopting a nonuniform constellation diagram. That is, on the modulation constellation diagram, a Euclidean distance between the ACK and the NACK<sub>1</sub> is longer than a Euclidean distance between the ACK<sub>1</sub> and the NACK<sub>2</sub>, and a Euclidean distance between the ACK and the NACK<sub>2</sub> is also longer than the Euclidean distance between the ACK<sub>1</sub> and the NACK<sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p0091" num="0091">Alternatively, the feedback information set further includes the number P of the CB sets.</p>
<p id="p0092" num="0092">Furthermore, the number P of the CB sets meets one of the following conditions: after the K CBs are divided into the P CB sets, a maximum of a number of incorrect CBs at the same index positions does not exceed a first preset threshold value G, wherein G is a positive integer and 1≤G≤P;<br/>
or, the number P of the CB sets meets that: after the K CBs are divided into the P sets, the maximum of the number of the incorrect CBs at the same index positions is minimum in division solutions when P adopts different values. For example, when P is 2, after division, the maximum of the number of the incorrect CBs at the same index positions is x2; when P is 3, after division, the maximum of the number of the incorrect CBs at the same index positions is x3; when P is 4, after division, the maximum of the number of the incorrect CBs at the same index positions is x4; and when x3 is minimum, P is determined to be 3.</p>
<p id="p0093" num="0093">Furthermore, when multiple values of the number P of the CB sets meet one of the conditions, the number P of the CB sets in the feedback information set is a maximum value in the values meeting the condition.</p>
<p id="p0094" num="0094">Alternatively, the feedback information set further includes at least one CB set division manner.</p>
<p id="p0095" num="0095">Alternatively, the feedback information set further includes the number Z of the correct or incorrect CB sets, in which Z is a positive integer and 1≤Z≤P.</p>
<p id="p0096" num="0096">Alternatively, the feedback information set further includes the CB error patterns of the incorrect CB sets, or the CB error pattern of the TB.<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --></p>
<p id="p0097" num="0097">Alternatively, the operation that the feedback information determination component determines the at least one kind of feedback information in the preset feedback information set according to the state of the P CB sets refers to that:
<ul id="ul0011" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>when the P CB sets are all correct CB sets, the feedback information determination component determines the correctness indication information (ACK) in the preset feedback information set as the feedback information;</li>
<li>furthermore, that the P CB sets are all correct CB sets is equal to one of the following conditions: the TB is a correct TB, or the K CBs are all correct CBs; and</li>
<li>when at least one CB set in the P CB sets is an incorrect CB set and the feedback information set includes one kind of incorrectness indication information NACK, the incorrectness indication information NACK in the preset feedback information set is determined as the feedback information.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0098" num="0098">Of course, the other information in the preset feedback information set may further be determined as the feedback information together.</p>
<p id="p0099" num="0099">Alternatively, the operation that the feedback information determination component determines the at least one kind of feedback information in the preset feedback information set according to the state of the P CB sets refers to that:
<ul id="ul0012" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>when the feedback information set at least includes the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub>, the feedback information determination component determines the incorrectness indication information in the preset feedback information set as the feedback information according to the number of the incorrect (or correct) CB sets in the P CB sets or according to the incorrectness rate (or correctness rate) of the CB sets. Specifically:</li>
<li>when the number of the incorrect CB sets (or the incorrectness rate of the CB sets) does not exceed a second preset threshold value, or when the number of the correct CB sets (or the correctness rate of the CB sets) exceeds a third preset threshold value, the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> in the preset feedback information set is determined as the feedback information; and</li>
<li>when the number of the incorrect CB sets (or the incorrectness rate of the CB sets) exceeds the second preset threshold value, or when the number of the correct CB sets (or the correctness rate of the CB sets) does not exceed the third preset threshold value, the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>2</sub> in the preset feedback information set is determined as the feedback information.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0100" num="0100">Of course, the other information in the preset feedback information set may further be<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> determined as the feedback information together.</p>
<p id="p0101" num="0101">Alternatively, the operation that the feedback information determination component determines the at least one kind of feedback information in the preset feedback information set according to the state of the P CB sets refers to that:
<ul id="ul0013" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>when the feedback information set at least includes the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub>, the feedback information determination component determines the incorrectness indication information in the preset feedback information set as the feedback information according to the CB error patterns of the incorrect CB sets. Specifically:</li>
<li>when a number of the incorrect CBs at the same index positions in the incorrect CB sets does not exceed a fourth preset threshold value, the first incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> in the preset feedback information set is determined as the feedback information; and</li>
<li>when the number of the incorrect CBs at the same index positions in the incorrect CB sets exceeds the fourth preset threshold value, the second incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>2</sub> in the preset feedback information set is determined as the feedback information.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0102" num="0102">Of course, the other information in the preset feedback information set may further be determined as the feedback information together.</p>
<heading id="h0006">Embodiment 1 (method embodiment)</heading>
<p id="p0103" num="0103">The embodiment discloses a feedback method, which is applied to a first transmission node. As shown in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 3</figref>, the method includes the following steps.</p>
<p id="p0104" num="0104">Step 101: the first transmission node receives a signal including a TB from a second transmission node, in which the TB includes K CBs and the K CBs are divided into P CB sets, and K and P are positive integers, K≥3 and 2≤P≤K.</p>
<p id="p0105" num="0105">Step 102: the first transmission node obtains states of the P CB sets according to the signal including the TB.</p>
<p id="p0106" num="0106">Step 103: the first transmission node determines at least one kind of feedback information in a preset feedback information set according to the states of the P CB sets.</p>
<p id="p0107" num="0107">Step 104: the first transmission node sends the determined feedback information to the second transmission node, in which the feedback information set at least includes correctness indication information (ACK) and n kinds of incorrectness indication information (NACK<sub>1</sub>, NACK<sub>2</sub>, ..., NACK<sub>n</sub>), n is an integer more than or equal to 1.</p>
<p id="p0108" num="0108">Alternatively, the first transmission node may be, but not limited to: any network<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> element with data receiving and signaling sending functions such as a terminal, an evolved Node B and a relay.</p>
<p id="p0109" num="0109">Alternatively, the second transmission node may be, but not limited to: any network element with a signaling receiving function such as a terminal, an evolved Node B and a relay.</p>
<p id="p0110" num="0110">Alternatively, each CB set in the P CB sets includes at least one CB in the TB.</p>
<p id="p0111" num="0111">Alternatively, each CB set in the P CB sets may be determined according to at least one preset CB set division manner and a number P of the CB sets.</p>
<p id="p0112" num="0112">Furthermore, the preset CB set division manner at least includes a continuous division manner or a discontinuous division manner.</p>
<p id="p0113" num="0113">Furthermore, the continuous division manner refers to that at least two CBs at adjacent positions in the TB are divided into the same CB set.</p>
<p id="p0114" num="0114">Furthermore, the discontinuous division manner refers to that CBs at any two adjacent positions in the TB may not be divided into the same CB set in the P CB sets.</p>
<p id="p0115" num="0115">Alternatively, the number P of the CB sets may be configured by the evolved Node B.</p>
<p id="p0116" num="0116">Furthermore, the number P of the CB sets is one of m preset positive integers, and is determined by the first transmission node and sent from the first transmission node to the second transmission node, and m≥1.</p>
<p id="p0117" num="0117">Alternatively, the number P of the CB sets may be autonomously determined by the first transmission node and sent from the first transmission node to the second transmission node.</p>
<p id="p0118" num="0118">Alternatively, the number P of the CB sets may also be determined according to a size of the TB.</p>
<p id="p0119" num="0119">Furthermore, specifically, the size of the TB is divided into multiple value intervals according to a sequence from small to large, and each value interval corresponds to the number P of the CB sets; and the number of the CB sets is determined according to a value interval of the size of the TB.</p>
<p id="p0120" num="0120">Alternatively, a number of CBs in each CB set may be determined according to the following method:
<ul id="ul0014" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>when K may be exactly divided by P, each CB set includes K/P CBs; and</li>
<li>when K may not be exactly divided by P, each CB set in <i>P</i><sub>1</sub> <i>= K</i> - <i>P</i> · [<i>K</i>/<i>P</i>] CB sets includes [<i>K</i>/<i>P</i>] CBs, and each CB set in <i>P<sub>2</sub></i> = <i>P</i> · [<i>K</i>/<i>P</i>] - <i>K</i> CB sets includes [<i>K</i>/<i>P</i>] original CBs and a filling CB, in which operators [<i>x</i>] and [<i>x</i>] respectively<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> represent a rounding-up or rounding-down operation over x, and P<sub>1</sub>+P<sub>2</sub>=P.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0121" num="0121">Here, a filling CB may be formed by any preset bit sequence, including, but not limited to, one of the following manners:
<ul id="ul0015" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>a first manner: a CB formed by an all-1 bit sequence or an all-0 bit sequence; and</li>
<li>a second manner: a CB in the K original CBs.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0122" num="0122">Alternatively, the state of the P CB sets may be determined according to at least one of the following parameters: a number of incorrect (or correct) CB sets in the P CB sets, an incorrectness rate (or correctness rate) of the CB sets, CB error patterns of the incorrect CB sets in the P CB sets and a CB error pattern of the TB.</p>
<heading id="h0007">Furthermore, the correct CB sets refer to that each of CB sets includes correct CBs.</heading>
<p id="p0123" num="0123">Furthermore, the incorrect CB sets refer to that each of the CB sets includes at least one incorrect CB.</p>
<p id="p0124" num="0124">Furthermore, the incorrectness rate (or correctness rate) of the CB sets refers to dividing the number of the incorrect (or correct) CB sets in the P CB sets by P.</p>
<p id="p0125" num="0125">Furthermore, the CB error patterns of the incorrect CB sets refer to positions (indexes) of incorrect (or correct) CBs in the incorrect CB sets.</p>
<p id="p0126" num="0126">Furthermore, the CB error pattern of the TB refers to positions (indexes) of incorrect (or correct) CBs in the TB.</p>
<p id="p0127" num="0127">Alternatively, when the feedback information set includes correctness indication information ACK and one kind of incorrectness indication information NACK, the correctness indication information ACK is used for indicating that the first transmission node correctly receives the TB.</p>
<p id="p0128" num="0128">Alternatively, when the feedback information set includes the correctness indication information ACK and the unique incorrectness indication information NACK, the unique incorrectness indication information NACK is used for indicating that the first transmission node does not correctly receive the TB.</p>
<p id="p0129" num="0129">Alternatively, when the feedback information set includes the correctness indication information ACK and the one kind of the incorrectness indication information NACK, the ACK is represented by a bit "0" and the NACK is represented by a bit "1"; or, the ACK is represented by the bit "1" and the "NACK" is represented by the bit "0".</p>
<p id="p0130" num="0130">Alternatively, when the feedback information set at least includes the correctness indication information ACK and two kinds of incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub>, the correctness indication information ACK is used for indicating that the first transmission node correctly receives the TB.<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --></p>
<p id="p0131" num="0131">Alternatively, when the feedback information set at least includes the correctness indication information ACK and the two kinds of incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub>, the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> is used for indicating that retransmitted data at least includes part of data obtained by packet coding on M CB sets in the P CB sets, in which M is a positive integer and 2≤M≤P.</p>
<p id="p0132" num="0132">Furthermore, the second transmission node performs packet coding on the M CB sets in the P CB sets to obtain S check CB sets, in which a length of each check CB set in the S check CB sets is T bits, M, S and T are all positive integers and 2≤M≤P; and<br/>
furthermore, the retransmitted data at least includes Q bits in each check CB set, in which Q is a positive integer and 1≤Q≤T.</p>
<p id="p0133" num="0133">Furthermore, packet coding refers to that bits or symbols at the same index position of each CB set in the M CB sets are coded to generate the S check CB sets.</p>
<p id="p0134" num="0134">Furthermore, a coding operation may be, but not limited to, one of the following manners: bit exclusive or (or called as modular two additions) coding, Reed-Solomon coding, BCH coding, linear coding such as digital fountain coding, symbol superimposition coding, network coding and the like.</p>
<p id="p0135" num="0135">Alternatively, when the feedback information set at least includes the correctness indication information ACK and the two kinds of incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub>, the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>2</sub> is used for indicating that the retransmitted data should at least include part of data of the TB.</p>
<p id="p0136" num="0136">Alternatively, when the feedback information set at least includes the incorrectness indication information ACK and the two kinds of incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub>, the ACK, the NACK<sub>1</sub> and the NACK<sub>2</sub> are respectively represented by any two bits.</p>
<p id="p0137" num="0137">Alternatively, when the feedback information set at least includes the incorrectness indication information ACK and the two kinds of incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub>, the ACK, the NACK<sub>1</sub> and the NACK<sub>2</sub> are modulated by adopting a nonuniform constellation diagram. That is, on the modulation constellation diagram, a Euclidean distance between the ACK and the NACK<sub>1</sub> is longer than a Euclidean distance between the ACK<sub>1</sub> and the NACK<sub>2</sub>, and a Euclidean distance between the ACK and the NACK<sub>2</sub> is also longer than the Euclidean distance between the ACK<sub>1</sub> and the NACK<sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p0138" num="0138">Alternatively, the feedback information set further includes the number P of the CB sets.<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --></p>
<p id="p0139" num="0139">Furthermore, the number P of the CB sets meets one of the following conditions: after the K CBs are divided into the P CB sets, a maximum of a number of incorrect CBs at the same index positions does not exceed a first preset threshold value G, in which G is a positive integer and 1≤G≤P;<br/>
or, the number P of the CB sets meets that: after the K CBs are divided into the P sets, the maximum of the number of the incorrect CBs at the same index positions is minimum in division solutions when P adopts different values.</p>
<p id="p0140" num="0140">Furthermore, when multiple values of the number P of the CB sets meet one of the conditions, the number P of the CB sets in the feedback information set is a maximum value in the values meeting the condition.</p>
<p id="p0141" num="0141">Alternatively, the feedback information set further includes at least one CB set division manner.</p>
<p id="p0142" num="0142">Alternatively, the feedback information set further includes the number Z of the correct or incorrect CB sets, in which Z is a positive integer and 1≤Z≤P.</p>
<p id="p0143" num="0143">Alternatively, the feedback information set further includes the CB error patterns of the incorrect CB sets, or the CB error pattern of the TB.</p>
<heading id="h0008">Example 1</heading>
<p id="p0144" num="0144">In the example, the first transmission node is a terminal, and the second transmission node is an evolved Node B.</p>
<p id="p0145" num="0145">Step A1: the terminal receives a signal including a TB from the evolved Node B, in which the TB includes K=8 CBs and the 8 CBs are divided into P=2 CB sets. As shown in <figref idref="f0002">Fig. 4</figref>, the CB set 1 includes CBs CB1, CB2, CB3 and CB4, and the CB set 2 includes CBs CB5, CB6, CB7 and CB8. In this example, a continuous division manner is adopted for the CB sets, in which a number P=2 of the CB sets is configured by the evolved Node B, and the evolved Node B selects P=2 from a preset group of numerical values {2, 3, 4, 5}, and sends P=2 to the terminal through downlink signaling.</p>
<p id="p0146" num="0146">Step A2: the terminal determines at least one kind of feedback information in a feedback information set according to states of the 2 CB sets, and sends the feedback information to the evolved Node B, in which the feedback information set includes incorrectness indication information (ACK), incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p0147" num="0147">In the example, it is supposed that the CB set 1 is incorrectly received and the CB set 2 is correctly received, that is, at least one CB in the CB set 1 is incorrectly received while<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> all the CBs in the CB set 2 are correctly received.</p>
<p id="p0148" num="0148">In the example, the states of the CB sets is a number of correct or incorrect CB sets, or a function of an incorrectness rate of the CB sets, and at this moment, the number of the correct CB sets is not smaller than a preset threshold value 1, or the number of the incorrect CB sets is not larger than the preset threshold value 1, or a correctness rate of the CB sets is not lower than a preset threshold value 0.5, or the incorrectness rate of the CB sets is not higher than the preset threshold value 0.5. Under such a condition, the terminal may recovery incorrect CBs (or CB sets) with a relatively higher probability by virtue of data obtained by packet coding in retransmitted data sent by the evolved Node B. Therefore, the terminal determines to feed back the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> to the evolved Node B. The NACK<sub>1</sub> may be represented by two bits. The incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> is used for indicating that the retransmitted data sent to the terminal by the evolved Node B should include part of data obtained by packet coding of the CB set 1 and the CB set 2. As shown in <figref idref="f0002">Fig. 5</figref>, a CB set A is obtained by packet coding of the CB set 1 and the CB set 2. The information NACK<sub>1</sub> is used for indicating that the retransmitted data should include Q bits in the CB A.</p>
<heading id="h0009">Example 2</heading>
<p id="p0149" num="0149">A difference between this example and example 1 is that: in the example, the number P of the CB set is determined according to a size of the TB. In the example, the size of the TB belongs to a preset value interval, and a number, corresponding to the value interval, of the CB sets is P=2. At this moment, the number P of the CB sets is not required to be sent between the evolved Node B and the terminal through the signaling.</p>
<p id="p0150" num="0150">The other difference between this example and example 1 is that: both the CB set 1 and the CB set 2 are incorrectly received, and at this moment, the number of the correct CB sets is smaller than the preset threshold value 1, or the number of the incorrect CB sets is larger than the preset threshold value 1, or the correctness rate of the CB sets is lower than the preset threshold value 0.5, or the incorrectness rate of the CB sets is higher than the preset threshold value 0.5. Under such a condition, when the retransmitted data only includes the data obtained by packet coding, the terminal may recover the incorrect CBs (or CB sets) only with a relatively lower probability, and when the retransmitted data includes part of data of the TB, the probability of the terminal in recovery of the incorrect CBs (or CB sets) may be increased. Therefore, the terminal determines to feed back the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>2</sub> to the evolved Node B. The incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>2</sub> is used for indicating that the retransmitted data should at<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> least include part of data of the TB. That is, the retransmitted data should at least include Q bits in the CB set 1 or the CB set 2.</p>
<heading id="h0010">Example 3</heading>
<p id="p0151" num="0151">A difference between this example and example 2 is that: in the example, the receiving state of the CB sets is determined according to CB error patterns the incorrect CB sets. It is supposed that the CB error patterns of the CB 1 and the CB set 2 in the example are shown in <figref idref="f0002">Fig. 6</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0152" num="0152">Moreover, incorrectly received CBs in the CB set 1 and the CB set 2 are represented by shaded areas, the CB error pattern of the CB set 1 may be represented by a vector err1=[1,0,1,0], and the CB error pattern of the CB set 2 may be represented by a vector err2=[0,1,0,1], in which the elements 1 represent positions of the incorrect CBs in the CB sets. It can be seen that a number of the incorrect CBs at any same position in the CB set 1 and the CB set 2 does not exceed 1. Under such a condition, the terminal may recover the incorrect CBs (or CB sets) with a relatively higher probability by virtue of the data obtained by packet coding in the retransmitted data sent by the evolved Node B. Therefore, the terminal determines to feed back the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> to the second transmission node.</p>
<heading id="h0011">Example 4</heading>
<p id="p0153" num="0153">A difference between this example and example 3 is that: in the example, the CB error patterns of the CB set 1 and the CB set 2 are shown in <figref idref="f0002">Fig. 7</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0154" num="0154">Moreover, the incorrectly received CBs in the CB set 1 and the CB set 2 are represented by shaded areas, the CB error pattern of the CB set 1 may be represented by the vector err1=[1,0,1,0], and the CB error pattern of the CB set 2 may be represented by the vector err2=[1,0,0,1], in which the elements 1 represent the positions of the incorrect CBs in the CB sets. It can be seen that first CBs in the CB set 1 and the CB set 2 are both incorrectly received, that is, a number of the incorrect CBs at a position exceeds 1. Under such a condition, when the retransmitted data only includes the data obtained by packet coding, the terminal may recover the incorrect CBs (or CB sets) only with a relatively lower probability, and when the retransmitted data includes part of data of the TB, the probability of the terminal in recovery of the incorrect CBs (or CB sets) may be increased. Therefore, the terminal determines to feed back the second incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>2</sub> to the second transmission node. The second incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>2</sub> is used for indicating that the retransmitted data should at least include part of data of the TB. That is, the retransmitted data should at least include<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> Q bits in the CB set 1 or the CB set 2.</p>
<heading id="h0012">Example 5</heading>
<p id="p0155" num="0155">A difference between this example and example 3 and example 4 is that: in the example, the CB error patterns are different, and in the example, the feedback information set further includes the number P of the CB sets. In the example, the states of the CB sets are determined according to the CB error patterns of the incorrect CB sets, and it is supposed that a CB error pattern of the TB is shown in <figref idref="f0003">Fig. 8</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0156" num="0156">When the 8 CBs are divided into 2 CB sets, as shown in <figref idref="f0003">Fig. 9</figref>, the CB error patterns of the CB sets may be represented by err1=[0,0,1,0] and err2=[1,0,1,0] respectively. At this moment, third CBs in the CB set 1 and the CB set 2 are both incorrect CBs, that is, the number of the incorrect CBs at the same index position exceeds the threshold value 1.</p>
<p id="p0157" num="0157">When the 8 CBs are divided into 3 CB sets, because the number of the CBs may not be exactly divided by the number of the CB sets, it is necessary to add a filling CB into the CB set 3 according to the CB set division manner of the example, and as shown in <figref idref="f0003">Fig. 10</figref>, the CB 9 is the filling CB.</p>
<p id="p0158" num="0158">CB error patterns of the CB sets may be respectively represented by err1=[0,0,1], err2=[0,1,0] and err3=[1,0,0]. It can be seen that the number of incorrect CBs at any same position in the CB set 1, the CB set 2 and the CB set 3 does not exceed 1.</p>
<p id="p0159" num="0159">At this moment, the information fed back to the evolved Node B by the terminal includes the number P=3 of the CB sets.</p>
<heading id="h0013">Example 6</heading>
<p id="p0160" num="0160">A difference between this example and example 3 and example 4 is that: in the example, the states of the CB sets are determined according to the CB error pattern of the TB, and the feedback information set further includes the CB error pattern of the TB.</p>
<p id="p0161" num="0161">In the example, the CB error pattern of the TB may be represented by err=[0,0,1,0,1,0,1,0],</p>
<p id="p0162" num="0162">At this moment, the information fed back to the evolved Node B by the terminal includes the CB error pattern of the TB.</p>
<heading id="h0014">Example 7</heading>
<p id="p0163" num="0163">A difference between this example and example 1 to example 6 is that the feedback information sent to the evolved Node B by the terminal is modulated by adopting a nonuniform constellation diagram. That is, on the modulation constellation diagram, a Euclidean distance between the ACK and the NACK<sub>1</sub> is longer than a Euclidean distance between the NACK<sub>1</sub> and the NACK<sub>2</sub>, and a Euclidean distance between the ACK and the<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> NACK<sub>2</sub> is also longer than the Euclidean distance between the NACK<sub>1</sub> and the NACK<sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p0164" num="0164">Specifically, the ACK, the NACK<sub>1</sub> and the NACK<sub>2</sub> sent to the evolved Node B by the terminal are modulated by a constellation diagram shown in <figref idref="f0003">Fig. 11</figref>.</p>
<heading id="h0015">Example 8</heading>
<p id="p0165" num="0165">A difference between this example and example 1 to example 7 is that the feedback information set in the example includes the incorrectness indication information ACK and incorrectness indication information NACK. At this moment, the feedback information sent to the evolved Node B by the terminal includes the NACK, and the NACK is used for indicating that the terminal does not correctly receive the TB.</p>
<heading id="h0016">Example 9</heading>
<p id="p0166" num="0166">A difference between this example and the example 5 is that: in the example, the feedback information set further includes the CB set division manner. In the CB sets, the continuous division manner is indicated by a bit "0", and the discontinuous division manner is indicated by a bit "1".</p>
<p id="p0167" num="0167">In the embodiment, the CB set division manner is determined according to the terminal, so that the information fed back to the evolved Node B by the terminal further includes the CB set indication manner indicated by the bit "0".</p>
<heading id="h0017">Embodiment 2 (device embodiment)</heading>
<p id="p0168" num="0168">The embodiment discloses a feedback device, which is applied to a first transmission node and includes:
<ul id="ul0016" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>a receiving component, arranged to receive a signal including a TB from a second transmission node, wherein the TB includes K CBs and the K CBs are divided into P CB sets, wherein K and P are positive integers, K≥3 and 2≤P≤K;</li>
<li>a state determination component, arranged to obtain states of the P CB sets according to the signal including the TB;</li>
<li>a feedback information determination component, arranged to determine at least one kind of feedback information in a preset feedback information set according to the state of the P CB sets, in which the feedback information set at least includes correctness indication information (ACK) and n kinds of incorrectness indication information (NACK<sub>1</sub>, NACK<sub>2</sub>, ..., NACK<sub>n</sub>), n is an integer more than or equal to 1; and</li>
<li>a sending component, arranged to send the determined feedback information to the second transmission node.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0169" num="0169">Alternatively, the first transmission node may be, but not limited to: any network element with data receiving and signaling sending functions such as a terminal, an evolved<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> Node B and a relay.</p>
<p id="p0170" num="0170">Alternatively, the second transmission node may be, but not limited to: any network element with a signaling receiving function such as a terminal, an evolved Node B and a relay.</p>
<p id="p0171" num="0171">Alternatively, each CB set in the P CB sets includes at least one CB in the TB.</p>
<p id="p0172" num="0172">Alternatively, each CB set in the P CB sets may be determined according to at least one preset CB set division manner and a number P of the CB sets.</p>
<p id="p0173" num="0173">Furthermore, the preset CB set division manner at least includes a continuous division manner or a discontinuous division manner.</p>
<p id="p0174" num="0174">Furthermore, the continuous division manner refers to that at least two CBs at adjacent positions in the TB are divided into the same CB set.</p>
<p id="p0175" num="0175">Furthermore, the discontinuous division manner refers to that CBs at any two adjacent positions in the TB may not be divided into the same CB set in the P CB sets.</p>
<p id="p0176" num="0176">Alternatively, the number P of the CB sets may be configured by the evolved Node B.</p>
<p id="p0177" num="0177">Furthermore, the number P of the CB sets may be one of m preset positive integers, and is sent to a terminal by the evolved Node B through signaling, and m≥1.</p>
<p id="p0178" num="0178">Alternatively, the number P of the CB sets may be autonomously determined by the first transmission node and sent from the first transmission node to the second transmission node.</p>
<p id="p0179" num="0179">Alternatively, the number P of the CB sets may also be determined according to a size of the TB.</p>
<p id="p0180" num="0180">Furthermore, specifically, the size of the TB is divided into multiple value intervals according to a sequence from small to large, and each value interval corresponds to a number P of the CB sets; and the number of the CB sets is determined according to a value interval of the size of the TB.</p>
<p id="p0181" num="0181">Alternatively, a number of CBs in each CB set may be determined according to the following method:
<ul id="ul0017" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>when K may be exactly divided by P, each CB set includes K/P CBs; and</li>
<li>when K may not be exactly divided by P, each CB set in <i>P</i><sub>1</sub> <i>= K</i> - <i>P</i> · [<i>K</i>/<i>P</i>] CB sets includes [<i>K</i>/<i>P</i>] CBs, and each CB set in <i>P<sub>2</sub></i> = <i>P</i> · [<i>K</i>/<i>P</i>] - <i>K</i> CB sets includes [<i>K</i>/<i>P</i>] original CBs and a filling CB, in which operators [<i>x</i>] and [<i>x</i>] respectively represent a rounding-up or rounding-down operation over x, and P<sub>1</sub>+P<sub>2</sub>=P.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0182" num="0182">Here, the filling CB may be formed by any preset bit sequence, including, but not<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> limited to, one of the following manners:
<ul id="ul0018" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>a first manner: a CB formed by an all-1 bit sequence or an all-0 bit sequence; and</li>
<li>a second manner: any CB in the K original CBs.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0183" num="0183">Alternatively, the device may further include a CB set division element, arranged to divide the K CBs of the TB into the P CB sets according to the CB set division manner and the number P of the CB sets.</p>
<p id="p0184" num="0184">Alternatively, the state of the P CB sets is determined according to at least one of the following parameters: a number of incorrect (or correct) CB sets in the P CB sets, an incorrectness rate (or correctness rate) of the CB sets, CB error patterns of the incorrect CB sets in the P CB sets and a CB error pattern of the TB.</p>
<heading id="h0018">Furthermore, the correct CB sets refer to that each CB sets includes correct CBs.</heading>
<p id="p0185" num="0185">Furthermore, the incorrect CB sets refer to that each of the CB sets includes at least one incorrect CB.</p>
<p id="p0186" num="0186">Furthermore, the incorrectness rate (or correctness rate) of the CB sets refers to dividing the number of the incorrect (or correct) CB sets in the P CB sets by P.</p>
<p id="p0187" num="0187">Furthermore, the CB error patterns of the incorrect CB sets refer to positions (indexes) of incorrect (or correct) CBs in the incorrect CB sets.</p>
<p id="p0188" num="0188">Furthermore, the CB error pattern of the TB refers to positions (indexes) of incorrect (or correct) CBs in the TB.</p>
<p id="p0189" num="0189">Alternatively, when the feedback information set includes correctness indication information ACK and one kind of incorrectness indication information NACK, the correctness indication information ACK is used for indicating that the first transmission node correctly receives the TB.</p>
<p id="p0190" num="0190">Alternatively, when the feedback information set includes the correctness indication information ACK and the unique incorrectness indication information NACK, the unique incorrectness indication information NACK is used for indicating that the first transmission node does not correctly receive the TB.</p>
<p id="p0191" num="0191">Alternatively, when the feedback information set includes the correctness indication information ACK and the unique incorrectness indication information NACK, the ACK is represented by a bit "0" and the NACK is represented by a bit "1"; or, the ACK is represented by the bit "1" and the "NACK" is represented by the bit "0".</p>
<p id="p0192" num="0192">Alternatively, when the feedback information set at least includes the correctness indication information ACK and two kinds of incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub>, the correctness indication information ACK is used for indicating that the first<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --> transmission node correctly receives the TB.</p>
<p id="p0193" num="0193">Alternatively, when the feedback information set at least includes the correctness indication information ACK and the two kinds of incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub>, the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> is used for indicating that retransmitted data at least includes part of data obtained by packet coding on M CB sets in the P CB sets, in which M is a positive integer and 2≤M≤P.</p>
<p id="p0194" num="0194">Furthermore, the second transmission node performs packet coding on the M CB sets in the P CB sets to obtain S check CB sets, in which a length of each check CB set is T bits, M, S and T are all positive integers and 2≤M≤P; and<br/>
the retransmitted data at least includes Q bits in each check CB set, in which Q is a positive integer and 1≤Q≤T.</p>
<p id="p0195" num="0195">Furthermore, packet coding refers to that bits or symbols at the same index positions in the M CB sets are coded to generate the S check CB sets.</p>
<p id="p0196" num="0196">Furthermore, a coding operation may be, but not limited to, one of the following manners: bit exclusive or (or called as modular two additions) coding, Reed-Solomon coding, BCH coding, linear coding such as digital fountain coding, symbol superimposition coding, network coding and the like.</p>
<p id="p0197" num="0197">Alternatively, when the feedback information set at least includes the correctness indication information ACK and the two kinds of incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub>, the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>2</sub> is used for indicating that the retransmitted data should at least include part of data of the TB.</p>
<p id="p0198" num="0198">Alternatively, when the feedback information set at least includes the incorrectness indication information ACK and the two kinds of incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub>, the ACK, the NACK<sub>1</sub> and the NACK<sub>2</sub> are respectively represented by any two bits.</p>
<p id="p0199" num="0199">Alternatively, when the feedback information set at least includes the incorrectness indication information ACK and the two kinds of incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub>, the ACK, the NACK<sub>1</sub> and the NACK<sub>2</sub> are modulated by adopting a nonuniform constellation diagram. That is, on the modulation constellation diagram, a Euclidean distance between the ACK and the NACK<sub>1</sub> is longer than a Euclidean distance between the ACK<sub>1</sub> and the NACK<sub>2</sub>, and a Euclidean distance between the ACK and the NACK<sub>2</sub> is also longer than the Euclidean distance between the ACK<sub>1</sub> and the NACK<sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p0200" num="0200">Alternatively, the feedback information set further includes the number P of the CB<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --> sets.</p>
<p id="p0201" num="0201">Furthermore, the number P of the CB sets meets one of the following conditions: after the K CBs are divided into the P CB sets, a maximum of a number of incorrect CBs at the same index positions does not exceed a first preset threshold value G, wherein G is a positive integer and 1≤G≤P;<br/>
or, the number P of the CB sets meets that: after the K CBs are divided into the P sets, the maximum of the number of the incorrect CBs at the same index positions is minimum in division solutions when P adopts different values.</p>
<p id="p0202" num="0202">Furthermore, when multiple values of the number P of the CB sets meet one of the conditions, the number P of the CB sets in the feedback information set is a maximum value in the values meeting the condition.</p>
<p id="p0203" num="0203">Alternatively, the feedback information set further includes the CB set division manner.</p>
<p id="p0204" num="0204">Alternatively, the feedback information set further includes the number Z of the correct or incorrect CB sets, in which Z is a positive integer and 1≤Z≤P.</p>
<p id="p0205" num="0205">Alternatively, the feedback information set further includes the CB error patterns of the incorrect CB sets, or the CB error pattern of the TB.</p>
<p id="p0206" num="0206">Alternatively, when the P CB sets are all correct CB sets, the first transmission node sends the correctness indication information ACK to the second transmission node.</p>
<p id="p0207" num="0207">Furthermore, that the P CB sets are all correct CB sets is equal to one of the following conditions: the TB is a correct TB, or the K CBs are all correct CBs.</p>
<p id="p0208" num="0208">Alternatively, when at least one CB set in the P CB sets is an incorrect CB set and the feedback information set includes one kind of incorrectness indication information NACK, the first transmission node sends the incorrectness indication information NACK in the preset feedback information set to the second transmission node.</p>
<p id="p0209" num="0209">Alternatively, when the feedback information set at least includes the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub>, the first transmission node determines the incorrectness indication information sent to the second transmission node according to the number of the incorrect (or correct) CB sets in the P CB sets or according to the incorrectness rate (or correctness rate) of the CB sets.</p>
<p id="p0210" num="0210">Furthermore, when the number of the incorrect CB sets (or the incorrectness rate of the CB sets) does not exceed a preset threshold value, or when the number of the correct CB sets (or the correctness rate of the CB sets) exceeds a preset threshold value, the first<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --> transmission node sends the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> to the second transmission node.</p>
<p id="p0211" num="0211">Furthermore, when the number of the incorrect CB sets (or the incorrectness rate of the CB sets) exceeds the preset threshold value, or when the number of the correct CB sets (or the correctness rate of the CB sets) does not exceed the preset threshold value, the first transmission node sends the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>2</sub> to the second transmission node.</p>
<p id="p0212" num="0212">Alternatively, when the feedback information set at least includes the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and NACK<sub>2</sub>, the first transmission node determines the incorrectness indication information sent to the second transmission node according to the CB error patterns of the incorrect CB sets.</p>
<p id="p0213" num="0213">Furthermore, when a number of the incorrect CBs at the same index positions in the incorrect CB sets does not exceed a preset threshold value, the first transmission node sends the first incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> to the second transmission node.</p>
<p id="p0214" num="0214">Furthermore, when the number of the incorrect CBs at the same index positions in the incorrect CB sets exceeds the preset threshold value, the first transmission node sends the second incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>2</sub> to the second transmission node.</p>
<heading id="h0019">Example 1</heading>
<p id="p0215" num="0215">In the example, the first transmission node is a terminal, and the second transmission node is an evolved Node B. The terminal or a device arranged in the terminal includes a receiving component 1201, a state determination component 1202, a feedback information determination component 1203 and a sending component 1204, as shown in <figref idref="f0004">Fig. 12</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0216" num="0216">The receiving component 1201 of the terminal is arranged to receive a signal including a TB from the evolved Node B, wherein the TB is formed by K=8 CBs, and is formed by P=2 CB sets. As shown in <figref idref="f0002">Fig. 4</figref>, a continuous division manner is adopted for the CB sets, wherein a number P=2 of the CB sets is configured by the evolved Node B, and the evolved Node B selects P=2 from a preset group of numerical values {2, 3, 4, 5}, and sends it to the terminal through downlink signaling.</p>
<p id="p0217" num="0217">The feedback information determination component 1203 of the terminal determines at least one kind of feedback information in a feedback information set according to states of the 2 CB sets, and sends the feedback information to the evolved Node B through the sending component 1204, in which the feedback information set includes incorrectness indication information ACK, incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> and<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --> incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p0218" num="0218">In the example, it is supposed that the CB set 1 is incorrectly received and the CB set 2 is correctly received, that is, at least one CB in the CB set 1 is incorrectly received while all the CBs in the CB set 2 are correctly received.</p>
<p id="p0219" num="0219">In the example, the states of the CB sets is a number of correct or incorrect CB sets, or a function of an incorrectness rate of the CB sets, and at this moment, the number of the correct CB sets is not smaller than a preset threshold value 1, or the number of the incorrect CB sets is not larger than the preset threshold value 1, or a correctness rate of the CB sets is not lower than a preset threshold value 0.5, or the incorrectness rate of the CB sets is not higher than the preset threshold value 0.5. Under such a condition, the terminal may recovery incorrect CBs (or CB sets) with a relatively higher probability by virtue of data obtained by packet coding in retransmitted data sent by the evolved Node B. Therefore, the terminal determines to feed back the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> to the evolved Node B. The NACK<sub>1</sub> may be represented by two bits. The incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> is used for indicating that the retransmitted data sent to the terminal by the evolved Node B should include part of data obtained by packet coding of the CB set 1 and the CB set 2. As shown in <figref idref="f0002">Fig. 5</figref>, a CB set A is obtained by packet coding of the CB set 1 and the CB set 2. The information NACK<sub>1</sub> is used for indicating that the retransmitted data should include Q bits in the CB A.</p>
<heading id="h0020">Example 2</heading>
<p id="p0220" num="0220">A difference between this example and example 1 is that: in the example, the number P of the CB set is determined according to a size of the TB. In the example, the size of the TB belongs to a preset value interval, and a number, corresponding to the value interval, of the CB sets is P=2. At this moment, the number P of the CB sets is not required to be sent between the evolved Node B and the terminal through the signaling.</p>
<p id="p0221" num="0221">The other difference between this example and example 1 is that: both the CB set 1 and the CB set 2 are incorrectly received in the receiving component 1201, and at this moment, the number of the correct CB sets is smaller than the preset threshold value 1, or the number of the incorrect CB sets is larger than the preset threshold value 1, or the correctness rate of the CB sets is lower than the preset threshold value 0.5, or the incorrectness rate of the CB sets is higher than the preset threshold value 0.5. Under such a condition, when the retransmitted data only includes the data obtained by packet coding, the terminal may recover the incorrect CBs (or CB sets) only with a relatively lower probability, and when the retransmitted data includes part of data of the TB, the probability<!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --> of the terminal in recovery of the incorrect CBs (or CB sets) may be increased. Therefore, the terminal determines to feed back the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>2</sub> to the evolved Node B. The incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>2</sub> is used for indicating that the retransmitted data should at least include part of data of the TB. That is, the retransmitted data should at least include Q bits in the CB set 1 or the CB set 2.</p>
<heading id="h0021">Example 3</heading>
<p id="p0222" num="0222">A difference between this example and example 2 is that: in the example, the receiving state of the CB sets is determined according to CB error patterns the incorrect CB sets. It is supposed that the CB error patterns of the CB 1 and the CB set 2 in the example are shown in <figref idref="f0002">Fig. 6</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0223" num="0223">Moreover, incorrectly received CBs in the CB set 1 and the CB set 2 are represented by shaded areas, the CB error pattern of the CB set 1 may be represented by a vector err1=[1,0,1,0], and the CB error pattern of the CB set 2 may be represented by a vector err2=[0,1,0,1], in which the elements 1 represent positions of the incorrect CBs in the CB sets. It can be seen that a number of the incorrect CBs at any same position in the CB set 1 and the CB set 2 does not exceed 1. Under such a condition, the terminal may recover the incorrect CBs (or CB sets) with a relatively higher probability by virtue of the data obtained by packet coding in the retransmitted data sent by the evolved Node B. Therefore, the terminal determines to feed back the incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>1</sub> to the second transmission node.</p>
<heading id="h0022">Example 4</heading>
<p id="p0224" num="0224">A difference between this example and example 3 is that: in the example, the CB error patterns of the CB set 1 and the CB set 2 are shown in <figref idref="f0002">Fig. 7</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0225" num="0225">Moreover, the incorrectly received CBs in the CB set 1 and the CB set 2 are represented by shaded areas, the CB error pattern of the CB set 1 may be represented by the vector err1=[1,0,1,0], and the CB error pattern of the CB set 2 may be represented by the vector err2=[1,0,0,1], in which the elements 1 represent the positions of the incorrect CBs in the CB sets. It can be seen that first CBs in the CB set 1 and the CB set 2 are both incorrectly received, that is, a number of the incorrect CBs at a position exceeds 1. Under such a condition, when the retransmitted data only includes the data obtained by packet coding, the terminal may recover the incorrect CBs (or CB sets) only with a relatively lower probability, and when the retransmitted data includes part of data of the TB, the probability of the terminal in recovery of the incorrect CBs (or CB sets) may be increased. Therefore, the terminal determines to feed back the second incorrectness indication<!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --> information NACK<sub>2</sub> to the second transmission node. The second incorrectness indication information NACK<sub>2</sub> is used for indicating that the retransmitted data should at least include part of data of the TB. That is, the retransmitted data should at least include Q bits in the CB set 1 or the CB set 2.</p>
<heading id="h0023">Example 5</heading>
<p id="p0226" num="0226">A difference between this example and example 3 and example 4 is that: in the example, the CB error patterns are different, and in the example, the feedback information set further includes the number P of the CB sets. In the example, the states of the CB sets are determined according to the CB error patterns of the incorrect CB sets, and it is supposed that a CB error pattern of the TB is shown in <figref idref="f0003">Fig. 8</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0227" num="0227">When the 8 CBs are divided into 2 CB sets, as shown in <figref idref="f0003">Fig. 9</figref>, the CB error patterns of the CB sets may be represented by err1=[0,0,1,0] and err2=[1,0,1,0] respectively. At this moment, third CBs in the CB set 1 and the CB set 2 are both incorrect CBs, that is, the number of the incorrect CBs at the same index position exceeds the threshold value 1.</p>
<p id="p0228" num="0228">When the 8 CBs are divided into 3 CB sets, because the number of the CBs may not be exactly divided by the number of the CB sets, it is necessary to add a filling CB into the CB set 3 according to the CB set division manner of the example, and as shown in <figref idref="f0003">Fig. 10</figref>, the CB 9 is the filling CB.</p>
<p id="p0229" num="0229">CB error patterns of the CB sets may be respectively represented by err1=[0,0,1], err2=[0,1,0] and err3=[1,0,0]. It can be seen that the number of incorrect CBs at any same position in the CB set 1, the CB set 2 and the CB set 3 does not exceed 1.</p>
<p id="p0230" num="0230">At this moment, the information fed back to the evolved Node B by the terminal includes the number P=3 of the CB sets.</p>
<heading id="h0024">Example 6</heading>
<p id="p0231" num="0231">A difference between this example and example 3 and example 4 is that: in the example, the state of the CB sets is determined according to the CB error pattern of the TB, and the feedback information set further includes the CB error pattern of the TB.</p>
<p id="p0232" num="0232">In the example, the CB error pattern of the TB may be represented by err=[0,0,1,0,1,0,1,0],</p>
<p id="p0233" num="0233">At this moment, the information fed back to the evolved Node B by the terminal includes the CB error pattern of the TB.</p>
<heading id="h0025">Example 7</heading>
<p id="p0234" num="0234">A difference between this example and example 1 to example 6 is that the feedback information sent to the evolved Node B by the terminal is further modulated by adopting a<!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --> nonuniform constellation diagram. That is, on the modulation constellation diagram, a Euclidean distance between the ACK and the NACK<sub>1</sub> is longer than a Euclidean distance between the NACK<sub>1</sub> and the NACK<sub>2</sub>, and a Euclidean distance between the ACK and the NACK<sub>2</sub> is also longer than the Euclidean distance between the NACK<sub>1</sub> and the NACK<sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p0235" num="0235">Specifically, the ACK, the NACK<sub>1</sub> and the NACK<sub>2</sub> sent to the evolved Node B by the terminal are modulated by a constellation diagram shown in <figref idref="f0003">Fig. 11</figref>.</p>
<heading id="h0026">Example 8</heading>
<p id="p0236" num="0236">A difference between this example and example 1 to example 7 is that the feedback information set in the example includes the incorrectness indication information ACK and incorrectness indication information NACK. At this moment, the feedback information sent to the evolved Node B by the terminal includes the NACK, and the NACK is used for indicating that the terminal does not correctly receive the TB.</p>
<heading id="h0027">Example 9</heading>
<p id="p0237" num="0237">A difference between this example and the example 5 is that: in the example, the feedback information set further includes the CB set division manner. In the CB sets, the continuous division manner is indicated by a bit "0", and the discontinuous division manner is indicated by a bit "1".</p>
<p id="p0238" num="0238">In the embodiment, the CB set division manner is determined according to the terminal, so that the information fed back to the evolved Node B by the terminal further includes the CB set indication manner indicated by the bit "0".</p>
<heading id="h0028">Example 10</heading>
<p id="p0239" num="0239">A difference between this example and example 1 to example 9 is that: in the example, the terminal further includes a CB set division component 1205, arranged to divide the K CBs of the TB into the P CB sets, as shown in <figref idref="f0004">Fig. 13</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0240" num="0240">Moreover, the CB set division component 1205 divides the K CBs into the P CB sets according to the CB set division manner (the continuous division manner or the discontinuous division manner) and the number of the CB sets.</p>
<p id="p0241" num="0241">Furthermore, the continuous division manner refers to that at least two CBs at adjacent positions in the TB are divided into the same CB set.</p>
<p id="p0242" num="0242">The discontinuous division manner refers to that CBs at any two adjacent positions in the TB may not be divided into the same CB set in the P CB sets.</p>
<p id="p0243" num="0243">The number P of the CB sets may be one of m preset positive integers, and is sent to the terminal by the evolved Node B through signaling; or,
<ul id="ul0019" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>the number P of the CB sets may be autonomously determined by the first<!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --> transmission node and sent from the first transmission node to the second transmission node; or,</li>
<li>the number P of the CB sets may further be determined according to a size of the TB. Specifically, the TB is divided into multiple value intervals according to a sequence from small to large, and each value interval corresponds to a number P of the CB sets.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0244" num="0244">Those skilled in the art should know that all or part of the steps of the method may be implemented by related hardware instructed by a program, and the program may be stored in a computer-readable storage medium, such as a read-only memory, a magnetic disk or an optical disk. Alternatively, all or part of the steps of the embodiment may also be implemented by one or more integrated circuits. Correspondingly, each component or element in the embodiment may be implemented in form of hardware, and may also be implemented in form of software function component. The disclosure is not limited to any specific hardware and software combination.</p>
<p id="p0245" num="0245">The scope of the invention is defined by the independent claims. Preferred embodiments are defined by the dependent claims.</p>
<heading id="h0029"><b><u>Industrial Applicability</u></b></heading>
<p id="p0246" num="0246">According to the technical solutions of the disclosure, a retransmitted data volume may be effectively reduced, and data retransmission efficiency may be improved. Therefore, the disclosure has high industrial practicability.</p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="35"> -->
<claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>A feedback method, applied to a first transmission node, comprising:
<claim-text>receiving, by the first transmission node, a signal comprising a Transmission Block, TB, from a second transmission node, wherein the TB comprises K Code Blocks, CBs, and the K CBs are divided into P CB sets, K and P are positive integers, K≥3 and 2≤P≤K (S101);</claim-text>
<claim-text>obtaining, by the first transmission node, states of the P CB sets according to the signal comprising the TB (S102);</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining, by the first transmission node, at least one kind of feedback information in a preset feedback information set according to the states of the P CB sets, wherein the feedback information set at least comprises: correctness indication information and n kinds of incorrectness indication information, n is an integer greater than or equal to 1 (S103); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending, by the first transmission node, the determined feedback information to the second transmission node (S104)</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the number P of the CB sets is one of m preset positive integers, and is determined by the first transmission node and sent from the first transmission node to the second transmission node, and m≥1.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>The feedback method as claimed in claim 1, wherein the feedback information set further comprises at least one CB set division manner.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>A feedback device, arranged in a first transmission node, comprising a receiving component (1201), a state determination component (1202), a feedback information determination component (1203) and a sending component (1204), wherein
<claim-text>the receiving component (1201) is arranged to receive a signal comprising a Transmission Block, TB, from a second transmission node, wherein the TB comprises K Code Blocks, CBs, and the K CBs are divided into P CB sets, K and P are positive integers, K≥3 and 2≤P≤K;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the state determination component (1202) is arranged to obtain states of the P CB sets according to the signal comprising the TB;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the feedback information determination component (1203) is arranged to determine at least one kind of feedback information in a preset feedback information set according to the states of the P CB sets, wherein the feedback information set at least comprises correctness indication information and n kinds of incorrectness indication information, n is an integer greater than or equal to 1; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the sending component (1204) is arranged to send the determined feedback information to the second transmission node;<!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the number P of the CB sets is one of m preset positive integers, and is determined by the first transmission node and sent from the first transmission node to the second transmission node, and m≥1.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>The device as claimed in claim 3, wherein the feedback information set further comprises at least one CB set division manner.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims02" lang="de"><!-- EPO <DP n="37"> -->
<claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Rückkopplungsverfahren, das auf einen ersten Übertragungsknoten angewendet wird, das Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>Empfangen, durch den ersten Übertragungsknoten, eines Signals, das einen Übertragungsblock (Transmission Block - TB) umfasst, von einem zweiten Übertragungsknoten, wobei der TB K Code-Blöcke (Code Blocks - CBs) umfasst und die K CBs in P CB-Sätze unterteilt sind, K und P positive ganze Zahlen sind, K≥3 und 2≤P≤K (S101);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Erhalten, durch den ersten Übertragungsknoten, von Zuständen der P CB-Sätze gemäß dem Signal, das den TB umfasst (S102);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Bestimmen, durch den ersten Übertragungsknoten, wenigstens einer Art von Rückkopplungsinformationen in einem voreingestellten Rückkopplungsinformationssatz gemäß den Zuständen der P CB-Sätze, wobei der Rückkopplungsinformationssatz wenigstens Folgendes umfasst: Richtigkeitsanzeigeinformationen und n Arten von Unrichtigkeitsanzeigeinformationen, n eine ganze Zahl größer oder gleich 1 ist (S103); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Senden, durch den ersten Übertragungsknoten, der bestimmten Rückkopplungsinformationen an den zweiten Übertragungsknoten (S104),</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei die Anzahl P der CB-Sätze eine von m voreingestellten positiven ganzen Zahlen ist und durch den ersten Übertragungsknoten bestimmt wird und von dem ersten Übertragungsknoten an den zweiten Übertragungsknoten gesendet wird, und m≥1.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Rückkopplungsverfahren nach Anspruch 1, wobei der Rückkopplungsinformationssatz ferner wenigstens eine CB-Satzaufteilungsmethode umfasst.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Rückkopplungsvorrichtung, die in einem ersten Übertragungsknoten angeordnet ist, die eine Empfangskomponente (1201), eine Zustandsbestimmungskomponente (1202), eine Rückkopplungsinformationsbestimmungskomponente (1203) und eine Sendekomponente (1204) umfasst, wobei
<claim-text>die Empfangskomponente (1201) angeordnet ist, um ein Signal, das einen Übertragungsblock (TB) umfasst, von einem zweiten Übertragungsknoten zu empfangen, wobei der TB K Code-Blöcke (CBs) umfasst und die K CBs in P CB-Sätze unterteilt sind, K und P positive ganze Zahlen sind, K≥3 und 2≤P≤K;</claim-text>
<claim-text>die Zustandsbestimmungskomponente (1202) angeordnet ist, um Zustände der<!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --> P CB-Sätze gemäß dem Signal, das den TB umfasst, zu erhalten;</claim-text>
<claim-text>die Rückkopplungsinformationsbestimmungskomponente (1203) angeordnet ist, um wenigstens eine Art von Rückkopplungsinformationen in einem voreingestellten Rückkopplungsinformationssatz gemäß den Zuständen der P CB-Sätze zu bestimmen, wobei der Rückkopplungsinformationssatz wenigstens Richtigkeitsanzeigeinformationen und n Arten von Unrichtigkeitsanzeigeinformationen umfasst, n eine ganze Zahl größer oder gleich 1 ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>die Sendekomponente (1204) angeordnet ist, um die bestimmten Rückkopplungsinformationen an den zweiten Übertragungsknoten zu senden;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei die Anzahl P der CB-Sätze eine von m voreingestellten positiven ganzen Zahlen ist und durch den ersten Übertragungsknoten bestimmt wird und von dem ersten Übertragungsknoten an den zweiten Übertragungsknoten gesendet wird, und m≥1.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 3, wobei der Rückkopplungsinformationssatz ferner wenigstens eine CB-Satzaufteilungsmethode umfasst.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims03" lang="fr"><!-- EPO <DP n="39"> -->
<claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Procédé de rétroaction, appliqué à un premier nœud de transmission, comprenant :
<claim-text>la réception, par le premier nœud de transmission, d'un signal comprenant un bloc de transmission, TB, à partir d'un second nœud de transmission, le TB comprenant K blocs de code, CB, et les K CB étant divisés en P ensembles de CB, K et P étant des entiers positifs, K ≥ 3 et 2 ≤ P ≤ K (S101) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'obtention, par le premier nœud de transmission, des états des P ensembles de CB en fonction du signal comprenant le TB (S102) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>la détermination, par le premier nœud de transmission, d'au moins un type d'informations de rétroaction dans un ensemble d'informations de rétroaction prédéfini en fonction des états des P ensembles de CB, l'ensemble d'informations de rétroaction comprenant au moins : des informations d'indication d'exactitude et n types d'informations d'indication d'inexactitude, n étant un entier supérieur ou égal à 1 (S103) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'envoi, par le premier nœud de transmission, des informations de rétroaction déterminées au second nœud de transmission (S104)</claim-text>
<claim-text>le nombre P des ensembles de CB étant l'un de m entiers positifs prédéfinis, et étant déterminé par le premier nœud de transmission et envoyé du premier nœud de transmission au second nœud de transmission, et m ≥ 1.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Procédé de rétroaction selon la revendication 1, l'ensemble d'informations de rétroaction comprenant en outre au moins un mode de division d'ensemble de CB.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Dispositif de rétroaction, agencé dans un premier nœud de transmission, comprenant un composant de réception (1201), un composant de détermination d'état (1202), un composant de détermination d'informations de rétroaction (1203) et un composant d'envoi (1204),
<claim-text>le composant de réception (1201) étant agencé pour recevoir un signal comprenant un bloc de transmission, TB, à partir d'un second nœud de transmission, le TB comprenant K blocs de code, CB, et les K CB étant divisés en P ensembles de CB, K et P étant des entiers positifs, K ≥ 3 et 2 ≤ P ≤ K ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>le composant de détermination d'état (1202) étant agencé pour obtenir des états des P ensembles de CB en fonction du signal comprenant le TB ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>le composant de détermination d'informations de rétroaction (1203) étant agencé pour déterminer au moins un type d'informations de rétroaction dans un ensemble<!-- EPO <DP n="40"> --> d'informations de rétroaction prédéfini selon les états des P ensembles de CB, l'ensemble d'informations de rétroaction comprenant au moins des informations d'indication d'exactitude et n types d'informations d'indication d'inexactitude, n étant un entier supérieur ou égal à 1 ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>le composant d'envoi (1204) étant agencé pour envoyer les informations de rétroaction déterminées au second nœud de transmission ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>le nombre P des ensembles de CB étant l'un de m entiers positifs prédéfinis, et étant déterminé par le premier nœud de transmission et envoyé du premier nœud de transmission au second nœud de transmission, et m &gt; 1.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Dispositif selon la revendication 3, l'ensemble d'informations de rétroaction comprenant en outre au moins une manière de division d'ensemble de CB.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="41"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1,2,3"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="125" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="42"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="4,5,6,7"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="154" he="230" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="43"> -->
<figure id="f0003" num="8,9,10,11"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="152" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="44"> -->
<figure id="f0004" num="12,13"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="88" he="228" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<ep-reference-list id="ref-list">
<heading id="ref-h0001"><b>REFERENCES CITED IN THE DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0001" num=""><i>This list of references cited by the applicant is for the reader's convenience only. It does not form part of the European patent document. Even though great care has been taken in compiling the references, errors or omissions cannot be excluded and the EPO disclaims all liability in this regard.</i></p>
<heading id="ref-h0002"><b>Patent documents cited in the description</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0002" num="">
<ul id="ref-ul0001" list-style="bullet">
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0001" dnum="EP24136274A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>24136274</doc-number><kind>A1</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0001">[0008]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0002" dnum="US2013195055A1"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2013195055</doc-number><kind>A1</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0002">[0008]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0003" dnum="EP2663007A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2663007</doc-number><kind>A1</kind></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0003">[0008]</crossref></li>
</ul></p>
</ep-reference-list>
</ep-patent-document>
