<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP20315092A1" file="EP20315092NWA1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3890364" kind="A1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSKBAHRIS..MTNORSMESMMAKHTNMD..........</B001EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  1100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3890364</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT APPLICATION</B121></B120><B130>A1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>20315092.5</B210><B220><date>20200331</date></B220><B250>en</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B430></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>H04W   4/021       20180101AFI20200914BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="2"><text>H04L  29/08        20060101ALI20200914BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="3"><text>H04W  12/00        20210101ALI20200914BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="4"><text>H04W   4/80        20180101ALI20200914BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="5"><text>H04M   1/725       20210101ALI20200914BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="6"><text>G06Q  20/18        20120101ALI20200914BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="7"><text>G06Q  30/06        20120101ALI20200914BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="8"><text>G06Q  20/32        20120101ALI20200914BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>G06Q  20/3276      20130101 LA20200909BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>G06Q  30/016       20130101 LI20210219BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="3"><text>G06Q  20/18        20130101 LA20200908BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="4"><text>H04L  67/025       20130101 LI20200909BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="5"><text>G08C2201/20        20130101 LA20200930BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="6"><text>G08C  17/02        20130101 LI20200930BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="7"><text>H04W   4/80        20180201 FI20200909BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="8"><text>H04M   1/72415     20210101 LI20210101RHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="9"><text>H04W  12/77        20210101 LI20210101RHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="10"><text>H04W  12/50        20210101 LI20210101RHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>VERFAHREN ZUM FERNZUGRIFF AUF EINEN VON EINEM KUNDENDIENSTGERÄT LOKAL BEREITGESTELLTEN DIENST ÜBER EINE MENSCH-MASCHINE-BERÜHRUNGSSCHNITTSTELLE</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>METHOD FOR REMOTELY ACCESSING A SERVICE LOCALLY PROVIDED BY A CUSTOMER SERVICE DEVICE VIA A TOUCH MAN-MACHINE INTERFACE</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>PROCÉDÉ POUR ACCÉDER À DISTANCE À UN SERVICE FOURNI LOCALEMENT PAR UN DISPOSITIF DE SERVICE CLIENT VIA UNE INTERFACE HOMME-MACHINE TACTILE</B542></B540><B590><B598>3</B598></B590></B500><B700><B710><B711><snm>Atos IT Services UK Limited</snm><iid>101825772</iid><irf>23742-EP</irf><adr><str>Second floor, Mid City Place 
71 High Holborn</str><city>London WC1V 6EA</city><ctry>GB</ctry></adr></B711></B710><B720><B721><snm>SMYTH, David</snm><adr><str>2 Rosebery View</str><city>Daigety Bay Fife KY11 9YH</city><ctry>GB</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B740><B741><snm>Cabinet Camus Lebkiri</snm><iid>101467264</iid><adr><str>25 rue de Maubeuge</str><city>75009 Paris</city><ctry>FR</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840><B844EP><B845EP><ctry>BA</ctry></B845EP><B845EP><ctry>ME</ctry></B845EP></B844EP><B848EP><B849EP><ctry>KH</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>MA</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>MD</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>TN</ctry></B849EP></B848EP></B800></SDOBI>
<abstract id="abst" lang="en">
<p id="pa01" num="0001">According to an aspect of the invention, it is provided a method for a user having a terminal (300), to remotely access one service provided by a customer service device (200) comprising a touch man-machine interface (201) and being associated with a service provider, the service being locally accessible via the touch man-machine interface (201), a mirroring application having a list of authorized service providers being installed on the terminal (300), comprising the following steps:<br/>
- Verifying if the service provider associated with the customer service device (200) is listed in the list of authorized service providers;<br/>
o If yes:<br/>
• Initiation by the terminal (300), of a pairing with the customer service device (200);<br/>
• Accessing the service on the terminal (300) via the mirroring application being configured to make the interface between the terminal (300) and the customer service device (200).<br/>
 <br/>
  
<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="123" he="93" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p>
</abstract>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<heading id="h0001"><b>TECHNICAL FIELD</b></heading>
<p id="p0001" num="0001">The technical field of the invention is the one of devices equipped with a touch man-machine interface and more particularly the one of customer service devices equipped with a touch man-machine interface.</p>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">The present invention relates to a method for remotely accessing a service provided by a customer service device comprising a touch man-machine interface, and to a terminal, a system and a computer program product enabling such a method to be implemented.</p>
<heading id="h0002"><b>BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</b></heading>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">In recent years, there is a huge growth in devices equipped with touch man-machine interfaces for consumer input. These touch man-machine interfaces, as for example touch screens or touch keypads, are used for example in digital drinks dispensers to order a drink, in fast-foods to order a meal, in planes for infotainment, or again in public areas for customer satisfaction or customer information.</p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">A customer service device equipped with a touch man-machine interface is therefore intended to be used by many customers, which raises hygiene issues since the customers do not necessarily have any opportunity to sanitize their hands before and after using the man-machine interface. A solution would be to put in place hand gel dispensers to cleanse before and after use, but these require maintenance and refilling and these dispensers could be vandalized or stolen.</p>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">Moreover, the customer services devices are located in public areas, which raises security issues. Actually, the customer services devices can be cloned, replaced in situ, or abused, for example customer satisfaction devices can be abused by selecting the high or low rating multiple times.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">There is therefore a need for a customer to securely access a service locally provided by a customer service device via its touch man-machine interface, without endangering his health.</p>
<heading id="h0003"><b>SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</b></heading>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">An object of the invention is to provide a secure and healthy access to a service traditionally accessible via the touch man-machine interface of a customer service device.</p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">To this end, according to a first aspect of the invention, it is provided a method for a user having a terminal, to remotely access at least one service provided by a customer service device comprising a touch man-machine interface and being associated with a service provider, the service being locally accessible via the touch man-machine interface, a mirroring application having a list of authorized service providers being installed on the terminal, the method comprising the following steps:
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="dash" compact="compact">
<li>Verifying if a first condition is met, the first condition being met if the service provider associated with the customer service device is listed in the list of authorized service providers;<br/>
∘ If the first condition is met:
<ul id="ul0002" list-style="bullet" compact="compact">
<li>Initiation by the terminal, of a pairing with the customer service device;</li>
<li>Once the terminal and the customer service device are paired, accessing the service on the terminal via the mirroring application being configured to make the interface between the terminal and the customer service device.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
Thanks to the invention, the user can access the service provided by the customer service device via the man-machine interface, for example the screen or the keypad, of his own terminal, that is without touching the touch man-machine interface of the customer service device, which is healthier. The access is more secure since the terminal is only allowed to pair with a customer service device<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> associated with a service provider in a list of defined and approved service providers. It is also possible to impose a short period of pairing to avoid any abuse.</p>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">Apart from the characteristics mentioned above in the previous paragraph, the method according to a first aspect of the invention may have one or several complementary characteristics among the following characteristics considered individually or in any technically possible combinations.</p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">According to a variant of the invention, the step of verification is performed by the terminal.<br/>
The step of verification is thus automatically performed without any user intervention.</p>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">According to a variant of the invention compatible with the previous variant, the terminal comprises a screen and the list of authorized service providers is displayed on the screen of the terminal.<br/>
The step of verification can thus be performed by the user.</p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">According to a variant of the invention compatible with the previous variants, each authorized service provider is associated with information in the list of authorized service providers, the information being selected among the following list of information: a list of customer service devices associated with the service provider, a location or a reference of each customer service devices associated with the service provider, customer trust rating for the service provider.<br/>
The user has thus information to decide whether or not he can trust the service provider and connect to the customer service device. It is especially relevant for ticketing or financial services.</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">According to a first embodiment of the invention compatible with the previous variants, a QR code is disposed on the customer service device and the step of initiation is realized by scanning the QR code via the terminal.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">It is thus possible to establish a peer-to-peer connection between the terminal and the customer service device, or to get information necessary to establish a connection, for example a Bluetooth or a WiFi connection.</p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">According to a second embodiment of the invention compatible with the previous variants and first embodiment, the step of initiation is realized by Bluetooth.<br/>
With the first and the second embodiment, the user does not need any internet connection and has to be close to the customer service device, which reinforces security.</p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">According to a third embodiment of the invention compatible with the previous variants and first embodiment, the step of initiation is realized by WiFi.</p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">According to a variant of the invention compatible with the previous variants and embodiments, the mirroring application is configured to mirror the touch man-machine interface on the terminal.<br/>
The user has thus access to the same services via his terminal than the one provided by the customer service device.</p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">According to a variant of the invention compatible with the previous variants and embodiments, the mirroring application is compatible with each authorized service provider of the list of authorized service providers.<br/>
Consequently, only one application is necessary to connect to customer service devices associated to different service providers. Actually, it is not required to subscribe to a specific application relative to the service that the user is attempting to interact with since the mirroring application has the ability for any new service to treat the user as a new customer in the same way as the user would, by interacting with the customer service device directly but without having to subscribe and load any new applications. Moreover, through the mirroring application, each service provider can customize the services offered to the user.</p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">According to a variant of the invention compatible with the previous variants and<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> embodiments, the method according to the first aspect of the invention comprises a step of exchange of information between the terminal and the mirroring application.<br/>
It is thus possible for a service provider to get information about the user. For example, localization information could be used by the service provider to test the reception of a given service in a given local market and get instant direct feedback from the user.</p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">According to a second aspect of the invention, it is provided a terminal comprising means for implementing the method according to the first aspect of the invention.</p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">According to a third aspect of the invention, it is provided a system comprising a terminal according to the second aspect of the invention and a customer service device comprising a touch man-machine interface, the customer service device being configured to locally give access to at least one service via the touch man-machine interface and being able to pair with a terminal.</p>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">According to a variant of the invention, the customer service provider has a QR code.</p>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">According to a variant of the invention compatible with the previous variant, the touch man-machine interface is a touch screen, a keypad, a keyboard, one or several buttons, a thumbwheel, a joystick, and/or a remote control.</p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">According to a fourth aspect of the invention, it is provided a computer program product comprising instructions which, when the program is executed by a computer, cause the computer to carry out the steps of the method according to the first aspect of the invention.</p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">The invention and its various applications will be better understood by reading the following description and examining the accompanying figures.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p>
<heading id="h0004"><b>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE FIGURES</b></heading>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">The figures are presented for information purposes only and in no way limit the invention.
<ul id="ul0003" list-style="dash" compact="compact">
<li><figref idref="f0001">Figure 1</figref> is a flow chart of the method of the invention.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0001">Figure 2</figref> schematically represents the second step of the method according to the invention.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">Figure 3</figref> schematically represents the third step of the method according to the invention.</li>
</ul></p>
<heading id="h0005"><b>DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</b></heading>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">Some embodiments of devices and methods in accordance with embodiments of the present invention are now described, by way of example only, and with reference to the accompanying drawings. The description is to be regarded as illustrative in nature and not as restrictive.</p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">A first aspect of the invention relates to a method for remotely accessing at least one service provided by a customer service device comprising a touch man-machine interface.</p>
<p id="p0029" num="0029">Traditionally, the service is locally provided by the customer service device via the touch man-machine interface, that is that a user has to interact with the touch man-machine interface to be provided with the service. The access to the service is therefore local since the user has to be in contact with the touch man-machine interface.</p>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">The touch man-machine interface is for example a touch screen, a keypad, a keyboard, one or several buttons, a thumbwheel, a joystick, or again a remote control.</p>
<p id="p0031" num="0031">The customer service device is for example a digital drinks dispenser providing a drink ordered via a keyboard, an airplane seat having a screen providing series and films ordered via a remote control during medium and long flights, or as illustrated in <figref idref="f0001">figures 2</figref> and <figref idref="f0002">3</figref>, the customer service device 200 is a customer<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> satisfaction terminal providing customers opinions about a given public place, the customers giving their opinion via a touch screen 201.</p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032">The customer service device 200 is associated with a service provider. For example, a digital drinks dispenser is associated with a drinks industry company, an airplane seat is associated with an airline company and a customer satisfaction terminal is associated with a company managing the public place on which people give their opinion.</p>
<p id="p0033" num="0033">The customer service device 200 must be able to establish at least one type of connection with a terminal, for example a WiFi connection and/or a Bluetooth connection and/or a peer-to-peer connection, that is to pair with a terminal.</p>
<p id="p0034" num="0034">A second aspect of the invention relates to a terminal for implementing the method of the invention.</p>
<p id="p0035" num="0035">For a user willing to remotely access one service provided by the customer service device 200, the terminal is a terminal belonging to the user.</p>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">The terminal is for example a laptop, a tablet or, as illustrated in <figref idref="f0001">figures 2</figref> and <figref idref="f0002">3</figref>, the terminal 300 is a smartphone. Broadly speaking, the terminal 300 is a device comprising at least a screen 301, a processor and a human-machine interface, for example a touch screen and/or a keyboard and/or a mouse.<br/>
The screen 301 and the human-machine interface can be one and the same device.</p>
<p id="p0037" num="0037">A mirroring application is installed on the terminal 300. The mirroring application has a list of authorized service providers, that is of service providers who were approved by a trustworthy entity, for example a regulatory authority.</p>
<p id="p0038" num="0038">In the list of authorized service providers, each authorized service provider is for example associated with some information. The information is for example a list of<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> customer service devices 200 associated with the service provider, and/or the location and/or the reference of each customer service devices 200 associated with the service provider, and/or a customer trust rating for the service provider.</p>
<p id="p0039" num="0039">The mirroring application is universal, that is the mirroring application is compatible with each authorized service provider of the list of authorized service providers.</p>
<p id="p0040" num="0040">The user via the terminal 300 can exchange information with the mirroring application, for example settings, as for example language preferences, credentials, as for example a password and/or a fingerprint, or again localization information.</p>
<p id="p0041" num="0041">As illustrated in <figref idref="f0001">figure 1</figref>, the method 100 of the invention comprises a first step 101 consisting in verifying if a first condition C1 is met.</p>
<p id="p0042" num="0042">The first condition C1 is met if the service provider associated with the customer service device 200 is listed in the list of authorized service providers in possession of the mirroring application.</p>
<p id="p0043" num="0043">In a first alternative of the invention, the first step 101 of the method 100 is performed by the terminal 300.<br/>
In a second alternative of the invention, the first step 101 of the method 100 is performed by the user.</p>
<p id="p0044" num="0044">For example, the first step 101 comprises a first sub-step 1011 consisting in obtaining the service provider associated with the customer service device 200.</p>
<p id="p0045" num="0045">In the first alternative, the service provider associated with the customer service device 200 is obtained by the terminal 300.<br/>
For example, the terminal 300 is configured to scan QR codes and the service provider associated with the customer service device 200 is obtained by scanning a QR code disposed on the customer service device 200, or the terminal 300<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> comprises geolocation means and the service provider associated with the customer service device 200 is obtained by geolocating the terminal 300 and comparing the location of the terminal 300 with the locations of customer service devices 200 associated with authorized services providers comprised in the list of authorized services providers, or the user enters the service provider associated with the customer service device 200 in the terminal 300 via the human-machine interface.</p>
<p id="p0046" num="0046">In the second alternative, the service provider associated with the customer service device 200 is obtained by the user.<br/>
The service provider associated with the customer service device 200 is for example obtained by reading an indication written on the customer service device 200.</p>
<p id="p0047" num="0047">The first step 101 then comprises a second sub-step 1012 consisting in comparing the service provider obtained at the first sub-step 1011 with the list of authorized services providers in possession of the mirroring application.</p>
<p id="p0048" num="0048">In the first alternative, the second sub-step 1012 is automatically performed by the terminal 300 via the mirroring application since the terminal 300 knows the service provider associated with the customer service device 200 from the first sub-step 1011 and the list of authorized service providers from the mirroring application.</p>
<p id="p0049" num="0049">II the second alternative, the second sub-step is performed by the user.<br/>
In the second alternative, the mirroring application displays the list of authorized service providers on the screen 301 of the terminal 300 and the comparison is performed by the user who knows the service provider associated with the customer service device 200 from the first sub-step 1011.</p>
<p id="p0050" num="0050">If the first condition C1 is met, a second step 102 and a third step 103 of the method 100 of the invention is performed.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></p>
<p id="p0051" num="0051">The second step 102 consists in initiating a pairing between the terminal 300 and the customer service device 200. The second step 102 is performed by the terminal 300.</p>
<p id="p0052" num="0052">According to a first embodiment of the invention illustrated in <figref idref="f0001">figure 2</figref>, a QR code 202 is disposed on the customer service device 200 and the terminal 300 is configured to scan QR codes, for example via the mirroring application.<br/>
The second step 102 is realized by scanning the QR code to enable a peer-to-peer connection to be established between the terminal 300 and the customer service device 200.</p>
<p id="p0053" num="0053">In <figref idref="f0001">figure 2</figref>, the customer service device 200 is a customer satisfaction terminal enabling a user to give its opinion by touching the option yes Y or the option no N on the touch screen 201 of the customer service device 200.<br/>
In <figref idref="f0001">figure 2</figref>, the terminal 300 is pairing with the customer service device 200 which is represented by a dotted arrow. The pairing is realized by scanning a QR code 202 disposed on the customer service device 200.</p>
<p id="p0054" num="0054">According to a second embodiment non illustrated in the figures, the second step 102 is realized by establishing a Bluetooth connection between the terminal 300 and the customer service device 200.</p>
<p id="p0055" num="0055">According to a third embodiment non illustrated in the figures, the second step 102 is realized by establishing a WiFi connection between the terminal 300 and the customer service device 200 via a WiFi network.</p>
<p id="p0056" num="0056">According to a fourth embodiment non illustrated in the figures, the second step 102 is realized by scanning a QR code 202 to obtain information enabling a connection, for example a Bluetooth or a WiFi connection, to be established between the terminal 300 and the customer service device 200.</p>
<p id="p0057" num="0057">Once the terminal 300 and the customer service device 200 are paired, the third step 103 consists in accessing the service provided by the customer service<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> device 200 on the terminal 300 via the mirroring application being configured to make the interface between the terminal 300 and the customer service device 200. For example, the mirroring application manages the human-machine interface of the terminal 300, for example by displaying a keyboard or allowing touchscreen, and/or defines how the user can navigate, what operations are allowed.</p>
<p id="p0058" num="0058">For example and as illustrated in <figref idref="f0002">figure 3</figref>, the mirroring application is configured to mirror the touch screen 201 of the customer service device 200 on the screen 301 of the terminal 300.<br/>
In <figref idref="f0002">figure 3</figref>, the screen 301 of the terminal 300 displays the same option yes Y and option no N that the one displayed on the touch screen 201 of the customer service device 200.</p>
<p id="p0059" num="0059">The mirroring application can also be configured to propose user-defined services.</p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="12"> -->
<claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Method (100) for a user having a terminal (300), to remotely access at least one service provided by a customer service device (200) comprising a touch man-machine interface (201) and being associated with a service provider, the service being locally accessible via the touch man-machine interface (201), <b>characterized in that</b> a mirroring application having a list of authorized service providers is installed on the terminal (300), the method (100) comprising the following steps:
<claim-text>- Verifying if a first condition (C1) is met (101), the first condition (C1) being met if the service provider associated with the customer service device (200) is listed in the list of authorized service providers;<br/>
∘ If the first condition (C1) is met:
<claim-text>• Initiation by the terminal (300), of a pairing with the customer service device (200, 102);</claim-text>
<claim-text>• Once the terminal (300) and the customer service device (200) are paired, accessing the service on the terminal (300) via the mirroring application being configured to make the interface between the terminal (300) and the customer service device (200, 103).</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Method (100) according to claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b> the terminal (300) comprises a screen (301) and the list of authorized service providers is displayed on the screen (301) of the terminal (300).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Method (100) according to any of the preceding claims, <b>characterized in that</b> each authorized service provider is associated with information in the list of authorized service providers, the information being selected among the following list of information: a list of customer service devices (200) associated with the service provider, a location or a reference of each customer service devices (200) associated with the service provider,<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> customer trust rating for the service provider.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Method (100) according to any of the preceding claims, <b>characterized in that</b> a QR code (202) is disposed on the customer service device (200) and the step (102) of initiation is realized by scanning the QR code (202) via the terminal (300).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Method (100) according to any of claims 1 to 4, <b>characterized in that</b> the step (102) of initiation is realized by Bluetooth or Wifi.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Method (100) according to any of the preceding claims, <b>characterized in that</b> the mirroring application is compatible with each authorized service provider of the list of authorized service providers.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Method (100) according to any of the preceding claims, <b>characterized in that</b> it comprises a step of exchange of information between the terminal (300) and the mirroring application.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>Terminal (300) comprising means for implementing the method (100) according to any of the preceding claims.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>System comprising the terminal (300) according to claim 8 and a customer service device (200) comprising a touch man-machine interface (201), the customer service device (200) being configured to locally give access to at least one service via the touch man-machine interface (201) and being able to pair with the terminal (300).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>A computer program product comprising instructions which, when the program is executed by a computer, cause the computer to carry out the steps of the method according to any of claims 1 to 7.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1,2"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="132" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="3"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="135" he="99" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<search-report-data id="srep" lang="en" srep-office="EP" date-produced=""><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="157" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="155" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data><search-report-data date-produced="20200909" id="srepxml" lang="en" srep-office="EP" srep-type="ep-sr" status="n"><!--
 The search report data in XML is provided for the users' convenience only. It might differ from the search report of the PDF document, which contains the officially published data. The EPO disclaims any liability for incorrect or incomplete data in the XML for search reports.
 -->

<srep-info><file-reference-id>23742-EP</file-reference-id><application-reference><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>20315092.5</doc-number></document-id></application-reference><applicant-name><name>Atos IT Services UK Limited</name></applicant-name><srep-established srep-established="yes"/><srep-invention-title title-approval="yes"/><srep-abstract abs-approval="yes"/><srep-figure-to-publish figinfo="by-applicant"><figure-to-publish><fig-number>3</fig-number></figure-to-publish></srep-figure-to-publish><srep-info-admin><srep-office><addressbook><text>MN</text></addressbook></srep-office><date-search-report-mailed><date>20200918</date></date-search-report-mailed></srep-info-admin></srep-info><srep-for-pub><srep-fields-searched><minimum-documentation><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr><text>H04L</text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr><text>G08C</text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr><text>H04M</text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr><text>G07G</text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr><text>G06Q</text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr><text>H04W</text></classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr></minimum-documentation></srep-fields-searched><srep-citations><citation id="sr-cit0001"><patcit dnum="US2018288594A1" id="sr-pcit0001" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=US2018288594&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2018288594</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>KIM KYUSANG [US]</name><date>20181004</date></document-id></patcit><category>X</category><rel-claims>1-10</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* abstract; figure 1 *</passage><passage>* paragraph [0029] - paragraph [0104] *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0002"><patcit dnum="WO2015162550A1" id="sr-pcit0002" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=WO2015162550&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2015162550</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>SCREEMO LTD [IL]</name><date>20151029</date></document-id></patcit><category>A</category><rel-claims>1-10</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* abstract; figure 1 *</passage><passage>* paragraph [0124] - paragraph [0174] *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0003"><patcit dnum="US2013131971A1" id="sr-pcit0003" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=US2013131971&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2013131971</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>PARRISH JOHN [US] ET AL</name><date>20130523</date></document-id></patcit><category>A</category><rel-claims>1-10</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* abstract; figure 4 *</passage><passage>* paragraph [0022] - paragraph [0070] *</passage></rel-passage></citation></srep-citations><srep-admin><examiners><primary-examiner><name>Lebas, Yves</name></primary-examiner></examiners><srep-office><addressbook><text>Munich</text></addressbook></srep-office><date-search-completed><date>20200909</date></date-search-completed></srep-admin><!--							The annex lists the patent family members relating to the patent documents cited in the above mentioned European search report.							The members are as contained in the European Patent Office EDP file on							The European Patent Office is in no way liable for these particulars which are merely given for the purpose of information.							For more details about this annex : see Official Journal of the European Patent Office, No 12/82						--><srep-patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2018288594</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20181004</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>AU</country><doc-number>2016332705</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20180426</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>CA</country><doc-number>3000655</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20170406</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>CN</country><doc-number>108369762</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20180803</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>3357044</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20180808</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2019501602</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20190117</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2018288594</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20181004</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2017058794</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20170406</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2015162550</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20151029</date></document-id></priority-application><text>NONE</text></patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2013131971</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20130523</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2013131971</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20130523</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2016104233</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20160414</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family></srep-patent-family></srep-for-pub></search-report-data>
</ep-patent-document>
