<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP18913432B1" file="EP18913432NWB1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3614771" kind="B1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSK..HRIS..MTNORS..SM..................</B001EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  2100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3614771</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT SPECIFICATION</B121></B120><B130>B1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>18913432.3</B210><B220><date>20180404</date></B220><B240><B241><date>20191122</date></B241><B242><date>20210319</date></B242></B240><B250>zh</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20200226</date><bnum>202009</bnum></B430><B450><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B450><B452EP><date>20210719</date></B452EP></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>H04W  76/28        20180101AFI20210624BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="2"><text>H04L   1/16        20060101ALI20210624BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="3"><text>H04L   1/18        20060101ALI20210624BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>H04L   1/1671      20130101 LI20200828BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>H04L   1/1851      20130101 LI20200828BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="3"><text>H04W  76/28        20180201 LI20200626BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="4"><text>H04L   1/1854      20130101 FI20200828BHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>VERFAHREN ZUR ÜBERTRAGUNG VON INFORMATIONEN UND ENDGERÄTEVORRICHTUNG</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>METHOD FOR TRANSMITTING INFORMATION AND TERMINAL DEVICE</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>PROCÉDÉ DE TRANSMISSION D'INFORMATIONS ET DISPOSITIF TERMINAL</B542></B540><B560><B561><text>WO-A1-2015/166846</text></B561><B561><text>WO-A1-2017/082244</text></B561><B561><text>CN-A- 105 191 439</text></B561><B562><text>CATT: "Handling of the DRX Ambiguous Period", 3GPP DRAFT; R2-1802147 HANDLING OF THE DRX AMBIGUOUS PERIOD - FINAL, 3RD GENERATION PARTNERSHIP PROJECT (3GPP), MOBILE COMPETENCE CENTRE ; 650, ROUTE DES LUCIOLES ; F-06921 SOPHIA-ANTIPOLIS CEDEX ; FR , vol. RAN WG2, no. Athens, Greece; 20180226 - 20180302 14 February 2018 (2018-02-14), XP051399143, Retrieved from the Internet: URL:http://www.3gpp.org/ftp/tsg%5Fran/WG2% 5FRL2/TSGR2%5F101/Docs/ [retrieved on 2018-02-14]</text></B562><B562><text>CATT: "Leftover Issues on DRX", 3GPP DRAFT; R2-1800166, 3RD GENERATION PARTNERSHIP PROJECT (3GPP), MOBILE COMPETENCE CENTRE ; 650, ROUTE DES LUCIOLES ; F-06921 SOPHIA-ANTIPOLIS CEDEX ; FRANCE , vol. RAN WG2, no. Vancouver, Canada; 20180122 - 20180126 12 January 2018 (2018-01-12), XP051386051, Retrieved from the Internet: URL:http://www.3gpp.org/ftp/tsg%5Fran/WG2% 5FRL2/TSGR2%5FAHs/2018%5F01%5FNR/Docs/ [retrieved on 2018-01-12]</text></B562><B562><text>"3rd Generation Partnership Project; Technical Specification Group Radio Access Network; NR; Medium Access Control (MAC) protocol specification (Release 15)", 3GPP STANDARD; TECHNICAL SPECIFICATION; 3GPP TS 38.321, 3RD GENERATION PARTNERSHIP PROJECT (3GPP), MOBILE COMPETENCE CENTRE ; 650, ROUTE DES LUCIOLES ; F-06921 SOPHIA-ANTIPOLIS CEDEX ; FRANCE, vol. RAN WG2, no. V15.1.0, 2 April 2018 (2018-04-02), pages 1-67, XP051450732, [retrieved on 2018-04-02]</text></B562><B562><text>OPPO: "CSI and SRS reporting for DRX Active time", 3GPP DRAFT; R2-1804431 - CSI AND SRS REPORTING FOR DRX ACTIVE TIME, 3RD GENERATION PARTNERSHIP PROJECT (3GPP), MOBILE COMPETENCE CENTRE ; 650, ROUTE DES LUCIOLES ; F-06921 SOPHIA-ANTIPOLIS CEDEX ; FRA , vol. RAN WG2, no. Sanya, China; 20180416 - 20180420 5 April 2018 (2018-04-05), XP051414760, Retrieved from the Internet: URL:http://www.3gpp.org/ftp/tsg%5Fran/WG2% 5FRL2/TSGR2%5F101bis/Docs/ [retrieved on 2018-04-05]</text></B562><B562><text>PANASONIC et al.: "Further Issues on Removing Optionality of CSI/SRS Transmission During Transient State", 3GPP TSG-RAN WG2 Meeting #81bis, R2-131503, 19 April 2013 (2013-04-19), XP050699604,</text></B562><B562><text>PANASONIC: "Further Issues on Removing Optionality of CSI/SRS Transmission During Transient State", 3GPP TSG-RAN WG2 Meeting #81bis, R2-131204, 19 April 2013 (2013-04-19), XP050699284,</text></B562><B565EP><date>20200709</date></B565EP></B560></B500><B700><B720><B721><snm>SHI, Cong</snm><adr><str>No. 18 Haibin Road, Wusha, Chang'an</str><city>Dongguan,  Guangdong 523860</city><ctry>CN</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>LIN, Yanan</snm><adr><str>No. 18 Haibin Road, Wusha, Chang'an</str><city>Dongguan,  Guangdong 523860</city><ctry>CN</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B730><B731><snm>GUANGDONG OPPO MOBILE TELECOMMUNICATIONS 
CORP., LTD.</snm><iid>101838366</iid><irf>G24740PWOEP</irf><adr><str>No. 18 Haibin Road</str><city>Wusha, Chang'an
Dongguan,
Guangdong 523860</city><ctry>CN</ctry></adr></B731></B730><B740><B741><snm>Manitz Finsterwald 
Patent- und Rechtsanwaltspartnerschaft mbB</snm><iid>100060405</iid><adr><str>Martin-Greif-Strasse 1</str><city>80336 München</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840><B860><B861><dnum><anum>CN2018081968</anum></dnum><date>20180404</date></B861><B862>zh</B862></B860><B870><B871><dnum><pnum>WO2019191954</pnum></dnum><date>20191010</date><bnum>201941</bnum></B871></B870></B800></SDOBI>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<heading id="h0001"><b>TECHNICAL FIELD</b></heading>
<p id="p0001" num="0001">Embodiments of the present application relate to the field of communications and in particular, relate to a method for transmitting information and a terminal device.</p>
<heading id="h0002"><b>BACKGROUND</b></heading>
<p id="p0002" num="0002">In Discontinuous Reception (DRX), if the terminal device is not in active Time, the terminal device will not report Channel State Information (CSI) or Sounding Reference Signal (SRS). And the terminal device which is in active Time may prolong the active Time or stop the active Time of the terminal device due to a piece of burst information, which may cause the terminal device to have insufficient time to determine whether to report CSI and/or SRS.</p>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">The document of <nplcit id="ncit0001" npl-type="s"><text>3GPP TSG-RAN WG2 #101 R2-1802147, entitled "Handling of the DRX Ambiguous Period</text></nplcit>", describes UE behaviors during the ORX ambiguous period, and the ambiguous period should be equal to the sum of the maximum time between the POCCH reception and the POSCH reception, The maximum POSCH processing time and the MAC CE processing time.</p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">The document of <nplcit id="ncit0002" npl-type="s"><text>3GPP TSG-RAN WG2 #Adhoc R2-1800166, entitled "Leftover Issues on DRX</text></nplcit>", describes UE behaviors when not in Active Time.</p>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">The document of <nplcit id="ncit0003" npl-type="s"><text>3GPP TS 38.321 V15.1.0, entitled "3rd Generation Partnership Project; Technical Specification Group Radio Access Network; NR; Medium Access Control (MAC) protocol specification (Release 15)</text></nplcit>", describes the NR MAC protocol, and specifically the document specifies the occasions that the MAC entity monitors the PDCCH in the DRX and determines to report the CSI of the PUCCH in different activation states.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p>
<heading id="h0003"><b>SUMMARY</b></heading>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">The present invention is defined in the independent claims. In view of this, the embodiments of the present application provide a method for transmitting information and a terminal device to enable the terminal device to have sufficient time to determine whether to report CSI and/or SRS.</p>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">In a first aspect, a method for transmitting information is provided, the method including: t receiving, by a terminal device, first information transmitted by a network device at an nth time unit, or transmitting, by the terminal device, the first information to the network device at the nth time unit, where the first information is used to indicate prolonging or stopping of an active Time of Discontinuous Reception (DRX); determining, by the terminal device, whether to report Channel State Information<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> (CSI) and/or Sounding Reference Signal (SRS) to the network device at an (n+m+q)th time unit, where m is determined based on a scheduling timing sequence set and/or an Acknowledgement(ACK)/ Negative acknowledgement (NACK) feedback timing sequence set, and the scheduling timing sequence set and the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set respectively include multiple values, where n is an integer, and q is any integer greater than or equal to 0.</p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">In a possible implementation, the method further includes: determining, by the terminal device, whether at the (n+m+q)th time unit the terminal device is in the active Time of the DRX; the determining, by the terminal device, whether to report Channel State Information (CSI) and/or Sounding Reference Signal (SRS) to the network device at an (n+m+q)th time unit includes: determining, by the terminal device, to report the CSI and/or SRS to the network device if at the (n+m+q)th time unit the terminal device is in the active Time of the DRX and in the case where CSI and/or SRS reporting is configured at the (n+m+q)th time unit; or determining, by the terminal device, not to report the CSI and/or SRS to the network device if at the (n+m+q)th time unit the terminal device is not in the active Time of the DRX.</p>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">In a possible implementation, the determining, by the terminal device, whether at the (n+m+q)th time unit the terminal device is in the active Time of the DRX includes: determining, by the terminal device, that at the (n+m+q)th time unit the terminal device is in the active Time of the DRX if the (n+m+q)th time unit is within a duration of a first timer, where start or restart of the first timer is triggered on the basis of the first information or second information which previously indicates to prolong the active Time of the DRX; or determining, by the terminal device, that at the (n+m+q)th time unit the terminal device is not in the active Time of the DRX if the (n+m+q)th time unit is a time unit after a timeout of the first timer.</p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">In a possible implementation, the first information is Downlink Control Information (DCI) for scheduling new transmission data or retransmission data, where m is a minimum value in the scheduling timing sequence set or any value in the scheduling timing sequence set indicated by the DCI.</p>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">In a possible implementation, the first information is a Medium Access Control<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> (MAC) Control Element (CE) signaling, where m is a minimum value in the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set or any value in the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set indicated by the first information.</p>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">In a possible implementation, the first information is a scheduling request, and m is a minimum value in the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set.</p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">In a possible implementation, the first information is downlink control information (DCI) for scheduling downlink data, and the method further includes: receiving, by the terminal device, a Physical Downlink data Sharing Channel (PDSCH) which carries the downlink data at an (n+p)th time unit, where p is a value of the scheduling timing sequence set, and the PDSCH includes a Medium Access Control (MAC) Control Element (CE) signaling, and the MAC CE is used to indicate to stop the active Time of the DRX; determining, by the terminal device, whether to report the CSI and/or SRS to the network device at an (n+p+r+x)th time unit, where r is a minimum value in the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set or any value of the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set indicated by the DCI, and x is any integer greater than or equal to 0.</p>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">In a possible implementation, a time unit is a time slot or an Orthogonal Frequency Division Multiplexing (OFDM) symbol.</p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">In a second aspect, a terminal device is provided for performing the methods of above first aspect or any of the possible implementations of the first aspect. In particular, the terminal device includes units for performing the methods of the above first aspect or any of the possible implementations of the first aspect.</p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016">In a third aspect, a terminal device is provided, the terminal device including: a memory, a processor, an input interface and an output interface, where the memory, the processor, the input interface and the output interface are connected by bus system. The memory is configured to store instructions, and the processor is configured to execute instructions stored in the memory to perform the methods of above first aspect or any of the possible implementations of the first aspect.</p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">In a fourth aspect, a computer memory medium is provided for storing computer software instructions for performing the methods of above first aspect or any of the<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> possible implementations of the first aspect, including programs designed for performing above aspects.</p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018">In a fifth aspect, a computer program product including instructions is provided, and when run on a computer, the computer program product causes the computer to perform the methods of above first aspect or any of implementations of the first aspect.</p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">These and other aspects of the present application will be more concise and understandable in the following description of the embodiments.</p>
<heading id="h0004"><b>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF DRAWINGS</b></heading>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li><figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic diagram of an application scenario according to an embodiment of the present application.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic diagram of another application scenario according to an embodiment of the present application.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic block diagram of a method for transmitting information according to an embodiment of the present application.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 4</figref> is another schematic block diagram of a method for transmitting information according to an embodiment of the present application.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0004">FIG. 5</figref> is yet another schematic block diagram of a method for transmitting information according to an embodiment of the present application.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0005">FIG. 6</figref> is yet another schematic block diagram of a method for transmitting information according to an embodiment of the present application.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0006">FIG. 7</figref> is a schematic block diagram of a terminal device of an embodiment of the present application.</li>
<li><figref idref="f0006">FIG. 8</figref> is another schematic block diagram of the terminal device according to an embodiment of the present application.</li>
</ul><!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p>
<heading id="h0005"><b>DESCRIPTION OF EMBODIMENTS</b></heading>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">The technical solutions in the embodiment of the present application will be clearly and completely described in the following with reference to the accompanying drawings in the embodiment of the present application.</p>
<p id="p0022" num="0022">It should be understood that the technical solutions of the embodiments of the present application can be applied to various communication systems, such as a Global System of Mobile communication (GSM) system, a Code Division Multiple Access (CDMA) system, Wideband Code Division Multiple Access (WCDMA) system, General Packet Radio Service (GPRS), Long Term Evolved (LTE) system, LTE Frequency Division Duplex (FDD) System, LTE Time Division Duplex (TDD), Universal Mobile Telecommunication System (UMTS), Worldwide Interoperability for Microwave Access (WiMAX) communication system, New Radio (NR) or future 5G systems, etc.</p>
<p id="p0023" num="0023">In particular, the technical solutions of the embodiments of the present application can be applied to various communication systems based on non-orthogonal multiple access technology, such as a Sparse Code Multiple Access (SCMA) system, and a Low Density Signature (LDS) system, etc. Of course, the SCMA system and the LDS system may also be referred to as other names in the communication field; further, the technical solutions of the embodiment of the present application can be applied to multi-carrier transmission system using non-orthogonal multiple access technology, for example, Orthogonal Frequency Division Multiplexing (OFDM) which uses non-orthogonal multiple access technology, Filter Bank Multi-Carrier (FBMC), General Frequency Division Multiplexing (GFDM), Filtered-OFDM (F-OFDM) system, etc.</p>
<p id="p0024" num="0024">The terminal device in the embodiment of the present application may refer to a User Equipment (UE), an access terminal, a user unit, a user station, a mobile radio station, a mobile station, a remote station, a remote terminal, a mobile device, a user terminal, a terminal, and a wireless communication device, user agent or user apparatus. The access terminal may be a cellular phone, a cordless phone, a Session<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> Initiation Protocol (SIP) phone, a Wireless Local Loop (WLL) station, a Personal Digital Assistant (PDA), an handheld device with wireless communication functions, computing equipment or other processing equipment connected to wireless modems, vehicle equipment, wearable device, terminal device in future 5G networks, terminal device in the future evolution of the Public Land Mobile Network (PLMN), or the like, which is not limited in the embodiment of the present application.</p>
<p id="p0025" num="0025">The network device in the embodiment of the present application may be an equipment for communicating with a terminal device, where the network device may be a Base Transceiver Station (BTS) in GSM or CDMA, a NodeB (NB) in a WCDMA system, an Evolutional NodeB (eNB or eNodeB) in the LTE system, or a wireless controller in a Cloud Radio Access Network (CRAN) scenario, or the network device may be a relay station, an access point, a vehicle equipment, a wearable device, a network device in the future 5G network, a network device in the future evolutional PLMN network, or the like, which is not limited in embodiment of the present application.</p>
<p id="p0026" num="0026">In a wireless network, when there is data to be transmitted, the UE will always monitor the Physical Downlink Control Channel (PDCCH), receive and transmit the data according to the indication message transmitted by the network side, which results in a large power consumption and data transmission delay of the UE. Therefore, the 3rd Generation Partnership Project (3GPP) standard protocol introduces Discontinuous Reception (DRX) energy saving strategy into the LTE system, where the DRX energy saving strategy is defined in the physical layer Media Access Control (MAC).</p>
<p id="p0027" num="0027">In the existing MAC layer protocol, to report CSI and SRS is described as follows: in DRX, if the terminal device is not in the active Time, the terminal device will not report the SRS or the CSI.</p>
<p id="p0028" num="0028">The active Time of the DRX refers to the total time in which the UE stays awake after waking up from the DRX. During this time period, the UE monitors the PDCCH, including all states that cause the UE to be in an active state, such as the start of the DRX cycle, or the reception of initial transmitted PDCCH, monitoring of<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> retransmission, or the like. The current protocol includes the following cases:
<ol id="ol0001" compact="compact" ol-style="">
<li>1. Running times of on Duration Timer, the DRX-Inactivity Timer, the DRX-Retransmission Timer, and the MAC-Contention Resolution Timer;</li>
<li>2. There is a scheduling Request (SR) which has been transmitted to the Physical Uplink Control Channel (PUCCH) and is in a suspended state (that is, the scheduling request has not been met, and so on);</li>
<li>3. There is an uplink grant for a suspended hybrid automatic repeat quest (HARQ) retransmission, and there is data in the corresponding HARQ buffer;</li>
<li>4. After the non-contention random access, the random access response message is successfully received; at this time, there should be a PDCCH transmitted to the UE to indicate a new transmission. though the PDCCH has not been received yet by the UE, and at this time the UE must be in the active state.</li>
</ol></p>
<p id="p0029" num="0029">Based on the behavior of reporting CSI and/or SRS as specified by the current protocol, the active Time may suddenly be prolonged or stopped due to a piece of burst information. Since the UE may not synchronize with the network, the following problems may occur:
<ol id="ol0002" compact="compact" ol-style="">
<li>1. The suddenly prolonged active Time may cause the UE to fail to report CSI and/or SRS at the active Time, where the CSI and/or SRS reporting is originally configured in the active Time.</li>
<li>2. The sudden stop of the active Time may cause the terminal to continue to report CSI and/or SRS during the inactive time.</li>
</ol></p>
<p id="p0030" num="0030">The reason why the above problems occur will be analyzed in detail below with reference to <figref idref="f0001">FIGs. 1</figref> and <figref idref="f0002">2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0031" num="0031">As shown in <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, the UE may start or restart the inactive timer from the time unit n. It is assumed that the length of the inactive timer is 2 time units, and the UE considers that the terminal device terminates inactive timer at the time unit (n+1). The network side receives the PDCCH for scheduling data in the time unit n and the time unit (n+1). However, the UE is not synchronized with network side about the transmission and reception, which renders the UE unaware that the inactive timer is restarted at the time unit (n+1); while for the time unit (n+2) at which CSI and/or SRS<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> reporting is configured, the UE considers that it is in an inactive state at the time unit (n+2), Therefore, the UE may not report CSI and/or SRS at the time unit (n+2).</p>
<p id="p0032" num="0032">As shown in <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>, the UE may start or restart the inactive timer from the time unit n. It is assumed that the length of the inactive timer is 2 time units, and the UE considers that the terminal device terminates inactive timer at the time unit (n+1). The network side receives a Media Access Control Control Element (MAC CE) carrying a Physical Downlink Shared Channel (PDSCH) at the time unit n and the time unit (n+1). The UE is not synchronized with network side about the transmission and reception, which renders the UE unaware that the inactive timer has been stopped at the time unit (n+1); while for the time unit (n+1) at which CSI and/or SRS reporting is configured, the UE considers that it is in an active state at the time unit (n+1). Therefore, the UE may report CSI and/or SRS at the time unit (n+1).</p>
<p id="p0033" num="0033">Therefore, the embodiment of the present application provides a method for transmitting information in view of the above problems. The technical solutions of the embodiments of the present application will be described in detail below.</p>
<p id="p0034" num="0034"><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic block diagram of a method for transmitting information according to an embodiment of the present application. As shown in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref>, the method 100 includes some or all of the following contents:
<ul id="ul0002" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>S110, the terminal device receives first information transmitted by a network device at an nth time unit, or transmits first information to a network device at an nth time unit, where the first information is used to indicate prolonging or stopping of an active Time of Discontinuous Reception (DRX);</li>
<li>S120, the terminal device determines whether to report Channel State Information (CSI) and/or Sounding Reference Signal (SRS) to the network device at an (n+m+q)th time unit, where m is determined based on the scheduling timing sequence set and/or ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set; the scheduling timing sequence set and the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set respectively include multiple values, where n is an integer, and m and q are any integers greater than or equal to 0.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0035" num="0035">In the embodiment of the present application, a time unit may be a slot, an<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> Orthogonal Frequency-Division Multiplexing (OFDM) symbol or other time domain unit. The slot is taken as example in many places for description, but the embodiment of the present application is not limited thereto.</p>
<p id="p0036" num="0036">In LTE, the period from the time the terminal device receives the data PDSCH to the time the terminal feeds back in response to the PDSCH is 4 ms, therefore the terminal device can determine whether to perform CSI and/or SRS 4 ms or more in advance. That is to say, 4 ms is sufficient for the terminal device to determine whether the PDCCH is successfully detected, and whether the PDSCH is successfully detected. For example, the time amount in advance can be determined to be 5 ms.</p>
<p id="p0037" num="0037">In NR, there are several points differing from LTE:
<ol id="ol0003" compact="compact" ol-style="">
<li>1. The PDCCH and its scheduled PDSCH may not be in one slot; the time between the PDCCH and its scheduled PDSCH is represented by the scheduling timing sequence set k0, for example, k0 may take {0, 1, 2, 3} slots, and may be configured by Radio Resource Control (RRC); while in LTE, k0 is 0, that is, the PDCCH and the PDSCH are in the same slot;</li>
<li>2. The time between reception of the PDSCH and the feedback of ACK/NACK is no longer fixed; the time between reception of the PDSCH by the UE and the feedback ACK/NACK by the UE is represented by the acknowledgement (ACK)/Negative Acknowledgement (NACK) feedback timing sequence set k1; this set can also be configured with a set of values by RRC and indicated by DCI; if it is not indicated by the DCI, the time may be 4 slots by default.</li>
</ol></p>
<p id="p0038" num="0038">In the embodiment of the present application, the method further includes: the terminal device determines whether at the (n+m+q)th time unit the terminal device is in the active Time of the DRX; that the terminal device determines whether to report the Channel State Information CSI and/or the Sounding Reference Signal SRS to the network device at the (n+m+q)th time unit includes: if at the (n+m+q)th time unit, the terminal device is in the active Time of the DRX, in the case where CSI and/or SRS reporting is configured at the (n+m+q)th time unit, the terminal device determines to report CSI and/or SRS to the network device; or if at the (n+m+q)th time, the terminal device is not in the active Time of the DRX, the terminal device determines not to<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> report the CSI and/or SRS to the network device.</p>
<p id="p0039" num="0039">In the embodiment of the present application, that the terminal device determines whether at the (n+m+q)th time unit the terminal device is in the active Time of the DRX includes: if the (n+m+q)th time unit is within the duration of the first timer, the terminal device determines that at the (n+m+q)th time unit, the terminal device is in the active Time of the DRX, where the start or restart of the first timer is triggered on the basis of the first information, or the second information which previously indicates to prolong the active Time of the DRX; or if the (n+m+q)th time unit is a time unit after the timeout of the first timer, the terminal device determines that, at the (n+m+q)th time unit, the terminal device is not in the active Time of DRX.</p>
<p id="p0040" num="0040">The terminal device can determine the value m based on the scheduling timing sequence set and/or the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set. For example, as shown in <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, the terminal device receives the PDCCH of the scheduling data at the time unit n, and the scheduling timing sequence set configured by the network side for the terminal device is {0, 1, 2, 3} time units; the PDCCH transmitted at the time unit n indicates the "1" in the scheduling timing sequence set to the terminal device, that is to say, the terminal device should receive the PDSCH at the time unit n+1, so that it can be confirmed that the PDCCH is successfully detected at the time unit n+1, then the terminal device can determine at the time unit n whether to report the CSI and/or the SRS at the time unit n+1 and after the time unit n+1, where the m in the embodiment of the present application is 1. As shown in <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>, the terminal device receives the PDSCH carrying the MAC CE at the time unit n, where the MAC CE can be used to indicate to stop the active Time of the DRX. The ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set configured by the network side for the terminal device is {0, 1, 2, 3} time units, and the terminal device may feed back the ACK/NACK information for the PDSCH to the network device in the time unit n+1, then it can be considered that the PDSCH is successfully detected by the terminal device at the time unit n+1, that is to say, the MAC CE is successfully detected, and the terminal device can determine at time unit n whether to report the CSI and/or the SRS at the time unit n+1 and after the time unit n+1, where m in the embodiment of the present application<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> is 1.</p>
<p id="p0041" num="0041">The terminal device may accord to the first information that is received by the network device or transmitted to the network device. For example, the first information may be Downlink Control Information (DCI) for scheduling new transmission or retransmission, or a Scheduling Request (SR) for requesting uplink transmission resources, or may be a MAC CE, such as a DRX MA CE command or a long DRX CE command, etc.</p>
<p id="p0042" num="0042">In an implementation, if the first information is Downlink Control Information (DCI) for scheduling new transmission data or retransmission data, then m is a minimum value in the scheduling timing sequence set or any value in the scheduling timing sequence set indicated by the DCI. For example, if the scheduling timing set k0 is {0, 1, 2, 3}, then the m may be 0; if the DCI indicates 1 in the k0, then the m is 1.</p>
<p id="p0043" num="0043">It should be noted that the data scheduled by the DCI may be downlink data of PDSCH, or uplink data of Physical Uplink Shared Channel (PUSCH), which is not limited in this embodiment of the present application.</p>
<p id="p0044" num="0044">In an implementation, if the first information is the Medium Access Control (MAC) Control Element (CE) signaling, where m is a minimum value in the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set or any value in the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set indicated by the first information. For example, if the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set k1 is {0, 1, 2, 3}, then the m may be 0; if the DCI indicates 1 in the k1, then the m is 1.</p>
<p id="p0045" num="0045">In an implementation, the first information is a scheduling request, where m is a minimum value in the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set. For example, if the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set k1 is {0, 1, 2, 3}, then the m may be 0.</p>
<p id="p0046" num="0046">It should be noted that, each time the terminal device receives the first information or transmits the first information to the network device, the terminal device needs to determine whether it needs to report CSI and/or SRS for the mth time unit after the time unit n and the following time unit at which time the first information is received or transmitted. And each determination will overwrite the<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> previous determination result. In other words, the solution of the embodiment of the present application can determine in advance whether the CSI and/or the SRS can be reported at each time unit in the time domain.</p>
<p id="p0047" num="0047">In the embodiment of the present application, the first information is downlink control information (DCI) for scheduling downlink data, and the method further includes: the terminal device receives the Physical Downlink data Sharing Channel (PDSCH) that carries the downlink data at the (n+p)th time unit, where p is a value of the scheduling timing sequence set, and the PDSCH includes a Medium Access Control (MAC) Control Element (CE) signaling, and the MAC CE is used to indicate to stop the active Time of the DRX; the terminal device determines whether to report the CSI and/or SRS to the network device at (n+p+r+x)th time unit, where r is a minimum value in the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set or any value of the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set indicated by the DCI; p, r and x are any integers greater than or equal to zero.</p>
<p id="p0048" num="0048">Specifically, the terminal device may receive the PDCCH for scheduling the downlink data at the time unit n, and the terminal device may restart the inactive timer. It is assumed that the length of the inactive timer is y time units, and the terminal device receives PDSCH at the time unit (n+p) according to the scheduling timing sequence set, where the PDSCH includes MAC CE, and p is less than or equal to y, that is to say, the time unit (n+p) is within the length of the inactive timer, then the terminal device can determine in advance at the time unit (n+p) whether to report the CSI and/or SRS to the network device at the time unit (n+p+r) and the following time unit, where r is a minimum value in the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set configured according to the network device or any value in the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set indicated by the PDCCH.</p>
<p id="p0049" num="0049">Embodiments 1 to 3 of the present application will be described in detail below with reference to <figref idref="f0003 f0004 f0005">FIGs. 4 to 6</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0050" num="0050">Embodiment 1: as shown in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 4</figref>, the UE receives a PDCCH in a current slot (such as n), and starts an inactive timer, and the PDCCH schedules new transmission data (possibly uplink or downlink); in the M slots after the current slot n (in this<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> embodiment, the downlink scheduling timing sequence is 2 slots, that is to say, the PDCCH differs from the corresponding PDSCH by 2 slots), the UE determines the (n+2)th slot and whether to report the CSI and/or SRS; if in the (n+2)th slot and the following slots, the UE is estimated to be in active Time (in this embodiment, the length of one inactive timer is 4 slots), if CSI and/or SRS reporting is configured in the slot, the UE reports CSI and/or SRS, such as in slot (n+2) and slot (n+3); if in the (n+2)th slot and following slots, the UE is estimated not to be in active Time, even if CSI and/or SRS reporting is configured in the slot, the UE does not report CSI and/or SRS, such as in slot (n+4), where m is decided by the scheduling timing sequence set k0 of the high-layer configuration, and if k0 includes multiple values, then m is the minimum value of k0, and m may also be a fixed value specified in a protocol, but the fixed value is related to the scheduling timing sequence; the above criteria applies to the DCI which receives scheduling data each time.</p>
<p id="p0051" num="0051">Embodiment 2: as shown in <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 5</figref>, the UE receives the downlink data scheduled by PDCCH in the current slot (such as n), and the scheduled PDSCH and PDCCH are in the same slot, and the PDSCH includes the DRX MAC CE command or the long DRX MAC CE command; then the active Time is suddenly stopped at the slot, and the terminal determines in the slot n that CSI and/or SRS should not be reported after the m slots (m is 2 in this embodiment, that is to say, the PDSCH differs from the corresponding ACK/NACK by 2 slots); in this embodiment, the terminal determines that in n+2 and following slots, CSI and/or SRS are not to be reported (even if the reporting is configured); where m is decided by the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set k1 of the high-layer configuration; if k1 includes multiple values, then m is the minimum value in k1; and m may also be a fixed value specified in a protocol, but the fixed value is related to the scheduling timing sequence.</p>
<p id="p0052" num="0052">Embodiment 3: as shown in <figref idref="f0005">FIG. 6</figref>, the UE receives a PDCCH in a current time slot (such as n), and the PDCCH schedules new downlink data, and the downlink data and the PDCCH are not in a slot, and the downlink data includes a DRX MAC. CE command or long DRX MAC CE command; in this embodiment, the PDCCH is in n slots, and the scheduled PDSCH is in n+2 slots (that is to say, the PDCCH differs<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> from the corresponding PDSCH by 2 slots); the UE determines at the current slot n whether to report the CSI and/or SRS in the m slots (in the present embodiment, x=2 slots) after the current slot and the following slots.</p>
<p id="p0053" num="0053">If in the (n+2)th slot and the following slots, the UE is estimated to be in the active Time, and if CSI and/or SRS reporting is configured in the slot, the UE reports CSI and/or SRS; in this embodiment, since the length of the inactive timer is 6 slots, slots from n+2 to n+5 are all estimated to be in active Time; if in the (n+2)th slot and following slots, the UE is estimated not to be in active Time, even if CSI and/or SRS reporting is configured in the slot, and the UE does not report CSI and/or SRS; for example, in slot n+6 and the following slots.</p>
<p id="p0054" num="0054">In the slot when the MAC CE is received, it is also determined whether, after the r slots, the UE is in active Time (in this embodiment r is 2, that is to say, the PDSCH differs from the corresponding ACK/NACK by 2 slots); then the UE at slot n+2 determines that slot n+4 and following slots are estimated not to be in active Time state. This determination replaces the previous determination, that is, n+4 and n+5 are re-determined to be not in active Time, that is to say, CSI and/or SRS are not to be reported in slot n+4 and following slots (even if the reporting is configured).</p>
<p id="p0055" num="0055">The determination time m after the PDCCH is received is decided by the high-level configuration k0, and the determination time r after the MAC CE is received is decided by the high-level configuration k1, and m and r may also be fixed values specified in a protocol, and they also may be equal..</p>
<p id="p0056" num="0056">It should be understood that the interaction, related characteristics, functions and the like between the network device and the terminal device described with reference to the network side correspond to related characteristics and functions of the terminal device. The related content has been described in detail in the above method 100, which for brevity, will not be repeated here.</p>
<p id="p0057" num="0057">It should also be understood that, in various embodiments of the present application, the serial numbers of the above processes does not mean the order for performing the process, and the order for performing the respective processes should be determined by the function and internal logic, and should not limit the<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> implementing process of the embodiment of the present application.</p>
<p id="p0058" num="0058">The method for transmitting information according to an embodiment of the present application is described in detail above, and apparatus for transmitting information according to an embodiment of the present application will be described below with reference to <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 7 and FIG. 8</figref>, and the technical features described in the method embodiments are applicable to the following apparatus embodiment.</p>
<p id="p0059" num="0059"><figref idref="f0006">FIG. 7</figref> is a schematic block diagram of a terminal device 200 of an embodiment of the present application. As shown in <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 7</figref>, the terminal device 200 includes
<ul id="ul0003" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li>a communicating unit 210, configured to receive the first information transmitted by network device, or transmitted to the network device at the nth time unit, where the first information is used to indicate prolonging or stopping of the active Time of the DRX;</li>
<li>a determining unit 220, configured to determine whether to report the Channel State Information (CSI) and/or the Sounding Reference Signal (SRS) to the network device at the (n+m+q)th time unit, where m is determined based on the scheduling timing sequence set and/or ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set, and the scheduling timing sequence set and the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set respectively include multiple values, and q is any integer greater than or equal to 0.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0060" num="0060">Therefore, the terminal device of the embodiment of the present application enables the terminal device to have sufficient time to determine whether to report the CSI and/or SRS.</p>
<p id="p0061" num="0061">In the embodiment of the present application, the determining unit is further configured to determine whether at the (n+m+q)th time unit the terminal device is in the active Time of the DRX; the determining unit is specifically configured to determine to report CSI and/or SRS to the network device if at the (n+m+q)th time unit, the terminal device is in the active Time of the DRX and in the case where CSI and/or SRS reporting is configured at the (n+m+q)th time unit; or determine not to report the CSI and/or SRS to the network device if at the (n+m+q)th time the terminal device is not in the active Time of the DRX.</p>
<p id="p0062" num="0062">In the embodiment of the present application, the determining unit is specifically<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> configured to determine that, at the (n+m+q)th time unit, the terminal device is in the active Time of the DRX if the (n+m+q)th time unit is within the duration of the first timer, where the start or restart of the first timer is triggered on the basis of the first information or the second information that previously indicates to prolong the active Time of the DRX; or determine that at the (n+m+q)th time unit the terminal device is not in the active Time of DRX if the (n+m+q)th time unit is a time unit after the timeout of the first timer.</p>
<p id="p0063" num="0063">In the embodiment of the present application, the first information is Downlink Control Information (DCI) for scheduling new transmission data or retransmission data, where m is a minimum value in the scheduling timing sequence set or any value in the scheduling timing sequence set indicated by the DCI.</p>
<p id="p0064" num="0064">In the embodiment of the present application, the first information is a Medium Access Control (MAC) Control Element (CE) signaling, where m is a minimum value in the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set or any value in the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set indicated by the first information.</p>
<p id="p0065" num="0065">In the embodiment of the present application, the first information is a scheduling request, where m is a minimum value in the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set.</p>
<p id="p0066" num="0066">In the embodiment of the present application, the first information is Downlink Control Information (DCI) for scheduling downlink data, and the communicating unit is further configured to receive the Physical Downlink data Sharing Channel (PDSCH) that carries the downlink data at the (n+p)th time unit, where p is a value of the scheduling timing sequence set, and the PDSCH includes a Medium Access Control (MAC) Control Element (CE) signaling, and the MAC CE is used to indicate to stop the active Time of the DRX; the determining unit is further configured to determine whether to report the CSI and/or SRS to the network device at (n+p+r+x)th time unit, where r is a minimum value in the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set or any value of the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set indicated by the DCI, x is any integer greater than or equal to zero.</p>
<p id="p0067" num="0067">In the embodiment of the present application, a time unit is a time slot or an<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> Orthogonal Frequency Division Multiplexing (OFDM) symbol.</p>
<p id="p0068" num="0068">It should be understood that the terminal device 200 according to the embodiment of the present application may correspond to the terminal device in the method embodiment of the present application, and the above and other operations and/or functions of the units in the terminal device 200 are respectively intended to achieve the corresponding process of the terminal device in the method of <figref idref="f0003 f0004 f0005">FIG. 3 to FIG. 6</figref>, which for brevity, will not be repeated here.</p>
<p id="p0069" num="0069">As shown in <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 8</figref>, the embodiment of the present application further provides the terminal device 300, which may be the terminal device 200 in <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 7</figref>, and can be configured to perform the content of the terminal device corresponding to the method 100 in <figref idref="f0003">FIG.3</figref>. The terminal device 300 includes: an input interface 310, an output interface 320, a processor 330, and a memory 340. The input interface 310, the output interface 320, the processor 330, and the memory 340 can be connected by bus system. The memory 340 is configured to store programs, instructions or codes. The processor 330 is configured to perform programs, instructions or codes in the memory 340 to control the input interface 310 to receive signals, control the output interface 320 to transmit signals, and complete the operations in the foregoing method embodiments.</p>
<p id="p0070" num="0070">Therefore, the terminal device of the embodiment of the present application enables the terminal device to have sufficient time to determine whether to report the CSI and/or SRS.</p>
<p id="p0071" num="0071">It should be understood that in the embodiment of the present application, the processor 330 may be a Central Processing Unit (CPU), and the processor 330 may also be other general purpose processors, digital signal processors, application specific integrated circuits, and field programmable gate array or other programmable logic device, discrete gates or transistor logic device, discrete hardware components, etc. The general purpose processor may be a microprocessor or the processor can be any conventional processor, etc.</p>
<p id="p0072" num="0072">The memory 340 can include a read-only memory and a random access memory, and provide instructions and data to the processor 330. A part of the memory 340 may also include a non-volatile random access memory. For example, the memory 340 can<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> also store information of the device type.</p>
<p id="p0073" num="0073">In the process of implementation, the content of the above method may be completed by an integrated logic circuit of hardware or an instruction in a form of software in the processor 330. The content of the method disclosed with reference to the embodiments of the present application may be directly completed by a hardware processor or by a combination of hardware and software modules in the processor. The software module can be located in a mature memory medium in the field such as random access memory, flash memory, read only memory, programmable read only memory or electrically erasable programmable memory, registers, and the like. The memory medium is located in the memory 340, and the processor 330 reads the information in the memory 340 and completes the contents of the above method in combination with its hardware. To avoid repetition, details will not be described herein.</p>
<p id="p0074" num="0074">In a specific embodiment, the communicating unit in the terminal device 200 can be implemented by the input interface 310 and the output interface 320 in <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 8</figref>, and the determining unit in the terminal device 200 can be implemented by the processor 330 in <figref idref="f0006">FIG. 8</figref>.</p>
<p id="p0075" num="0075">Those ordinary skilled in the art will realize that the units and algorithm steps of the various examples described in combination with the embodiments disclosed herein can be implemented by electronic hardware or a combination of computer software and electronic hardware. Whether these functions are performed in hardware or software depends on the specific application and design constraint condition of the technical solution. Professional skilled in the art can use different methods to implement the described functions for each particular application, but such implementation should not be considered beyond the scope of the present application.</p>
<p id="p0076" num="0076">Those skilled in the art can clearly understand that for the convenience and brevity of the description, as to the specific working process of the system, the apparatus and the unit described above, reference can be made to the corresponding process in the foregoing method embodiment, which will not be repeated herein.</p>
<p id="p0077" num="0077">In the several embodiments provided by the present application, it should be<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> understood that the disclosed systems, apparatuses, and methods may be implemented in other ways. For example, the apparatus embodiments described above are merely illustrative, for example, the division of the unit is only a logical function division, in actual implementation, there may be other division manners, for example, multiple units or components may be combined or may be integrated into another system, or some features can be ignored or not performed. On the other hand, the mutual coupling or direct coupling or communication connection shown or discussed may be an indirect coupling or communication connection through some interfaces, apparatuses or units, and may be in electrical, mechanical or other forms.</p>
<p id="p0078" num="0078">The units described as separate components may or may not be physically separated, and the components displayed as units may or may not be physical units, that is, the components may be located in one place, or may be distributed to multiple network units. Some or all of the units may be selected according to actual needs to achieve the purpose of the solution of the embodiment.</p>
<p id="p0079" num="0079">In addition, respective functional units in embodiments of the present application may be integrated into one processing unit, or each unit may exist physically separately, or two or more units may be integrated into one unit.</p>
<p id="p0080" num="0080">This function can be stored on a computer readable memory medium, if the function is implemented in the form of a software function unit and sold or used as an independent product. Based on such understanding, the technical solution of the present application in essence or a part that contributes to the prior art, or a part of the technical solution, may be embodied in the form of a software product which is stored in a memory medium, where the memory medium includes a number of instructions are used to cause a computer device (which may be a personal computer, server, or network device, etc.) to perform all or part of the steps of each embodiment of the present application. The foregoing memory medium includes: a USB drive, a mobile hard disk, a Read-Only Memory (ROM), a Random Access Memory (RAM), a magnetic disk, an optical disk, or other media which can store program codes.</p>
<p id="p0081" num="0081">The foregoing is only a specific embodiment of the present application, but the scope of protection of the present application is not limited to this. Any skilled in the<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> art that are familiar with the art can readily think of changes or substitutions within the technical scope disclosed in the present application. Therefore, the scope of protection of the present application should be determined by the scope of protection of the claims.</p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> -->
<claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>A method for transmitting information, comprising:
<claim-text>receiving (S110), by a terminal device, first information sent by a network device at an nth time unit, or sending, by a terminal device, second information to the network device at an nth time unit, wherein the first information and the second information are used to indicate prolonging or stopping of an active Time of Discontinuous Reception, DRX;</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>characterized in that</b> the method further comprises:
<claim-text>determining (S120), by the terminal device in advance, whether to report at least one of Channel State Information, CSI, and Sounding Reference Signal, SRS, to the network device at an (n+m+q)th time unit, wherein m is determined based on at least one of a scheduling timing sequence set and an Acknowledgement, ACK/ Negative Acknowledgement, NACK, feedback timing sequence set, and the scheduling timing sequence set and the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set respectively comprise multiple values, wherein n is an integer, and wherein m are any integers greater than 0 or equal to 0, and q=1, 2, 3, ..., Q, wherein Q are any integers greater than 1;</claim-text>
<claim-text>reporting, by the terminal device, the at least one of CSI and SRS to the network device at the (n+m+q)th time unit, if determining to report the at least one of CSI and SRS to the network device at the (n+m+q)th time unit.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>The method according to claim 1, wherein the method further comprises:
<claim-text>determining, by the terminal device in advance, whether at the (n+m+q)th time unit the terminal device is in the active Time of the DRX;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the determining (S120), by the terminal device in advance, whether to report at least one of Channel State Information, CSI, and Sounding Reference Signal, SRS, to the network device at an (n+m+q)th time unit comprises:
<claim-text>determining, by the terminal device in advance, to report at least one of the CSI and SRS to the network device if at the (n+m+q)th time unit the terminal device is in<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> the active Time of the DRX and in the case where at least one of CSI reporting and SRS reporting is configured at the (n+m+q)th time unit; or</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining, by the terminal device in advance, not to report at least one of the CSI and SRS to the network device if at the (n+m+q)th time unit the terminal device is not in the active Time of the DRX.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>The method according to claim 2, wherein the determining, by the terminal device in advance, whether at the (n+m+q)th time unit the terminal device is in the active Time of the DRX comprises:
<claim-text>determining, by the terminal device in advance, that at the (n+m+q)th time unit the terminal device is in the active Time of the DRX if the (n+m+q)th time unit is within a duration of a first timer, wherein start or restart of the first timer is triggered on the basis of the first information or the second information or information which previously indicates to prolong the active Time of the DRX; or</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining, by the terminal device in advance, that at the (n+m+q)th time unit the terminal device is not in the active Time of the DRX if the (n+m+q)th time unit is a time unit after a timeout of the first timer.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>The method according to any one of claims 1 to 3, wherein the first information is Downlink Control Information, DCI, for scheduling new transmission data or retransmission data, wherein m is a minimum value in the scheduling timing sequence set or any value in the scheduling timing sequence set indicated by the DCI.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>The method according to any one of claims 1 to 3, wherein the first information is a Medium Access Control, MAC, Control Element, CE, signaling, wherein m is a minimum value in the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set or any value in the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set indicated by the first information.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>The method according to any one of claims 1 to 3, wherein the second information is a scheduling request, and m is a minimum value in the ACK/NACK<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> feedback timing sequence set.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>The method according to any one of claims 1 to 4, wherein the first information is downlink control information, DCI, for scheduling downlink data, and the method further comprises:
<claim-text>receiving, by the terminal device, a Physical Downlink data Sharing Channel PDSCH, which carries the downlink data at an (n+p)th time unit, wherein p is a value of the scheduling timing sequence set, and the PDSCH comprises a Medium Access Control, MAC, Control Element, CE, signaling, and the MAC CE is used to indicate to stop the active Time of the DRX;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining, by the terminal device, whether to report at least one of the CSI and SRS to the network device at an (n+p+r+x)th time unit, wherein r is a minimum value in the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set or any value of the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set indicated by the DCI, and p, r and x are any integers greater than or equal to 0.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>A terminal device (200), comprising:
<claim-text>a communicating unit (210), configured to receive first information sent by a network device at an nth time unit, or send second information to a network device at an nth time unit, wherein the first information and the second information are used to indicate prolonging or stopping of an active Time of Discontinuous Reception, DRX;</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>characterized by</b> further comprising:
<claim-text>a determining unit (220), configured to determine in advance whether to report at least one of Channel State Information, CSI, and Sounding Reference Signal, SRS, to the network device at an (n+m+q)th time unit, wherein m is determined based on at least one of a scheduling timing sequence set and an Acknowledgement, ACK/ Negative Acknowledgement, NACK, feedback timing sequence set, and the scheduling timing sequence set and the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set respectively comprise multiple values, wherein n is an integer, and wherein m are any integers greater than or equal to 0, and q=1, 2, 3, ..., Q, wherein Q are any integers greater than<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> 1;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the communicating unit (210) is further configured to report the at least one of CSI and SRS to the network device at the (n+m+q)th time unit, if determine to report the at least one of CSI and SRS to the network device at the (n+m+q)th time unit.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>The terminal device (200) according to claim 8, wherein the determining unit (220) is further configured to:
<claim-text>determine in advance whether at the (n+m+q)th time unit the terminal device is in the active Time of the DRX;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the determining unit (220) is specifically configured to:
<claim-text>determine in advance to report at least one of the CSI and SRS to the network device if at the (n+m+q)th time unit the terminal device is in the active Time of the DRX and in the case where at least one of CSI reporting and SRS reporting is configured at the (n+m+q)th time unit; or</claim-text>
<claim-text>determine in advance not to report at least one of the CSI and SRS to the network device if at the (n+m+q)th time unit the terminal device is not in the active Time of the DRX.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>The terminal device (200) according to claim 9, wherein the determining unit (220) is specifically configured to:
<claim-text>determine in advance that at the (n+m+q)th time unit the terminal device is in the active Time of the DRX if the (n+m+q)th time unit is within a duration of a first timer, wherein start or restart of the first timer is triggered on the basis of the first information or the second information or information which previously indicates to prolong the active Time of the DRX; or</claim-text>
<claim-text>determine in advance that at the (n+m+q)th time unit the terminal device is not in the active Time of the DRX if the (n+m+q)th time unit is a time unit after a timeout of the first timer.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>The terminal device (200) according to any one of claims 8 to 10, wherein the<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> first information is Downlink Control Information, DCI, for scheduling new transmission data or retransmission data, wherein m is a minimum value in the scheduling timing sequence set or any value in the scheduling timing sequence set indicated by the DCI.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>The terminal device (200) according to any one of claims 8 to 10, wherein the first information is a Medium Access Control, MAC, Control Element, CE, signaling, wherein m is a minimum value in the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set or any value in the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set indicated by the first information.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>The terminal device (200) according to any one of claims 8 to 10, wherein the second information is a scheduling request, and m is a minimum value in the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>The terminal device (200) according to any one of claims 8 to 11, wherein the first information is downlink control information, DCI, for scheduling downlink data, and the communicating unit (210) is further configured to:
<claim-text>receive a Physical Downlink data Sharing Channel, PDSCH , which carries the downlink data at an (n+p)th time unit, wherein p is a value of the scheduling timing sequence set, and the PDSCH comprises a Medium Access Control, MAC, Control Element, CE, signaling, and the MAC CE is used to indicate to stop the active Time of the DRX;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the determining unit (220) is further configured to:<br/>
determine in advance whether to report at least one of the CSI and SRS to the network device at an (n+p+r+x)th time unit, wherein r is a minimum value in the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set or any value of the ACK/NACK feedback timing sequence set indicated by the DCI, and p, r and x are any integers greater than or equal to 0.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-01-0015" num="0015">
<claim-text>The terminal device (200) according to any one of claims 8 to 14, wherein a time unit is a time slot or an Orthogonal Frequency Division Multiplexing, OFDM, symbol.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims02" lang="de"><!-- EPO <DP n="28"> -->
<claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Verfahren zum Übertragen von Informationen, umfassend:
<claim-text>Empfangen (S110) von ersten Informationen, die durch eine Netzwerkvorrichtung zu einer n-ten Zeiteinheit gesendet werden, durch eine Endgerätevorrichtung, oder Senden von zweiten Informationen an die Netzwerkvorrichtung zu einer n-ten Zeiteinheit, wobei die ersten Informationen und die zweiten Informationen dazu verwendet werden, das Verlängern oder Anhalten einer aktiven Zeit des diskontinuierlichen Empfangs, DRX, anzugeben;</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> das Verfahren ferner umfasst: Bestimmen (S120) durch die Endgerätevorrichtung im Voraus, ob mindestens eines von Kanalzustandsinformationen, CSI, und Sondierungsreferenzsignal, SRS, zu einer (n+m+q)-ten Zeiteinheit an die Netzwerkvorrichtung zu melden ist, wobei m basierend auf mindestens einem von einem Zeitplanungszeitfolgesatz und einem Bestätigungs-/Negativbestätigungs-, ACK/NACK-, Rückmeldungszeitfolgesatz bestimmt wird, und der Zeitplanungszeitfolgesatz und der ACK/NACK-Rückmeldungszeitfolgesatz jeweils mehrere Werte umfassen, wobei n eine ganze Zahl ist und wobei m beliebige ganze Zahlen größer als 0 oder gleich 0 sind, und q=1, 2, 3, ... , Q, wobei Q beliebige ganze Zahlen größer als 1 sind;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Melden des mindestens einen von CSI und SRS durch die Endgerätevorrichtung an die Netzwerkvorrichtung zur (n+m+q)-ten Zeiteinheit, falls bestimmt wird, das<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --> mindestens eines von CSI und SRS zur (n+m+q)-ten Zeiteinheit an die Netzwerkvorrichtung zu melden.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Verfahren gemäß Anspruch 1, wobei das Verfahren ferner umfasst:
<claim-text>Bestimmen durch die Endgerätevorrichtung im Voraus, ob sich die Endgerätevorrichtung zur (n+m+q)-ten Zeiteinheit in der aktiven Zeit des DRX befindet;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Bestimmen (S120) durch die Endgerätevorrichtung im Voraus, ob mindestens eines von Kanalzustandsinformationen, CSI, und Sondierungsreferenzsignal, SRS, zu einer (n+m+q)-ten Zeiteinheit an die Netzwerkvorrichtung zu melden ist, umfasst:
<claim-text>Bestimmen durch die Endgerätevorrichtung im Voraus, mindestens eines von CSI und SRS an die Netzwerkvorrichtung zu melden, falls sich die Endgerätevorrichtung zur (n+m+q)-ten Zeiteinheit in der aktiven Zeit des DRX befindet und in dem Fall, in dem mindestens eine von der CSI-Meldung und der SRS-Meldung zur (n+m+q)-ten Zeiteinheit eingerichtet ist; oder</claim-text>
<claim-text>Bestimmen durch die Endgerätevorrichtung im Voraus, mindestens eines von CSI und SRS nicht an die Netzwerkvorrichtung zu melden, falls sich die Endgerätevorrichtung zur (n+m+q)-ten Zeiteinheit nicht in der aktiven Zeit des DRX befindet.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Verfahren gemäß Anspruch 2, wobei das Bestimmen durch die Endgerätevorrichtung im Voraus, ob sich die Endgerätevorrichtung zur (n+m+q)-ten Zeiteinheit in der aktiven Zeit des DRX befindet, umfasst:
<claim-text>Bestimmen durch die Endgerätevorrichtung im Voraus, dass sich die Endgerätevorrichtung zur (n+m+q)-ten Zeiteinheit in der aktiven Zeit des DRX befindet, falls die (n+m+q)-te Zeiteinheit innerhalb einer Dauer eines ersten Zeitgebers liegt, wobei der Start oder Neustart des ersten Zeitgebers basierend auf den ersten Informationen oder den zweiten Informationen oder Informationen, die vorher eine Verlängerung der aktiven Zeit des DRX angeben, ausgelöst wird; oder<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>Bestimmen durch die Endgerätevorrichtung im Voraus, dass sich die Endgerätevorrichtung zur (n+m+q)-ten Zeiteinheit nicht in der aktiven Zeit des DRX befindet, falls die (n+m+q)-te Zeiteinheit eine Zeiteinheit nach einer Zeitüberschreitung des ersten Zeitgebers ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Verfahren gemäß einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 3, wobei die ersten Informationen Downlink-Steuerungsinformationen, DCI, zum zeitlichen Planen neuer Übertragungsdaten oder von Wiederholungsübertragungsdaten sind, wobei m ein Minimalwert in dem Zeitplanungszeitfolgesatz oder ein beliebiger Wert in dem Zeitplanungszeitfolgesatz ist, der durch die DCI angegeben wird.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Verfahren gemäß einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 3, wobei die ersten Informationen eine Mediumzugriffssteuerungs-, MAC-, Steuerelement-, CE-, Signalisierung sind, wobei m ein Minimalwert im ACK/NACK-Rückmeldungszeitfolgesatz oder ein beliebiger Wert im ACk/NACK-Rückmeldungszeitfolgesatz ist, der durch die ersten Informationen angegeben wird.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Verfahren gemäß einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 3, wobei die zweiten Informationen eine Zeitplanungsanforderung sind und m ein Minimalwert im ACK/NACK-Rückmeldungszeitfolgesatz ist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Verfahren gemäß einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 4, wobei die ersten Informationen Downlink-Steuerungsinformationen, DCI, zum zeitlichen Planen von Downlink-Daten sind, und das Verfahren ferner umfasst:
<claim-text>Empfangen eines physischen Downlink-Datenteilungskanals, PDSCH, durch die Endgerätevorrichtung, der die Downlink-Daten zu einer (n+p)-ten Zeiteinheit überträgt, wobei p ein Wert des Zeitplanungszeitfolgesatzes ist und der PDSCH eine Mediumzugriffssteuerungs-, MAC-, Steuerelement-, CE-, Signalisierung umfasst und das MAC<!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --> CE verwendet wird, um anzugeben, die aktive Zeit des DRX anzuhalten;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Bestimmen durch die Endgerätevorrichtung, ob mindestens eines von CSI und SRS an die Netzwerkvorrichtung zu einer (n+p+r+x)-ten Zeiteinheit zu melden ist, wobei r ein Minimalwert in dem ACK/NACK-Rückmeldungszeitfolgesatz oder ein beliebiger Wert des ACK/NACK-Rückmeldungszeitfolgesatzes ist, der durch die DCI angegeben wird, und p, r und x beliebige ganze Zahlen größer oder gleich 0 sind.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>Endgerätevorrichtung (200), umfassend:
<claim-text>eine Kommunikationseinheit (210), die dazu eingerichtet ist, erste Informationen zu empfangen, die durch eine Netzwerkvorrichtung zu einer n-ten Zeiteinheit gesendet werden, oder zweite Informationen an eine Netzwerkvorrichtung zu einer n-ten Zeiteinheit zu senden, wobei die ersten Informationen und die zweiten Informationen dazu verwendet werden, eine Verlängerung oder ein Anhalten einer aktiven Zeit des diskontinuierlichen Empfangs, DRX, anzugeben;</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> sie ferner umfasst:
<claim-text>eine Bestimmungseinheit (220), die dazu eingerichtet ist, im Voraus zu bestimmen, ob mindestens eines von Kanalzustandsinformationen, CSI, und Sondierungsreferenzsignal, SRS, zu einer (n+m+q)-ten Zeiteinheit an die Netzwerkvorrichtung zu melden sind, wobei m basierend auf mindestens einem von einem Zeitplanungszeitfolgesatz und einem Bestätigungs-/Negativbestätigungs-, ACK/NACK-, Rückmeldungszeitfolgesatz bestimmt wird, und der Zeitplanungszeitfolgesatz und der ACK/NACK-Rückmeldungszeitfolgesatz jeweils mehrere Werte umfassen, wobei n eine ganze Zahl ist und wobei m beliebige ganze Zahlen größer oder gleich 0 sind, und q=1, 2, 3, ..., Q, wobei Q beliebige ganze Zahlen größer als 1 sind;</claim-text>
<claim-text>die Kommunikationseinheit (210) ferner dazu eingerichtet ist, das mindestens eine von CSI und SRS an die Netzwerkvorrichtung zur (n+m+q)-ten Zeiteinheit zu<!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --> melden, falls bestimmt wird, das mindestens eines von CSI und SRS an die Netzwerkvorrichtung zur (n+m+q)-ten Zeiteinheit zu melden.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>Endgerätevorrichtung (200) gemäß Anspruch 8, wobei die Bestimmungseinheit (220) ferner dazu eingerichtet ist:
<claim-text>im Voraus zu bestimmen, ob sich die Endgerätevorrichtung zur (n+m+q)-ten Zeiteinheit in der aktiven Zeit des DRX befindet;</claim-text>
<claim-text>die Bestimmungseinheit (220) speziell dazu eingerichtet ist:
<claim-text>im Voraus zu bestimmen, mindestens eines von CSI und SRS an die Netzwerkvorrichtung zu melden, falls sich die Endgerätevorrichtung zur (n+m+q)-ten Zeiteinheit in der aktiven Zeit des DRX befindet und in dem Fall, in dem mindestens eines von CSI-Meldung und SRS-Meldung zur (n+m+q)-ten Zeiteinheit eingerichtet ist; oder</claim-text>
<claim-text>im Voraus zu bestimmen, mindestens eines von CSI und SRS nicht an die Netzwerkvorrichtung zu melden, wenn sich die Endgerätevorrichtung zur (n+m+q)-ten Zeiteinheit nicht in der aktiven Zeit des DRX befindet.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>Endgerätevorrichtung (200) gemäß Anspruch 9, wobei die Bestimmungseinheit (220) speziell dazu eingerichtet ist:
<claim-text>im Voraus zu bestimmen, dass sich die Endgerätevorrichtung zur (n+m+q)-ten Zeiteinheit in der aktiven Zeit des DRX befindet, falls die (n+m+q)-te Zeiteinheit innerhalb einer Dauer eines ersten Zeitgebers liegt, wobei der Start oder Neustart des ersten Zeitgebers basierend auf den ersten Informationen oder den zweiten Informationen oder Informationen, die vorher eine Verlängerung der aktiven Zeit des DRX angeben, ausgelöst wird; oder</claim-text>
<claim-text>im Voraus zu bestimmen, dass sich die Endgerätevorrichtung zur (n+m+q)-ten Zeiteinheit nicht in der aktiven Zeit des DRX befindet, falls die (n+m+q)-te Zeiteinheit eine Zeiteinheit nach einer Zeitüberschreitung des ersten Zeitgebers ist.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>Endgerätevorrichtung (200) gemäß einem der Ansprüche 8 bis 10, wobei die ersten Informationen Downlink-Steuerungsinformationen, DCI, zum zeitlichen Planen neuer Übertragungsdaten oder von Wiederholungsübertragungsdaten sind, wobei m ein Minimalwert in dem Zeitplanungszeitfolgesatz oder ein beliebiger Wert in dem Zeitplanungszeitfolgesatz ist, der durch die DCI angegeben wird.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>Endgerätevorrichtung (200) gemäß einem der Ansprüche 8 bis 10, wobei die ersten Informationen eine Mediumzugriffssteuerungs-, MAC-, Steuerelement-, CE-, Signalisierung sind, wobei m ein Minimalwert im Ack/NACK-Rückmeldungszeitfolgesatz oder ein beliebiger Wert im Ack/NACK-Rückmeldungszeitfolgesatz ist, der durch die ersten Informationen angegeben wird.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>Endgerätevorrichtung (200) gemäß einem der Ansprüche 8 bis 10, wobei die zweiten Informationen eine Zeitplanungsanforderung sind und m ein Minimalwert im ACK/NACK-Rückmeldungszeitfolgesatz ist.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>Endgerätevorrichtung (200) gemäß einem der Ansprüche 8 bis 11, wobei die ersten Informationen Downlink-Steuerungsinformationen, DCI, zum zeitlichen Planen von Downlink-Daten sind, und die Kommunikationseinheit (210) ferner dazu eingerichtet ist:
<claim-text>durch die Endgerätevorrichtung einen physischen Downlink-Datenteilungskanal, PDSCH, zu empfangen, der die Downlink-Daten zu einer (n+p)-ten Zeiteinheit zu übertragen, wobei p ein Wert des Zeitplanungszeitfolgesatzes ist und der PDSCH eine Mediumzugriffssteuerungs-, MAC-, Steuerelement-, CE-, Signalisierung umfasst und das MAC CE verwendet wird, um anzugeben, die aktive Zeit des DRX anzuhalten;</claim-text>
<claim-text>die Bestimmungseinheit (220) ferner dazu eingerichtet ist: zu bestimmen, ob mindestens eines von CSI und SRS an die Netzwerkvorrichtung zu einer (n+p+r+x)-ten Zeiteinheit<!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --> zu melden ist, wobei r ein Minimalwert in der ACK/NACK-Rückmeldungszeitfolge oder ein beliebiger Wert des ACK/NACK-Rückmeldungszeitfolgesatzes ist, der durch die DCI angegeben wird, und p, r und x beliebige ganze Zahlen größer oder gleich 0 sind.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-de-01-0015" num="0015">
<claim-text>Endgerätevorrichtung (200) gemäß einem der Ansprüche 8 bis 14, wobei eine Zeiteinheit ein Zeitschlitz oder ein Orthogonal-Frequenzteilungsmultiplex-, OFDM-, Symbol ist.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<claims id="claims03" lang="fr"><!-- EPO <DP n="35"> -->
<claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>Procédé de transmission d'informations, comprenant :
<claim-text>la réception (S110), par un dispositif terminal, de premières informations envoyées par un dispositif de réseau à une nième unité de temps, ou l'envoi, par un dispositif terminal, de deuxièmes informations au dispositif de réseau à une nième unité de temps, les premières informations et les deuxièmes informations étant utilisées pour indiquer la continuation ou l'arrêt d'un Temps actif de Réception Discontinue, DRX ;</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>caractérisé en ce que</b> le procédé comprend en outre :
<claim-text>la détermination (S120), par le dispositif terminal, à l'avance, de la notification ou non d'Informations d'Etat de Canal, CSI, et/ou d'un Signal de Référence de Sondage, SRS, au dispositif de réseau à une (n+m+q)ième unité de temps, où m est déterminé en fonction d'un ensemble de séquences temporelles d'ordonnancement et/ou d'un ensemble de séquences temporelles de retour d'Accusé de Réception, ACK/Accusé de Réception Négatif, NACK, et l'ensemble de séquences temporelles d'ordonnancement et l'ensemble de séquences temporelles de retour ACK/NACK comprennent respectivement de multiples valeurs, où n est un entier, et m est un entier quelconque supérieur à 0 ou égal à 0, et q = 1, 2, 3, ..., Q, où Q est un entier quelconque supérieure à 1 ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>la notification, par le dispositif terminal, des CSI et/ou du SRS au dispositif de réseau à la (n+m+q)ième unité de temps, s'il est déterminé de notifier les CSI<!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --> et/ou le SRS au dispositif de réseau à la (n+m+q) ième unité de temps.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, lequel procédé comprend en outre :
<claim-text>la détermination, par le dispositif terminal, à l'avance, du fait qu'à la (n+m+q)ième unité de temps le dispositif terminal est ou non dans le Temps actif de la DRX ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>la détermination (S120), par le dispositif terminal, à l'avance, de la notification ou non d'Informations d'Etat de Canal, CSI, et/ou d'un Signal de Référence de Sondage, SRS, au dispositif de réseau à une (n+m+q)ième unité de temps, comprend :
<claim-text>la détermination, par le dispositif terminal, à l'avance, de la notification des CSI et/ou du SRS au dispositif de réseau si, à la (n+m+q)ième unité de temps, le dispositif terminal est dans le Temps actif de la DRX et dans le cas où la notification des CSI et/ou la notification du SRS est configurée à la (n+m+q)ième unité de temps ; ou</claim-text>
<claim-text>la détermination, par le dispositif terminal, à l'avance, de la non notification des CSI et/ou du SRS au dispositif de réseau si, à la (n+m+q)ième unité de temps, le dispositif terminal n'est pas dans le Temps actif de la DRX.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 2, dans lequel la détermination, par le dispositif terminal, à l'avance, du fait qu'à la (n+m+q)ième unité de temps le dispositif terminal est ou non dans le Temps actif de la DRX comprend :
<claim-text>la détermination, par le dispositif terminal, à l'avance, du fait qu'à la (n+m+q)ième unité de temps le dispositif terminal est dans le Temps actif de la DRX si la (n+m+q)ième unité de temps est comprise dans une durée mesurée par un premier minuteur, le démarrage ou redémarrage du premier minuteur étant déclenché en fonction des premières informations ou des deuxième<!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --> informations ou d'informations indiquant au préalable de prolonger le Temps actif de la DRX ; ou</claim-text>
<claim-text>la détermination, par le dispositif terminal, à l'avance, du fait qu'à la (n+m+q)ième unité de temps le dispositif terminal n'est dans le Temps actif de la DRX si la (n+m+q)ième unité de temps est une unité de temps tombant après l'expiration du premier minuteur.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 3, dans lequel les premières informations sont des Informations de Commande de Liaison Descendante, DCI, pour l'ordonnancement de nouvelles données de transmission ou de données de retransmission, où m est une valeur minimale dans l'ensemble de séquences temporelles d'ordonnancement ou toute valeur dans l'ensemble de séquences temporelles d'ordonnancement indiquée par les DCI.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 3, dans lequel les premières informations sont une signalisation d'Elément de Commande, CE, de Commande d'Accès au Support, MAC, où m est une valeur minimale dans l'ensemble de séquences temporelles de retour ACK/NACK ou toute valeur dans l'ensemble de séquences temporelles de retour ACK/NACK indiquée par les premières informations.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 3, dans lequel les deuxièmes informations sont une demande d'ordonnancement, et m est une valeur minimale dans l'ensemble de séquences temporelles de retour ACK/NACK.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 4, dans lequel les premières informations sont des informations de commande de liaison descendante, DCI, pour l'ordonnancement de données de liaison descendante, et le procédé comprend en outre :<!-- EPO <DP n="38"> -->
<claim-text>la réception, par le dispositif terminal, d'un Canal Physique de Partage de Données de Liaison Descendante, PDSCH, qui transporte les données de liaison descendante à une (n+p) ième unité de temps, où p est une valeur de l'ensemble de séquences temporelles d'ordonnancement, et le PDSCH comprend une signalisation d'Elément de Commande, CE, de Commande d'Accès au Support, MAC, et le CE MAC est utilisé pour indiquer d'arrêter le Temps actif de la DRX ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>la détermination, par le dispositif terminal, de la notification ou non des CSI et/ou du SRS au dispositif de réseau à une (n+p+r+x) ième unité de temps, où r est une valeur minimale dans l'ensemble de séquences temporelles de retour ACK/NACK ou toute valeur dans l'ensemble de séquences temporelles de retour ACK/NACK indiquée par les DCI, et p, r et x sont des entiers quelconques supérieurs ou égaux à 0.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>Dispositif terminal (200), comprenant :
<claim-text>une unité de communication (210), configurée pour recevoir des premières informations envoyées par un dispositif de réseau à une nième unité de temps, ou envoyer des deuxièmes informations à un dispositif de réseau à une nième unité de temps, les premières informations et les deuxièmes informations étant utilisées pour indiquer la continuation ou l'arrêt d'un Temps actif de Réception Discontinue, DRX ;</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>caractérisé en ce qu'</b>il comprend en outre :
<claim-text>une unité de détermination (220), configurée pour déterminer à l'avance de notifier ou non des Informations d'Etat de Canal, CSI, et/ou un Signal de Référence de Sondage, SRS, au dispositif de réseau à une (n+m+q)ième unité de temps, où m est déterminé en fonction d'un ensemble de séquences temporelles d'ordonnancement et/ou d'un ensemble de séquences temporelles de retour d'Accusé de Réception, ACK/Accusé de Réception Négatif, NACK, et l'ensemble de séquences temporelles d'ordonnancement et l'ensemble de séquences temporelles de retour ACK/NACK comprennent respectivement de multiples valeurs, où n est un entier, et m est un entier quelconque supérieur à 0<!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --> ou égal à 0, et q = 1, 2, 3, ..., Q, où Q est un entier quelconque supérieure à 1 ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'unité de communication (210) étant en outre configurée pour notifier les CSI et/ou le SRS au dispositif de réseau à la (n+m+q)ième unité de temps, s'il est déterminé de notifier les CSI et/ou le SRS au dispositif de réseau à la (n+m+q)ième unité de temps.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>Dispositif terminal (200) selon la revendication 8, dans lequel l'unité de détermination (220) est en outre configurée pour :
<claim-text>déterminer à l'avance si, à la (n+m+q)ième unité de temps, le dispositif terminal est ou non dans le Temps actif de la DRX ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'unité de détermination (220) étant spécifiquement configurée pour :
<claim-text>déterminer à l'avance de notifier les CSI et/ou le SRS au dispositif de réseau si, à la (n+m+q)ième unité de temps, le dispositif terminal est dans le Temps actif de la DRX et dans le cas où la notification des CSI et/ou la notification du SRS est configurée à la (n+m+q)ième unité de temps ; ou</claim-text>
<claim-text>déterminer à l'avance de ne pas notifier les CSI et/ou le SRS au dispositif de réseau si, à la (n+m+q)ième unité de temps, le dispositif terminal n'est pas dans le Temps actif de la DRX.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>Dispositif terminal (200) selon la revendication 9, dans lequel l'unité de détermination (220) est spécifiquement configurée pour :
<claim-text>déterminer à l'avance qu'à la (n+m+q)ième unité de temps le dispositif terminal est dans le Temps actif de la DRX si la (n+m+q)ième unité de temps est comprise dans une durée mesurée par un premier minuteur, le démarrage ou redémarrage du premier minuteur étant déclenché en fonction des premières informations ou des deuxième informations ou d'informations indiquant au préalable de prolonger le Temps actif de la DRX ; ou<!-- EPO <DP n="40"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>déterminer à l'avance qu'à la (n+m+q)ième unité de temps le dispositif terminal n'est dans le Temps actif de la DRX si la (n+m+q)ième unité de temps est une unité de temps tombant après l'expiration du premier minuteur.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>Dispositif terminal (200) selon l'une quelconque des revendications 8 à 10, dans lequel les premières informations sont des Informations de Commande de Liaison Descendante, DCI, pour l'ordonnancement de nouvelles données de transmission ou de données de retransmission, où m est une valeur minimale dans l'ensemble de séquences temporelles d'ordonnancement ou toute valeur dans l'ensemble de séquences temporelles d'ordonnancement indiquée par les DCI.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012">
<claim-text>Dispositif terminal (200) selon l'une quelconque des revendications 8 à 10, dans lequel les premières informations sont une signalisation d'Elément de Commande, CE, de Commande d'Accès au Support, MAC, où m est une valeur minimale dans l'ensemble de séquences temporelles de retour ACK/NACK ou toute valeur dans l'ensemble de séquences temporelles de retour ACK/NACK indiquée par les premières informations.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013">
<claim-text>Dispositif terminal (200) selon l'une quelconque des revendications 8 à 10, dans lequel les deuxièmes informations sont une demande d'ordonnancement, et m est une valeur minimale dans l'ensemble de séquences temporelles de retour ACK/NACK.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014">
<claim-text>Dispositif terminal (200) selon l'une quelconque des revendications 8 à 11, dans lequel les premières informations sont des informations de commande de liaison descendante, DCI, pour l'ordonnancement de données de liaison descendante, et l'unité de communication (210) est en outre configurée pour :
<claim-text>recevoir un Canal Physique de Partage de Données de Liaison Descendante, PDSCH, qui transporte les données de liaison descendante à une (n+p)ième unité de temps,<!-- EPO <DP n="41"> --> où p est une valeur de l'ensemble de séquences temporelles d'ordonnancement, et le PDSCH comprend une signalisation d'Elément de Commande, CE, de Commande d'Accès au Support, MAC, et le CE MAC est utilisé pour indiquer d'arrêter le Temps actif de la DRX ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'unité de détermination (220) étant en outre configurée pour :<br/>
déterminer à l'avance de notifier ou non les CSI et/ou le SRS au dispositif de réseau à une (n+p+r+x)ième unité de temps, où r est une valeur minimale dans l'ensemble de séquences temporelles de retour ACK/NACK ou toute valeur dans l'ensemble de séquences temporelles de retour ACK/NACK indiquée par les DCI, et p, r et x sont des entiers quelconques supérieurs ou égaux à 0.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-fr-01-0015" num="0015">
<claim-text>Dispositif terminal (200) selon l'une quelconque des revendications 8 à 14, dans lequel une unité de temps est un créneau temporel ou un symbole de multiplexage par répartition orthogonale en fréquence, OFDM.</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="42"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="118" he="85" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="43"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="112" he="84" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="44"> -->
<figure id="f0003" num="3,4"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="146" he="152" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="45"> -->
<figure id="f0004" num="5"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="136" he="61" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="46"> -->
<figure id="f0005" num="6"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="137" he="97" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="47"> -->
<figure id="f0006" num="7,8"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="75" he="120" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<ep-reference-list id="ref-list">
<heading id="ref-h0001"><b>REFERENCES CITED IN THE DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0001" num=""><i>This list of references cited by the applicant is for the reader's convenience only. It does not form part of the European patent document. Even though great care has been taken in compiling the references, errors or omissions cannot be excluded and the EPO disclaims all liability in this regard.</i></p>
<heading id="ref-h0002"><b>Non-patent literature cited in the description</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0002" num="">
<ul id="ref-ul0001" list-style="bullet">
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0001" npl-type="s"><article><atl>Handling of the DRX Ambiguous Period</atl><serial><sertitle>3GPP TSG-RAN WG2 #101 R2-1802147</sertitle></serial></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0001">[0003]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0002" npl-type="s"><article><atl>Leftover Issues on DRX</atl><serial><sertitle>3GPP TSG-RAN WG2 #Adhoc R2-1800166</sertitle></serial></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0002">[0004]</crossref></li>
<li><nplcit id="ref-ncit0003" npl-type="s"><article><atl>3rd Generation Partnership Project; Technical Specification Group Radio Access Network; NR; Medium Access Control (MAC) protocol specification (Release 15)</atl><serial><sertitle>3GPP TS 38.321 V15.1.0</sertitle></serial></article></nplcit><crossref idref="ncit0003">[0005]</crossref></li>
</ul></p>
</ep-reference-list>
</ep-patent-document>
