<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5.1//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5-1.dtd">
<!-- This XML data has been generated under the supervision of the European Patent Office -->
<ep-patent-document id="EP20193398A1" file="EP20193398NWA1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3890190" kind="A1" date-publ="20211006" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5-1">
<SDOBI lang="en"><B000><eptags><B001EP>ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSKBAHRIS..MTNORSMESMMAKHTNMD..........</B001EP><B005EP>J</B005EP><B007EP>BDM Ver 2.0.12 (4th of August) -  1100000/0</B007EP></eptags></B000><B100><B110>3890190</B110><B120><B121>EUROPEAN PATENT APPLICATION</B121></B120><B130>A1</B130><B140><date>20211006</date></B140><B190>EP</B190></B100><B200><B210>20193398.3</B210><B220><date>20200828</date></B220><B250>en</B250><B251EP>en</B251EP><B260>en</B260></B200><B300><B310>202016837896</B310><B320><date>20200401</date></B320><B330><ctry>US</ctry></B330></B300><B400><B405><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B405><B430><date>20211006</date><bnum>202140</bnum></B430></B400><B500><B510EP><classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>H03K  17/06        20060101AFI20210423BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="2"><text>H03K  17/0812      20060101ALI20210423BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr sequence="3"><text>H03K  17/689       20060101ALI20210423BHEP        </text></classification-ipcr></B510EP><B520EP><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="1"><text>H03K  17/689       20130101 LI20210114BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="2"><text>H03K2217/0081      20130101 LA20210114BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="3"><text>H03K  17/08128     20130101 LI20210114BHEP        </text></classification-cpc><classification-cpc sequence="4"><text>H03K  17/06        20130101 FI20210114BHEP        </text></classification-cpc></classifications-cpc></B520EP><B540><B541>de</B541><B542>GATE-TREIBERSCHALTUNG MIT REDUZIERTEM LEISTUNGSHALBLEITER-LEITUNGSVERLUST</B542><B541>en</B541><B542>GATE DRIVER CIRCUIT WITH REDUCED POWER SEMICONDUCTOR CONDUCTION LOSS</B542><B541>fr</B541><B542>CIRCUIT D'ATTAQUE DE GRILLE À PERTE DE CONDUCTION DE SEMI-CONDUCTEUR DE PUISSANCE RÉDUITE</B542></B540><B590><B598>2</B598><B598>3</B598></B590></B500><B700><B710><B711><snm>Delta Electronics, Inc.</snm><iid>101162235</iid><irf>P 110233</irf><adr><str>186 Ruey Kuang Road</str><city>Neihu, Taipei 11491</city><ctry>TW</ctry></adr></B711></B710><B720><B721><snm>Zhou, Yan</snm><adr><str>49756 Great Falls Road</str><city>Canton, MI Michigan 48188</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>Klesyk, Krzysztof</snm><adr><str>48804 Pebble Lane</str><city>Novi, MI Michigan 48374</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>Hampo, Richard Joseph</snm><adr><str>5333 Dixboro Farms Drive</str><city>Ann Arbor, MI Michigan 48105</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B721><B721><snm>Gui, Yingying</snm><adr><str>25822 Wembley Drive</str><city>Novi, MI Michigan 48374</city><ctry>US</ctry></adr></B721></B720><B740><B741><snm>Uexküll &amp; Stolberg</snm><iid>101312292</iid><adr><str>Partnerschaft von 
Patent- und Rechtsanwälten mbB 
Beselerstraße 4</str><city>22607 Hamburg</city><ctry>DE</ctry></adr></B741></B740></B700><B800><B840><ctry>AL</ctry><ctry>AT</ctry><ctry>BE</ctry><ctry>BG</ctry><ctry>CH</ctry><ctry>CY</ctry><ctry>CZ</ctry><ctry>DE</ctry><ctry>DK</ctry><ctry>EE</ctry><ctry>ES</ctry><ctry>FI</ctry><ctry>FR</ctry><ctry>GB</ctry><ctry>GR</ctry><ctry>HR</ctry><ctry>HU</ctry><ctry>IE</ctry><ctry>IS</ctry><ctry>IT</ctry><ctry>LI</ctry><ctry>LT</ctry><ctry>LU</ctry><ctry>LV</ctry><ctry>MC</ctry><ctry>MK</ctry><ctry>MT</ctry><ctry>NL</ctry><ctry>NO</ctry><ctry>PL</ctry><ctry>PT</ctry><ctry>RO</ctry><ctry>RS</ctry><ctry>SE</ctry><ctry>SI</ctry><ctry>SK</ctry><ctry>SM</ctry><ctry>TR</ctry></B840><B844EP><B845EP><ctry>BA</ctry></B845EP><B845EP><ctry>ME</ctry></B845EP></B844EP><B848EP><B849EP><ctry>KH</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>MA</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>MD</ctry></B849EP><B849EP><ctry>TN</ctry></B849EP></B848EP></B800></SDOBI>
<abstract id="abst" lang="en">
<p id="pa01" num="0001">A gate driver circuit (200, 400) receiving an input control signal (106) and providing a voltage at a gate terminal (102) of a semiconductor switching device (101) (e.g., an IGBT) may include: (i) a first voltage source (202) providing a first voltage; (ii) a second voltage source (109) providing a second voltage, wherein the first voltage is higher than the second voltage; and (iii) a selector circuit (203) selecting either the first voltage or the second voltage to be placed on the gate terminal (102) of the semiconductor switching device (101) based on the input control signal's logic state.
<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="160" he="94" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
<img id="iaf02" file="imgaf002.tif" wi="127" he="102" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p>
</abstract>
<description id="desc" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
<heading id="h0001">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to driver circuits for power semiconductor devices, such as driver circuits for insulated-gate bipolar transistors (IGBTs) or metal-oxide-semiconductor field-effect transistors (MOSFETs) in high-voltage, high-current applications.</p>
<heading id="h0002">DISCUSSION OF THE RELATED ART</heading>
<p id="p0002" num="0002"><figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> shows a conventional gate driver circuit 100 for driving a gate terminal of a power semiconductor device 101. In <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, the power semiconductor device 101 is exemplified by an IGBT; however, the power semiconductor device 101 may be any one of numerous other devices (e.g., a MOSFET). As known to those of ordinary skill in the art, the conventional gate driver circuit 100 often includes also signal isolation, power supply, monitoring and protection circuits. These other circuits are omitted from <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, for clarity of illustration. As shown in <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, the gate driver circuit 100 includes (i) a buffer stage 108 formed, for example, by bipolar junction transistors (BJTs) NPN BJT Q<sub>1</sub> and PNP BJT Q<sub>2</sub>; and (ii) turn-on and turn-off gate resistors Ron and Roff. The buffer stage 108 is connected between a power supply circuit 109 (e.g., + 15 volts) and the ground reference. The gate driver circuit 100 receives an input control signal 106 (e.g., an input control signal from a microprocessor) and provides an output signal at the gate terminal 102 of the IGBT 101. The input control signal 106 causes the buffer stage 108 to turn on either the NPN BJT Q<sub>1</sub> or the PNP BJT Q<sub>2</sub> to charge or discharge the gate terminal 102 of the IGBT 101. Although the NPN BJT Q<sub>1</sub> and PNP BJT Q<sub>2</sub> are used<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> to illustrate the buffer stage 108, other switching devices, such as MOSFETs, may also be used to implement the buffer stage 108. When the input control signal 106 is at a high voltage, the NPN BJT Q<sub>1</sub> is conducting, thereby charging the capacitance of the gate terminal 102 of the IGBT 101 to the voltage of the power supply circuit 109 through the resistor Ron. Conversely, when the input control signal 106 is at a low voltage, the PNP BJT Q<sub>2</sub> is conducting, thereby discharging the capacitance at the gate terminal 102 of the IGBT 101 to ground through the resistor Roff.</p>
<p id="p0003" num="0003">Because of the transconductance of the IGBT 101, current i<sub>C</sub> at a collector terminal 103 of the IGBT 101 is determined by the gate-emitter voltage (V<sub>GE</sub>) across the gate terminal 102 and an emitter terminal 104 of the IGBT 101. The higher voltage V<sub>GE</sub> is, the higher is current i<sub>C</sub>, which results in a lower collector-emitter voltage (V<sub>CE</sub>) at which current i<sub>C</sub> becomes saturated. To achieve the lowest possible conduction losses, a high voltage from the power supply circuit 109 is preferred. However, the resulting higher gate-emitter voltage V<sub>GE</sub> may result in a correspondingly higher short-circuit current, if a short-circuit condition occurs. This is because, under a short circuit condition, the higher gate-emitter voltage (V<sub>GE</sub>) causes the collector current i<sub>C</sub> to increase more rapidly than when a lower gate-emitter voltage is present. Also, as the gate terminal 102 is fully charged, the collector current i<sub>C</sub> has a higher value, as the IGBT 101 is operating at a higher desaturation current level. Taking all these factors into consideration, the output voltage of the power supply circuit 109 is usually selected, as a tradeoff, to be +15 volts.</p>
<p id="p0004" num="0004">Various schemes to improve the gate driver circuit of a power semiconductor device are known in the prior art. For example, <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US7265601B"><text>U.S. Patent 7,265,601 ("Ahmad</text></patcit>"), entitled "Adaptive Gate Drive Voltage Circuit",<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> discloses a method that reduces losses in a DC/DC converter by optimizing gate drive voltage. In Ahmad, the driver circuit adjusts the gate voltage based on the output load current; specifically, the gate voltage is reduced at a low load current and increased at a high load current. As another example, <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="US9444448B"><text>U.S. Patent 9,444,448 ("Wagoner</text></patcit>"), entitled "High performance IGBT gate drive", discloses applying one or more intermediate voltages near the IGBT's threshold voltage to control the rate of change of the collector-emitter voltage and the rate of change of the collector current during turn-off. Wagoner's scheme optimizes for reducing switching loss.</p>
<heading id="h0003">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p0005" num="0005">According to one embodiment of the present invention, a gate driver circuit receiving an input control signal and providing a voltage at a gate terminal of a semiconductor switching device (e.g., an IGBT) may include: (i) a first voltage source providing a first voltage; (ii) a second voltage source providing a second voltage, wherein the first voltage is higher than the second voltage; and (iii) a selector circuit selecting either the first voltage or the second voltage to be placed on the gate terminal of the semiconductor switching device based on the input control signal's logic state. The selector circuit may delay the input control signal by a predetermined time interval.</p>
<p id="p0006" num="0006">In one embodiment, the selector circuit includes (i) a first transistor providing the first voltage source to the gate terminal of the semiconductor switching device in a conducting state, the first transistor having a gate terminal that receives an enable signal that causes it to switch between the conducting state and a non-conducting state; and (ii) a second transistor receiving the input control signal and providing the enable signal to the gate terminal of the first transistor according to the input control<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> signal's logic state. An RC circuit may be provided in the signal path of the enable signal, such that, when the first transistor connects the first voltage source to the gate terminal of the semiconductor switching device, the voltage at the gate terminal of the semiconductor switching device rises to the first voltage at a slew rate determined by the RC circuit.</p>
<p id="p0007" num="0007">In one embodiment, a buffer stage is connected between a power supply terminal and a ground reference, wherein the selector circuit provides the selected voltage at the power supply terminal of the buffer stage, and wherein the buffer stage has an output terminal coupled to the gate terminal of the semiconductor switching device, and wherein the buffer stage provides the voltage at its power supply terminal to its output terminal based on the input control signal's logic state. The output terminal of the buffer stage may be coupled to the gate terminal of the semiconductor switching device by a resistor.</p>
<p id="p0008" num="0008">In one embodiment, the second voltage source may include a voltage regulator that receives the first voltage as an input voltage, and wherein the voltage regulator provides the second voltage as a regulated output voltage.</p>
<p id="p0009" num="0009">In one embodiment, the circuitry in the gate driver circuit is divided into a high-voltage domain and a low-voltage domain that are isolated from each other, wherein the first and the second voltages are signals in the high-voltage domain and wherein the input control signal is a signal in the low-voltage domain.</p>
<p id="p0010" num="0010">The input control signal may be provided from a control circuit, such as a microprocessor.</p>
<p id="p0011" num="0011">The present invention is better understood upon consideration of the detailed description below in conjunction with the drawings.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p>
<heading id="h0004">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p0012" num="0012">
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none" compact="compact">
<li><figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> shows a conventional gate driver circuit 100 for driving a gate terminal of a power semiconductor device 101;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> shows a gate driver circuit 200 in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention;</li>
<li><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates an operation of a power supply selector circuit 203 in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention; and</li>
<li><figref idref="f0004">FIG. 4</figref> shows a gate driver circuit 400, which is one implementation of the gate driver circuit 200 of <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>.</li>
</ul></p>
<p id="p0013" num="0013">To facilitate cross-referencing among the FIG.s, like elements are assigned like reference numerals.</p>
<heading id="h0005">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p0014" num="0014">The present disclosure will now be described more specifically with reference to the following embodiments. It is to be noted that the following descriptions of preferred embodiments of this disclosure are presented herein for purpose of illustration and description only. It is not intended to be exhaustive or to be limited to the precise form disclosed.</p>
<p id="p0015" num="0015">The present invention provides a gate driver circuit that provides an adjustable output power supply voltage for driving a gate terminal of a power semiconductor device. The adjustable output power supply voltage reduces the saturation voltage in the power semiconductor device during turn-on, without compromising its desirable short-circuit current characteristics. <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> shows a gate driver circuit 200 in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. In <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>, in addition to a power supply circuit 109, buffer stage 108, turn-on and turn-off resistors Ron and Roff of <figref idref="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, the gate driver circuit 200 also includes a<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> higher-voltage power supply circuit 202, a power supply selection circuit 201, a power supply selector circuit 203 and a control circuit 204. In the gate driver circuit 200, the power supply selector circuit 203 causes the power supply selection circuit 201 to select the output voltage of either the power supply circuit 109 or the higher-voltage power supply circuit 202 to place at a terminal 112 as the power supply voltage to drive a gate terminal 102 of an IGBT 101, during different times of the IGBT operations. The higher-voltage power supply circuit 202 provides at the terminal 112 a higher voltage (e.g., 18.5 volts) than the voltage (e.g., 15 volts) supplied by the power supply circuit 109. The power supply selection circuit 201 may be implemented by one or more semiconductor switches and the power supply selector circuit 203 may be implemented by a logic circuit that operates the switches in the power supply selection circuit 201.</p>
<p id="p0016" num="0016"><figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates an operation of the power supply selector circuit 203 in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. As shown in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref>, waveform 351 represents an input control signal 106 received into the buffer stage 108 and the power supply selector circuit 203. Waveform 352 represents the voltage waveform at the gate terminal 102. When the IGBT 101 is turned off, the voltage at the terminal 112 is provided by the power supply circuit 109 (i.e., 15 volts). When the input control signal 106 goes high at time t<sub>0</sub>, turn-on transistor Q<sub>1</sub> turns on and the gate terminal 102 of the IGBT 101 goes to the lower supply voltage (i.e., 15 volts), such that collector current i<sub>C</sub> increases at a limited slew rate. Therefore, if a short-circuit condition exists at this time, the short-circuit current is limited by the lower power supply voltage. With the lower power supply voltage at its gate terminal 102, the desaturation current in the IGBT 101 is also limited.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p>
<p id="p0017" num="0017">After a predetermined delay (i.e., time interval (t<sub>1</sub> - t<sub>0</sub>)), the power supply selector circuit 203 causes the voltage at the terminal 112 to be sourced from the higher-voltage power supply 202 (e.g., at 18.5 volts), which increases the voltage at the gate terminal 102 of the IGBT 101. At this higher voltage, the IGBT 101's saturation voltage across a collector terminal 103 and an emitter terminal 104 (i.e., V<sub>CE</sub>) is reduced. When the input control signal 106 returns to low, the power supply selector circuit 203 causes the voltage at the terminal 112 to be sourced from the power supply circuit 109 (i.e., returning the voltage at the terminal 112 to 15 volts). In some embodiments, the transition between the power supply circuit 109 to the higher-voltage power supply circuit 202 (i.e., from 15 volts to 18.5 volts), and vice versa, can occur gradually over a predetermined time period. For example, the transition can be controlled by an RC circuit; in that case, the voltage at the terminal 112 rises or falls at a rate that may be characterized by a time constant.</p>
<p id="p0018" num="0018"><figref idref="f0004">FIG. 4</figref> shows a gate driver circuit 400, which is one implementation of the gate driver circuit 200 of <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>. As shown in <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 4</figref>, the circuitry of the gate driver circuit 400 is divided into a low-voltage domain 400a and a high-voltage domain 400b. The low-voltage domain 400a includes logic circuits that provide the control functions of the gate driver circuit 400, and the high-voltage domain 400b includes a high-voltage circuitry that drives the gate terminal 102 of the IGBT 101. Circuitry in the low-voltage domain 400a may be isolated from circuitry in the high-voltage domain 400b using conventional isolation techniques, such as optical isolation or other semiconductor devices.</p>
<p id="p0019" num="0019">As show in <figref idref="f0004">FIG. 4</figref>, a power supply transformer 308 implements the higher supply voltage (e.g., 18.5 volts) of the higher-voltage power supply circuit 202 of <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>. The power supply<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> transformer 308 is enabled and initialized by a low-voltage logic circuit (i.e., power supply driver 305). The control circuit 204 of <figref idref="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> is implemented in the gate driver circuit 400 by a microprocessor 204, which issues the input control signal 106 to a logic circuit 306 and an isolated gate driver integrated circuit 307. The isolated gate driver integrated circuit 307, which receives the higher supply voltage from the higher-voltage power supply circuit 202, includes a voltage regulator 309 which provides a regulated output voltage (e.g., 15 volts) on the terminal 112. In this manner, the isolated gate driver integrated circuit 307 implements the power supply circuit 109. In addition, the buffer stage 108 is also implemented in the isolated gate driver integrated circuit 307 by supplying the voltage at the terminal 112 to a terminal 110 during turn-on and by grounding terminal 111 during turn-off. The isolated gate driver integrated circuit 307 may be implemented by, for example, an MC33GD3100 integrated circuit from NXP semiconductors N.V.</p>
<p id="p0020" num="0020">In one embodiment, the digital logic circuit 306 delays the input control signal 106 by the predetermine delay (e.g., time interval (t<sub>1</sub> - t<sub>0</sub>) in <figref idref="f0003">FIG. 3</figref>). The delayed input control signal 106 enters the high-voltage domain 400b through the digital signal isolator circuit 301 to turn on PMOS driver 302 which, in turn, turns on a PMOS transistor 303. Conducting the PMOS transistor 303 places the higher supply voltage of the power supply transformer 308 on the terminal 112. The PMOS driver 302 may be implemented by a bipolar transistor (e.g., a un2217 bipolar transistor) driving an RC circuit that achieves a more gradual slew rate (i.e., with an RC time constant) to transition to the higher supply voltage. As the voltage at the terminal 112 rises, the voltage regulator 309 turns off, and the higher supply voltage is provided on the terminal 110 of the turn-on resistor Ron. During turn-off, the PMOS driver 302 turns off the PMOS transistor<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> 303 and the terminal 112 returns to the regulated output voltage of the voltage regulator 309.</p>
<p id="p0021" num="0021">Without impacting short-circuit performance, the method of the present invention drives the gate terminal of a power semiconductor device at a higher power supply voltage to achieve a reduced saturation voltage in the power semiconductor device during conduction. In this manner, the trade-off in a conventional gate driver circuit between a lower saturation voltage when the power semiconductor device is conducting and a high short-circuit current is avoided. Since the voltage at the gate terminal of the power semiconductor device is increased during its conducting state, the power semiconductor device's conduction loss is reduced, thereby resulting in both enhanced system efficiency and a reduced thermal stress.</p>
</description>
<claims id="claims01" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="10"> -->
<claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001">
<claim-text>A gate driver circuit (200, 400) receiving an input control signal (106) and providing a voltage at a gate terminal (102) of a semiconductor switching device (101), comprising:
<claim-text>a first voltage source (202) providing a first voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second voltage source (109) providing a second voltage, wherein the first voltage is higher than the second voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a selector circuit (203) selecting either the first voltage or the second voltage to be placed on the gate terminal (102) of the semiconductor switching device (101) based on the input control signal's logic state.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002">
<claim-text>The gate driver circuit (200, 400) of Claim 1, wherein the selector circuit (203) delays the input control signal (106) by a predetermined time interval.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003">
<claim-text>The gate driver circuit (200, 400) of Claim 1, wherein the selector circuit (203) comprises:
<claim-text>a first transistor (303) providing the first voltage source (202) to the gate terminal (102) of the semiconductor switching device (101) in a conducting state, the first transistor (303) having a gate terminal that receives an enable signal that causes it to switch between the conducting state and a non-conducting state; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second transistor (302) receiving the input control signal (106) and providing the enable signal to the gate terminal of the first transistor (303) according to the input control signal's logic state.</claim-text></claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004">
<claim-text>The gate driver circuit (200, 400) of Claim 3, further comprising an RC circuit in the signal path of the enable signal, such that when the first transistor (303) connects the first voltage source (202) to the gate terminal<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> (102) of the semiconductor switching device (101), the voltage at the gate terminal (102) of the semiconductor switching device (101) rises to the first voltage at a slew rate determined by the RC circuit.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005">
<claim-text>The gate driver circuit (200, 400) of Claim 1, further comprising a buffer stage (108) connected between a power supply terminal (112) and a ground reference, wherein the selector circuit (203) provides the selected voltage at the power supply terminal (112) of the buffer stage (108).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006">
<claim-text>The gate driver circuit (200, 400) of Claim 5, wherein the buffer stage (108) has an output terminal coupled to the gate terminal (102) of the semiconductor switching device (101), and wherein the buffer stage (108) provides the voltage at its power supply terminal (112) to its output terminal based on the input control signal's logic state.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007">
<claim-text>The gate driver circuit (200, 400) of Claim 6, wherein the output terminal of the buffer stage (108) is coupled to the gate terminal (102) of the semiconductor switching device (101) by a resistor (Ron, Roff).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008">
<claim-text>The gate driver circuit (200, 400) of Claim 1, wherein the second voltage source (109) comprises a voltage regulator (309) receiving the first voltage as an input voltage, and wherein the voltage regulator (309) provides the second voltage as a regulated output voltage.</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009">
<claim-text>The gate driver circuit (200, 400) of Claim 1, comprising a high-voltage domain (400b) and a low-voltage domain (400a) that are isolated from each other, wherein the first and the second voltages are signals in the high-voltage domain (400b) and wherein the input control signal (106) is a signal in the low-voltage domain (400a).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010">
<claim-text>The gate driver circuit (200, 400) of Claim 1, wherein the input<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> control signal (106) is received from a control circuit (204).</claim-text></claim>
<claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011">
<claim-text>The gate driver circuit (200, 400) of Claim 10, wherein the control circuit (204) comprises a microprocessor (204).</claim-text></claim>
</claims>
<drawings id="draw" lang="en"><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> -->
<figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="118" he="141" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> -->
<figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="131" he="220" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> -->
<figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="104" he="129" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> -->
<figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="150" he="200" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure>
</drawings>
<search-report-data id="srep" lang="en" srep-office="EP" date-produced=""><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="157" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="157" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0003" file="srep0003.tif" wi="157" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0004" file="srep0004.tif" wi="155" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data><search-report-data date-produced="20210121" id="srepxml" lang="en" srep-office="EP" srep-type="ep-sr" status="n"><!--
 The search report data in XML is provided for the users' convenience only. It might differ from the search report of the PDF document, which contains the officially published data. The EPO disclaims any liability for incorrect or incomplete data in the XML for search reports.
 -->

<srep-info><file-reference-id>P 110233</file-reference-id><application-reference><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>20193398.3</doc-number></document-id></application-reference><applicant-name><name>Delta Electronics, Inc.</name></applicant-name><srep-established srep-established="yes"/><srep-unity-of-invention><p id="pu0001" num="">1. claims: 1-7, 9-11<br/>Gate driver circuit with selectable voltage supply</p><p id="pu0002" num="">1.1. claims: 1-4, 10<br/>Implementation details of the gate driver circuit</p><p id="pu0003" num="">1.2. claims: 5-7<br/>Buffer stage in the gate driver circuit</p><p id="pu0004" num="">1.3. claim: 9<br/>High and low voltage domains in the gate driver circuit</p><p id="pu0005" num="">1.4. claim: 11<br/>Control circuit of the gate driver circuit comprising a microprocessor</p><p id="pu0006" num="">2. claim: 8<br/>Voltage regulator providing the second voltage from the first voltage</p><p id="pu0007" num="">Please note that all inventions mentioned under item 1, although not necessarily linked by a common inventive concept, could be searched without effort justifying an additional fee.</p><srep-search-fees><srep-fee-4><claim-num>1-7, 9-11</claim-num></srep-fee-4></srep-search-fees></srep-unity-of-invention><srep-invention-title title-approval="yes"/><srep-abstract abs-approval="yes"/><srep-figure-to-publish figinfo="by-examiner"><figure-to-publish><fig-number>2,3</fig-number></figure-to-publish></srep-figure-to-publish><srep-info-admin><srep-office><addressbook><text>DH</text></addressbook></srep-office><date-search-report-mailed><date>20210430</date></date-search-report-mailed></srep-info-admin></srep-info><srep-for-pub><srep-fields-searched><minimum-documentation><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr><text>H03K</text></classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr></minimum-documentation></srep-fields-searched><srep-citations><citation id="sr-cit0001"><patcit dnum="US2009066402A1" id="sr-pcit0001" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=US2009066402&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2009066402</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>HIYAMA KAZUAKI [JP]</name><date>20090312</date></document-id></patcit><category>X</category><rel-claims>1-4,9-11</rel-claims><category>Y</category><rel-claims>5-7</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* paragraph [0083] - paragraph [0084]; figures 1, 3, 4, 5 *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0002"><patcit dnum="US6333665B1" id="sr-pcit0002" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=US6333665&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>6333665</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><name>ICHIKAWA KOHSAKU [JP]</name><date>20011225</date></document-id></patcit><category>X</category><rel-claims>1-4,9-11</rel-claims><category>A</category><rel-claims>5-7</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* the whole document *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0003"><patcit dnum="JP2012049946A" id="sr-pcit0003" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=JP2012049946&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2012049946</doc-number><kind>A</kind><name>TOYOTA MOTOR CORP</name><date>20120308</date></document-id></patcit><category>Y</category><rel-claims>5-7</rel-claims><category>A</category><rel-claims>1-4,9-11</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* abstract; figure 1 *</passage></rel-passage></citation><citation id="sr-cit0004"><patcit dnum="US2016226386A1" id="sr-pcit0004" url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=US2016226386&amp;CY=ep"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2016226386</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><name>FUKUTA JUNICHI [JP]</name><date>20160804</date></document-id></patcit><category>A</category><rel-claims>1-7,9-11</rel-claims><rel-passage><passage>* abstract; figure 2 *</passage></rel-passage></citation></srep-citations><srep-admin><examiners><primary-examiner><name>Fermentel, Thomas</name></primary-examiner></examiners><srep-office><addressbook><text>The Hague</text></addressbook></srep-office><date-search-completed><date>20210121</date></date-search-completed></srep-admin><!--							The annex lists the patent family members relating to the patent documents cited in the above mentioned European search report.							The members are as contained in the European Patent Office EDP file on							The European Patent Office is in no way liable for these particulars which are merely given for the purpose of information.							For more details about this annex : see Official Journal of the European Patent Office, No 12/82						--><srep-patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2009066402</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20090312</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2009071956</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20090402</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2009066402</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20090312</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2010148846</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20100617</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>6333665</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20011225</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>AU</country><doc-number>735847</doc-number><kind>B2</kind><date>20010719</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>CN</country><doc-number>1264955</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20000830</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>3666843</doc-number><kind>B2</kind><date>20050629</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2000253646</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20000914</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>6333665</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20011225</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2012049946</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120308</date></document-id></priority-application><text>NONE</text></patent-family><patent-family><priority-application><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2016226386</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20160804</date></document-id></priority-application><family-member><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>6394421</doc-number><kind>B2</kind><date>20180926</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2016144255</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20160808</date></document-id></family-member><family-member><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2016226386</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20160804</date></document-id></family-member></patent-family></srep-patent-family></srep-for-pub></search-report-data>
<ep-reference-list id="ref-list">
<heading id="ref-h0001"><b>REFERENCES CITED IN THE DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0001" num=""><i>This list of references cited by the applicant is for the reader's convenience only. It does not form part of the European patent document. Even though great care has been taken in compiling the references, errors or omissions cannot be excluded and the EPO disclaims all liability in this regard.</i></p>
<heading id="ref-h0002"><b>Patent documents cited in the description</b></heading>
<p id="ref-p0002" num="">
<ul id="ref-ul0001" list-style="bullet">
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0001" dnum="US7265601B"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>7265601</doc-number><kind>B</kind><name>Ahmad</name></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0001">[0004]</crossref></li>
<li><patcit id="ref-pcit0002" dnum="US9444448B"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>9444448</doc-number><kind>B</kind><name>Wagoner</name></document-id></patcit><crossref idref="pcit0002">[0004]</crossref></li>
</ul></p>
</ep-reference-list>
</ep-patent-document>
